<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=science&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/science</title><description>Hot posts in /r/science (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:28:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_mouw-styles-communityIcon_xtjipkhhefi41-144x400.png</url><title>/r/science</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://newatlas.com/adhd-autism/adhd-brains-mri-scans/</link><title>ADHD brains really are built differently – we've just been blinded by the noise | Scientists eliminate the gray area when it comes to gray matter in ADHD brains (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2oxu/adhd_brains_really_are_built_differently_weve/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2oxu/adhd_brains_really_are_built_differently_weve/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2oxu/adhd_brains_really_are_built_differently_weve/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/ae65cf9/2147483647/strip/true/crop/8168x4288+0+578/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F98%2F27%2Fbba57b0044c7ab2a9f2f392a9a2f%2Fdepositphotos-479798050-xl.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study significantly strengthens the case that attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) brains are structurally unique, thanks to a new scanning technique known as the traveling-subject method. It isn't down to new technology &ndash; but better use of it.</p><p>A team of Japanese scientists led by Chiba University has corrected the inconsistencies in brain scans of <a href="https://newatlas.com/tag/adhd/">ADHD</a> individuals, where mixed results from <a href="https://newatlas.com/tag/mri/">magnetic resonance imaging</a> (MRI) studies left researchers unable to say for certain whether neurodivergency could be identified in the lab. Some studies reported smaller <a href="https://newatlas.com/clarity-transparent-brain/27024/">gray matter volumes</a> in children with ADHD compared to those without, while others showed no difference or even larger volumes. With some irony, it's been a gray area for diagnostics and research.</p><p>Here, the researchers employed an innovative technique called the traveling-subject (TS) method, which removed the "technical noise" that has traditionally distorted multi-site MRI studies. The result is a more reliable look at the ADHD brain &ndash; and a clearer picture of how the condition is linked to structural differences.</p><p>Essentially, different hospitals, clinics or research facilities use different scanners, with varying calibration, coils and software. When researchers pool data from multiple sites, they risk confusing biological variation with machine error. Statistical correction tools exist &ndash; like the widely used &ldquo;ComBat&rdquo; method &ndash; but these can sometimes overcorrect, erasing real biological signals along with noise. That&rsquo;s a big problem for conditions like ADHD, where the predicted structural differences are subtle &ndash; so if the measurement noise is louder than the biological effect, results end up contradictory.</p><p>The TS method takes a more hands-on approach &ndash;&nbsp;basically making the scans uniform across a study group. The researchers recruited 14 non-ADHD volunteers and scanned each of them across four different MRI machines over three months. Since the same person&rsquo;s brain doesn&rsquo;t change in that short window, any differences between scans are from the machines themselves. This template served as a sort of neurotypical control, which allowed the researchers to further investigate a much larger dataset from the Child Developmental MRI database, which included 178 "typically developing" children and 116 kids with ADHD.</p><p>What they found was that once the scanner bias was removed, the results became much clearer. Children with ADHD showed smaller brain volumes in the <a href="https://newatlas.com/molecular-scaffold-neurodegenerative-disease-dementia-motor-neuron/32400/">frontotemporal regions</a> compared to their typically developing peers. These brain areas are central to attention and information processing, emotional regulation, executive function and decision-making &ndash;&nbsp;all markers of ADHD.</p><p>"Despite these promising results, this study had some limitations," the team noted in the paper. "The study sample may not fully represent the broader population of children with ADHD. The participants were drawn from specific geographical regions and clinical settings, which could limit the generalizability of the findings to other populations. Additionally, this study only examined the brain structure characteristics in children with ADHD elucidated using harmonization."</p><p>While the new findings will need to be validated on a larger scale, the TS method could help with earlier diagnosis of ADHD and personalized treatments that track how therapies affect brain structure. It could also remove some of the stigma associated with ADHD, offering black-and-white, measurable evidence that <a href="https://newatlas.com/medical/adhd-affects-connectivity-across-whole-brain/">neurodivergent brains are different</a> &ndash; neurobiological evidence that isn't based on behavior or self-reporting.</p><p>The research also shows that, like any biology student who has struggled with experiment design will know, accurate data is all about getting the methods of testing right. </p><p>"This study demonstrated the effectiveness of the TS method in correcting measurement bias in multi-site MRI studies involving children with ADHD," the researchers added. "These findings highlight significant structural differences in the brains of patients with ADHD, particularly in the middle temporal gyrus, and underscore the importance of using robust harmonization techniques to improve the reproducibility and accuracy of neuroimaging research."</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41380-025-03142-6"><i>Molecular Psychiatry</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.chiba-u.ac.jp/e/news/research/_0905_brain_e.html">Chiba University</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 04:31:09 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02901-3</link><title>My blue is your blue: different people’s brains process colours in the same way. Neuroscientists can predict what colour a person is looking at using a machine-learning tool trained on the brain activity of others. (nature.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc000l/my_blue_is_your_blue_different_peoples_brains/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc000l/my_blue_is_your_blue_different_peoples_brains/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc000l/my_blue_is_your_blue_different_peoples_brains/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article><div><header><div><ul> <li><span>NEWS</span></li> <li><time>08 September 2025</time></li> </ul><div><p>Neuroscientists can predict what colour a person is looking at using a machine-learning tool trained on the brain activity of others. </p></div></div></header> </div><div><figure><picture><source srcset="//media.nature.com/lw767/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_51430836.jpg?as=webp 767w, //media.nature.com/lw319/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_51430836.jpg?as=webp 319w"><img alt="A happy couple hold up a set of paint colour cards against a blue wall in their home." src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/lw767/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_51430836.jpg"><figcaption><p><span>Our brains seem to respond to specific colours in a similar way. </span><span>Credit: Hispanolistic/Getty</span></p></figcaption></source></picture></figure><p>Is the colour you see the same as what I see? It&rsquo;s a question that has puzzled both philosophers and neuroscientists for decades, but has proved notoriously difficult to answer.</p><p>Now, a study that recorded patterns of brain activity in 15 participants suggests that colours are represented and processed in the same way in the brains of different people. The findings were published in the <i>Journal of Neuroscience </i>on 8 September<sup><a href="https://www.nature.com#ref-CR1">1</a></sup>.</p><p>&ldquo;Now we know that when you see red or green or whatever colour, that it activates your brain very similarly to my brain,&rdquo; says study co-author Andreas Bartels, a cognitive neuroscientist at the University of Tubingen and the Max Planck Institute, both in Tubingen, Germany. &ldquo;Even at a very low level, things are represented similarly across different brains, and that is a fundamentally new discovery.&rdquo;</p><p>Bartels and his colleague Michael Bannert wanted to explore how different colours are represented in parts of the brain associated with vision, and how consistent this is across different people.</p><article><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-01252-3"><img alt src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/w400/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_50911966.jpg"><p>Brand-new colour created by tricking human eyes with laser</p></a></article><p>The pair used functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) to compare activity in the brains of a group of participants while they viewed different colours. This allowed them to create a map of brain activity that showed how each hue was represented neurologically. They then trained a machine learning model called a linear classifier on this data, and used it to predict which colours were being viewed by members of a second group of study participants, on the basis of their brain activity.</p></div><p><em>doi: https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-025-02901-3</em></p><div><h2>References</h2></div><h2>Related Articles</h2> <ul> <li><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-01252-3"> <img src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/lw100/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_50911966.jpg" alt> Brand-new colour created by tricking human eyes with laser </a> </p></li> <li><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-02696-z"> <img src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/lw100/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_24090952.jpg" alt> Colour me better: fixing figures for colour blindness </a> </p></li> <li><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/news/mantis-shrimp-s-super-colour-vision-debunked-1.14578"> Mantis shrimp's super colour vision debunked </a> </p></li> </ul> <h2>Subjects</h2> <section> <h2>Latest on:</h2> </section> </article> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 02:40:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/attraction-goes-beyond-looks-study-shows-voices-scents-and-motion-all-matter/</link><title>Attraction goes beyond looks: Study shows voices, scents, and motion all matter. Physical attraction is not simply about being objectively good-looking. Instead, attraction seems to arise from a mix of shared traits, personal preferences, and subtle non-verbal signals that go beyond facial features. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nblv67/attraction_goes_beyond_looks_study_shows_voices/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nblv67/attraction_goes_beyond_looks_study_shows_voices/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nblv67/attraction_goes_beyond_looks_study_shows_voices/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/couple-in-bed.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>New research published in the <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/bjop.12787">British Journal of Psychology</a></em> provides evidence that physical attraction is not simply about being objectively good-looking. Instead, attraction seems to arise from a complex mix of shared traits, personal preferences, and subtle non-verbal signals that go far beyond facial features. The study examined how people rate others&rsquo; attractiveness based on face, voice, body motion, and scent. While some patterns of agreement emerged, much of what made someone attractive varied across individuals.</p><p>Traditionally, studies on attractiveness have focused heavily on faces, often identifying broad preferences for features like facial symmetry, averageness, and sexual dimorphism. These patterns were interpreted as indicators of biological fitness and often presumed to hold across individuals and contexts. But attraction in the real world is rarely limited to a headshot. People communicate with their voices, bodies, and even their body odor, all of which may contribute to how they are perceived.</p><p>The researchers aimed to move beyond this narrow focus by examining multiple non-verbal cues simultaneously. They also wanted to understand whether patterns of attractiveness are truly universal or shaped by personal compatibility. In particular, they were interested in whether same-sex judgments&mdash;which are typically more platonic&mdash;differ from opposite-sex judgments, which tend to be influenced by mate selection.</p><p>The researchers recruited 61 young adults to serve as &ldquo;non-verbal agents&rdquo;&mdash;individuals who provided various sensory stimuli for evaluation&mdash;and 71 other young adults to serve as &ldquo;perceivers&rdquo; who rated these stimuli. The agent group included both men and women who were photographed, recorded speaking, filmed making neutral expressions, and asked to provide body odor samples by wearing sweat-collecting pads under their arms while exercising. This process was designed to capture information across four sensory channels: sight (photos and video), sound (voice), motion (video), and smell (body odor).</p><p>The perceivers each rated eight agents (a balanced mix of male and female) across these modalities. Each modality was presented separately to avoid cross-contamination of impressions. For example, perceivers smelled odor samples in isolation and were later shown silent videos or heard voice recordings. They rated each stimulus on a seven-point attractiveness scale, alongside questions about emotional impressions and other subjective reactions. However, for this study, only the attractiveness ratings were analyzed.</p><p>The researchers used advanced statistical modeling to examine three main questions: First, do different modalities vary in how attractive they are perceived? Second, are certain modalities redundant&mdash;meaning, does finding someone&rsquo;s voice attractive predict finding their face attractive? Third, do common or personal preferences dominate attractiveness judgments, and does this vary between same- and opposite-sex interactions?</p><p>Across the board, the researchers observed that multimodal stimuli&mdash;videos with synchronized audio&mdash;were rated as most attractive, suggesting that richer, more dynamic inputs provide more favorable impressions. At the other end of the scale, body odor stimuli were rated least attractive on average. Faces, voices, and silent videos landed in the middle.</p><p>However, the variation in attractiveness scores between modalities was relatively small. The biggest difference observed between any two modalities was less than one point on a seven-point scale. This suggests that while people have modest preferences for certain types of input, no single channel dominates the attractiveness landscape.</p><p>There was also evidence that some modalities carried redundant information. For example, people who were rated as attractive based on their voice were often also rated as attractive based on their appearance. This pattern held across both opposite-sex and same-sex judgments.</p><p>The strongest associations were between face and voice, while the weakest were between body odor and photo. However, body odor attractiveness did show a consistent positive link with how someone moved&mdash;implying that more dynamic cues like scent and motion may reflect overlapping traits, such as health or hormonal state.</p><p>Interestingly, the study also revealed that the weight of personal preference varied by context. When people rated opposite-sex individuals, the variation in ratings could be explained equally by traits of the person being rated (common preferences) and the rater themselves (personal preferences).</p><p>In contrast, when participants rated same-sex individuals, the variation was more strongly shaped by personal preferences. This suggests that in same-sex interactions, which tend to be more platonic, subjective compatibility may play a larger role than universally agreed-upon features.</p><p>This finding provides support for the idea that attractiveness serves multiple functions. While traditional theories focus on mate selection, the researchers argue that attraction also influences broader social outcomes, such as friendship formation, team cohesion, or general likability. Previous studies have shown that attractive people are often judged as more trustworthy, intelligent, and socially competent&mdash;a phenomenon known as the halo effect. These impressions can shape interactions in many social domains, not just romantic ones.</p><p>The research took a comprehensive look at various non-verbal cues, but it is not without its limitations. All participants were young adults in good health, and the study was conducted in a controlled laboratory setting. These constraints limit how generalizable the results are to other age groups, health statuses, or more naturalistic social contexts.</p><p>The researchers also focused on isolated impressions rather than interactions, so it remains unclear how these non-verbal cues play out in ongoing relationships. Future research might examine how dynamic impressions change over time or explore how shared attraction influences social bonding in real-world settings.</p><p>Another limitation was that the study did not measure how attraction relates to behavioral outcomes. While certain traits were judged as attractive, the researchers did not examine whether these traits led to greater cooperation, friendship, or romantic interest in actual interactions. Addressing this gap could help clarify the functional consequences of perceiver-driven preferences.</p><p>The researchers also noted the need for further investigation into the specific components of motion and scent that contribute to attractiveness. For instance, future studies might use point-light displays to isolate movement style or analyze odor samples for chemical composition.</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/bjop.12787">Attraction in every sense: How looks, voice, movement and scent draw us to future lovers and friends</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Annett Schirmer, Marcel Franz, Lea Krismann, Vanessa N&ouml;ring, Marlen Gro&szlig;e, Mehmet Mahmut, and Ilona Croy.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://sp-ao.shortpixel.ai/client/to_webp,q_glossy,ret_img,w_250,h_85/https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/follow-on-google-news-1.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 17:34:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/fecal-microbiota-transplant-obese-adolescents/</link><title>A single fecal microbiota transplant in obese teens delivered long-lasting metabolic benefits, shrinking waistlines, reducing body fat and inflammation, and lowering heart disease risk markers, which were still visible four years later. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbjcmt/a_single_fecal_microbiota_transplant_in_obese/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbjcmt/a_single_fecal_microbiota_transplant_in_obese/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbjcmt/a_single_fecal_microbiota_transplant_in_obese/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/9b39a40/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F30%2Faf%2F58bc4a844176b95c8c3026d22fd6%2Fdepositphotos-44814743-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A single fecal microbiota transplant in obese teens delivered long-lasting metabolic benefits, shrinking waistlines, reducing body fat and inflammation, and lowering heart disease risk markers, which were still visible four years later.</p><p>We&rsquo;ve covered <a href="https://newatlas.com/fecal-transplant-super-donor-microbiome-gut-bacteria/58148/">fecal transplantation</a> studies before. While it might not be an appropriate topic for dinner table conversation, the rise in research acknowledging the importance of the <a href="https://newatlas.com/obesity-microbiome-immune-system-gut-bacteria/60766/">gut microbiome</a> on pretty much the <i>entire</i> body has shone a spotlight back on the treatment.</p><p>Eight years ago, 87 adolescents participated in a groundbreaking study led by the University of Auckland, New Zealand, in which they received a single fecal microbiota transplant (FMT) to treat their obesity. The researchers have now published the results of their follow-up study, conducted more than four years later.</p><p>&ldquo;What is impressive is that just a single FMT treatment produced a dramatic reduction in metabolic syndrome that lasted at least four years,&rdquo; said <a href="https://profiles.auckland.ac.nz/w-cutfield">Wayne Cutfield, MD</a>, a Professor of Pediatric Endocrinology at the <a href="https://www.auckland.ac.nz/en/liggins.html">Liggins Institute</a> at the University of Auckland and the study&rsquo;s co-corresponding author. &ldquo;This means participants are at much lower risk of developing diabetes and heart disease over the long term.&rdquo;</p><p>The eighty-seven obese adolescents recruited into the trial were aged between 14 and 18. Half received FMT capsules &ndash; yes, taken via the mouth &ndash; made from healthy, lean donors. The others received placebo capsules. Participants in the treatment group swallowed 28 capsules over two days, each containing gut bacteria from four donors. For the first six months, the trial was a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. After that, participants were unblinded (that is, they knew whether they&rsquo;d received treatment or a placebo) but followed up four years later.</p><p>After around four-and-a-half years, 55 participants (63% of the original group) came back for checks that included DEXA body scans, blood tests, blood pressure measurements, diet and activity questionnaires, and stool samples for gut microbiome analysis. A DEXA (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry) scan is a non-invasive medical imaging test that uses low-dose X-rays to accurately measure a person&rsquo;s bone density, total body fat, and lean muscle mass.</p><p>The researchers found that while there were no significant differences in weight and body mass index (BMI) between the FMT and placebo groups, those who&rsquo;d had FMT had smaller waistlines (10 cm/3.9 in on average) and around 5% less total body fat on follow-up. They had lower severity scores for <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/fecal-transplant-fiber-supplement-obesity-metabolic-syndrome/">metabolic syndrome</a>, much lower <a href="https://newatlas.com/inflammation-off-switch-itaconate/54003/">inflammation</a>, and higher levels of &ldquo;good&rdquo; <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/high-density-lipoprotein-cholesterol-glaucoma/">HDL cholesterol</a>. No major difference was seen in blood sugar control or most other cholesterol and lipid markers.</p><p>&ldquo;More than one in three of the original teenage participants in our study had metabolic syndrome,&rdquo; Cutfield said. &ldquo;Metabolic syndrome has severe consequences, including a doubling in risk of death from heart disease or stroke and a five-fold increased risk of type 2 diabetes.&rdquo;</p><p>Astonishingly, FMT led to long-lasting changes in gut bacteria and viruses. The donor-derived bacterial and viral strains that participants in the treatment group had taken were still present after four years. Some participants retained many donor strains, others very few.</p><p>&ldquo;It really makes us think about the timeframes over which we look for the impacts of microbiome-based treatments,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s other corresponding author, <a href="https://profiles.auckland.ac.nz/justin-osullivan">Professor Justin O&rsquo;Sullivan, PhD</a>, Director of the Liggins Institute. &ldquo;Imagine being able to program your microbiome to reduce the risk of conditions before they occur. This work is paving the way for next-generation probiotics that target specific conditions through sustained changes to the microbiome.&rdquo;</p><p>Commercialization of a microbiome-based treatment for metabolic syndrome is the researchers&rsquo; end goal.</p><p>&ldquo;Our holy grail is to develop a super mix of bacteria that can be taken to prevent or moderate metabolic syndrome,&rdquo; said Cutfield. &ldquo;The first step is to prove our bespoke combination of bacteria actually works.&rdquo;</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62752-4"><i>Nature Communications</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.auckland.ac.nz/en/news/2025/08/28/the-good-shit-helping-obese-teens-study.html">University of Auckland</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:13:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://theconversation.com/researchers-watched-150-episodes-of-bluey-they-found-it-can-teach-kids-about-resilience-for-real-life-262202</link><title>Researchers watched 150 episodes of Bluey – they found it can teach kids about resilience for real life. Resilience isn’t just about “toughing it out”. It’s the ability to cope with challenges, adapt to setbacks and recover from difficulties. (theconversation.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb4z3b/researchers_watched_150_episodes_of_bluey_they/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb4z3b/researchers_watched_150_episodes_of_bluey_they/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb4z3b/researchers_watched_150_episodes_of_bluey_they/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.theconversation.com/files/683154/original/file-20250731-56-42nytz.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&rect=0%2C125%2C2000%2C1000&q=45&auto=format&w=1356&h=668&fit=crop' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>She&rsquo;s six years old, lives in Brisbane and might just be one of the best resilience coaches on television. </p><p>We&rsquo;re talking about Bluey, the animated Aussie pup whose adventures have captured the hearts of families around the world. </p><p>But as our <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/20590776.2025.2526340">new study</a> reveals, Bluey isn&rsquo;t just entertaining kids, she&rsquo;s modelling how to to deal with life&rsquo;s ups and downs.</p><h2>Why is resilience so important?</h2><p>Resilience isn&rsquo;t just about &ldquo;toughing it out&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0149763421004930?via%3Dihub">ability</a> to cope with challenges, adapt to setbacks and recover from difficulties. It&rsquo;s a vital part of healthy child <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2227-9067/5/7/98">development</a>.</p><p>Research shows resilience helps children manage stress, regulate their emotions, build better relationships, and even perform better at school. Without it, children may be more vulnerable to anxiety, depression and poor coping skills later in <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10826-022-02424-9">life</a>.</p><p>Children today face growing mental health challenges, including around anxiety and <a href="https://theconversation.com/parents-are-increasingly-saying-their-child-is-dysregulated-what-does-that-actually-mean-221989">emotional dysregulation</a>. For example, a <a href="https://www.adelaide.edu.au/newsroom/news/list/2024/02/06/young-australians-are-still-struggling">2023 national resilience survey</a> of almost 140,000 students found more than one in four primary and one in three secondary students reported high levels of psychological distress.</p><p>Research shows the <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/psychiatry/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2025.1594658/full">earlier we support resilience-building, the better</a>. Early interventions help build healthy coping skills before negative patterns take hold. </p><h2>How TV can help</h2><p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/jgc.2021">Storytelling</a> in films, books and TV can show children how to navigate challenges &ndash; not through lectures, but by <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0273229716300983?via%3Dihub">modelling behaviours</a> like emotional regulation, problem-solving and empathy.</p><p><a href="https://cdn.ncte.org/nctefiles/store/samplefiles/journals/la/la0813animals.pdf">Animal characters in storytelling</a> also offer valuable learning opportunities for children, who are naturally drawn to animals. </p><p>Bluey first aired in 2018. It has since become <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2025/jul/21/bbc-targets-adults-in-the-latest-adventure-for-its-top-dog-bluey?">Australia&rsquo;s most successful children&rsquo;s program</a>, with <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/maryroeloffs/2025/07/14/bluey-outranks-streamings-most-popular-originals-including-squid-game/">billions of views</a> worldwide. </p><p>It is known for its realistic portrayal of young family life. Yet until now, no one had systematically examined how it &ndash; or any kid&rsquo;s TV show &ndash; presents resilience on screen.</p><h2>So we watched all 150 Bluey episodes</h2><p>In our study, we analysed every episode of Bluey from seasons one to three. The 150 episodes added up to 18 hours of Bluey, Bingo, Chilli, Bandit and their friends. </p><p>For each episode, we looked closely at the storyline, characters and themes, identifying moments where a character faced a challenge and showed a resilient response.</p><p>To guide our analysis, we used the <a href="https://bibalex.org/baifa/Attachment/Documents/115519.pdf">Grotberg Resilience Framework</a>. This is a widely recognised model in psychology that breaks resilience into three key elements. </p><p><strong>1. I have:</strong> involving the support systems around a child, such as family, friends, and community role models they can rely on.</p><p><strong>2. I can:</strong> involving practical coping skills, like solving problems, managing emotions and asking for help when needed.</p><p><strong>3. I am:</strong> involving a child&rsquo;s inner strengths like confidence, optimism, emotional regulation and a sense of self worth.</p><h2>&lsquo;It&rsquo;s out of our hands&rsquo;</h2><p>Our research found nearly half of all episodes (73 out of 150) included a clear resilience message as either a primary or secondary theme. </p><p>Nearly two-thirds of the resilience moments were facilitated by a parent &mdash; most often Bluey&rsquo;s mum. This fits with the &ldquo;I have&rdquo; category of resilience, which highlights how children draw strength from caring adults when things get tough. </p><p>For example in The Show (season two episode 19), Bingo accidentally drops a breakfast tray and bursts into tears. Mum gently models emotional coaching explaining her coping process: &ldquo;I have a little cry, I pick myself up, dust myself off, and keep going.&rdquo; <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2212657024000278?">Research</a> shows that when caregivers model how to acknowledge distress, express feelings, and then recover with calm, children gradually learn to manage negative emotions effectively.</p><p>Later in the episode, Bingo repeats those exact words when things go wrong again. </p><h2>&lsquo;Well, that was fun&rsquo;</h2><p>Bluey and her sister also frequently demonstrate practical coping skills on their own. </p><p>In Keepy Uppy (season one, episode three), the final balloon in a game pops. The kids pause, take it in, and smile. &ldquo;Well, that was fun,&rdquo; they say. </p><p>In a single moment, we see disappointment, emotional regulation, and reframing &ndash; the core of the &ldquo;I can&rdquo; category.</p><h2>Everyday moments, powerful messages</h2><p>We also see characters overcoming challenges with their own inner strength. In Seesaw (season two, episode 27) Pom Pom shows determination and self-confidence to get to the top of the seesaw and save her friends, in an example of &ldquo;I am&rdquo;. As she declares, &ldquo;Pomeranians are a small but hardy breed&rdquo;.</p><p>We found Bluey touches on almost all of the <a href="https://bibalex.org/baifa/Attachment/Documents/115519.pdf">core elements of resilience</a>: trusting relationships, emotional communication, problem-solving, self-regulation, empathy and more.</p><p>In Sheepdog (season three, episode 11), mum Chilli tells her family she needs &ldquo;20 minutes&rdquo; of alone time. Bluey is worried she&rsquo;s done something wrong. Later, during play, Bluey gently echoes her mum&rsquo;s words to a toy: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s hard work looking after you. I just need 20 minutes.&rdquo;</p><p>That simple moment models self-care and perspective-taking as well as empathy. For kids, learning that grown-ups need rest too is a powerful message.</p><h2>How to watch Bluey with your kids</h2><p>Of course, no screen can replace real relationships. But when parents watch shows like Bluey with their kids, they become powerful teaching <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B978012809481500002X">tools</a>.</p><p>So the next time your child wants to watch an episode for the tenth time, don&rsquo;t feel guilty &ndash; join them. When parents watch too, those moments become conversation starters. For example, &ldquo;What do you think Bluey felt then?&rdquo;, &ldquo;Have you ever felt like that?&rdquo; or &ldquo;What would you do in that situation?&rdquo;</p><p>Talking about what kids see on screen can help them reflect, process, and build the skills they need to cope, adapt and grow. </p><hr><p><em>CQUniversity student Kelly Bohl and co-host of Bluey podcast Gotta Be Done Mary Bolling contributed to the original research on which this article is based.</em></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 02:40:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/environment/plant-pollen-coral-friendly-sunscreen/</link><title>Experimental new sunscreen forgoes minerals, replacing them with plant pollen. When applied to animal skin in lab tests, it rated SPF 30, blocking 97% UV rays. It had no effect on corals, even after 60 days. By contrast, corals died of bleaching within 6 days of exposure to commercial sunscreens. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naovap/experimental_new_sunscreen_forgoes_minerals/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naovap/experimental_new_sunscreen_forgoes_minerals/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naovap/experimental_new_sunscreen_forgoes_minerals/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/4d86cb1/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1992x1046+0+141/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fb7%2Fce%2Fa0abfc7c4be7acfca7d7c483a42c%2Fscreenshot-2025-09-04-at-9-49-13-am.jpeg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"> <article><div><ps-carousel> <template> </template><div><p>The camellia-pollen-based microgel applied to a test subject's hand (left), alongside its natural source</p><p>NTU Singapore</p></div><div><div><p><span>1</span>/<span>2</span> </p><div><p>(From left) NTU Singapore PhD student Deng Jingyu, Research Fellow Dr. Ferhan Abdul Rahim, Research Fellow Dr. Shahrudin Ibrahim, and Prof. Cho Nam-Joon (holding the raw pollen and the pollen-based sunscreen in a bottle)</p><p>NTU Singapore</p></div></div><div><p><span>2</span>/<span>2</span> </p><div><p>The camellia-pollen-based microgel applied to a test subject's hand (left), alongside its natural source</p><p>NTU Singapore</p></div></div></div></ps-carousel></div><div><p>Minerals such as titanium dioxide and zinc oxide are very effective sunscreen ingredients, but they can harm coral reefs if used in their non-nanoparticle form. An experimental new sunscreen forgoes the minerals altogether, replacing them with "just-as-effective" plant pollen.</p><p>The pollen-based sunscreen was developed by a team of scientists at Singapore's Nanyang Technological University, working with colleagues from Seoul National University in South Korea.</p><p>They experimented with both sunflower and <a href="https://newatlas.com/science/t-budbots-bacterial-biofilms/">camellia flower</a> pollen, getting the best results from the latter. Camellia pollen is considered nonallergenic, and is widely available as a relatively inexpensive health supplement.</p><p>The researchers utilized "a proprietary water-based process that does not involve harsh chemicals or high heat" to remove the inner contents of individual pollen grains. This left behind an outer coating of a tough natural biopolymer known as sporopollenin, which was converted into a transparent microgel no thicker than a human hair.</p><p>When applied to animal skin in lab tests, that gel was found to block harmful ultraviolet rays as effectively as a conventional mineral- or chemical-based sunscreen with an SPF rating of about 30. This means it blocked approximately 97% of the UV rays.</p><p>As an added benefit, because sporopollenin absorbs less energy than regular sunscreen in the visible to near-infrared spectrum, the microgel was found to keep the skin a total of 5 &ordm;C (9 &ordm;F) cooler for 20 minutes after application.</p><p>And importantly, the gel had no effect on corals after being added to the water in which they were living, even after 60 days. By contrast, the corals died of bleaching within six days of exposure to commercial sunscreens.</p><div><figure><div><figcaption>(From left) NTU Singapore PhD student Deng Jingyu, Research Fellow Dr. Ferhan Abdul Rahim, Research Fellow Dr. Shahrudin Ibrahim, and Prof. Cho Nam-Joon (holding the raw pollen and the pollen-based sunscreen in a bottle)</figcaption><p>NTU Singapore</p></div></figure> </div><p>"We know that pollen is naturally UV-resistant, as its shell needs to protect its inner contents from harsh environmental conditions, including sunlight," says the lead scientist, NTU's Prof. Cho Nam-Joon. "We wanted to develop an affordable and effective natural sunscreen that is non-allergenic to humans and eco-friendly to the environment."</p><p>The research is described in a paper that was recently published in the journal <a href="https://advanced.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/adfm.202516936"><i>Advanced Functional Materials</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.ntu.edu.sg/news/detail/scientists-develop-coral-safe-cooling-sunscreen-from-pollen">Nanyang Technological University</a><br></p></div></article><div><h2>Tags</h2> </div><div><div><p>Based out of Edmonton, Canada, Ben Coxworth has been writing for New Atlas since 2009 and is presently Managing Editor for North America. An experienced freelance writer, he previously obtained an English BA from the University of Saskatchewan, then spent over 20 years working in various markets as a television reporter, producer and news videographer. Ben is particularly interested in scientific innovation, human-powered transportation, and the marine environment. </p></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/2a314cb/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1000x666+0+0/resize/1000x666!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F26%2F7f%2F338a618a44c784a25bb819f45f14%2Fscientists-develop-cooling-sunscreen-from-pollen-which-is-coral-safe.jpeg"></p><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/fe23897/2147483647/strip/true/crop/243x243+60+0/resize/100x100!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F1a%2Fff%2F6c02760f4fe7b724c9be9314ee92%2Fstaff-bio-icon-ben-coxworth.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 14:59:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.durham.ac.uk/news-events/latest-news/2025/09/study-shows-the-lack-of-me-time-for-new-mothers/</link><title>Study shows the lack of ‘me time’ for new mothers, and research suggests that insufficient personal time may contribute to higher stress levels, lower mental well-being, and increased risk of postpartum burnout (durham.ac.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8z6r/study_shows_the_lack_of_me_time_for_new_mothers/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8z6r/study_shows_the_lack_of_me_time_for_new_mothers/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8z6r/study_shows_the_lack_of_me_time_for_new_mothers/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.durham.ac.uk/media/durham-university/central-news-and-events-images/New-mums-WEB.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>New mothers only have about an hour out of their waking day for rest, according to new research by our psychologists. </p><div><p>The study also shows that time &lsquo;alone&rsquo; for new mothers is now always with their baby present and this time is rarely restful.</p><p>Instead, it is filled with non-stop chores and emotional overload leading to increased stress, loneliness and emotional exhaustion.</p><h4>Quality me-time</h4><p>When mothers had even small amounts of quality me-time - where they were not looking after the baby or working for example - they felt better.</p><p>The researchers say their findings highlight the need for greater support to help parents get more quality me-time or at least breaks from childcare and chores.</p><p>They suggest looking to other countries where there are examples of government-subsidised services that assist with chores and cooking. This kind of support could help ease the burden for new parents, especially those without support nearby.</p><h4>Loneliness and stress</h4><p>The mothers in the study said that being alone with a baby doesn&rsquo;t always feel like true solitude. For many, it&rsquo;s a mix of feeling isolated, responsible, and constantly on alert - even when no one else is around.</p><p>On average, the mothers in the study had less than a third of their day for &lsquo;personal time,&rsquo; scattered in short bursts. This time included things like showering, eating, or walking, usually done quickly and often with interruptions. The constant physical and mental multi-tasking left many feeling deprived of true me-time.</p><p>Many mothers feel like they are "always on", even during supposed breaks. The emotional and mental demands of caring for a baby, combined with the loss of meaningful alone time, can increase feelings of loneliness and make it harder to recover from daily stress.</p><h4>Time at home</h4><p>The largest share of mothers&rsquo; days, around 60 per cent, was spent at home, much of it devoted to childcare, which took clear priority. Personal time often overlapped with chores, errands, and occasional social activities, while rest and relaxation tended to fall to the bottom of the list.</p><p>The study also showed that loneliness in new mothers isn&rsquo;t always about the lack of people around you. It can come from a loss of personal identity, lack of meaningful social connections, or simply from feeling unsupported. This is especially true for single mothers, those without family support, or those whose babies have additional needs.</p><h4>Find out more</h4> <ul> <li>You can read the <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/bjop.70019">research paper</a> in the British Journal of Psychology.</li> <li>Visit the <a href="https://www.solitude-lab.com/family-recharge">Solitude Lab</a> to find out more about our research in this area.</li> <li>The research was led by <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/staff/thuy-vy-nguyen/">Dr Thuy-vy Nguyen</a> from our Department of Psychology working with colleagues from the University of York, Leeds Beckett University and University College London. It was funded by the <a href="https://www.ukri.org/councils/esrc/">Economic and Social Research Council</a> (ESRC).</li> <li>Thuy-vy is also a Fellow of the <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/research-methods/">Durham Research Methods Centre</a>, <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/wolfson/">Wolfson Research Institute for Health and Wellbeing</a> and the <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/medical-humanities/">Institute for Medical Humanities</a>.</li> <li>Our Department of Psychology is ranked 84th in the QS World University Rankings by Subject 2025.&nbsp;Visit our <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/">Psychology webpages</a> for more information on our undergraduate and postgraduate programmes.</li> </ul> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 01:19:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/#google_vignette</link><title>Heterosexual men rate partners less favorably after pornography exposure, and research suggests this effect may be linked to altered perceptions of attractiveness and relationship satisfaction (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8tge/heterosexual_men_rate_partners_less_favorably/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8tge/heterosexual_men_rate_partners_less_favorably/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8tge/heterosexual_men_rate_partners_less_favorably/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/brain-1.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>The latest psychology and neuroscience discoveries.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 01:13:25 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/news/study-highlights-cultural-differences-in-parenting-and-reveals-that-how-babies-are-soothed-matters-more-than-how-fast-/</link><title>The way babies are soothed may be more important than how quickly mothers respond. UK mothers responded more quickly, but Ugandan infants recovered faster. UK mothers used more verbal reassurance and less tactile contact. Ugandan mothers used more tactile strategies, particularly breastfeeding. (durham.ac.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.durham.ac.uk/media/durham-university/central-news-and-events-images/news/Infant-comforting-web-pic.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>The way in which babies are soothed could be more important than how quickly mothers respond, according to new research revealing cultural differences in how babies are comforted.&#8239;&#8239; </p><div><p><span>Researchers including Professor Zanna Clay of our Psychology Department observed mother&ndash;infant interactions in urban UK and rural Ugandan communities.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>They focused on how mothers soothed their babies following naturally occurring episodes of distress.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Challenging assumptions&nbsp;</h4><p><span>They found that although the UK mothers responded to their babies' distress more quickly, Ugandan infants actually recovered faster.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This challenges long-standing assumptions rooted in Western models of parenting by showing that maternal promptness is not the only factor influencing how infants manage their emotions.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Instead, the type of soothing behaviour used, which is shaped by cultural context, may play a key role in helping babies regulate distress.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>While both UK and Ugandan mothers soothed their babies at three months with tactile contact, like breastfeeding, UK mothers tended to use more verbal reassurance and less tactile contact as babies grew older.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>By comparison, Ugandan mothers were more likely to rely on tactile strategies, particularly breastfeeding, even with older infants.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Everyday interactions&nbsp;</h4><p><span>The researchers analysed 147 naturally occurring episodes of infant distress involving 82 infants aged three and six months.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Unlike controlled lab settings or surveys, the observations reflected genuine, everyday spontaneous parent&ndash;infant interactions.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>In both countries, infants recovered more quickly when mothers responded faster.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>But notably, Ugandan mothers - who tended to respond more slowly - soothed their infants more effectively using tactile strategies, like breastfeeding, leading to quicker recovery.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This effect appears to stem from cultural differences in caregiving style and suggests that soothing methods may be more influential than speed of response alone.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The researchers hope these insights will inform more culturally inclusive approaches to parenting support and early intervention.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The research has been published in the journal Developmental Psychology and was funded by the European Research Council.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Find out more&nbsp;</h4> <ul> <li><span>Read the full paper in the journal </span><a href="https://doi.org/10.1037/dev0002038"><span>Developmental Psychology</span></a><span>.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> <li><span>Learn more about the work of </span><a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/staff/zanna-e-clay/"><span>Professor Zanna Clay</span></a><span>.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> <li><span>Our Department of Psychology is ranked 84th in the QS World University Rankings by Subject 2025. Visit our </span><a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/"><span>Psychology webpages</span></a><span> for more information on our undergraduate and postgraduate programmes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> </ul> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 16:27:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.additudemag.com/chronic-boredom-working-memory-attention-control/</link><title>A new study has found that people with ADHD traits experience boredom more often and more intensely than peers, linked to poor attention control and working memory (additudemag.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i0.wp.com/www.additudemag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/understand-conditions-adhd-research-and-news.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><em>September 1, 2025</em></p><p>Poor working memory and attention control may help explain why people with ADHD experience boredom more often and more acutely than do their non-ADHD peers. &ldquo;Part of the reason individuals with ADHD often experience boredom is due to difficulty controlling their attention and using their working memory effectively, leading to interpretations of that situation as boring,&rdquo; explains a study published last month in the <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/10870547251356723"><em>Journal of Attention Disorders</em></a>.<sup><a href="https://www.additudemag.com#footnote1">1</a></sup></p><p>In the small study, young adults completed self-reported measures of ADHD symptoms (using the Barkley Adult ADHD Rating Scale and the Wender Utah Rating Scale) and <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-so-bored-how-to-cure-boredom-adhd/">propensity for boredom</a> (on the Short Boredom Proneness Scale). They also submitted performance-based cognitive measures of <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/working-memory-deficit-weak-short-term-memory-symptoms-test-adults/">working memory</a> and attentional control. Based on their ADHD symptom self-reports, 31 participants were placed in the ADHD traits group and 57 in the control group.</p><p>Participants in the ADHD group experienced significantly higher levels of proneness to <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-bored-life-is-boring-impulsive-decisions/">boredom</a> compared to the control group (<em>d</em>&thinsp;=&thinsp;2.09), confirming previous research findings. Researchers also discovered that proneness to boredom and inclusion in the ADHD trait group were associated with significantly worse performance on working memory and attention control tests. &ldquo;Both attention control and <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/improve-working-memory/">working memory</a> factors partially mediated the relation between <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/slideshows/i-am-bored-agitation-restlessness/">ADHD and boredom</a>, accounting for 5.8% and 6.4% of the variance in ADHD-related boredom, respectively,&rdquo; researchers explained.</p><p>The findings of the study, the first to connect ADHD traits and boredom to performance-based <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/what-is-executive-function-disorder/">executive function</a> measures, support the Cognitive Theory of Boredom, which suggests that the experience of boredom is a result of the inability to direct attention on the task at hand.</p><p>One of the researchers who originated this theory, John Eastwood, Ph.D., co-author of <a href="https://www.hup.harvard.edu/books/9780674984677"><em>Out of My Skull: The Psychology of Boredom</em></a>, discussed the close association between boredom and ADHD in the recent <em>ADDitude</em> article, <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-so-bored-how-to-cure-boredom-adhd/"><em>Why ADHD Brains Go Over-Bored</em></a>,</p><p>&ldquo;Boredom points to our need to have agency, to be the captain of our own ship,&rdquo; Eastwood says, adding that the struggle to be self-directed is common among <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/what-is-adhd-symptoms-causes-treatments/">people with ADHD</a>, who are often corrected and directed by parents and teachers from a young age.</p><p>&ldquo;When a feeling like boredom is uncomfortable, we are sometimes unable to hear its deeper message because we just try to make the feeling go away,&rdquo; explains Eastwood. &ldquo;But boredom often has a message for us. I would encourage people to take boredom seriously, try not to be afraid or intolerant of it. There may be an opportunity to see how you can live in a way that gives fuller expression to who you are.&rdquo;</p><p>Eastwood also offered pragmatic interventions for those who experience chronic boredom, recommending adaptive, intentional responses to replace automatic, <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/stressors-adhd-brain/">stress responses</a>.</p><ul> <li>Instead of using avoidance-based coping strategies, such as a long break in the bathroom during a lecture, <strong>try engagement-based strategies,</strong> such as gamifying the experience &ndash; for instance, noting whenever the professor uses a three-syllable word.</li> <li>Strategies that help people <strong>tolerate intense emotions with a minimal stress response</strong>, such as active forms of <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/mindfulness-meditation-for-adhd/">mindfulness</a>, such as yoga or mindful walking, may also be effective with boredom</li> </ul> <h3>View Article Sources</h3><p><a></a><small><sup>1</sup>Orban, S. A., Blessing, J. S., Sandone, M. K., Conness, B., &amp; Santer, J. (2025). Why Are Individuals With ADHD More Prone to Boredom? Examining Attention Control and Working Memory as Mediators of Boredom in Young Adults With ADHD Traits. <em>Journal of Attention Disorders</em>, <em>0</em>(0). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/10870547251356723">https://doi.org/10.1177/10870547251356723</a></small></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 22:31:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/army-basic-training-appears-to-reshape-how-the-brain-processes-reward/</link><title>Army basic training appears to reshape how the brain processes reward. The stress experienced during basic combat training may dampen the brain’s ability to respond to rewarding outcomes. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/us-army-soldiers.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpsc.2025.05.007">Biological Psychiatry: Cognitive Neuroscience and Neuroimaging</a></em> suggests that stress experienced during basic combat training may dampen the brain&rsquo;s ability to respond to rewarding outcomes. Researchers found that Army National Guard recruits showed a measurable decline in neural signals linked to reward processing after completing a physically and emotionally demanding 10-week training program. The findings suggest that real-world stressors can influence how the brain processes both positive and negative feedback, with potential implications for resilience and mental health.</p><p>The ability to respond to rewards is considered an important aspect of healthy emotional functioning. Previous research has shown that greater neural responsiveness to rewards is associated with positive outcomes such as well-being, motivation, and resilience to stress. On the other hand, reduced responsiveness has been linked to symptoms of anhedonia, which refers to the loss of interest or pleasure in typically enjoyable activities. Anhedonia is a symptom seen across many psychiatric disorders, including depression.</p><p>Laboratory studies have demonstrated that acute or chronic stress can reduce the brain&rsquo;s responsiveness to rewards, possibly by disrupting dopamine signaling. However, much of this prior research has either relied on artificial stress manipulations in lab settings or retrospective self-reports of stress that may be biased.</p><p>Few studies have assessed how real-world, naturally occurring stressors affect neural reward processing over time. The authors of the current study sought to fill this gap by using a longitudinal design to examine how stress during a real-world challenge &mdash; basic combat training &mdash; might influence brain function.</p><p>The researchers drew on data from the ARMOR study, a large, ongoing project that investigates resilience and stress responses in military service members. From the broader sample, a subset of 123 Army National Guard recruits participated in a neuroimaging substudy. These participants were assessed before and after completing a 10-week basic combat training program. The training is designed to prepare civilians for military service and is widely recognized as a stressful experience due to its intense physical, psychological, and social demands.</p><p>Participants completed a computerized gambling task while their brain activity was recorded using electroencephalography, a method that tracks electrical signals from the scalp. The task involved choosing between two options to either win or lose points, with the outcome determined at random. This setup allowed the researchers to measure how the brain responded to positive (gain) or negative (loss) feedback. A particular brain signal, known as the reward positivity (or RewP), was used as a marker of reward processing. The RewP typically occurs between 175 and 325 milliseconds after feedback is received.</p><p>In addition to recording brain activity, the researchers also assessed each participant&rsquo;s experience of stress during training using the Basic Training Stressors Scale. This self-report measure captures both the frequency and perceived impact of various stressors related to performance, interpersonal dynamics, and living conditions. The stress survey was completed about two weeks after the end of basic training, prior to the follow-up brain scan.</p><p>The researchers also examined brain activity in specific frequency bands&mdash;delta and theta oscillations&mdash;associated with reward and loss processing, respectively. These time-frequency analyses provide an additional window into the dynamics of neural responses and may tap into different mechanisms than the traditional event-related potentials like the RewP.</p><p>The main finding was that neural responses to both rewards and losses were significantly reduced after the recruits completed basic training. This decrease was observed in the RewP time window and was not explained by the length of time between study visits. Interestingly, the difference between reward and loss responses did not change significantly, indicating that the decline occurred across both types of feedback rather than being specific to one.</p><p>The researchers then looked at whether self-reported stress during basic training was related to these changes in brain activity. They found that higher levels of perceived stress were associated with a smaller neural response to rewards, although this relationship weakened when additional variables were included in the model. This suggests that the subjective impact of stress, more than just the number of stressors, might influence how the brain adapts to stressful situations.</p><p>While the time-domain measures of brain activity showed a clear decline, analyses of delta and theta oscillations did not show consistent changes following training. This distinction may reflect differences in the neural processes captured by each approach. Time-domain signals like the RewP are typically phase-locked to feedback and reflect a more synchronized response, while time-frequency measures capture a broader and more variable range of neural activity. The researchers suggest that stress might reduce the consistency of brain responses rather than their amplitude, which could explain the discrepancy.</p><p>Participants who had stronger delta-band power before training were more likely to report lower levels of stress afterward. This finding hints at the possibility that some individuals may have a form of neural resilience, where their brains are better equipped to maintain reward sensitivity in the face of stress. These individuals may perceive stressful experiences as less overwhelming or disruptive, possibly buffering them from negative psychological outcomes.</p><p>While the study provides new evidence linking real-world stress to reduced reward responsiveness, the authors acknowledge some limitations. Most notably, there was no control group of recruits who completed the same assessments but did not undergo basic training. Without such a comparison, it is not possible to definitively conclude that the observed changes were caused by the stress of training rather than other factors, such as natural brain development or repeated exposure to the task.</p><p>Additionally, while participants reported on their stress shortly after completing training, the follow-up brain assessments occurred several months later. This introduces uncertainty about the timing of changes in reward processing relative to stress exposure. The study also cannot determine whether the observed neural changes have any lasting behavioral or psychological effects. Participants were generally high-functioning and did not show elevated levels of depression or anxiety, so the long-term impact of reduced reward responsiveness remains unclear.</p><p>The study raises important questions about whether these changes are temporary or long-lasting, and whether they might predict vulnerability to future mental health problems. It also suggests that individuals who enter stressful situations with higher reward sensitivity may be more resilient, but further research is needed to explore this possibility.</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S2451902225001661">Neural Response to Reward and Loss Following Basic Combat Training</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Clara Freeman, Eric Rawls, Collin D. Teich, Scott R. Sponheim, Melissa A. Polusny, and Craig Marquardt.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:33:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/sedentary-parents-children-mirror/</link><title>The activity level of parents affects the activity level of their kids: When parents sit too much, their kids tend to follow suit. But if parents keep active, children don’t mirror the same sedentary habits. It highlights the power of parents as role models for healthier lifestyles. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/5f4932d/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F90%2Fa8%2F19527eb24ba3b345a3aa55b27d1d%2Fdepositphotos-547980888-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>When parents sit too much, their kids tend to follow suit. But if parents keep active, children don&rsquo;t mirror the same sedentary habits, a new study has shown. It highlights the power of parents as role models for healthier lifestyles.</p><p>The <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7700832/">health risks</a> associated with an <a href="https://newatlas.com/30-minutes-sedentary-mortality/51323/">inactive</a> or sedentary lifestyle are pretty well known: <a href="https://newatlas.com/disease/obesity/high-speed-internet-access-obesity/">obesity</a>, heart disease, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, and type 2 diabetes. But what if parents are inactive? Are their children likely to follow suit?</p><p>A new study led by researchers from S&atilde;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Brazil, has investigated how parents&rsquo; activity levels affect the activity levels of their kids.</p><p>&ldquo;The results indicate that parents&rsquo; level of physical activity can directly influence their children&rsquo;s habits,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s corresponding author, <a href="https://portaldocentes.unesp.br/portaldocentes/docentes/105083">Diego Christ&oacute;faro, PhD</a>, an assistant professor at UNESP. &ldquo;In other words, when parents maintain a more active routine, their children are less likely to remain seated for long periods.&rdquo;</p><p>The researchers recruited 182 young people (aged six to 17) and their parents (161 mothers, 136 fathers). Participants&rsquo; sedentary behavior and physical activity were objectively measured with accelerometers worn on the hip for seven days. Parents were categorized as &ldquo;physically active&rdquo; if they did 150 minutes or more of moderate-to-vigorous activity per week, or as &ldquo;insufficiently active&rdquo; if they didn't.</p><p>Statistical analysis was used to look at whether sedentary behavior in parents was associated with sedentary behavior in children, adjusting for age, sex, socioeconomic status, and the child&rsquo;s own activity levels. The researchers found high sedentary levels in all groups. Children, mothers, and fathers all averaged around eight to nine hours of sedentary time per day. There was a strong association between mother and child sedentary time, although no significant association when mothers were active. A modest but significant association was seen between father and child sedentary time. As with mothers, there was no association when fathers were active.</p><p>The study&rsquo;s findings suggest that the sedentary habits of children mirror their parents only when the parents are inactive. When parents are active, their kids&rsquo; sedentary behavior doesn&rsquo;t track as closely.</p><p>&ldquo;Sedentary habits are the result of multiple factors, such as lack of access, time, and places where physical activity can be practiced,&rdquo; Christofaro said. &ldquo;However, our study shows that parents&rsquo; habits can affect their children&rsquo;s health. Therefore, we believe that these results can support public policies and campaigns aimed at promoting a more active lifestyle in the family environment.&rdquo;</p><p>Because the study was cross-sectional, it only looked at one point in time, so it can&rsquo;t prove cause and effect. Additionally, families volunteered to take part, which may not represent the general population. The study was conducted in Brazil; results may differ in other cultural or social settings. And the lack of randomization in the study reduces the ability to generalize the findings widely.</p><p>Regardless of these limitations, the study suggests that kids are more likely to adopt sedentary habits if their parents are inactive. Which, in turn, suggests that active parents protect kids from sedentary behavior. So, when parents meet physical activity guidelines, this can break the &ldquo;like parent, like child&rdquo; cycle. Encouraging parents to be more physically active could be an effective strategy to reduce sedentary behavior in children and adolescents.</p><p>The study was funded, in part, by the S&atilde;o Paulo Research Foundation (FAPESP) and published in the journal <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666337625000691"><i>Sports Medicine and Health Science</i></a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Source: <a href="https://agencia.fapesp.br/study-confirms-that-inactive-parents-contribute-to-sedentary-behavior-in-their-children/55757">Ag&ecirc;ncia FAPESP</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:15:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495132-a-single-dose-of-lsd-seems-to-reduce-anxiety/</link><title>A single dose of LSD seems to reduce anxiety (newscientist.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n8ek01/a_single_dose_of_lsd_seems_to_reduce_anxiety/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n8ek01/a_single_dose_of_lsd_seems_to_reduce_anxiety/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n8ek01/a_single_dose_of_lsd_seems_to_reduce_anxiety/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/04150347/SEI_264621700.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section> <figure><figcaption><div><p>Can psychedelics help treat generalised anxiety disorder?</p><p>Science Photo Library/Alamy</p></div></figcaption></figure><p>A single dose of the psychedelic drug LSD seems to reduce anxiety without lasting side effects.</p><p>&ldquo;Ours is the first modern trial to look specifically at LSD, or any psychedelic, for generalised anxiety disorder,&rdquo; says <a href="https://mindmed.co/team/dan-karlin-md-ma/">Dan Karlin</a> at biotech company MindMed in New York.</p><p>The condition is characterised by excessive worry about a broad range of things, such as work and relationships. First-line treatment includes mood-enhancing drugs, like selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and other antidepressants, and talking therapies.</p><p>But <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7653736/">about half of people don&rsquo;t respond</a> to such treatments. &ldquo;For a lot of people, SSRIs are not very effective, they have intolerable side effects [such as feeling emotionally numb] because people have to take them on a daily basis, and they only work while you&rsquo;re taking them,&rdquo; says Karlin.</p><p>Previous studies have suggested that LSD may be an alternative. The <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2430072-psychedelic-toxins-from-toads-could-treat-depression-and-anxiety/">psychedelic</a> is often used recreationally for its <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2416478-microdosing-lsd-increases-the-complexity-of-your-brain-signals/">mind-altering</a>, hallucinogenic effects. Karlin says it is thought to act by increasing levels of the mood-boosting chemical serotonin in the brain, which some people say induces a profound emotional experience in them. He adds that it may also <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494391-just-one-dose-of-psilocybin-seems-to-be-enough-to-rewire-the-brain/">enhance the brain&rsquo;s ability to rewire itself</a> and form new thought patterns.</p><p>But until now, no trial comparing people taking LSD with others taking placebo pills has explored whether the substance can benefit those with generalised anxiety disorder.</p><p>To fill this gap, Karlin and his colleagues recruited 198 adults with the condition. The participants slowly tapered off any anxiety medications they had been using, but those who were receiving psychotherapy continued with their sessions.</p><p>In a survey commonly used in clinics, the participants then rated the severity of each of 14 symptoms, such as feeling worried, tense or struggling to focus, on a scale of 0 to 4. Out of a maximum total score of 56, the participants scored 30, on average, above the threshold of 24 for severe anxiety.</p><p>Next, the team randomly split the participants into five groups that either took LSD &ndash; at various doses of 25, 50, 100 or 200 micrograms &ndash; or placebo pills, without being told which they were given. A day later, those who had received 100 and 200 microgram doses, but not the other groups, already reported an improvement in symptoms, says Karlin.</p><p>A month later, those who had received the 100 and 200 microgram doses experienced an average 21 and 19 point reduction in anxiety, respectively, with the improvement sustained until the end of the study, three months after the dosing day. About 46 per cent of these participants went into remission, which is a score of 7 or below.</p><p>Meanwhile, those taking the placebo and the two lower doses saw between a 14 and 17 point reduction in anxiety over the same period, with about 20 per cent going into remission. This suggests the lower doses provided no additional relief beyond the placebo.</p><p>The benefit seen by the two highest dose groups is a substantial improvement above the placebo, says <a href="https://profiles.ucl.ac.uk/5848-sunjeev-kamboj">Sunjeev Kamboj</a> at University College London. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s a clinically meaningful improvement in terms of impairment and distress,&rdquo; he says.</p><p>The improvement in the placebo group, a phenomenon commonly seen in anxiety trials, probably resulted from a mixture of factors, such as people feeling attended to and cared for as part of the trial, says Kamboj.</p><p>The team found that most participants could accurately guess whether they had taken LSD or the placebo. This is common with psychedelics because they have hallucinogenic side effects for many people. In all the groups, some participants&nbsp;also experienced nausea and headaches in the 12 hours after treatment.</p><p>Those on lower doses of LSD and on the placebo experienced changes in visual perception like hallucinations at far lower rates than those on the higher doses of the psychedelic. This makes it hard to tell whether the LSD-related benefits were due to a person&rsquo;s expectations based on the effects they felt or the direct effects of the drug on the brain, says Kamboj.</p><p>Despite this caveat, the study provides some of the best evidence to date that LSD could be a useful treatment for anxiety, he says. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s a very promising finding that you can get a very rapid effect in symptom reduction, that would be extremely meaningful to patients.&rdquo;</p><p>The results are promising enough that the US Food and Drug Administration has designated MindMed&rsquo;s LSD formulation as a Breakthrough Therapy, which expedites the process for drug development. Karlin says the team is carrying out larger trials that will track benefits beyond three months, with results expected in the next couple of years.</p><section><p>Topics:</p></section> </section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 21:44:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/toilet-smartphone-use-hemorrhoids/</link><title>Smartphone scrolling on toilet linked to higher hemorrhoid risk, raising risk of hemorrhoids by nearly 50%, from extra minutes spent sitting. 66% reported using phone on toilet. 37% stayed on toilet for more than 5 minutes. Most common reasons were to read news (54%) and use social media (44%). (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n85czq/smartphone_scrolling_on_toilet_linked_to_higher/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n85czq/smartphone_scrolling_on_toilet_linked_to_higher/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n85czq/smartphone_scrolling_on_toilet_linked_to_higher/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/216c52a/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F59%2F1f%2Feef8321f42eeb77f92479c407aec%2Fdepositphotos-332243026-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Scrolling on your smartphone while on the toilet may be doing more than passing the time. A new study has found it could raise your risk of hemorrhoids by nearly 50%, thanks to the extra minutes spent sitting.</p><p>Sitting on a cold surface. Eating spicy foods. Poor hygiene. Those are some of the old wives&rsquo; tales about hemorrhoids that are pure myth. However, sometimes such beliefs turn out to be backed by science.</p><p>New research led by Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) in Boston has found that smartphone use while <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/automated-toilet-flushing-device-bacteria/">on the toilet</a> increases the risk of hemorrhoids.</p><p>&ldquo;Using a smartphone while on the toilet was linked to a 46% increased chance of having hemorrhoids,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s corresponding author, <a href="https://findadoc.bidmc.org/details/5679/">Trisha Pasricha, MD, MPH</a>, from BIDMC&rsquo;s Division of Gastroenterology. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re still uncovering the many ways smartphones and our modern way of life impact our health. It&rsquo;s possible that how and where we use them &ndash; such as while in the bathroom &ndash; can have unintended consequences.&rdquo;</p><p>It's probably worthwhile starting with an explanation of what hemorrhoids are. If you&rsquo;re familiar, you can skip the next couple of paragraphs.</p><p>&ldquo;We all have hemorrhoid cushions &ndash; vascular cushions made of blood vessels, connective tissue, and smooth muscle &ndash; right at the end of our GI [gastrointestinal] tract,&rdquo; Pasricha explained. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s a normal part of our body. It&rsquo;s only when they get engorged that we notice them and that&rsquo;s when they become symptomatic and they&rsquo;re called hemorrhoids.</p><p>"When they become engorged, they often bleed and become uncomfortable. The external ones are the ones that can cause itching. It can feel like there&rsquo;s a bump, it can feel like there&rsquo;s something there and they&rsquo;re difficult to clean. And then that kind of like causes this vicious cycle of like more discomfort, more irritation. The more angry they get, the more likely they are to bleed. It can really just spiral.&rdquo;</p><div><figure><div><figcaption>The most popular phone-related activities were scrolling through the news and social media</figcaption></div></figure> </div><p>For the study, the researchers recruited 125 adults aged 45 and older who were scheduled to undergo routine colonoscopies. Participants filled out surveys about demographics, physical activity, fiber intake, and bathroom habits (including smartphone use). The <a href="https://theromefoundation.org/rome-iv/rome-iv-criteria/">Rome IV</a> questionnaire was used to assess bowel function and straining. Doctors performing the colonoscopies visually confirmed whether participants had hemorrhoids.</p><p>Smartphone users were compared to non-users. Statistical methods were used to adjust for confounding factors like age, sex, body mass index (BMI), fiber intake, exercise and straining. Of all the participants, 66% reported using their phone on the toilet. Phone users spent more time sitting than non-users: 37% of users stayed on the toilet for more than five minutes per visit, compared to just 7% of non-users. The most common things people did on the toilet were read the news (54%) and use social media (44%). Smartphone users were younger and exercised less on average than non-users.</p><p>Colonoscopy confirmed that 43% of all participants had hemorrhoids. After adjusting for other risk factors, smartphone use on the toilet was linked to a 46% higher risk of hemorrhoids. Straining did <i>not</i> independently predict hemorrhoids in the phone user group, suggesting that time spent sitting is more relevant.</p><p>&ldquo;This study bolsters advice to people in general to leave the smartphones outside the bathroom and try to spend no more than a few minutes to have a bowel movement,&rdquo; said Pasricha. &ldquo;If it&rsquo;s taking longer, ask yourself why. Was it because [having] a bowel movement was really so difficult, or was it because my focus was elsewhere?</p><p>"It&rsquo;s incredibly easy to lose track of time when we&rsquo;re scrolling on our smartphones &ndash; popular apps are designed entirely for that purpose. But it&rsquo;s possible that constantly sitting longer on the toilet than you intended because you&rsquo;re distracted by your smartphone could increase your risk of hemorrhoids. We need to study this further, but it&rsquo;s a safe suggestion to leave the smartphone outside the bathroom when you need to have a bowel movement.&rdquo;</p><p>The study has drawn comment from other GI experts, such as <a href="https://profiles.auckland.ac.nz/j-dowrick">Jarrah Dowrick, PhD</a>, a research fellow with the Gastrointestinal Research Group at the Auckland Bioengineering Institute, University of Auckland.</p><p>&ldquo;From what I can see, this paper is a thinly veiled study of the relationship between time spent on the toilet and hemorrhoids, but using the catchier hook of &lsquo;phone use&rsquo; to attract wider attention,&rdquo; said Dowrick. &ldquo;While the reality of modern screen addiction does make the smartphone narrative more compelling, the real story here is that spending longer on a seated toilet appears to be linked with hemorrhoid presentation.</p><p>&ldquo;This is still an important finding. There is a surprising lack of evidence for commonly believed hemorrhoid risk factors like low fiber intake, straining, constipation, age, sex differences, pregnancy, and time on the toilet. Studies like this one are vital to empower clinicians to make evidence-based recommendations to patients. Phone or no, this study suggests limiting each visit to the toilet to five minutes where possible.&rdquo;</p><p>There are some key limitations to the study. Its cross-sectional design means it can show associations but not prove cause and effect. Additionally, because participants&rsquo; behavior was self-reported, time spent on the toilet and straining could be affected by recall bias. And, the participants were over 45 undergoing colonoscopies, so results may not reflect younger populations or the general public. Finally, the study didn&rsquo;t measure how many years people had been using phones on the toilet.</p><p>Nonetheless, the study has real-world implications. Its findings suggest that it&rsquo;s not so much straining but prolonged sitting without pelvic support that raises hemorrhoid risk. So, medical professionals might want to recommend limiting toilet sessions &ndash;especially with phone &ndash; to five minutes or less.</p><p>Larger, long-term future studies could track whether years of toilet-phone use worsen hemorrhoid rates, and behavioral interventions such as timers might help reduce sitting time.</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0329983&amp;utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=plos006"><i>PLOS One</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.bidmc.org/about-bidmc/news/2025/09/how-smartphones-may-increase-hemorrhoid-risk">BIDMC in Boston</a>, <a href="https://www.scimex.org/newsfeed/scrolling-on-the-toilet-linked-to-haemorrhoids">Scimex</a></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/ea0aa0c/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1333+0+0/resize/1440x960!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fb7%2F06%2F0573537247c887347faadbde0a8f%2Fviralyft-nq7y-rauzdy-unsplash.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:50:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0924977X25001300</link><title>Study of the drug Semiglutide (sold as Wegovy, Ozempic) shows it significantly lowers cocaine seeking behavior in rats, suggesting it may be a candidate for development as a treatment for cocaine dependency. (sciencedirect.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7wfe9/study_of_the_drug_semiglutide_sold_as_wegovy/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7wfe9/study_of_the_drug_semiglutide_sold_as_wegovy/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7wfe9/study_of_the_drug_semiglutide_sold_as_wegovy/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0924977X25X00067-cov150h.gif' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-content"><span><span>Skip to main content</span></span></a><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-title"><span><span>Skip to article</span></span></a></p><header></header><div><article><div><p><span>Under a Creative Commons </span><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><span><span>license</span></span></a></p><p>Open access</p></div><div><h2>Abstract</h2><div><p>Currently, no pharmaceutical treatments exist for cocaine use disorder, which is characterized by dysregulated motivation, intense drug craving, compulsive drug-seeking behavior, and relapse during abstinence. While short-acting glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor (GLP-1R) reduces cocaine-related behaviors, its impact is limited by low affinity towards GLP-1R. Semaglutide may be beneficial in this context as it is long-acting with greater potency and affinity for the GLP-1R. Its superiority is substantiated in studies on alcohol and alcohol use disorder (AUD) as it profoundly reduces alcohol intake in animals and patients with AUD, whereas exendin-4 (Ex4) slightly reduces alcohol intake in rats, whereas it does not alter alcohol intake in AUD patients. However, it remains to be explored whether its beneficial effects extend to more complex cocaine-related behaviors, the aim of the present study. Using the cocaine self-administration paradigm in male rats, we tested the efficacy of different doses of semaglutide to reduce voluntary cocaine taking, the motivation to consume cocaine, and the reinstatement of cocaine-seeking behavior. Furthermore, we explored the effects of semaglutide on cocaine-evoked dopamine levels in the nucleus accumbens (NAc). Semaglutide decreased cocaine self-administration, the motivation to consume cocaine, and cocaine reinstatement in male rats. Moreover, semaglutide attenuated cocaine-induced elevation of dopamine levels in mice and rats. Additionally, neither of the tested doses altered kaolin intake, a measurement of malaise, in cocaine-experienced rats. These findings further support the role of GLP-1R in cocaine taking and imply that semaglutide should be tested as a candidate for treating cocaine use disorder.</p></div></div><ul><li><li></ul><div><h2>Keywords</h2><p><span>GLP-1</span></p><p><span>Cocaine</span></p><p><span>Semaglutide</span></p><p><span>Gut-brain peptides</span></p><p><span>CUD</span></p></div><section><header><h2>Cited by (0)</h2></header></section><div><dl><dt><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#bfn1"><span><span><sup>1</sup></span></span></a></dt><dd><p>These authors contributed equally to this work.</p></dd></dl></div><p><span>&copy; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V.</span></p></article></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 06:28:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/common-artificial-sweeteners-linked-to-cognitive-decline-in-large-study/</link><title>People who consumed higher amounts of artificial sweeteners (aspartame, saccharin, erythritol, xylitol, sorbitol) showed steeper drops in verbal fluency, memory, and cognitive function over 8 years. This link was stronger in people with diabetes but also observed with people without it. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7r2xd/people_who_consumed_higher_amounts_of_artificial/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7r2xd/people_who_consumed_higher_amounts_of_artificial/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7r2xd/people_who_consumed_higher_amounts_of_artificial/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/sweetener.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in the journal <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000214023">Neurology</a></em> provides evidence that regular consumption of certain artificial and low-calorie sweeteners may be linked to a faster decline in memory and other cognitive abilities over time. Using data from more than 12,000 middle-aged and older adults in Brazil, researchers found that individuals who consumed higher amounts of these sweeteners tended to show steeper drops in verbal fluency, memory, and overall cognitive function over an eight-year period. The association appeared stronger in people with diabetes but was also observed among participants without the condition.</p><p>With global dementia cases projected to triple by 2050, researchers are increasingly focused on identifying lifestyle factors that might influence cognitive aging. While sugary diets have been linked to poorer brain health, many individuals have shifted toward low- and no-calorie sweeteners as perceived healthier alternatives. These sweeteners&mdash;commonly found in diet beverages, yogurts, protein bars, and tabletop products&mdash;include aspartame, saccharin, acesulfame potassium, and sugar alcohols like erythritol and xylitol.</p><p>Despite their widespread use, concerns have grown around their potential health effects. Prior studies have linked artificial sweeteners to higher risks of diabetes, cardiovascular problems, and depression, even when consumed within official safety limits. Some research has also suggested a potential connection between these sweeteners and dementia or poor memory, but evidence from large-scale, long-term studies has been lacking. The current study was designed to address this gap.</p><p>The research drew on data from the Brazilian Longitudinal Study of Adult Health (ELSA-Brasil), a multicenter cohort that began in 2008 and enrolled over 15,000 public employees aged 35 and older from six cities across Brazil. After excluding individuals with incomplete dietary data or extreme reported calorie intake, the final sample included 12,772 adults, with an average age of 52 at baseline. Participants were followed over three waves of assessment: 2008&ndash;2010, 2012&ndash;2014, and 2017&ndash;2019&mdash;a span of approximately eight years.</p><p>At the start of the study, participants completed a detailed food frequency questionnaire that asked about their diet over the past year. This allowed researchers to estimate the intake of seven specific low- and no-calorie sweeteners: aspartame, saccharin, acesulfame potassium, erythritol, xylitol, sorbitol, and tagatose.</p><p>Based on total daily intake, participants were divided into three consumption groups. The lowest group averaged 20 milligrams per day, while the highest group averaged 191 milligrams per day&mdash;an amount equivalent to the aspartame content of one can of diet soda. Among all sweeteners, sorbitol was consumed in the highest quantity, with an average intake of 64 milligrams per day.</p><p>Cognitive performance was assessed at the start, middle, and end of the follow-up period. The battery of tests included measures of verbal fluency, working memory, word recall, and processing speed, enabling researchers to track changes in memory, language, and general thinking skills. These scores were standardized to allow comparison across waves and participants.</p><p>After statistically adjusting for a wide range of factors&mdash;including age, sex, income, physical activity, blood pressure, cardiovascular disease, body mass index, and diet quality&mdash;the researchers found that individuals in the highest tertile of sweetener consumption showed a 62% faster decline in global cognitive scores than those in the lowest group. This translated to an estimated 1.6 additional years of cognitive aging over the eight-year period. Participants in the middle group experienced a 35% faster decline, equivalent to about 1.3 extra years of aging.</p><p>The association between sweetener intake and cognitive decline was strongest in adults under the age of 60. In this group, higher consumption was linked to steeper losses in verbal fluency and overall cognition. Among those aged 60 and older, the study did not find a significant association between sweetener intake and cognitive performance. The researchers also found that the relationship between sweetener use and cognitive decline was stronger in individuals with diabetes compared to those without.</p><p>When each sweetener was analyzed separately, consumption of aspartame, saccharin, acesulfame potassium, erythritol, xylitol, and sorbitol was associated with faster decline in global cognition, especially in memory and verbal fluency. In contrast, tagatose&mdash;a naturally occurring sugar found in some dairy products and fruits&mdash;was not associated with cognitive decline.</p><p>Notably, the trend held even when looking at the frequency of consumption, rather than the exact quantity. Participants who consumed any type of low- or no-calorie sweetener on a daily basis showed a significantly faster decline in memory, language, and overall cognitive function compared to those who consumed sweeteners only occasionally or not at all.</p><p>&ldquo;Low- and no-calorie sweeteners are often seen as a healthy alternative to sugar, however our findings suggest certain sweeteners may have negative effects on brain health over time,&rdquo; explained Claudia Kimie Suemoto of the University of S&atilde;o Paulo, the senior author of the study.</p><p>Although the study was large and followed participants over several years, the researchers caution against drawing firm conclusions about cause and effect. The study relied on self-reported dietary data collected only at the beginning of the study, which may not capture long-term changes in diet. People with certain health conditions, such as diabetes or obesity, may also be more likely to consume artificial sweeteners in place of sugar, raising the possibility that underlying health issues, rather than the sweeteners themselves, contributed to cognitive decline.</p><p>In addition, while the researchers adjusted for a wide range of demographic, clinical, and lifestyle factors, unmeasured variables could still play a role. The study also lacked brain imaging or biological markers that could offer clues about how these sweeteners might affect brain structure or function.</p><p>Despite these caveats, the new findings add to a growing body of research raising concerns about the long-term safety of common sugar substitutes. Recent laboratory studies have suggested that erythritol, a sugar alcohol frequently used in low-carbohydrate and ketogenic products, <a href="https://www.psypost.org/popular-sugar-substitute-erythritol-may-impair-brain-blood-vessel-health-study-finds/">may impair the function of blood vessels in the brain</a>. In one in vitro study, erythritol increased oxidative stress and reduced nitric oxide production in human endothelial cells, potentially disrupting blood flow and increasing the risk of stroke.</p><p>Epidemiological studies have also linked elevated levels of erythritol in the blood to higher risks of heart attacks and strokes, while clinical trials have reported increased platelet reactivity following erythritol intake&mdash;another possible contributor to clot formation.</p><p>Sucralose, another widely used sweetener, <a href="https://www.psypost.org/a-common-calorie-free-sweetener-alters-brain-activity-and-appetite-control-new-research-suggests/">has been implicated in altered brain activity</a> related to hunger and reward. A recent brain imaging study found that sucralose increased activity in the hypothalamus, a region involved in appetite regulation, and heightened connectivity with brain areas involved in motivation and sensory processing. These effects varied depending on sex and body weight, with women and individuals with obesity showing stronger responses. Such findings suggest that sucralose may disrupt the brain&rsquo;s normal signaling related to satiety, potentially contributing to overeating or altered eating behavior over time.</p><p>While these studies do not focus directly on cognition, they raise broader concerns about how artificial sweeteners may influence brain health through vascular, metabolic, and neural pathways&mdash;concerns that align with the new findings from Brazil.</p><p>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000214129">an accompanying editorial</a> published in <em>Neurology</em>, Rush University physician scientist Thomas M. Holland wrote that these findings pose &ldquo;a fundamental question&rdquo; to the medical community. &ldquo;In our efforts to prevent stroke and preserve cognition through dietary modification, are we inadvertently recommending substances that may accelerate the very cognitive decline we seek to prevent?&rdquo;</p><p>The new study, according to Holland, has &ldquo;provided neurologists, and the broader medical community, caring for cognitively at-risk populations, with critical evidence that dietary counseling must extend beyond traditional cardiovascular risk reduction to address the potential cognitive effects of food additives, particularly artificial sweeteners. Supporting long-term brain health requires a proactive, integrated approach, optimizing diet, movement, sleep, stress, cognitive stimulation, and social connection to build cognitive resilience over time.&rdquo;</p><p>Given the widespread consumption of artificial sweeteners, especially among people seeking to manage weight or blood sugar, researchers emphasize the need for more longitudinal and experimental studies to clarify their potential effects on the brain. Future research should include repeated dietary assessments over time, neuroimaging to detect changes in brain structure, and biomarkers of inflammation and neurotoxicity.</p><p>There is also a need to examine whether certain populations&mdash;such as people with diabetes, metabolic syndrome, or low insulin sensitivity&mdash;are more vulnerable to the potential harms of artificial sweeteners. In addition, researchers should compare the cognitive effects of natural sweeteners like tagatose, stevia, or monk fruit to those of synthetic ones.</p><p>&ldquo;While we found links to cognitive decline for middle-aged people both with and without diabetes, people with diabetes are more likely to use artificial sweeteners as sugar substitutes,&rdquo; said Suemoto. &ldquo;More research is needed to confirm our findings and to investigate if other refined sugar alternatives, such as applesauce, honey, maple syrup or coconut sugar, may be effective alternatives.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000214023">Association Between Consumption of Low- and No-Calorie Artificial Sweeteners and Cognitive Decline: An 8-Year Prospective Study</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Natalia Gomes Gon&ccedil;alves, Euridice Martinez-Steele, Paulo A. Lotufo, Isabela Bensenor, Alessandra C. Goulart, Sandhi Maria Barreto, Luana Giatti, Carolina Perim de Faria, Maria del Carmen Bisi Molina, Paulo Caramelli, Dirce Maria Marchioni, and Claudia Kimie Suemoto.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 02:39:22 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
