<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:39:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2025-09-15/california-covid-surge-is-peaking-but-the-battle-over-vaccine-access-is-just-beginning</link><title>California says it can no longer trust Washington on COVID vaccines. A major battle is looming (latimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhn3n1/california_says_it_can_no_longer_trust_washington/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhn3n1/california_says_it_can_no_longer_trust_washington/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 9 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhn3n1/california_says_it_can_no_longer_trust_washington/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://ca-times.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/01fd508/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1575+0+213/resize/1200x630!/quality/75/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcalifornia-times-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Ff0%2F58%2F8f84f20642be95b689007188f656%2F1473411-me-kaiser-covid-vaccines02-cs.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>California&rsquo;s late summer COVID surge is showing signs of peaking, but the state&rsquo;s war with the Trump administration over vaccines is just beginning.</p><p>Coronavirus levels in California&rsquo;s wastewater remain &ldquo;<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nwss/rv/COVID19-national-data.html">very high</a>,&rdquo; according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, as they are in much of the country. But some other COVID-19 indicators are starting to fall in the Golden State.</p><p>The shift comes as California state officials and mainstream medical organizations are breaking from the Trump administration&rsquo;s recent revisions to federal vaccine guidelines. </p><p>The changes, made under the leadership of vaccine-skeptic Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr., have been so dramatic that a number of medical experts and officials now express little to no confidence in two key agencies within that department &mdash; the CDC and Food and Drug Administration. </p><p>A key turning point came in June, when Kennedy <a href="https://www.latimes.com/world-nation/story/2025-06-09/rfk-jr-ousts-entire-cdc-vaccine-advisory-committee">ousted everyone on the</a> CDC&rsquo;s respected Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, which issues recommendations on who should receive various types of vaccines. </p><p>Their replacements &mdash; some of whom have criticized vaccines and spread misinformation, according to the Associated Press &mdash; have led officials and other experts in some states to doubt or dismiss the latest CDC guidance. </p><p>The CDC&rsquo;s immunization committee &ldquo;is no longer a trusted source for vaccine guidance,&rdquo; Dr. Matt Willis, the former public health officer for Marin County, <a href="https://yourlocalepidemiologistca.substack.com/p/measles-death-covid-hospitalizations">wrote</a> on the blog Your Local Epidemiologist in California. </p><p>In the past, medical and scientific groups were confident in the CDC&rsquo;s data analysis and trusted the agency&rsquo;s vaccine guidelines. And so that guidance informed key matters including which vaccines should be covered by insurance, and professional medical societies were aligned on immunization recommendations, according to Dr. Erica Pan, the director of the California Department of Public Health and state health officer. </p><p>&ldquo;Now what we&rsquo;re seeing is a divergence,&rdquo; Pan <a href="https://youtu.be/JfEbRVAvIys?si=xcamtcNPvT-TMlyG&amp;t=107">said</a> during a webinar Tuesday. </p><p>California is moving away from the CDC&rsquo;s guidance and toward recommendations issued by medical groups, such as professional organizations of pediatricians, family physicians, obstetricians and gynecologists. </p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;ll be aligning our immunization recommendations with trusted national medical professional organizations,&rdquo; rather than the CDC, Pan said, &ldquo;given the termination of the vaccine experts with that subject matter expertise.&rdquo; </p><p>A number of local health departments, including from Los Angeles, Orange and San Francisco counties, are endorsing the California Department of Public Health&rsquo;s vaccine guidance.</p><p>A Reuters/Ipsos poll <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/just-1-4-americans-believe-100430636.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly90LmNvLw&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAALKrBUlF4BDB4HTa-L-cnjgk279exuLAe0t27Sqi9YjUc7W8QlV8sHi9WmZtttthgPp_ZJfKrn90MGtnJciVKP4pLmi7E5JGb66svGPuCQTrsH8lkIpzdxoPM62yJd9iBPIae3eaS8wL6oKjaECYYWEab6VxR-geePp_mny7HAaD">said</a> that just 1 in 4 Americans believe that the recommendations for fewer vaccines from the Trump administration were based on scientific evidence and facts.</p><p>California, Washington, Oregon and Hawaii have also united to establish the West Coast Health Alliance, which is intended to provide science-based immunization guidance. Pan said the alliance isn&rsquo;t intended to be a competitor to the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, but to evaluate guidance from other professional medical groups &ldquo;to make recommendations for our states and for our insurers.&rdquo; </p><p>Already, compared with the CDC, the California Department of Public Health has far more expansive recommendations on who should get the now-available updated COVID vaccine. </p><p><a href="https://www.cdph.ca.gov/Programs/CID/DCDC/Pages/COVID-19/Covid19Vaccines.aspx">It recommends</a> that all adults get vaccinated, as the <a href="https://www.aafp.org/news/media-center/statements/aafp-announces-fall-immunization-recommendations-reaffirming-commitment-to-vaccine-safety-and-public-health.html">American Academy of Family Physicians</a> recently endorsed; that those who are pregnant get vaccinated, as endorsed by the <a href="https://www.acog.org/news/news-releases/2025/08/acog-releases-updated-maternal-immunization-guidance-covid-influenza-rsv">American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists</a>; and that the youngest children &mdash; ages 6 months to 23 months &mdash; get vaccinated, as endorsed by the <a href="https://publications.aap.org/aapnews/news/32836">American Academy of Pediatrics</a>. </p><p>California and the pediatricians group also recommend all children with underlying health conditions get vaccinated. They also say any child should be able to get the vaccine if their parents wish. </p><p>The FDA, on the other hand, has approved COVID-19 vaccines only for those ages 65 and older, as well as younger individuals with underlying medical conditions. That means non-senior-age adults may need to either talk with a medical provider before they can get vaccinated or &ldquo;attest&rdquo; to a pharmacy that they have an underlying medical condition that makes them eligible.</p><p>The CDC also recently said that it now has &ldquo;no guidance&rdquo; on whether pregnant women should get the vaccine. </p><p>Some experts have noted that the guidance is contradictory, given that the CDC also says people who are at risk of severe illness if they get COVID-19 should get vaccinated &mdash; and pregnant women are.</p><p>In some states, pharmacy chains are being forced to ask people to bring in a prescription authorizing them to get the COVID-19 vaccine, at least for another week. As of Friday, CVS said that was the case in Arizona, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Maine, North Carolina, Oregon, Utah and West Virginia, as well as the District of Columbia. </p><p>The CDC could be poised to make getting a vaccine even more difficult for some Americans. The Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices is weighing a plan to recommend the COVID-19 vaccine only for those ages 75 and older, and instruct younger people to speak with a healthcare provider before they get the vaccine, the Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2025/09/12/covid-vaccine-child-death-cdc/">reported</a> Friday. That could mean an additional hurdle for even younger seniors to get the vaccine. </p><p>The Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices is expected to meet Thursday and Friday. </p><p>There is some indication that vaccine providers are taking an expansive view of who can be inoculated, however. </p><p>Kaiser Permanente unveiled a <a href="https://healthy.kaiserpermanente.org/health-wellness/coronavirus-information/vaccine-appointments?kp_shortcut_referrer=kp.org/covidvaccine">website</a> announcing that its members ages 6 months and older can get the updated COVID vaccine at its facilities at no cost. </p><p>&ldquo;Vaccination remains one of the safest and most effective ways to help protect against severe illness. This includes children and families whose health would be at risk if they got COVID-19,&rdquo; Kaiser says. </p><p>On its site for California members, Kaiser said people don&rsquo;t need to provide additional documentation to get the vaccine, nor do they need an individual prescription. </p><p>The official CDC <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/covid/hcp/clinical-care/underlying-conditions.html">list</a> of conditions that could justify getting the vaccine is also extensive, including risk factors like being overweight, physically inactive or having ever smoked. </p><p>A Times reporter visiting a large retail pharmacy was also told that a qualifying reason for a person under the age of 65 to get the COVID-19 vaccine was if they had a family member who was at risk of severe illness. </p><p>Some Californians were subjected to <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2025-09-06/vaccine-chaos-even-some-vulnerable-seniors-cant-get-covid-shots-amid-spiking-cases">tough</a> eligibility questions in the first days the shots were available. But Dr. Peter Chin-Hong, a UC San Francisco infectious diseases expert, said that everybody he&rsquo;s talked to recently &ldquo;seem to have been getting it without problems, which is reassuring to me, because I want to get one, too.&rdquo; </p><p>The California Legislature is also taking action. State lawmakers on Friday <a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB144">passed</a> Assembly Bill 144, which would <a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billAnalysisClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB144">allow</a> the California Department of Public Health to not just rely on the federal government to outline what kinds of vaccines insurance providers are required to cover, but also take into account guidance from professional medical societies.</p><p>&ldquo;At a time when misinformation is fueling fear and mistrust, we must safeguard the proven standards that keep families and communities healthy,&rdquo; California Medical Assn. President Dr. Shannon Udovic-Constant said in a <a href="https://www.cmadocs.org/newsroom/news/view/ArticleId/50978/CMA-introduces-legislation-to-safeguard-vaccine-access-in-California">statement</a> supporting the legislation.</p><p>Pan <a href="https://youtu.be/JfEbRVAvIys?si=SyMOd7Mo91uvJtpG&amp;t=313">said</a> she expects COVID-19 cases to decline statewide by October. Flu and respiratory syncytial virus are expected to begin ramping up by early October, and the combined respiratory viral season is expected to peak at the end of December and the start of January in California. </p><p>One of the changes to vaccine recommendations this year is <a href="https://www.latimes.com/science/story/2023-05-03/us-approves-1st-vaccine-for-rsv-after-decades-of-attempts">that the RSV vaccine</a> is now recommended for adults as young as 50 who are at increased risk of severe illness, Pan said. Previously, the recommendation was for adults ages 60 to 74 at increased risk for severe illness. All adults ages 75 and older are also recommended to get the RSV vaccine. </p><p>Another disease to watch out for is pertussis, also known as whooping cough. Sen. Bill Cassidy (R-La.), who is also a physician, <a href="https://x.com/SenBillCassidy/status/1966252751400341809">said</a> on social media Thursday that his state is suffering its worst whooping cough outbreak in 35 years, with 368 cases this year, including two infants who died. &ldquo;Most hospitalized were not up-to-date on vaccines,&rdquo; Cassidy wrote. </p><div><h3>More to Read </h3> </div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:47:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://mastodon.social/@chatcontrol/115204439983078498</link><title>Danish Minister of Justice: "We must break with the totally erroneous perception that it is everyone's civil liberty to communicate on encrypted messaging services." (mastodon.social)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhhw1k/danish_minister_of_justice_we_must_break_with_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhhw1k/danish_minister_of_justice_we_must_break_with_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhhw1k/danish_minister_of_justice_we_must_break_with_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/115/204/429/589/501/969/original/6cb579f59a0a0da4.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:42:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2025/09/14/apple-blocks-daily-mail-from-news-app/</link><title>Apple blocks Daily Mail from news app (telegraph.co.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nh1kq5/apple_blocks_daily_mail_from_news_app/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nh1kq5/apple_blocks_daily_mail_from_news_app/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nh1kq5/apple_blocks_daily_mail_from_news_app/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.telegraph.co.uk/content/dam/briefs/2025/09/12/TELEMMGLPICT000439612291_17576854293780_trans_NvBQzQNjv4BqYS1acP-ch22p5qESP2v6g4TQXy-JIYeNHjz2OazuOpE.jpeg?impolicy=OG-Standard' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2025/07/29/daily-mail-abandons-mailonline-in-digital-push/">The Daily Mail</a> has called for a crackdown on Apple amid accusations that the tech giant has shut the publisher out of its news app.</p><p>Apple has refused to allow the Mail to feature its articles on Apple News, Britain&rsquo;s most widely used news app, the news group has told the Competition and Markets Authority (CMA).</p><p>It claims Apple is concerned that allowing the Mail onto its app will harm other outlets and that the publisher&rsquo;s size would &ldquo;overwhelm Apple&rsquo;s ecosystem&rdquo;.</p><p>The Mail says that Apple News&rsquo;s growing influence means it has become as indispensable as Google search and calls for the CMA to tackle the company&rsquo;s &ldquo;arbitrary and discriminatory practices&rdquo;.</p><p>In a submission to the regulator, DMG Media, the Mail&rsquo;s owner, said that it had joined Apple News&rsquo;s launch in the United States in 2015, but declined to be part of the subsequent UK version.</p><p>At the time, the Mail was Britain&rsquo;s most popular news website, and the company wished &ldquo;to avoid the risk of Apple News cannibalising the Daily Mail&rsquo;s high-quality traffic&rdquo;. It also said that results from its experiment in the US were &ldquo;extremely disappointing&rdquo; and brought in &ldquo;no revenue&rdquo;.</p><p>It has since decided to join Apple News, which is now used by more than one in four adults in Britain, making it the most widely adopted news app in Britain.</p><p>However, the Mail said it has been stonewalled by Apple. The tech giant first insisted it was not allowing new publishers onto the app and then refused the Mail access, according to the filing.</p><p>&ldquo;The main reason given was that Apple only wanted to add partners which would grow the pie, and did not want to take share away from existing partners,&rdquo; it said. &ldquo;We were also told, paradoxically, both that the number of articles we publish and the strength of our user engagement would overwhelm Apple&rsquo;s ecosystem.&rdquo;</p><p>Apple News is pre-installed on iPhones and headlines from the app are built into the phone&rsquo;s operating system. This makes it a crucial source of readers for publishers, but the Mail claims it also gives the tech giant huge power.</p><p>&ldquo;Apple uses its dominance in mobile ecosystems to advantage Apple News,&rdquo; the company said.</p><p>&ldquo;Not being a participant in Apple News is no longer an option &ndash; it has become indispensable to running a successful online news publishing business.&rdquo;</p><p>Apple is facing a crackdown from the CMA under new competition laws, although the way it manages Apple News is not believed to be part of the regulator&rsquo;s work on the company. The Telegraph is a member of the Apple News+ subscription service.</p><p>The Daily Mail&rsquo;s efforts to join Apple News come as the publisher grapples with the impact of <a href="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/2025/08/24/daily-mail-crackdown-google-ai-after-traffic-tanks/">Google&rsquo;s new AI functions</a>.</p><p>In a separate submission to the CMA last month, DMG Media said the tech giant&rsquo;s new AI overviews &ndash; which summarise articles &ndash; had sparked a fall in referrals from Google searches of as much as 89pc.</p><p>The Mail, which is the UK&rsquo;s largest news source behind the BBC, is racing to reduce its reliance on tech platforms and advertising revenues and is instead shifting its focus to digital subscriptions.</p><p>In July, the publisher said it was scrapping its MailOnline brand and renaming its digital offering Daily Mail in an effort to create a combined global audience across both its app and website. Bosses have outlined a target of reaching one million digital subscribers in the next three years.</p><p>However, the overhaul has sparked a brutal series of redundancy rounds for Mail journalists as the outlet seeks to further integrate its print and digital titles into a seven-day operation.</p><p>Apple have been approached for comment</p><p>DMG Media declined to comment.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 01:43:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/chinas-great-firewall-springs-huge-leak</link><title>China’s Great Firewall suffers its biggest leak ever as 500GB of source code and docs spill online — censorship tool has been sold to three different countries (tomshardware.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nglfx5/chinas_great_firewall_suffers_its_biggest_leak/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nglfx5/chinas_great_firewall_suffers_its_biggest_leak/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nglfx5/chinas_great_firewall_suffers_its_biggest_leak/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/wMEAHYgm2jbsxJhyBZuvLe.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Chinese censorship sprang <a href="https://gfw.report/blog/geedge_and_mesa_leak/en/">a major leak</a> on September 11, when researchers confirmed that more than 500GB of internal documents, source code, work logs, and internal communications from the so-called Great Firewall were dumped online, including packaging repos and operational runbooks used to build and maintain China&rsquo;s national traffic filtering system.</p><p>The files appear to originate from Geedge Networks, a company that has long been linked to Fang Binxing &mdash; widely described as the &ldquo;father&rdquo; of the Great Firewall &mdash; and from the MESA lab at the Institute of Information Engineering, a research arm of the Chinese Academy of Sciences.</p><p>A leaked deployment sheet reveals that the system was rolled out across 26 data centers in Myanmar, with live dashboards monitoring 81 million simultaneous TCP connections. The system was reportedly operated by Myanmar&rsquo;s state-run telecoms company and integrated into core Internet exchange points, thereby enabling mass blocking and selective filtering.</p><p>And it doesn&rsquo;t stop at Myanmar. Partner reporting from <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/geedge-networks-mass-censorship-leak/"><em>WIRED</em></a> and <a href="https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2025/09/pakistan-mass-surveillance-and-censorship-machine-is-fueled-by-chinese-european-emirati-and-north-american-companies">Amnesty International</a> reveals that Geedge&rsquo;s DPI infrastructure has been exported to other states &mdash; Pakistan, Ethiopia, and Kazakhstan being among the recipients &mdash; where it&rsquo;s often used alongside lawful intercept platforms. In Pakistan, Geedge&rsquo;s equipment allegedly forms part of a larger system known as WMS 2.0, which is capable of conducting blanket surveillance on mobile networks in real-time.</p><p>The scale and specificity of this leak offer a rare glimpse into how China&rsquo;s censorship check is engineered and commercialized. <em>WIRED&rsquo;s </em>reporting also describes how the leaked documents show Geedge&rsquo;s system can intercept unencrypted HTTP sessions.</p><div><section><p>Get Tom's Hardware's best news and in-depth reviews, straight to your inbox.</p></section></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 13:32:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/media-censorship-accountability-charlie-kirk-act-b2825988.html</link><title>Trump shares call for media ‘accountability’ with ‘Charlie Kirk Act’ after shooting (the-independent.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nghkfj/trump_shares_call_for_media_accountability_with/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nghkfj/trump_shares_call_for_media_accountability_with/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nghkfj/trump_shares_call_for_media_accountability_with/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://static.the-independent.com/2025/09/13/16/53/5050-Templete-(1).jpg?trim=0,0,0,0&width=1200&height=800&crop=1200:800' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Donald Trump has shared a video calling for the president to reinstate a Cold War-era media &ldquo;accountability&rdquo; law in response to the assassination of right-wing activist Charlie Kirk, with a petition calling for its revival gathering more than 5,000 signatures within 13 hours.</p><p>Following the 31-year-old Kirk&rsquo;s killing at Utah Valley University and the arrest of 22-year-old <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/charlie-kirk-shooting-tyler-robinson-hate-b2825465.html">Tyler Robinson</a>, TikTok user Ellie May called for the president to reintroduce the Smith&#8209;Mundt Act, a U.S. law once intended to prevent domestic dissemination of U.S.-backed foreign media, and to give it a new name: the &ldquo;Charlie Kirk Act.&rdquo; </p><p>May&rsquo;s video went viral and was shared on the president&rsquo;s Truth Social account.</p><p>In her video, May accused media outlets of &ldquo;spreading propaganda&rdquo; and<a href="https://www.the-independent.com/topic/misinformation"></a> conspiracy theories that spread rapidly across social media platforms. </p><p>AI&#8209;generated images and false claims misidentifying the suspect were among the content circulated, some of which gained additional reach via Grok, X&rsquo;s AI chatbot. It reportedly acknowledged errors only after several false posts had already gone viral. </p><div><figure><figcaption>MAGA supporter Ellie May is calling on President Donald Trump to reinstate the Cold War-era Smith&#8209;Mundt Act after Charlie Kirk's death<span> (Getty Images/TikTok/@official_elly_may)</span></figcaption></figure></div><p>&ldquo;I think the only way to bring forward decent change in this country is to start speaking up,&rdquo; May told <em>The Independent </em>in a direct message on X.</p><p>&ldquo;We had one Charlie Kirk before he passed since his death,&rdquo; May added. &ldquo;We have seen more people who have never put their faces in front of a camera start speaking truth to power. I think this is, not to play words on his organization, a <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/charlie-kirk-tyler-robinson-suspect-b2825455.html">turning point</a> in our country.&rdquo;</p><p>Changing the law would require an act of Congress.</p><p>In her TikTok video, where she largely reads from the <a href="https://www.change.org/p/enact-the-charlie-kirk-act-to-restore-media-accountability?recruiter=1375406487&amp;">Change.org </a>petition she created, May, who told <em>The Independent</em> she only began engaging in elections in 2016, when she became eligible to vote, claims that media outlets frequently label individuals as &ldquo;fascists,&rdquo; &ldquo;Nazis,&rdquo; &ldquo;white supremacists,&rdquo; or &ldquo;bigots&rdquo; without evidence, fueling public hostility.</p><p>She argued that accountability should extend beyond traditional news outlets to include content creators who disseminate propaganda and half&#8209;truths online. </p><p>&ldquo;Each violation should be subject to a fine amounting to at least 35 percent of the company's value,&rdquo; May read from the online proposal she wrote. &ldquo;Baseless accusations, such as labeling individuals as bigots, fascists, or racist, without verifiable proof, tarnish reputations and endanger lives. Such acts should not be tolerated and must invite strict accountability measures.&rdquo;</p><p>Her petition, which has <a href="https://x.com/officialellymay/status/1966888975274225830">5,000 signatures</a> in less than a day since its launch, also includes the proposal of &ldquo;stringent penalties for social media companies that censor information unfairly.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Each violation should be subject to a fine amounting to at least 35 percent of the company's value,&rdquo; May wrote. &ldquo;Baseless accusations, such as labeling individuals as bigots, fascists, or racist, without verifiable proof, tarnish reputations and endanger lives. Such acts should not be tolerated and must invite strict accountability measures.&rdquo;</p><p>May told <em>The Independent</em> that the response to her petition has been &ldquo;a lot more digestible&rdquo; than she expected.</p><p>&ldquo;Each time I check, it&rsquo;s going up by about 100 signatures, so I feel like this could become a pivotal moment in American history,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;If I were to ratio it percentage-wise, it&rsquo;s about a 70-30, and the 70 percent are behind it.&rdquo;</p><p>May called on Trump in her video to restore the Smith&#8209;Mundt Act, which she falsely claimed was abolished in 2013 by then-President Barack Obama and then-Vice President Joe Biden, and to rename it in Kirk&rsquo;s honor. </p><div><figure><figcaption>May&rsquo;s proposal also includes severe penalties for social media companies that engage in censorship or allow unverified defamatory labels<span> (Copyright 2025 The Associated Press. All rights reserved.)</span></figcaption></figure></div><p>Obama did not abolish the Smith-Mundt Act. Instead, his administration oversaw the passage of the Smith-Mundt Modernization Act of 2012, which amended parts of the original law.</p><p>Nothing in that bill applies to what private media organizations in the can or cannot publish.</p><p>The original 1948 act created a ban on the domestic dissemination of informational materials produced by the U.S. government intended for foreign audiences, like those from the <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/voice-of-america-director-fired-illegal-b2802264.html">Voice of America</a>.</p><p>The amendment, becoming effective on July 2, 2013, lifted the decades-old ban, so Americans can access content from the U.S. Agency for Global Media and the media organizations that it supports.</p><p>May also posted a <a href="https://x.com/officialellymay/status/1966874352408019209">follow-up video</a> to X on Saturday addressing backlash she received for allegedly promoting media &ldquo;<a href="https://www.the-independent.com/topic/censorship">censorship</a>,&rdquo; captioning the post, &ldquo;Do not put words in my mouth that I didn&rsquo;t say.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;So here&rsquo;s what we're not going to do: We're not going to conflate what I said with your feelings,&rdquo; May said. &ldquo;I'm not calling for censorship, I'm calling for media organizations to be held accountable for the ignorant s**t that they say.&rdquo;</p><p>May criticized viral claims suggesting Robinson was a MAGA-aligned, ultra-conservative Republican, as well as proliferation of AI-doctored photos related to <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/crime/tyler-robinson-family-republican-b2825943.html">Robinson&rsquo;s political views, </a>including altered images of the shooter in MAGA apparel and allegedly fabricated screenshots showing donations to pro-Trump causes, which May insisted are entirely fake.</p><p>&ldquo;That photo does not f***ing exist,&rdquo; she said. </p><div><figure><figcaption>Kirk&rsquo;s alleged killer, Tyler Robinson, 22, is being held without bail at the Utah County Jail</figcaption></figure></div><p>Erika Kirk, Charlie&rsquo;s widow, vowed Friday to continue his legacy by advancing the right-wing movement he founded in an emotional tribute from Phoenix, Arizona.</p><p>As she addressed supporters, Erika, who is also the mother of their two young children, promised to grow Turning Point USA, the conservative youth organization her husband started, into &ldquo;the biggest thing this nation has ever seen.&rdquo;</p><p>Robinson is being <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/charlie-kirk-shooting-tyler-robinson-suspect-erika-live-updates-b2825825.html">held without bail </a>at the Utah County Jail. He is expected to be formally charged with aggravated murder, felony discharge of a firearm causing serious bodily injury, and obstruction of justice. </p><p>Aggravated murder is a capital felony under Utah law, which means if convicted, Robinson could face the death penalty.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.the-independent.com/2025/09/13/12/Charlie_Kirk_Vigil_37414.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://static.the-independent.com/2025/09/12/20/Charlie_Kirk_Shot_40179.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 09:43:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://theintercept.com/2025/09/13/marco-rubio-revoke-us-passports-terrorism/</link><title>New Bill Would Give Marco Rubio “Thought Police” Power to Revoke U.S. Passports (theintercept.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngft6b/new_bill_would_give_marco_rubio_thought_police/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngft6b/new_bill_would_give_marco_rubio_thought_police/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngft6b/new_bill_would_give_marco_rubio_thought_police/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://theintercept.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GettyImages-2221348960-e1757705424289.jpg?fit=8208%2C4104&w=1200&h=800' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>In March,</span> Secretary of State Marco Rubio stripped Turkish doctoral student R&uuml;meysa &Ouml;zt&uuml;rk&rsquo;s of her visa based on what a court later found was nothing more than her <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/30/tufts-rumeysa-ozturk-ice-immigration-op-ed/">opinion piece</a> critical of Israel.</p><p>Now, a bill introduced by the chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee is ringing alarm bells for civil liberties advocates who say it would grant Rubio the power to revoke the passports of American citizens on similar grounds.</p><p>The provision, sponsored by Rep. Brian Mast, R-Fla., as part of a larger State Department reorganization, is <a href="https://docs.house.gov/Committee/Calendar/ByEvent.aspx?EventID=118618">set for a hearing</a> Wednesday. </p><p>Mast&rsquo;s legislation says that it takes aim at &ldquo;terrorists and traffickers,&rdquo; but critics say it could be used to deny American citizens the right to travel based solely on their speech. (The State Department said it doesn&rsquo;t comment on pending legislation.)</p><blockquote>&ldquo;Rubio has claimed the power to designate people terrorist supporters based solely on what they think.&rdquo;</blockquote><p>Seth Stern, the director of advocacy at Freedom of the Press Foundation, said the bill would open the door to &ldquo;thought policing at the hands of one individual.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Marco Rubio has claimed the power to designate people terrorist supporters based solely on what they think and say,&rdquo; Stern said, &ldquo;even if what they say doesn&rsquo;t include a word about a terrorist organization or terrorism.&rdquo;</p><h2><strong>Vague &ldquo;Terrorist&rdquo; Designations</strong></h2><p>Mast, for his part, has publicly voiced his <a href="https://washingtonreporter.news/p/exclusive-free-him-more-like-deport">support</a> for &ldquo;kicking terrorist sympathizers out of our country.&rdquo; At the time, he was talking about deporting Mahmoud Khalil, a Palestinian green-card holder who the Trump administration <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/06/20/mahmoud-khalil-homeland-security-investigations-ice-surveillance/">detained and attempted to deport</a> based on what <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/13/briefing-podcast-mahmoud-khalil-free-speech/">critics of the move</a> said were <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/10/mahmoud-khalil-palestine-columbia-immigration-deport/">his pro-Palestine views</a>.</p><p>Mast&rsquo;s new bill claims to target a narrow set of people. One section grants the secretary of state the power to revoke or refuse to issue passports for people who have been convicted &mdash; or merely charged &mdash; of material support for terrorism. (Mast&rsquo;s office did not respond to a request for comment.)</p><p>Kia Hamadanchy, a senior policy counsel at the American Civil Liberties Union, said that language would accomplish little in practice, since terror convictions come with stiff prison sentences and pre-trial defendants are typically denied bail.</p><p>The other section sidesteps the legal process entirely. Rather, the secretary of state would be able to deny passports to people whom they determine &ldquo;has knowingly aided, assisted, abetted, or otherwise provided material support to an organization the Secretary has designated as a foreign terrorist organization.&rdquo;</p><p>The reference to &ldquo;material support&rdquo; disturbed advocates who have long warned that the government can misuse statutes criminalizing &ldquo;material support&rdquo; for terrorists &mdash; first passed after the 1996 Oklahoma City federal building bombing and toughened after the 9/11 attacks &mdash; to punish speech.</p><p>Some of those fears have been borne out. The Supreme Court <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/national/2010/06/22/court-upholds-ban-on-terrorrelated-aid/c652dfbe-39cb-49eb-8b8a-139fc388a4a9/">ruled in 2010</a> that even offering advice about international law to designated terror groups could be classified as material support.</p><p>The government even deemed a woman who was kidnapped and forced to cook and clean for Salvadoran guerrillas a material supporter of terrorism, <a href="https://theintercept.com/2018/06/09/immigration-terrorism-prosecutions-material-support-united-states/">in order to justify her deportation.</a></p><p>Since the October 7 Hamas attacks, pro-Israel lawmakers and activists have ratcheted up attempts to expand the scope and use of anti-terror laws.</p><p>The <a href="https://theintercept.com/2024/02/21/adl-palestine-terrorism-legislation/">Anti-Defamation League</a> and the Louis D. Brandeis Center for Human Rights Under Law <a href="https://theintercept.com/2024/02/21/adl-palestine-terrorism-legislation/">suggested in a letter</a> last year that Students for Justice in Palestine was providing &ldquo;material support&rdquo; for Hamas through its on-campus activism.</p><p>Lawmakers also tried to pass a<a href="https://theintercept.com/2024/11/10/trump-nonprofit-tax-exempt-political-enemies/"> &ldquo;nonprofit killer&rdquo; bill</a> that would allow the Treasury secretary to strip groups of their charitable status if they are deemed a &ldquo;terrorist-supporting organization.&rdquo; The bill was beaten back by a coalition of nonprofit groups, most recently during the debate over the <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/05/19/nonprofit-killer-trump-big-beautiful-bill/">so-called Big, Beautiful Bill.</a></p><p>Mast&rsquo;s bill contains eerily similar language, Stern said.</p><p>&ldquo;This is an angle that lawmakers on the right seem intent on pursuing &mdash; whether through last year&rsquo;s nonprofit killer bill, or a bill like this,&rdquo; Stern said.</p><p>The provision particularly threatens journalists, Stern said. He noted that Sen. Tom Cotton, R-Ark., in November 2023 <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2023/11/tom-cotton-hamas-journalists-fake-news-disinformation-netanyahu-gantz/">demanded a Justice Department &ldquo;national security investigation&rdquo;</a> of The Associated Press, CNN, New York Times, and Reuters over freelance photographers&rsquo; images of the October 7 attacks.</p><p>Rubio also revoked &Ouml;zt&uuml;rk&rsquo;s visa on what appears to be nothing more than an op-ed she wrote for the Tufts University student newspaper in 2024 &mdash; which <a href="https://www.tuftsdaily.com/article/2024/03/4ftk27sm6jkj">did not mention Hamas</a> &mdash; calling on the school to <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/30/tufts-rumeysa-ozturk-ice-immigration-op-ed/">divest from companies tied to Israel</a>.</p><p>Since taking office, Rubio has also added groups to the State Department&rsquo;s list of foreign terrorist organizations at a blistering pace, focusing largely on gangs and <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/08/15/trump-mexico-war-cartels/">drug cartels </a>that were previously the domain of the criminal legal system.</p><h2><strong>Free Speech Exception?</strong></h2><p>There is an ostensible safety valve in Mast&rsquo;s bill. Citizens would be granted the right to appeal to Rubio within 60 days of their passports being denied or revoked.</p><p>That provided little comfort to the ACLU&rsquo;s Hamadanchy, who is helping rally opposition to the bill.</p><p>&ldquo;Basically, you can go back to the secretary, who has already made this determination, and try to appeal. There&rsquo;s no standard set. There&rsquo;s nothing,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Hamadanchy said the provision granting the secretary of state discretionary power over passports appeared to be an attempt to sidestep being forced to provide evidence of legal violations.</p><p>&ldquo;I can&rsquo;t imagine that if somebody actually provided material support for terrorism there would be an instance where it wouldn&rsquo;t be prosecuted &mdash; it just doesn&rsquo;t make sense,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>While the &ldquo;nonprofit killer&rdquo; bill drew only a smattering of opposition on the right from libertarian-minded conservatives such as Rep. Thomas Massie, R-Ky., Stern said Republicans should be just as concerned about the potential infringement of civil liberties in the passport bill.</p><p>The law, he said, would also grant nearly unchecked power to a Democratic secretary, he said.</p><p>&ldquo;Lately, it appears that the right is so convinced that it will never be out of power that the idea that one day the shoe might be on the other foot doesn&rsquo;t resonate,&rdquo; Stern said. &ldquo;What is to stop a future Democratic administration from designating an anti-abortion activist, a supporter of West Bank settlements, an anti-vaxxer to be a supporter of terrorism and target them the same way? The list is endless.&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 08:08:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/13/business/charlie-kirk-death-fired-comments</link><title>People are getting fired for allegedly celebrating Charlie Kirk’s murder. It looks like a coordinated effort (cnn.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngd46f/people_are_getting_fired_for_allegedly/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngd46f/people_are_getting_fired_for_allegedly/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 15 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngd46f/people_are_getting_fired_for_allegedly/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/ap25255111943391.jpg?c=16x9&q=w_800,c_fill' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><cite> <span>New York</span> &nbsp;&mdash;&nbsp; </cite> </p><p>Dozens of social media posts and messages about the murder of Charlie Kirk, including some that celebrated his death, are being spotlighted by conservative activists, Republican elected officials and a doxxing website as part of an online campaign to punish the posters behind the messages. </p><p>Prominent far-right influencer Laura Loomer, a US senator, and a site called &ldquo;Expose Charlie&rsquo;s Murderers&rdquo; have all drawn attention to people who have posted messages about Kirk&rsquo;s Wednesday assassination. </p><p>The campaigns show how social media posts or personal messages &mdash; even by accounts with few followers or from people who are not public figures &mdash; could easily be surfaced and publicized, and people&rsquo;s personal information can be spread across the internet at a time when doxxing is easier than ever. </p><p>The Charlie&rsquo;s Murderers site, whose domain was registered anonymously and which says it is not a doxxing site, claims it has &ldquo;received nearly 30,000 submissions,&rdquo; according to a message on the site&rsquo;s front page on midday Saturday. Currently, there are a few dozen submissions published on the site. &ldquo;This website will soon be converted into a searchable database of all 30,000 submissions, filterable by general location and job industry. This is a permanent and continuously-updating archive of Radical activists calling for violence.&rdquo; </p><p>Most people whose messages have been posted on the site do not seem to refer to themselves as activists, nor did it seem many were calling for violence. Administrators for the site did not respond to a request for comment. The site also opened an X account on Friday. </p><p>Loomer posted on X on Wednesday, hours after the fatal shooting, that &ldquo;I will be spending my night making everyone I find online who celebrates his death Famous, so prepare to have your whole future professional aspirations ruined if you are sick enough to celebrate his death.&rdquo; CNN was unable to reach Loomer for comment. </p><p>On <a href="https://x.com/ParkerThayer/status/1966199376247926941">X</a>, one account has begun a running &ldquo;Trophy Case&rdquo; &mdash; a &ldquo;mega-thread of all of the people Twitter gets fired, updated live as the news comes in,&rdquo; with dozens of entries of people it claims have lost their jobs. </p><p>And after MSNBC fired senior political analyst <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/11/msnbc-fires-matthew-dowd-charlie-kirk-shooting">Matthew Dowd</a> after he said Kirk&rsquo;s rhetoric might have contributed to his shooting, President Donald Trump himself weighed in. </p><p>&ldquo;They fired this guy, Dowd from (MSNBC), who&rsquo;s a terrible guy, terrible human being, but they fired him. I hear they&rsquo;re firing other people,&rdquo; Trump said on Fox News on Friday morning. <a href="https://matthewdowd.substack.com/p/a-time-to-see-with-new-eyes">On his Substack</a> after the firing, Dowd said the &ldquo;Right Wing media mob&rdquo; attacked him on several platforms. CNN has reached out to Dowd for comment. </p><p>Some of the people whose posts have been highlighted say they&rsquo;re now receiving a barrage of harassment and are worried about becoming the victims of violence. </p><p>For example, Canadian independent journalist Rachel Gilmore posted that she is &ldquo;terrified&rdquo; about retaliation from Kirk&rsquo;s &ldquo;far-right fans&rdquo; after the shooting. That post is the first listed on the anonymous website, including a part where Gilmore said she hoped Kirk survives. She said in a <a href="https://x.com/atRachelGilmore/status/1966553673581912495">video</a> online that she did not celebrate Kirk&rsquo;s death and said she hoped he survives in another post. She also said she received a &ldquo;tsunami&rdquo; of threats and called the last 48 hours of her life &ldquo;a living hell.&rdquo; </p><p><a href="https://x.com/GeoRebekah">Rebekah Jones</a>, a former Florida coronavirus data scientist <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/05/27/us/florida-report-coronavirus-numbers-manipulated">who in 2022 claimed</a> the state of Florida pressured her to manipulate pandemic data, said she contacted the police twice about death threats and about the &ldquo;hit list,&rdquo; her name for the anonymous site. Jones&rsquo; claims about Florida&rsquo;s pandemic data were found to be &ldquo;unsubstantiated,&rdquo; according to a state inspector general report, a finding she disagrees with. </p><p>Jones posted about Kirk on Wednesday, writing: &ldquo;Save your sympathies for the innocent bystanders caught in the crossfire of MAGA&rsquo;s violent political messaging machine.&rdquo; The website republished that post along with other pieces of Jones&rsquo; personal information. </p><p>&ldquo;It is absolutely fair to call it a coordinated harassment campaign,&rdquo; said Laura Edelson, assistant professor at Northeastern University and director of the Cybersecurity for Democracy Project. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s absolutely why it exists, to coordinate and target the harassment toward the selected individuals.&rdquo; </p><p>Some Republican elected officials are also publicizing people who posted about Kirk&rsquo;s murder, including some public-sector employees like teachers. </p><p>Republican Sen. Marsha Blackburn of Tennessee <a href="https://x.com/MarshaBlackburn/status/1965966859259490315">said</a> a Middle Tennessee State University employee should be removed after writing they had &ldquo;ZERO sympathy&rdquo; for Kirk&rsquo;s death. The university <a href="https://www.tennessean.com/story/news/local/2025/09/11/charlie-kirk-death-mtsu-assistant-dean-fired-comments/86090129007/">confirmed</a> to CNN in a statement that the employee was fired &ldquo;effective immediately.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;No university employee who celebrates the assassination of Charlie Kirk should be trusted to shape the minds of the next generation in the classroom. The firing of this MTSU employee was the right decision, and it sends a clear message that this kind of reprehensible behavior must not be tolerated,&rdquo; Blackburn said in a statement to CNN. </p><p>GOP Rep. Nancy Mace of South Carolina also encouraged the firing of a public school teacher, whom the school district later <a href="https://www.kktv.com/2025/09/11/teacher-no-longer-employed-saying-america-became-greater-after-charlie-kirk-shooting-district-confirms/?outputType=amp">confirmed</a> to local news was no longer employed with the district. </p><p>And private companies, such as <a href="https://x.com/FreddysUSA/status/1966159699197264332">Freddy&rsquo;s Frozen Custard &amp; Steakburgers</a> and the <a href="https://www.wral.com/news/local/panthers-employee-fired-controversial-comments-charlie-kirk-death-raleigh/">Carolina Panthers</a>, have also let employees go for their social media posts about Kirk. </p><p>DC Comics <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/11/entertainment/dc-comics-red-hood-charlie-kirk">canceled</a> the just-released &ldquo;Red Hood&rdquo; comic book series after its author, Gretchen Felker-Martin, made comments about Kirk&rsquo;s death on social media. </p><p>In since-deleted posts captured in screengrabs shared by other social media users, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/11/entertainment/dc-comics-red-hood-charlie-kirk">Felker-Martin</a> allegedly wrote on social media after news of Kirk&rsquo;s death: &ldquo;Hope the bullet&rsquo;s OK.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;At DC Comics, we place the highest value on our creators and community and affirm the right to peaceful, individual expression of personal viewpoints. Posts or public comments that can be viewed as promoting hostility or violence are inconsistent with DC&rsquo;s standards of conduct,&rdquo; the company, which like CNN&#8239;is owned by Warner Bros. Discovery, said in a statement. CNN has reached out to representatives for Felker-Martin for comment. </p><p>In most places, private companies can fire employees for any reason &mdash; and that includes crass social media posts, said Jeffrey Hirsch, a professor of labor and employment law at the University of North Carolina. It&rsquo;s a little trickier for public sector employees, but their firings are also justified if the speech is &ldquo;so egregious it disrupts operations.&rdquo; </p><p>In a 1987 <a href="https://firstamendment.mtsu.edu/article/rankin-v-mcpherson/">case</a>, the Supreme Court decided that it was constitutionally protected speech, and not grounds for firing, for a government employee to tell her co-workers she was sorry that a would-be assassin failed to kill President Reagan. </p><p>And it&rsquo;s extra sensitive for teachers, Hirsch said, since they work with young people, especially if the posts are applauding political violence. &ldquo;The reality of the situation is, if they&rsquo;re getting flooded, even if it&rsquo;s from one political wing, with complaints, it&rsquo;s likely to push an employer to fire somebody,&rdquo; he said. </p><div><picture><source height="undefined" width="679" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_679,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="967" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_967,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill" alt="People visit a memorial for Charlie Kirk at the Turning Point USA headquarters on September 12, in Phoenix." height="3723" width="5584"></source></source></source></source></source></picture> </div><p>In other cases, some social media users highlighted Kirk&rsquo;s pro-Second Amendment stance, including <a href="https://x.com/JasonSCampbell/status/1643977032509067272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1643977032509067272%7Ctwgr%5E7e432a9549d971e4b137121ddba2b23374452b57%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsweek.com%2Fcharlie-kirk-says-gun-deaths-worth-it-2nd-amendment-1793113">past</a> news reports that he said some gun deaths were &ldquo;unfortunately&rdquo; worth it to keep the Second Amendment. </p><p>The highlighted social media entries span a range of responses to Kirk&rsquo;s shooting. One post, for example, simply noted the world continued on. </p><p>The website says its explicit aim is to get the people it spotlights fired.&#8239;It was <a href="https://www.whois.com/whois/charliesmurderers.com">registered</a> through a privacy service with an address in Iceland. </p><p>And the site&rsquo;s name already implies that the people whose information it shares are responsible for Kirk&rsquo;s murder, paving the way for harassment, Hank Teran, CEO at open-source threat intelligence platform Open Measures, told CNN. The website also echoes back to Kirk-founded conservative group Turning Point&rsquo;s &ldquo;Professor Watchlist,&rdquo; whose <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/sep/17/turning-point-usa-professor-watchlist">purpose</a> was to unmask what it called &ldquo;radical professors,&rdquo; but often led to harassment and violent threats directed toward people named on that list. </p><p>Altogether, &ldquo;it could be reasonable to conclude that there&rsquo;s some intent to incite harassment,&rdquo; Teran said. </p><p>High political tensions across the country are ramping up people&rsquo;s emotional responses, said Edelson, the Northeastern professor, and it &ldquo;creates a need to do something.&rdquo; </p><p>The blanket blame on &ldquo;the left&rdquo; in some cases extends the blame past the shooter into an amorphous enemy, Whitney Phillips, assistant professor of information politics and ethics at the University of Oregon, told CNN. </p><p>&ldquo;Attempts to call out people designated as being celebratory of Kirk&rsquo;s death, or merely critical of Kirk&rsquo;s life, work to give shape and weight to that enemy,&rdquo; Philips said. That feeds into &ldquo;a false culture war framing.&rdquo; As a result, she said, disconnected groups can be perceived as &ldquo;a downright spiritual enemy of conservatives, and by extension, of America itself.&rdquo; </p><p><em>CNN&rsquo;s Dan Heching contributed to this report.&#8239;</em> </p><p>This story has been updated with additional content. </p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234109280.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 05:52:44 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
