<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=selfhosted&amp;averagePostsPerDay=4&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/selfhosted</title><description>Hot posts in /r/selfhosted (roughly 4 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 08:15:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_32hch-styles-communityIcon_b2t5inv46z331-144x400.png</url><title>/r/selfhosted</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/</link><title>Are there any benefits /drawbacks to putting all of your dockers in 1 compose file?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>New to self hosting and just wondering if there any benefits/drawbacks to putting all of your dockers in 1 compose file?</p><p>Or related dockers together? The Arr stack in one, media/nas in another, productivity in another, helpful tools in another etc. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:49:02 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1njos09</link><title>Built my own server monitoring tool (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hi, </p><p>I wanted to make a dashboard / monitoring tool for my homelab but I didn&#39;t like those that were available and I wanted to create something interesting so I just decided to just do it myself. Basically it checks availability of my web services both by pinging an url and by checking if a matching process is running.</p><p>I wanted to by notified immediately so it also contains a discord integration that sends a message to my private channel if availability of any website changes.</p><p>I also added some fun hw monitoring tools like CPU / RAM usage, volume usage and also external temperature and humidity sensor (DHT22, bought it for like 5 bucks and wanted to try somehing hardwarish for my raspberry pi).</p><p>So far it&#39;s not dockerized, it only runs as a process via pm2. Do you like this project and would you be interested in running it, if I were to make it a docker container? Or contribute with some interesting ideas? It&#39;s open-source in and made Kotlin, you can find it here <a href="https://github.com/rex1234/vaponitor">https://github.com/rex1234/vaponitor</a></p><p>cheers</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/0eyhfekedspf1.png?width=2402&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=b8f3dd79d89cc1eaa7f277cdfbe26a28cd2b02ba" height="1540" width="2402" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/wn0w58kedspf1.png?width=2294&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=9b7075d4f8149946fdfd31adff4c88b197013473" height="1636" width="2294" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/18wobdledspf1.png?width=2483&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=026cdf9773da0995f92889afc2abfd47e6797235" height="1858" width="2483" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/6ec9s7kedspf1.png?width=985&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f16496c16355d30edd0659cb901be15eb3ccd8d3" height="1606" width="985" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/bc1wt7kedspf1.png?width=2352&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=09f029e6267e28c1850ca4ee200f1dcc73fb59e9" height="1370" width="2352" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:15:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1njon8x</link><title>I think I finally finished my Glance dashboard (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I have been working on customizing my Glance setup and I think it is finally in a good place.</p><ul><li>One main page with some monitoring, internet favorites, and my self-hosted services</li><li>One media page</li><li>A mobile and tablet page (same as desktop but without the monitoring)</li><li>And one homepage page that I still need to finalize</li></ul><p>Thanks to the Reddit community for all the Glance setups shared here — they really helped me build mine in return. I still need to set up a GitHub repo so I can share my config as well.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/7xxh67kodspf1.png?width=2796&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=3044f9cdacc548646b3f481692712179c45d7f13" height="2066" width="2796" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/g9hemckodspf1.png?width=2766&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=76bcb8fd259652b2aab67c89098e44aa7d0b1e26" height="2072" width="2766" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:10:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/x85efw7c6spf1.png</link><title>PlexAniBridge - Plex to AniList synchronization (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge">https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge</a><br/>Docs: <a href="https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org">https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org</a></p><p>Hello all, this is an announcement for PlexAniBridge, a tool I developed to synchronize your Plex media server with your AniList profile. Even if you don&#39;t use Plex or AniList, you might find the <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings">mappings database</a> this project spawned interesting.</p><p>So, I built this project because I wanted my Plex watch progress and AniList to stay in sync without manual effort - which is why I spent the last year working on something to save me a couple of minutes of effort. Anyways, I also wanted to avoid the pitfalls the existing solutions have - they either rely on fragile title search, require manual AniList to Plex mappings, or are overly simplistic and miss out on a lot of useful fields. This fixes all of that, and a lot more.</p><p>PlexAniBridge runs alongside your Plex server and keeps AniList and Plex aligned: watch status, episode progress, started/completed dates, ratings, reviews, watchlists, rewatch counts, etc. It&#39;s very customizable; it can be conservative, aggressive, or destructive if you explicitly opt in.</p><p>First of all, arguably the most impressive feature of PlexAniBridge is its <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings">curated anime mappings database</a> (shoutout to <a href="https://github.com/LuceoEtzio">Luceo</a> for contributing to so much of the mappings 🤲). This database is a separate repository that contains mappings for, as of September 17, 2025, 19,916 AniList entires. For context the entire AniList database only has <a href="https://anilist.co/site-stats">~21K</a> entries. That&#39;s 94.8% coverage! The coverage is so great that title-based fuzzy search is disabled by default (but can be opted-in). In fact, my personal library has 99.98% coverage; the kicker? That stat is for episode/movie coverage - not entire shows/seasons. Yes, 99.98% of my EPISODES are mapped to AniList, including special seasons. Okay, I just had to nerd-out about that. Thank you again to Luceo on GitHub for the awesome work on this database.</p><h1>Core features</h1><ul><li>Multi-profile: you can setup multiple profiles with dozens of distinct settings and customization (maybe too much); sync different Plex servers, libraries, and accounts to different AniList users</li><li>Sync modes: you can do interval-based scans, poll for changes, or use Plex webhooks for instant updates; or any combination of those</li><li>Per-field control: Exclude any fields (e.g. score or notes) from being synced to AniList if you want to keep them separate</li><li>Web UI: there&#39;s a really nice web UI to look at sync history, stats, and manage mappings (unfortunately no web UI for configuration yet, but it&#39;s coming, hopefully)</li><li>Automatic AniList backups (JSON snapshots) + included restore functionallity through the UI or a CLI script</li><li>Undo: every sync operation is recorded with before/after state; selected operations can be undone via the UI</li><li>Custom mappings: add or override mappings through the UI or by dropping JSON files in the data dir</li><li>Smart matching: Uses a curated anime mappings DB first. Title search fallback is disabled by default; you can turn it on and control how strict (0–100 similarity threshold)</li><li>Local vs &quot;online&quot; Plex metadata mode: honestly, this feature isn&#39;t that stable, but I thought I&#39;d mention it since it&#39;s helped some users before; online mode can be used to query the Plex metadata server for when data in your local Plex server is incomplete or missing</li><li>Dockerized: easy to deploy, minimal dependencies, single container</li><li>More features to come 🔥</li></ul><h1>Nerd stuff</h1><p>Skip this if you don&#39;t care about the nitty-gritty or if you&#39;re not a nerd like me :-)</p><ul><li>Python (FastAPI + SQLAlchemy + async stack), Svelte frontend (served as a static SPA)</li><li>SQLite for internal state and history tracking</li><li>Caching layers: very intelligent caching to memoize and minimize API calls to AniList and Plex</li><li>Rate limit handling: automatic retries with backoff for AniList API limits (seriously how is it still 30 / minute in 2025)</li></ul><h1>Links</h1><ul><li>Repo: <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge">https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge</a></li><li>Docs: <a href="https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org">https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org</a></li><li>Mappings DB: <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings">https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings</a></li><li>Discord (chat/help): <a href="https://discord.gg/ey8kyQU9aD">https://discord.gg/ey8kyQU9aD</a></li></ul><p>Note: this project is intended for use with the official Plex Metadata agents. Third-party agents (e.g. HAMA) are not supported and may lead to unexpected behavior.</p><p>If this scratches the same itch for you, spin it up, run a dry run, and see if your list settles into shape. Now, fire away with questions.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/x85efw7c6spf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:36:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/zml26e8owppf1.png</link><title>Self-hosted Start Page - Flame (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I found this start-page that can be self-hosted in a Docker container, and so far I love it! I have it set as the home page in Firefox, but I wish I could also set it as the new-tab page. Sometimes I forget all the hostnames and ports for all my various containers, and this makes it so I no longer need to remember them.</p><p>They use the Material-Design-Icons from Google. That icon repository does contain some brand-specific icons, but for the others I had to do some searching online for specific SVGs. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/zml26e8owppf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:07:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nj79tv/mailarchiver_update_two_months_later_thank_you/</link><title>Mail-Archiver Update: Two Months Later - Thank You r/selfhosted!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nj79tv/mailarchiver_update_two_months_later_thank_you/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nj79tv/mailarchiver_update_two_months_later_thank_you/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nj79tv/mailarchiver_update_two_months_later_thank_you/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey everyone!</p><p>Two months ago, I shared my Mail-Archiver project here and WOW - the response has been absolutely incredible! I want to take a moment to thank you guys for all the support, feedback, ideas, and contributions you&#39;ve provided. You&#39;ve truly helped transform this from a personal tool into something much bigger.</p><h1>What&#39;s New Since My Last Post?</h1><p>The feature list has grown tremendously thanks to your suggestions and contributions. Here are the main improvements and additions:</p><ul><li><strong>Multi-User Support</strong> - No longer just for single users! Multiple people can now manage their own archives</li><li><strong>Microsoft 365 Integration</strong> - Full support for O365 mailboxes (this was highly requested!)</li><li><strong>Advanced Import/Export</strong> - Better bulk operations and support for eml and mbox file import and export</li><li><strong>Two-Factor Authentication</strong> - Enhanced security for multi-user environments</li><li><strong>Improved Search</strong> - Much faster and more accurate search even in specific fields</li><li><strong>Multi-Language Support</strong> - The interface is now available in multiple languages</li><li><strong>Performance Optimizations</strong> - Significantly faster search operations</li><li><strong>Dark Mode</strong> - The interface now has a dark mode</li></ul><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/7la71ozznopf1.jpg?width=1671&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=60a4cf8733000bcced30f5e677a4fcbf4384c4b6">https://preview.redd.it/7la71ozznopf1.jpg?width=1671&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=60a4cf8733000bcced30f5e677a4fcbf4384c4b6</a></p><h1>The Power of Community</h1><p>What started as a simple personal backup solution has evolved into a comprehensive email archiving platform, and that&#39;s entirely thanks to this community. That initial post here was truly the starting shot. Since then, there&#39;s been incredible activity and collaboration happening on GitHub. Your feature requests, bug reports, and code contributions have been invaluable.</p><h1>Quick Reminder - What Mail-Archiver Does:</h1><ul><li>Automatically archives emails from multiple accounts (IMAP or M365)</li><li>Stores everything in a local PostgreSQL database</li><li>Provides powerful cross-mailbox search capabilities</li><li>Offers flexible export and restore options</li><li>Maintains complete offline access to your email history</li><li>Now supports multiple users</li></ul><h1>What&#39;s Next?</h1><p>I&#39;m continuing to work on even more features based on your ongoing feedback. The roadmap includes a REST API and additional integrations.</p><p><strong>GitHub repo</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/s1t5/mail-archiver">https://github.com/s1t5/mail-archiver</a></p><p>Thank you again, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a>! Your enthusiasm and contributions have made this project so much better than I ever imagined!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:43:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niqq0i/update_harborguard_scan_and_patch_container_image/</link><title>[Update] HarborGuard - Scan and Patch Container Image Vulnerabilities!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niqq0i/update_harborguard_scan_and_patch_container_image/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niqq0i/update_harborguard_scan_and_patch_container_image/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niqq0i/update_harborguard_scan_and_patch_container_image/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/16suu10yskpf1.png?width=1406&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=8753034216984f8d9943e6e7056a4a4693cf6de8">https://preview.redd.it/16suu10yskpf1.png?width=1406&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=8753034216984f8d9943e6e7056a4a4693cf6de8</a></p><p><strong>TL;DR:</strong> Harbor Guard started as a open soucre dashboard for vulnerability scanning and analysis. Today, HarborGuard can scan an image → pull vulnerability fix data → apply the patch → rebuild the image → and export a <strong>patched image</strong>.</p><h1>Welcome to <a href="https://github.com/HarborGuard/HarborGuard">HarborGuard</a> v0.2b!</h1><p><strong>Existing Features</strong></p><ul><li>Run multiple scanners (Trivy, Grype, Syft, Dockle, OSV, Dive) from one dashboard</li><li>Scan from remote registries</li><li>Group vulnerabilities by severity</li><li>Triage issues (false positives, active tracking)</li><li>Image layer analysis</li><li>Export JSON/ZIP reports</li><li>REST API for automation</li></ul><p>Mentioned above, the major update to the platform is automated patching for scanned image vulnerabilities.</p><p><strong>Why this matters</strong><br/>Scanning alone creates context. <strong>Patching closes the loop.</strong> The goal is to take lead time from <em>weeks</em> to <em>hours-days</em> by making the “is this fixavble?” step obvious and automatable.</p><p><strong>Links</strong><br/>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/HarborGuard/HarborGuard">https://github.com/HarborGuard/HarborGuard</a><br/>Demo: <a href="https://demo.harborguard.co">https://demo.harborguard.co</a></p><p><strong>What I’d love feedback on</strong></p><ul><li>Which registries should I prioritize (GHCR/Harbor/ECR)?</li><li>Opinions on default policies (seeking to bake into CI/CD pipelines for scanning before deployment).</li><li>Interest in image signing (cosign/Notary v2) scanned images and signing patched images.</li></ul></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:40:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ninye6/those_who_use_different_subdomains_for_internal/</link><title>Those who use different (sub)domains for internal and external access - why do you do that?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ninye6/those_who_use_different_subdomains_for_internal/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ninye6/those_who_use_different_subdomains_for_internal/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ninye6/those_who_use_different_subdomains_for_internal/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey,</p><p>I&#39;ve been researching how people use their domain(s) and I noticed that quite a few use a different domain for internal and external access (e.g. &quot;mydomain.com&quot; for external access and &quot;mydomain.org&quot; for internal access). Then there are those who use the same domain but a different subdomain (e.g. &quot;mydomain.com&quot; for external access and &quot;internal.mydomain.com&quot; for internal access).</p><p>I don&#39;t really understand why though. Wouldn&#39;t it be cleaner to just use the same domain for both? Does it bring any significant security benefits?</p><p>Thanks!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 23:00:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niilk8/help_us_pick_an_opensource_product_to_build_in_12/</link><title>Help us pick an open-source product to build in 12 months - tell us your real pain points</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niilk8/help_us_pick_an_opensource_product_to_build_in_12/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niilk8/help_us_pick_an_opensource_product_to_build_in_12/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1niilk8/help_us_pick_an_opensource_product_to_build_in_12/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Small CS team at the university with a full year for a school project (which needs to be released as open source) wants to build and ship one useful, privacy-respecting open-source product. We’ll work in public, maintain it after 1.0, and we’re looking for your real, recurring pain to solve.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:41:27 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nihtgy/giveaway_rugreennasync_10k_celebration/</link><title>Giveaway - r/UgreenNASync 10K celebration</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nihtgy/giveaway_rugreennasync_10k_celebration/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nihtgy/giveaway_rugreennasync_10k_celebration/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nihtgy/giveaway_rugreennasync_10k_celebration/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>We, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/UgreenNASync">r/UgreenNASync</a>, just hit 10,000 members on Reddit, and we think there’s still room for improvement. That’s why we chose <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a> to do a collab.</p><p>To celebrate this incredible achievement, we’re giving back to the community with this amazing giveaway, featuring Ugreen’s new DH series NAS!</p><p>👉 How to enter:</p><ol><li>Join the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a> and <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/UgreenNASync">r/UgreenNASync</a> subreddit</li><li>Answer these questions:<ul><li>what, according to you, is the best selfhosted app to put on a NAS</li><li>How you would use a DH NAS</li></ul></li></ol><p>If you have done all these steps, you are in! ✅</p><p>📅 Giveaway Dates: September 16 – September 26</p><p>🎁 Prizes:<br/>🥇: 1 UGreen DH4300 Plus<br/>🥈: 1 UGreen DH2300<br/>🏅: 2*1 UGREEN MagFlow 10000mAh Powerbank  </p><p>🏆 4 winners will be selected randomly after the giveaway ends and announced both here on Reddit.</p><p>Let’s make the road to the next 10K even more exciting together. Good luck everyone!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 19:11:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</link><title>Plex Breached 2025-09-09: "Action required: Notice of a potential security incident"</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Thanks <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/LeftBus3319">/u/LeftBus3319</a> + <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/FnnKnn">/u/FnnKnn</a></p><ol><li><p><a href="https://plex.tv/reset">Reset your Plex account password immediately</a>, making sure to check &quot;Sign out connected devices after password change&quot;</p></li><li><p>To <a href="https://support.plex.tv/articles/204281528-why-am-i-locked-out-of-server-settings-and-how-do-i-get-in/">reclaim your server</a> you can use SSH Tunneling to get access to <em>your server&#39;s</em> localhost:32400 on your <em>personal</em> host with <code>ssh -L 32400:localhost:32400 serverUser@serverHost</code> - <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd62qn0/">link</a></p></li></ol><hr/><p>Announcement page:<a href="https://links.plex.tv/s/vb/Vn7XtnwDSSaqqDUYoHu1P57ZgZ1FsHgTO2PTIBl6jEOUiHBH3LGmI3nLdDfopQa54PatUwZQhT0Bz8rKAi--jTM4ATdsBHpe4c1Yljr89VkoCOavEGH5wn5Fi_filLNeOMo-lnNqLSLpJpI/lOe98S8UWKdmPnp9StQz9R1-kOSTpWhr/12">https://links.plex.tv/s/vb/Vn7XtnwDSSaqqDUYoHu1P57ZgZ1FsHgTO2PTIBl6jEOUiHBH3LGmI3nLdDfopQa54PatUwZQhT0Bz8rKAi--jTM4ATdsBHpe4c1Yljr89VkoCOavEGH5wn5Fi_filLNeOMo-lnNqLSLpJpI/lOe98S8UWKdmPnp9StQz9R1-kOSTpWhr/12</a></p><p>Announcement screenshot:<a href="https://i.imgur.com/0PMRvVY.png">https://i.imgur.com/0PMRvVY.png</a></p><blockquote><p>Dear Plex User,</p><p>We have recently experienced a security incident that may potentially involve your Plex account information. We believe the actual impact of this incident is limited; however, action is required from you to ensure your account remains secure.</p><p>What happened</p><p>An unauthorized third party accessed a limited subset of customer data from one of our databases. While we quickly contained the incident, information that was accessed included emails, usernames, and securely hashed passwords.</p><p>Any account passwords that may have been accessed were securely hashed, in accordance with best practices, meaning they cannot be read by a third party. Out of an abundance of caution, we recommend you immediately reset your password by visiting <a href="https://plex.tv/reset">https://plex.tv/reset</a>. Rest assured that we do not store credit card data on our servers, so this information was not compromised in this incident.</p><p>What we&#39;re doing</p><p>We&#39;ve already addressed the method that this third party used to gain access to the system, and we&#39;re undergoing additional reviews to ensure that the security of all of our systems is further hardened to prevent future attacks.</p><p>What you must do</p><p>We kindly request that you reset your Plex account password immediately by visiting <a href="https://plex.tv/reset">https://plex.tv/reset</a>. When doing so, there&#39;s a checkbox to &quot;Sign out connected devices after password change,&quot; which we recommend you enable. This will sign you out of all your devices (including any Plex Media Server you own) for your security, and you will then need to sign back in with your new password. We understand that this means a little more work for you, but it will provide additional security to your account.</p><p>Additional Security Measures You Can TakeWe remind you that no one at Plex will ever reach out to you over email to ask for a password or credit card number for payments. For further account protection, we also recommend enabling two-factor authentication on your Plex account if you haven’t already done so.</p><p>Lastly, we sincerely apologize for any inconvenience this situation may cause you. We take pride in our security systems, which helped us quickly detect this incident, and we want to assure you that we are working swiftly to prevent potential future incidents from occurring.</p><p>For step-by-step instructions on how to reset your password, visit: <a href="https://support.plex.tv/articles/account-requires-password-reset">https://support.plex.tv/articles/account-requires-password-reset</a></p><p>Thank you,</p><p>The Plex Team</p></blockquote></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 03:00:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</link><title>Welcome to /r/SelfHosted! Please Read This First</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><h1>Welcome to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">/r/selfhosted</a>!</h1><p>We thank you for taking the time to check out the subreddit here! </p><h2>Self-Hosting</h2><p>The concept in which you host your own applications, data, and more. Taking away the &quot;unknown&quot; factor in how your data is managed and stored, this provides those with the willingness to learn and the mind to do so to take control of their data without losing the functionality of services they otherwise use frequently. </p><h2>Some Examples</h2><p>For instance, if you use dropbox, but are not fond of having your most sensitive data stored in a data-storage container that you do not have direct control over, you may consider NextCloud</p><p>Or let&#39;s say you&#39;re used to hosting a blog out of a Blogger platform, but would rather have your own customization and flexibility of controlling your updates? Why not give WordPress a go. </p><p>The possibilities are endless and it all starts here with a server. </p><h2>Subreddit Wiki</h2><p>There have been varying forms of a wiki to take place. While currently, there is no <em>officially</em> hosted wiki, we do have a <a href="https://github.com/r-selfhosted/wiki">github repository</a>. There is also at least one unofficial mirror that showcases the live version of that repo, listed on the index of the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki">reddit-based wiki</a></p><h2>Since You&#39;re Here...</h2><p>While you&#39;re here, take a moment to get acquainted with our few but important <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki/rules">rules</a></strong></p><p>And if you&#39;re into Discord, <a href="https://discord.gg/UrZKzYZfcS">join here</a></p><p>When posting, please apply an appropriate flair to your post. If an appropriate flair is not found, please let us know! If it suits the sub and doesn&#39;t fit in another category, we will get it added! <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fselfhosted">Message the Mods</a></strong> to get that started.</p><p>If you&#39;re brand new to the sub, we highly recommend taking a moment to browse a couple of our awesome self-hosted and system admin tools lists.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/Kickball/awesome-selfhosted">Awesome Self-Hosted App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/n1trux/awesome-sysadmin">Awesome Sys-Admin App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/veggiemonk/awesome-docker">Awesome Docker App List</a></p><p>In any case, lot&#39;s to take in, lot&#39;s to learn. Don&#39;t be disappointed if you don&#39;t catch on to any given aspect of self-hosting right away. We&#39;re available to help! </p><p>As always, happy (self)hosting!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 06:59:15 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
