<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=askscience&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/askscience</title><description>Hot posts in /r/askscience (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 08:42:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-VXukRtebQAtdj6BUMLlOjCh3XnLH9_oScHxsDJ-vsio-144x400.png</url><title>/r/askscience</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/</link><title>If you filled a jetfighter cockpit with fluid would the pilot feel less GForce?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>So the pilot completely hooked to some sort of breathing system. If you filled the cockpit with fluid or gelatinous fluid would the pilot feel less GForce pulling harder maneuver</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>No.   The pilot would feel the same amount of force.  </p><p>However, being completely supported would allow the pilot to handle more acceleration than they would with limited contact points.  There is still a limit, however, where you start damaging internal organs.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/nf3qkt5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.esa.int/gsp/ACT/projects/liquid_ventilation/">https://www.esa.int/gsp/ACT/projects/liquid_ventilation/</a><br/>It seems there was some testing on this and, yes, it can help but the limiting factor is air in the lungs causing the fluid to press down on people&#39;s chest, so if you can somehow figure out a way to make air into a liquid and not have the person die from that, you can go to even higher g-forces.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/nf3rrp5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Very tangentially relevant but the Expanse book series actually had an advanced society doing exactly that. But it was used for high G maneuvers in SPACE! Do note that this is science fiction. </p><p>They even filled the lungs with a breathable fluid! </p><p>&quot;Full-Submersion Crash Couch</p><p>A Full-Submersion Crash Couch or Fully-Immersive Crash Couch is a device that completely surrounds the human body in shock-absorbing gel, and fills the lungs with highly oxygenated fluid to make the chest cavity as incompressible as possible, likely for days. Custom Laconian crash couch seats are surrounded by screens and instruments that can be yanked away in under a second, and the couch chamber filled with a breathable fluid for high-g burn shortly after.[3] Ships equipped with them could make the travel time from one system to another almost trivial by comparison to the standard science vessels and freighters of the civilian fleet. A journey of weeks could be accomplished in days. The Laconian science vessel Falcon was one of he first ships equipped with this type of crash couch.&quot;</p><p><a href="https://expanse.fandom.com/wiki/Crash_couch">https://expanse.fandom.com/wiki/Crash_couch</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/nf3znr6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It kind of depends on what you mean. Force is force. No matter what a g is pulled on the pilot when the plane pulls a g. However springs and cushions can dampen a force, to a point. If the g pulls the pilot back into the seat, then the seat cushion is that spring. Adding a fluid around the pilot won’t help in that scenario but having a more cushioned chair will, again only up to a certain point. Theoretically cushioning all around the pilot of adding a fluid (air already is a fluid but I assume you mean a more viscous one like a liquid) could help dampen forces in other directions. I don’t know much about fighter pilot seats, but I assume they are already well engineered for this.</p><p>A big issue is really the g forces inside the body. Those forces cause blood to pool, make breathing difficult, etc. An external fluid won’t help with that. Filling up a pilots lungs with a breathable fluid could help some of those issues though.</p><p>Tl/dr: unlikely to be worth it</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/nf3qnwy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They&#39;ll still &quot;feel&quot; the same g-force, and their inner ear will still register the same acceleration as they would otherwise.</p><p>But it gets interesting the effects of that g-force. Normally, without any support,  blood pools in the legs and lower extremities as the g-force increases. This is because blood is denser than air and so the lower extremities essentially bulge outward as the pressure of the blood exceeds the pressure of the air. If this happens too much and too long, you lose blood to the brain and the pilot passes out.</p><p>But if you filled the cockpit with fluid with the same, or even higher, density than blood, and hold the fluid in a rigid container around the pilot, the blood will no longer pool. This is because the fluid now exerts its own pressure on the body that matches the force of the blood at the same g-force.</p><p>So while your pilot will &quot;feel&quot; the same force, they&#39;ll *tolerate* it better than with just air alone.</p><p>Kinda like how whales can withstand ocean depths, but die if you put them on land. The ocean water supports their weight,  but air does not. You accelerate a pilot to high-g, they&#39;re essentially whales. and survive better in water than in air. </p><p>Further reading: <a href="https://apps.dtic.mil/sti/tr/pdf/ADA278125.pdf">https://apps.dtic.mil/sti/tr/pdf/ADA278125.pdf</a></p><p>the military already tested the concept and in experiments in a centrifuge pilots could withstand greater g-forces than usual.</p><p>Some g-suits use fluid but i don&#39;t know if they are standard issue or still experimental.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/nf42qdj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Theoretically you can have a person immersed completely in liquid in a fixed rigid container. This would allow the acceleration forces to be equally distributed over the surface of the body.   </p><p>You wouldn&#39;t have unlimited tolerance due to the heterogenous density of the human body, but it would be significantly augmented.   </p><p>Then you need to suck the air out of your lungs, because the lungs have a lower density than the rest of the body and will get squished. You would then have to fill the lungs with a fluid with the same density as the outside fluid. ECMO which we use in ICUs has been one of the things that has been proposed to continue to get respiration with air free lungs.   </p><p>This paper has some interesting ideas: <a href="http://www.esa.int/gsp/ACT/doc/BNG/ACT-RPR-BNG-2007-09-SuperAstronaut-IAC.pdf">Beyond astronauts capabilities: a critical review</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/nf4up9n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yes, the fluid basically would act to increase pressure around the pilot&#39;s legs to keep the blood from pooling in the lower extremities. The downside is that the fluid will greatly increase the weight of the aircraft, and there&#39;s also the problem of being able to breathe and easily get in and out of the cockpit. </p><p>You can achieve the same effect with a g-suit. This is a flight suit that  has inflatable bladders that constrict around the pilot&#39;s legs when under heavy G&#39;s.<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G-suit">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G-suit</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nksvhv/if_you_filled_a_jetfighter_cockpit_with_fluid/nf3rkpi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 08:58:56 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/</link><title>Why does testosterone deepen human voices?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hiya!  I thought to ask because I do not know where to find this answer and this subreddit might be able to give me the answer google cannot give.  Plus, when I do look it up, the entire focus is on the mechanisms for deepening voices rather than the particulars in what pressures and advantages/purposes would evolve and keep such a trait.</p><p>I&#39;ve noticed that primarily humans developed deeper voices in the presence of elevated testosterone.  Granted, not everyone does but the vast majority of people with decently elevated levels of testosterone do end up with deeper voices.</p><p>Feel free to correct me here, but I&#39;ve noticed most other animals do not get deeper voices when there is higher levels of testosterone in their system.</p><p>So, why does testosterone make humans develop deeper voices?</p><p>edit: thanks for the answers!</p><p>I think I&#39;ll give some further context on my curiosity.</p><p>I&#39;ve been on testosterone for a number of years and my voice has deepened as a result.  Though, I did forget the aspect of how one utilizes their voice that impacts how deep it is registered as.  I love my deep voice and pondered the above questions for the above mentioned reasons.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Greater distance between natural resting place for vocal cords and mouth.  Larger chest cavity, etc.</p><p>Here, fun trick, hum and hold the note.  Now slowly raise it.  Does it feel like a vibrating ring rising up through your head?  Try and get it to feel like it&#39;s strongest around your eye balls (if that isn&#39;t where it was by default).  That&#39;s you actually raising your voice box.  Now, puff out/raise your chest.  Just suck in your gut let it puff out/up your chest.  Chances are that raised your voice a little more.  Finally, if you can figure out how to lock your adam&#39;s apple in place mid-swallow or cough, you can really achieve a higher pitched voice.</p><p>Altogether, some men can legitimately sound like women with these techniques.</p><p>Sound is a matter of vibrations and space.  Faster vibrations and smaller space = higher pitch.  Naturally, slower vibration + large space = lower pitch.</p><p>Testosterone isn&#39;t really why voice pitch lowers, it more encourages the development of One&#39;s physiology which facilitates lower pitched voices.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/nf5edh8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Testosterone is a hormone. A hormone is a chemical messenger which gives instruction to your body to do something </p><p>In puberty - the body releases testosterone which instructs your body to grow and change (muscles, balls drop, more aggression etc) including your vocal cords. Longer chords create lower bass sound, just like a guitar string</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/nf5n3p1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;ll go from a musical point of view - thicker strings = deeper notes. Testosterone enlarges lots of things in the body, muscle (with training) may be the main focus with it but heart muscle and clitoris among others all see growth. Not a certainty I know but there&#39;s probably not much research done as numbers of women who &#39;supplement&#39; openly has to be low.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/nf5fjyt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There&#39;s an element of this whereby testosterone in development -&gt; larger average body size -&gt; deeper voice, but you can very clearly compare cisgendered men and women of the same height and chest size and hear that that&#39;s not the whole difference. There is also an element of sexual selection and sexual signalling.</p><p>Many animals use certain features as signals to others of their species to indicate their fitness as a mate. Because deep voices indicate size, and size indicates ability to successfully feed yourself and stay healthy, at some point in our primate history, female hominids started to prefer males with deeper voices. Deeper voices were then selected for specifically, past the point where it indicated the underlying feature of size.</p><p><a href="https://link.springer.com/rwe/10.1007/978-3-031-08956-5_186-1">https://link.springer.com/rwe/10.1007/978-3-031-08956-5_186-1</a></p><p>As noted elsewhere in the thread, there is also a significant cultural component to how we mentally identify a speaking voice as &#39;male&#39; or &#39;female,&#39; which is learned as a child or teenager by both men and women.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/nf5jgjm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The very basic answer is that testosterone is a growth hormone and as such will cause the vocal cords/larynx etc to grow. The larger this set up is then generally speaking the lower the natural resting pitch will be.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/nf5l60e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sometimes things don’t have a selective advantage but are just side effects of other things that do.  T has quite a lot of changes that help males get selected for mating but also have changes that are side effects that might be nutril or even detrimental (immune suppression).  A deeper voice may just be a side effect or other selected for characteristics.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkpa32/why_does_testosterone_deepen_human_voices/nf6svti/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:07:33 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkn76q/how_can_proteins_handle_pressure/</link><title>How can proteins handle pressure?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkn76q/how_can_proteins_handle_pressure/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkn76q/how_can_proteins_handle_pressure/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkn76q/how_can_proteins_handle_pressure/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Maybe this is a stupid question, but I’ve been doing a lot of reading recently about the structural mechanisms behind protein function. They all seem so intricate and exact, that I’m having a hard time understand how they could work under high pressure, especially considering how protein dense cells are. </p><p>Am I destroying a good amount of proteins every time I put pressure on a limb? How does this not cause massive cell death in that area? Or can ribosomes, motor proteins, structural proteins continue working just fine even if I’ve just smacked my hand against a wall?</p><p>I hope this question makes sense…</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The menachial stress of everyday pressure is absorbed at macroscopic levels by bones, joints, skin and so on. You&#39;re rarely putting any significant compressive stress on proteins. The highest stress on your tissue is tensile stress on muscles and the relevant proteins here are specifically evolved to work for this.However proteins can be destroyed / damaged by other molecules violently bumping into them and that happens simply when your body temperature gets too hot.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkn76q/how_can_proteins_handle_pressure/nf5d5t0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Basically proteins are very small - they don&#39;t undergo the kind of stress and shear forces you&#39;re imagining because the way they&#39;re in contact with their surroundings is basically being bounced around by individual molecules. When you put pressure on your tissue, there just isn&#39;t a differential stress across the length of most proteins. It&#39;s more like the whole protein encounters maybe a few more bonks per nanosecond from the water molecules in your cytosol, and not just in one spot but randomly all over. </p><p>Proteins typically fold into their working configuration in a way that minimizes their energy in certain ways. A protein that is bent out of shape is like a ball at the top of a hill - it wants to roll back down to the lower energy configuration. Many proteins can become permanently misshapen in the right circumstances, but this is usually due to temperature or chemistry changes. A protein that gets too hot may flop into a non-functional configuration, then fold up incorrectly when it cools off or react with other chemicals because a usually-hidden part is exposed in the unfolded shape. This mostly won&#39;t happen from mechanical stresses across such a vast object as your body tissues.</p><p>When you smack your hand into the wall, you&#39;re applying a relatively sharp force to the molecules that make up your cells - but not directly. This force arises as some molecules of your hand interact with the wall molecules and then bounce into more hand molecules and so on in a complicated chain of bonks. While the total energy of your slap may seem pretty high on the scale of a molecule, it is very rapidly spread out among very many molecules, such that the average kinetic energy of all the molecules in your hand barely changes at all. Each protein in your hand will barely register an increased frequency of molecular bonks, and they won&#39;t be concentrated in a way that puts more pressure on one side of the protein vs another.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkn76q/how_can_proteins_handle_pressure/nf5p49h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Covalent bonds are incredibly strong. When materials do fail by yielding or breaking, they break along fault lines at much larger scales than individual molecules. When you tear a plastic bag, none of the individual polymers are being broken apart, but the weaker bonds between the molecules are being disrupted.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nkn76q/how_can_proteins_handle_pressure/nf6wxn9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 04:32:05 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/</link><title>How do you navigate in space?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>If you are traveling in space, how do you know your position relative to your destination and starting point?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It depends on the mission. Near Earth, just use Earth as reference. If you are orbiting something else, use that. The Sun and stars are (almost) always available, too. The time needed for radio signals from Earth is a useful distance measurement, too.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/nf1d3y9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>On the simplest level, you pick a point of reference, and make all your measurements based on that point of reference.  </p><p>Most of our spaceflight is done in earth orbit.  Your frame of reference is (mostly) earth, and the prime meridian. Ground stations, GPS, the sun, and start trackers can all work together to provide orientation, time, and tight physical tracking of your &quot;thing in space&quot;.  No one system provides the resolution you need for things like docking, or even geostationary station keeping.  </p><p>In short, you&#39;re using a clock, calendar, and spotting the sun and certain starts to determine exactly where you are.  </p><p>OK, the more interesting question that&#39;s relevant to 21st century humans.  How do know where you are, when you&#39;re somewhere outside the earth moon system.  This gets a lot more interesting, but the answer is mostly the same.  But as we get further from earth, earth based reference points become much less useful.  We know where planets, stars, and other solar objects are via an almanac, and since we know where things &quot;should be&quot; we can look at where they are, and do the math to see where our spacecraft is.  </p><p>In Sci-Fi when they talk of &quot;checking star charts&quot; is actual like.. real techniques.  </p><p>So that&#39;s a lot of how you can tell where you are in local space, your starting point, I assume, was on a big rock.  Big rocks follow very regular orbital patterns.  As long as you know what time it is, you know where your starting point is. </p><p>Ok, now lets talk about deep space.  This gets really hard.  At some distance our solar system becomes a point in space, which makes triangulating your position very tricky.  The way we&#39;ve determined how to do deep space naviation is by making records of quazars.  They are essentially blinking lights in the cosmos, which are very regular, and we can use them like GPS, or Loran to determine where we are.  </p><p>That&#39;s to say, you can very easily, get lost in space.  If you don&#39;t know where you started, things get really hard.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/nf2jxrg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In interstellar space, the relative positions and timing of pulsars can tell you where you are, where you&#39;re heading, how fast you&#39;re going, and even the rough date. There are so few outside forces working on a spacecraft that dead reckoning should be sufficient most of the time, though. You&#39;d just want confirmation after completing a slingshot maneuver or some other interaction. Within the solar system, radio communication with Earth is usually part of the picture, along with inertial systems and star tracking. (See Very Long Baseline Interferometry.) Without Earth, or a comparable source of extremely precise orbital parameters, you&#39;re going to need optical tracking of multiple bodies in the system and a fair amount of computing power if you want to get anywhere specific. Station-keeping relative to two bodies is of course much easier.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/nf2kwjr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Dead reckoning is the &quot;easy&quot; way - it&#39;s not like anything can hide in space. But it&#39;s also not super precise.</p><p>It depends how precise you need.  Radio delay range-finding (or laser, or any other distance-measuring method) to a target whose position you know can give you a fairly precise distance... but that only narrows your position down to anywhere on the surface of a sphere around the target at that distance. You need another source of information to figure out where you are on the sphere.</p><p>For probes that often comes from knowing it&#39;s position against the backdrop of stars, giving you both a highly accurate distance and a less accurate direction from a known location.  But there are alternatives.</p><p>If you have range finding to a second object, that gives you a second sphere you know you&#39;re on the surface of - which lets you know you&#39;re somewhere on the circle where the two spheres intersect.  A third target will give you a third sphere - and you&#39;ll know you&#39;re somewhere where that sphere intersects the circle you&#39;ve already narrowed it down to - so only one or two points.  If you already know roughly where you are, you can possibly rule out the second point... otherwise you&#39;ll need a 4th target and sphere to guarantee that there&#39;s only one point you could be at.</p><p>That&#39;s basically how GPS works, with a bit more complexity under the hood since you also have to calculate your distance based on the lag between synchronized signals.  But there are alternatives.</p><p>---</p><p>If you know the position of two targets relative to each other, then the angle you see between them will again narrow down your position to a somewhat more complicated surface - basically, you could be on a circle perpendicular to the line between them, at the right distance to get that angle... or you could be closer, to they would appear further apart, but closer to one end than the other, looking at the line between them at an angle, so they would look closer together, with the two effects combining to give you the same apparent separation.  I don&#39;t think the surface is a sphere... but it&#39;s some well-defined shape that&#39;s a perfectly symmetrical rotation around the line between the two targets.</p><p>Add a third target, and you go from one connecting line between them to three, and you know you&#39;re lying on the intersection of a similar rotated surface around each of those lines.  Just like with range-spheres that might not be enough to narrow you down to only one point... but a 4th target adds three more lines and their surfaces, which should be plenty.</p><p>The location you get that way probably won&#39;t be as precise as with range-spheres... that depends on just how far away the targets are, and how precisely you can measure the angles between them, which is unlikely to get anywhere close to the precision with which you can measure range-finding times... but it&#39;s still pretty good.  And if you can add range-finding to at least one target that can add a lot of precision in one direction.  And if the target is your destination, then that&#39;s the most important exact distance to know anyway.</p><p>That&#39;s basically how sextants work - you measure the angle between targets, which combined with a known distance from the center of the Earth lets you pinpoint where you are reasonably accurately.  Not perfectly... but you rarely need perfect.  Just close enough so that you can make sure you&#39;re heading in the right direction - you can make further corrections as you go - the closer you are to the targets, the more precise your measurements.</p><p>---</p><p>For interstellar travel normal range-finding won&#39;t work - stars are too far away.  Measuring angles (and parallax, as closer stars appear to move faster than further ones) will let you keep track of roughly where you are, though given the distances involved it will be pretty imprecise.  But we can also potentially do one better, using stable pulsars whose positions and timings are well mapped as something similar to GPS. Though with the closest pulsar being almost 400 light years away, the precision will suffer somewhat.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1nk5rqk/how_do_you_navigate_in_space/nf2q7sa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:02:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/</link><title>I remember a few years ago there was a story about how the expansion of the universe slowed down by like, decimal. Any updates there?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m butchering this with my wording but I remember a story maybe 2-3 years ago about how basically, whatever data we use to track the perpetual expansion of the universe since the big bang slowed down just the <em>tiniest</em> amount and essentially no one has ever seen that happen before. Does this ring any bells to anyone and are there any updates of what we learned since then? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I don&#39;t know what specifically you are referring to. But the expansion of the universe is measured as the Hubble constant, which lots of people have tried to estimate and gotten slightly different estimates. The generally agreed upon consensus is that it&#39;s around 70km/s/Mparsec. However different measurements give slightly different values, sometimes 68, sometimes 74. It&#39;s also an area of investigation whethet the Hubble constant has been constant throughout the lifetime of the universe (excluding inflation) or if it has or will vary. </p><p>Whatever news story you&#39;re thinking of was likely sensationalized reporting about a slight discrepancy in the measurement of the exact value of the Hubble constant.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/netdq3t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It doesn&#39;t slow down, it&#39;s still accelerating.</p><p>The simplest model is a constant dark energy density, which will make distances between galaxy clusters increase exponentially (with a time constant of ~16 billion years) once the impact of the matter density becomes negligible. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dark_Energy_Spectroscopic_Instrument">DESI</a> has seen some hint that the dark energy density might have decreased by ~10% over time. That&#39;s still an accelerated expansion, just a bit less acceleration than expected (if their measurement turns out to be right and not just a statistical fluctuation or systematic error).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/netyq51/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I remember reading about this too. Maybe this is  the one: <a href="https://phys.org/news/2025-09-dark-energy-evolving-astrophysicists-possibilities.html">https://phys.org/news/2025-09-dark-energy-evolving-astrophysicists-possibilities.html</a></p><p>This is brand new emerging research. From the article it seems the researcher believes the distant universe will still just be cold and dark.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/nexjez0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Red Giants burn brightly before they start to fuse helium. We&#39;ve noticed that they burn at a very predictable luminosity right before they &quot;tip&quot; to helium fusion in a bright flash. Because JWST can see more of these distant red giants, we can judge distance to those galaxies more accurately. We also have the red shift: the amount of expansion, aka a &quot;speed.&quot; Divide speed by distance and you have a rate. THAT is essentially the Hubble Constant.  Greatly simplified, but that is the core concept.  </p><p>We can also measure type 1a supernovas, which are also a consistent brightness, and do measurements with Ligo on neutron star mergers for expansion rate calculations.  With all of these methods converging, as well as new telescopes coming online, we will be able to nail down the Hubble constant with a lot more certainty in the next 10 years, as an educated guess.  Right now we have a disagreement between methods of about 9%. I bet we can get it down to 1% soon.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/netq80x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What you’re remembering matches the new DESI results from March 2025. They didn’t see the universe <em>stopping</em> expansion, but their galaxy-survey data suggests dark energy may not be perfectly constant, the rate of accelleration itself could be slightly weakening over time. We’re still in an accelerating universe, but the “push” seems weaker than before. It’s very preliminary (not 5-sigma yet), but it lines up with the idea that dark energy might evolve instead of staying fixed. Future missions like Euclid and Roman should pin this down.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/nez5fa3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This may be relevant:</p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/space/comments/1bi2dbh/james_webb_telescope_confirms_there_is_something/">https://www.reddit.com/r/space/comments/1bi2dbh/james_webb_telescope_confirms_there_is_something/</a></p><p>The James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) has confirmed a significant discrepancy in the measurement of the expansion rate of the universe</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njtyhz/i_remember_a_few_years_ago_there_was_a_story/nf5vjbm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 05:56:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/</link><title>Do aquatic mammals yawn?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I yawned, then my dog yawned, then it dawned on me i never thought about a whale or dolphin “yawning”, i understand they have blowholes which is much different than a mouth so would they even feel the need to yawn, and if they cant would the neurological urge to be present?</p><p>Seals yawn, thats cool.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/3vb9xy/do_aquatic_animals_yawn/">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/3vb9xy/do_aquatic_animals_yawn/</a><br/>It looks like, yes, dolphins and whales can yawn and even other animals like fish. Some good links in this thread about it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/nessf79/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yes, aquatic mammals like dolphins, seals, and whales do yawn. It is often linked to similar reasons as land mammals, such as oxygen intake, brain cooling, or even social signaling. Though it might look a bit different underwater, the behavior is still there.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/nev38pk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Green sea turtle snuggles into a sea sponge and lets out a big yawn before a nap.&quot;</p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/NatureIsFuckingLit/comments/ngyf9t/green_sea_turtle_snuggles_into_a_sea_sponge_and/">https://www.reddit.com/r/NatureIsFuckingLit/comments/ngyf9t/green_sea_turtle_snuggles_into_a_sea_sponge_and/</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/nexd8rg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yep, aquatic mammals do yawn, but it varies by group. Seals, sea lions and otters show very clear “classic” yawns when they’re sleepy or stretching, and in their case it can also be a mild threat display. Dolphins and whales do a version called “jaw-gaping,” which looks like a yawn but might be more about social signaling or stretching jaw muscles rather than being tired. Either way, it’s definitely a thing in the water!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/nez5wn3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Dogs don’t catch a yawn in quite the same way humans do, it’s more about communication and a social bond. Dogs tend to yawn for these reasons rather than being tired, although they can yawn for that reason as well.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njr71s/do_aquatic_mammals_yawn/nf26hco/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 03:53:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njppuz/gravitational_wave_event_discussion_for/</link><title>Gravitational Wave Event discussion for non-astronomers?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njppuz/gravitational_wave_event_discussion_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njppuz/gravitational_wave_event_discussion_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njppuz/gravitational_wave_event_discussion_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>A few days ago I got this neat app on my phone (<a href="https://www.ligo.caltech.edu/page/GWPhoneAlerts">https://www.ligo.caltech.edu/page/GWPhoneAlerts</a>) that alerts me when there&#39;s been a possible GWE (gravitational wave event) detected by LIGO etc. It&#39;s pretty cool, and today there was what looks like a biggish one (99% chance it&#39;s a black hole merger event?). However I really don&#39;t understand most of what it&#39;s showing me, or the broader context (this big event today - is it likely to get downgraded later? etc etc). Like, should I be excited? Or blah? I need to know how to feel about this event that was rated as being as strong as, uh... a false alarm that would occur once every 286986 years.</p><p>Is there some place on the internet where GWE nerds excitedly discuss these events as they appear? Where I could learn to understand the skymaps, etc? I would promise not to bother anyone, if I could sneak in to listen..</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Here is the event: <a href="https://gracedb.ligo.org/superevents/S250917aq/view/">https://gracedb.ligo.org/superevents/S250917aq/view/</a></p><p>List: <a href="https://gracedb.ligo.org/superevents/public/O4/">https://gracedb.ligo.org/superevents/public/O4/</a></p><p>There was a similar event September 12, and another one September 6, and another one September 1. They are all likely to be binary black hole mergers, and many of the candidates in between (with a higher false alarm rate) should be real events as well.</p><p>LIGO/Virgo have confirmed well over 100 of these, with something like 300 more candidates. How excited you should be is up to you, but this isn&#39;t anything uncommon.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njppuz/gravitational_wave_event_discussion_for/nety8cn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:53:10 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/</link><title>Please explain how humans and other primates ended up with a "broken" GULO gene. How does a functioning GULO gene work to produce vitamin C? Could our broken GULO gene be fixed?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Basically, what the title asks. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>For anyone else wondering, GLUO is responsible for Vitamin C production.   L-gulonolactone oxidase - Wikipedia <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/L-gulonolactone_oxidase">https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/L-gulonolactone_oxidase</a></p><p>Changes in genes are pretty random, it&#39;s basically because our DNA is constantly bombarded by radiation, copied by processes that don&#39;t perfectly validate what they copied, and generally f**ked with by things like viruses among other causes. </p><p>Natural selection is the name for pressure that is applied on living creatures in a natural environment.  If creatures are good enough at finding food and mates, they&#39;ll reproduce and their genes will live on.  If creatures are bad at either of those things, their genes die with them or are at least less likely to survive. </p><p>Primates losing their ability to self-produce Vitamin C was random, but because primates keep eating fruit that contained bountiful vitamin C, it never hindered their ability to find food or mates so the gene was perpetuated to the next generations.  Eventually, the broken gene became the default.</p><p>**</p><p>For your other question as to how L-Gulonolactone oxidase produces vitamin C, it&#39;s really just a catalyst for a reaction that produces the precursor for Ascorbic Acid (Vitamin C).  Just one piece of the long puzzle.  </p><p>As to if that gene could be fixed, I would absolutely believe that we have the capacity to do it with CRISPER CAS-9 but any effort would immediately and almost <em>preemptively</em> run afowl of any ethics boards unless you were smart enough to plot a course through a lot of long, difficult research.  Or you could just eat a banana or any other cheap, easily available fruit.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/nesosm7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The ability to make your own Vitamin C was presumably lost because apes were living in the jungle and eating lots of fruit, which was naturally rich in Vitamin C.  So, if a mutation in that gene happened, it was not fatal, and the apes were able to continue reproducing.  The gene product is a protein enzyme that catalyzes the Vitamin C molecule.  The actual synthesis (the chemical steps) is beyond my pay grade😄. In theory, gene therapy could introduce a functional gene into an organism, but it would probably be easier to just eat an orange (or an otherwise nutritionally balanced diet), take a vitamin pill, or even like a few tablespoons of ketchup per day is enough.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/nesq590/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There&#39;s a pretty good scientific and entertaining book called Human Errors about this and other broken and inefficient genes, systems, etc in humans.</p><p>Apparently mammals synthesize vitamin c in the liver from glucose through a multi step enzymatic process. And over time the gulo gene mutated in primates so much that it broke the last step of that process. The last enzyme is no longer produced. Since vitamin c was likely abundant in their diet, it was not a problem solved by natural selection and it was passed on to humans that way, as a broken pseudo gene.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/neszcte/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The problem with trying to fix the gene is we&#39;ve had 60 million years of evolving to conserve and store vitamin C, so turning production on again could mean our bodies create too much of it which can lead to a whole heap of health issues. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/net826l/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Maybe I misunderstand, but what was the avantage of not being capable of vitamine C production, a broken GULO gene? Humans in extrême environments (arctic regions, deserts) could easily benefit from a working GULO ?And aren&#39;t there humans that have it accidentally turned on?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/net2577/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Also there’s evidence that not having this gene enables us to store fat better, which was a significant contributor to our ancestors being able to migrate out of Africa, so… all things considered, I’d like that gene back, but most of us wouldn’t be here if we still had it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/neycnze/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It seems people are still confused about how natural selection works.... My understanding is that if a gene is mutated, either to add a function or breaks a function, but the mutation has no effect on survival, then natural selection does not care about it.  Those individuals with the mutated gene carry on reproducing and passing on the mutated gene. If those with that gene mutation out compete or are the only group that survives a disaster, then that gene can become dominant and the default. Actually, the concept of natural selection does not care about genes at all, it only cares about survival and passing on the specific copy of DNA that exists in the individual, if situations make that untenable then that copy of DNA does out.</p><p>And to be honest, how do we KNOW,  there is not a group out there that DOES still produce vit c? We have a general idea that that gene is gone, but we have not tested every lineage known.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njeg86/please_explain_how_humans_and_other_primates/nevlrbb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:49:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/</link><title>Ask Anything Wednesday - Engineering, Mathematics, Computer Science</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Welcome to our weekly feature, Ask Anything Wednesday - this week we are focusing on <strong>Engineering, Mathematics, Computer Science</strong></p><p>Do you have a question within these topics you weren&#39;t sure was worth submitting? Is something a bit too speculative for a typical <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskScience">/r/AskScience</a> post? No question is too big or small for AAW. In this thread you can ask any science-related question! Things like: &quot;What would happen if...&quot;, &quot;How will the future...&quot;, &quot;If all the rules for &#39;X&#39; were different...&quot;, &quot;Why does my...&quot;.</p><p><strong>Asking Questions:</strong></p><p>Please post your question as a top-level response to this, and our team of panellists will be here to answer and discuss your questions. The other topic areas will appear in future Ask Anything Wednesdays, so if you have other questions not covered by this weeks theme please either hold on to it until those topics come around, or go and post over in our sister subreddit <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskScienceDiscussion">/r/AskScienceDiscussion</a> , where every day is Ask Anything Wednesday! Off-theme questions in this post will be removed to try and keep the thread a manageable size for both our readers and panellists.</p><p><strong>Answering Questions:</strong></p><p>Please only answer a posted question if you are an expert in the field. <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/wiki/index#wiki_answering_askscience">The full guidelines for posting responses in AskScience can be found here</a>. In short, this is a moderated subreddit, and responses which do not meet our quality guidelines will be removed. Remember, peer reviewed sources are always appreciated, and anecdotes are absolutely not appropriate. In general if your answer begins with &#39;I think&#39;, or &#39;I&#39;ve heard&#39;, then it&#39;s not suitable for <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskScience">/r/AskScience</a>.</p><p>If you would like to become a member of the AskScience panel, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/about/sticky">please refer to the information provided here</a>.</p><p>Past AskAnythingWednesday posts <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/search?q=flair%3A%27meta%27&amp;restrict_sr=on&amp;sort=new&amp;t=all">can be found here</a>. Ask away!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>If changing state of a particle instantly changes it&#39;s counterpart multiple light-years away, does that mean state information travels faster than light?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/neqff9z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What would happen to a star like UY Scuti if a black hole of near-Solar mass fell onto it?Just a nova of some sort? Would the much larger star just burn around it?Would the star cataclysmically implode around the falling black hole?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/nevsk13/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How can people &quot;see&quot; and feel gravitational ripples? Would it be something like when you see heat going up from the asphalt and if you defocus your sight it looks like reality is &quot;bending&quot;? As for the feel part, would it be similar to when you are experiencing a close earthquake and your body feels like a jelly for a few miliseconds or you&#39;d feel like a force that is pushing/pulling you? Thanks</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/nf1apyl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Statistics question here.</p><p>Let&#39;s say I combine saliva samples from multiple people into batches to save money and test each batch for the presence of coronavirus. If at least one person in the batch has the virus, I get a positive result for that batch. However, each batch can contain samples from different numbers of people.</p><p>How would I be able to calculate the prevalence of Covid among the population?</p><p>For example, I might have the following data:</p><p>Batch 1 - 5 samples - Negative<br/>Batch 2 - 1 sample - Negative<br/>Batch 3 - 25 samples - Positive<br/>Batch 4 - 11 samples - Positive<br/>Batch 5 - 2 samples - Negative<br/>etc...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/nepilfl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If i have a wire that doesnt have a constant diameter, how is the line resistance affected?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/nexbss9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Is turbulent flow just a bunch of three body problems interacting?</p><p>As in, solve one, solve the other.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/netz9rm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Does P=NP?  Why or why not?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1njdyj3/ask_anything_wednesday_engineering_mathematics/nerbxpa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:30:28 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
