<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=selfhosted&amp;averagePostsPerDay=4&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/selfhosted</title><description>Hot posts in /r/selfhosted (roughly 4 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 23:38:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_32hch-styles-communityIcon_b2t5inv46z331-144x400.png</url><title>/r/selfhosted</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ncdj4i/looking_for_offline_selfhosted_alternatives_to/</link><title>Looking for offline / self-hosted alternatives to Postman</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ncdj4i/looking_for_offline_selfhosted_alternatives_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ncdj4i/looking_for_offline_selfhosted_alternatives_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1ncdj4i/looking_for_offline_selfhosted_alternatives_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’ve been trying to move away from Postman since it feels heavier with every update and keeps pushing cloud sync. For local development, I’d rather keep things simple and offline.</p><p>So far I’ve checked out a few different options. Bruno is interesting because it stores everything in plain text, which makes version control with Git a lot easier. Hoppscotch caught my eye too since it’s open source and can be self-hosted if you want it running in your own setup. I also gave Hurl a shot, which is neat if you’re comfortable with the CLI since it uses text files for defining API calls.</p><p>Some people suggested Yaak (from the original Insomnia founder) and also Insomnium, which is basically a community fork of Insomnia before the company started changing things. On the more old-school side, there’s SoapUI, which still works fine if you need SOAP and complex testing. And then there are lighter takes like Apidog, which feels closer to Postman but works nicely offline too.</p><p>Curious what others here are using — are you sticking with Postman, or have you fully switched to a self-hosted / offline setup?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 14:10:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</link><title>Plex Breached 2025-09-09: "Action required: Notice of a potential security incident"</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Thanks <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/LeftBus3319">/u/LeftBus3319</a> + <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/FnnKnn">/u/FnnKnn</a></p><ol><li><p><a href="https://plex.tv/reset">Reset your Plex account password immediately</a>, making sure to check &quot;Sign out connected devices after password change&quot;</p></li><li><p>To <a href="https://support.plex.tv/articles/204281528-why-am-i-locked-out-of-server-settings-and-how-do-i-get-in/">reclaim your server</a> you can use SSH Tunneling to get access to <em>your server&#39;s</em> localhost:32400 on your <em>personal</em> host with <code>ssh -L 32400:localhost:32400 serverUser@serverHost</code> - <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd62qn0/">link</a></p></li></ol><hr/><p>Announcement page:<a href="https://links.plex.tv/s/vb/Vn7XtnwDSSaqqDUYoHu1P57ZgZ1FsHgTO2PTIBl6jEOUiHBH3LGmI3nLdDfopQa54PatUwZQhT0Bz8rKAi--jTM4ATdsBHpe4c1Yljr89VkoCOavEGH5wn5Fi_filLNeOMo-lnNqLSLpJpI/lOe98S8UWKdmPnp9StQz9R1-kOSTpWhr/12">https://links.plex.tv/s/vb/Vn7XtnwDSSaqqDUYoHu1P57ZgZ1FsHgTO2PTIBl6jEOUiHBH3LGmI3nLdDfopQa54PatUwZQhT0Bz8rKAi--jTM4ATdsBHpe4c1Yljr89VkoCOavEGH5wn5Fi_filLNeOMo-lnNqLSLpJpI/lOe98S8UWKdmPnp9StQz9R1-kOSTpWhr/12</a></p><p>Announcement screenshot:<a href="https://i.imgur.com/0PMRvVY.png">https://i.imgur.com/0PMRvVY.png</a></p><blockquote><p>Dear Plex User,</p><p>We have recently experienced a security incident that may potentially involve your Plex account information. We believe the actual impact of this incident is limited; however, action is required from you to ensure your account remains secure.</p><p>What happened</p><p>An unauthorized third party accessed a limited subset of customer data from one of our databases. While we quickly contained the incident, information that was accessed included emails, usernames, and securely hashed passwords.</p><p>Any account passwords that may have been accessed were securely hashed, in accordance with best practices, meaning they cannot be read by a third party. Out of an abundance of caution, we recommend you immediately reset your password by visiting <a href="https://plex.tv/reset">https://plex.tv/reset</a>. Rest assured that we do not store credit card data on our servers, so this information was not compromised in this incident.</p><p>What we&#39;re doing</p><p>We&#39;ve already addressed the method that this third party used to gain access to the system, and we&#39;re undergoing additional reviews to ensure that the security of all of our systems is further hardened to prevent future attacks.</p><p>What you must do</p><p>We kindly request that you reset your Plex account password immediately by visiting <a href="https://plex.tv/reset">https://plex.tv/reset</a>. When doing so, there&#39;s a checkbox to &quot;Sign out connected devices after password change,&quot; which we recommend you enable. This will sign you out of all your devices (including any Plex Media Server you own) for your security, and you will then need to sign back in with your new password. We understand that this means a little more work for you, but it will provide additional security to your account.</p><p>Additional Security Measures You Can TakeWe remind you that no one at Plex will ever reach out to you over email to ask for a password or credit card number for payments. For further account protection, we also recommend enabling two-factor authentication on your Plex account if you haven’t already done so.</p><p>Lastly, we sincerely apologize for any inconvenience this situation may cause you. We take pride in our security systems, which helped us quickly detect this incident, and we want to assure you that we are working swiftly to prevent potential future incidents from occurring.</p><p>For step-by-step instructions on how to reset your password, visit: <a href="https://support.plex.tv/articles/account-requires-password-reset">https://support.plex.tv/articles/account-requires-password-reset</a></p><p>Thank you,</p><p>The Plex Team</p></blockquote></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 03:00:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r5Y1I1Zol2k</link><title>Self Hosted YouTube algorithm (youtube.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbzs1e/self_hosted_youtube_algorithm/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbzs1e/self_hosted_youtube_algorithm/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbzs1e/self_hosted_youtube_algorithm/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I stumbled on this project that uses python and the youtube api to create an improved youtube video recommendation dashboard. Instead of relying on google to suggest videos, you can use an LLM to create your own recommendations. </p><p><a href="https://github.com/rosadiaznewyork/video-finder-algorithm">https://github.com/rosadiaznewyork/video-finder-algorithm</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><iframe width="356" height="200" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r5Y1I1Zol2k?feature=oembed&enablejsapi=1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="I Got So Annoyed with YouTube I Built My Own"></iframe></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 02:32:05 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbyzan/storyteller_v2_is_available/</link><title>Storyteller v2 is available!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbyzan/storyteller_v2_is_available/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbyzan/storyteller_v2_is_available/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbyzan/storyteller_v2_is_available/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://smoores.dev/post/announcing_storyteller_v2/">https://smoores.dev/post/announcing_storyteller_v2/</a></p><p>This has been a <em>long</em> time coming (5 months!). It&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve posted on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a> about Storyteller, and it&#39;s improved a lot since then!</p><p>As always, happy to answer questions and chat.</p><p><a href="https://smoores.dev/images/storyteller-sample-library-2.png">Screenshot</a></p><p>Storyteller is a self-hosted ebook and audiobook platform, with built-in support for automatically generating WhisperSync-style &quot;readaloud&quot; books. You provide it with an EPUB file and your audiobook, and it will automatically align the text with the audio, providing you with a new EPUB file that has the audio baked in via Media Overlays.</p><p>You can then use the Storyteller mobile apps, or other reader apps such as BookFusion and Kobo (the app, not the devices, unfortunately), to read and/or listen to your books.</p><p>With v2, Storyteller is now gunning to be your fully featured ebook, audiobook, and readaloud book library management system. It supports standalone ebooks and audiobooks (with mobile app and web reader/listener support coming soon!), advanced search and sort functions, and a wide array of features for managing your library’s metadata and organizing your collections. And you can now point Storyteller at your existing &quot;books&quot; folder and have it automatically import books as they&#39;re added to your filesystem.</p><p>Oh, and we support OAuth and OIDC, now!</p><p>Take a look at the blog post or <a href="https://storyteller-platform.gitlab.io/storyteller/docs/managing-your-library/">the new docs</a> for some more detail about what&#39;s new!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 02:01:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbqvye/turn_your_iphone_into_a_powerful_selfhosted_ocr/</link><title>Turn Your iPhone Into a Powerful Self-Hosted OCR Server</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbqvye/turn_your_iphone_into_a_powerful_selfhosted_ocr/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbqvye/turn_your_iphone_into_a_powerful_selfhosted_ocr/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nbqvye/turn_your_iphone_into_a_powerful_selfhosted_ocr/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a>! I&#39;ve built something that might interest you folks who love running your own services.</p><h2>What is it?</h2><p><strong>OCR Server</strong> transforms your iPhone into a local OCR (Optical Character Recognition) server that runs entirely on your device. No cloud dependencies, no API keys, no data leaving your network.</p><ul><li>100% Self-hosted: Runs locally on your iPhone</li><li>Privacy-first: Zero cloud dependencies, all processing happens on-device</li><li>Network accessible: Any device on your LAN can use it via simple HTTP API</li><li>Powered by Apple&#39;s Vision Framework: Industry-leading accuracy</li><li>Completely free: No subscriptions, no usage limits</li></ul><h2>Features</h2><ul><li>Multi-language support with automatic detection</li><li>Bounding box coordinates for each detected text element</li><li>Web interface for quick testing</li><li>JSON API for programmatic access</li><li>Real-time system monitoring (CPU, memory, thermal, battery)</li><li>Configurable recognition levels (Fast vs Accurate)</li></ul><h2>API Example</h2><p><code>curl -H &quot;Accept: application/json&quot; \  -X POST http://&lt;YOUR IP&gt;:8000/upload \  -F &quot;file=@01.png&quot;</code></p><p>Response looks like this:</p><p><code>{  &quot;success&quot;: true,  &quot;message&quot;: &quot;File uploaded successfully&quot;,  &quot;ocr_result&quot;: &quot;Hello\nWorld&quot;,  &quot;image_width&quot;: 1247,  &quot;image_height&quot;: 648,  &quot;ocr_boxes&quot;: [    {      &quot;text&quot;: &quot;Hello&quot;,      &quot;x&quot;: 434.7201472051599,      &quot;y&quot;: 269.3123034733379,      &quot;w&quot;: 216.30970547749456,      &quot;h&quot;: 69.04344177246088    },    {      &quot;text&quot;: &quot;World&quot;,      &quot;x&quot;: 429.5100030105896,      &quot;y&quot;: 420.4043957924413,      &quot;w&quot;: 242.85499225518635,      &quot;h&quot;: 73.382080078125    }  ]}</code></p><h2>Use Cases Perfect for <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a></h2><ul><li>Document digitization without cloud services</li><li>Screenshot text extraction for documentation</li><li>Multi-device OCR cluster using multiple iPhones</li></ul><h2>Links</h2><ul><li><strong>App Store:</strong> <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/ocr-server/id6749533041">Download OCR Server</a></li><li><strong>GitHub:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/riddleling/iOS-OCR-Server">Source Code (MIT License)</a></li></ul><h2>Pro Tips for Self-Hosters</h2><ul><li>Enable Guided Access to prevent accidental app switching</li><li>Connect to power for 24/7 operation</li><li>Use a dedicated iPhone if you have an old one lying around</li><li>Integrate with scripts - the JSON API works great with Python</li></ul><p>TL;DR: Free iPhone app that turns your phone into a powerful local OCR server. No cloud, no subscriptions, just plug-and-play document text extraction for your network.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:01:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nb8q13/release_of_first_component_of_screenlite_a/</link><title>Release of first component of Screenlite, a self-hosted digital signage platform</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nb8q13/release_of_first_component_of_screenlite_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nb8q13/release_of_first_component_of_screenlite_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nb8q13/release_of_first_component_of_screenlite_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hi everyone,</p><p>About three months ago, I shared the beginnings of Screenlite, an open-source, self-hosted digital signage CMS with player apps planned for Windows, Linux, web browsers, and Android.</p><p>Since then, I’ve been working steadily. There’s a lot of ongoing work on the CMS itself, and I’m committing changes almost every day. It’s still a long road, but this is the first step where the community can get involved.</p><p>As part of the project, I’ve built a small Android browser with kiosk-like fullscreen mode. The idea is to test and refine features early, since many of them will later be reused in the full Screenlite Android player.</p><p>Even on its own, this app can already be useful for simple digital signage use cases — for example, showing schedules, menus, dashboards, or other web apps fullscreen on a TV or tablet.</p><h1>Current features</h1><ul><li>starts automatically on boot and stays in the foreground</li><li>hides system UI and prevents the device from sleeping</li><li>retries on network errors</li><li>supports rotation (0°, 90°, 180°, 270°)</li><li>TV-friendly interface</li></ul><p>Repo: <a href="https://github.com/screenlite/web-kiosk">https://github.com/screenlite/web-kiosk</a></p><h1>How you can help</h1><ul><li>Try out the APK (available under Releases) on Android TV, box, or tablet</li><li>Report bugs or share feedback about what works / doesn’t work</li><li>Suggest improvements that would make it more useful within the scope of a kiosk-style browser</li></ul><p>This is just the first piece, but it’s already something you can run and test. Your feedback now will help shape both this lightweight app and the upcoming Screenlite Android player.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 05:21:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nazopm/saving_energy_in_selfhosting_wakeonlan_and_rust/</link><title>Saving Energy in Self-Hosting, Wake-on-LAN, and Rust</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nazopm/saving_energy_in_selfhosting_wakeonlan_and_rust/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nazopm/saving_energy_in_selfhosting_wakeonlan_and_rust/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nazopm/saving_energy_in_selfhosting_wakeonlan_and_rust/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><h1>Introduction</h1><p>Some time ago, I started exploring the world of self-hosting, and since it’s so addictive, you always find yourself thinking about which new services you could host. I have a pretty simple machine, an Intel i3 (4th gen) with an RTX 1650 4GB GPU not too power-hungry.</p><p>Since my GPU was underused, I decided to install <a href="https://ollama.com">Ollama</a>, a tool that allows running AI models locally. After testing Ollama, I quickly realized that 4GB wasn’t enough to run the latest models.</p><h1>Hardware Upgrade</h1><p>With this new problem, I now had the perfect excuse to upgrade my other machine the one I use for gaming. After a lot of research, I managed to get a good deal on an RX 7900 XTX. Now I have 24GB to run the latest models. But I was surprised by its power consumption, easily pulling <del>over 300 watts</del> around 45 watts in idle. This raised a red flag: keeping this machine on 24/7 would be far from energy-efficient.</p><h1>Initial Idea</h1><p>What if I had a way to power on the machine only when I needed it? I’d need another device to manage it. A Raspberry Pi would be perfect, since I could leave it running 24/7 (its power draw is minimal), and it could turn the power-hungry machine on and off.</p><h1>Wake-on-LAN</h1><p>With that in mind, I started looking into ways to remotely turn my machine on. That’s when I discovered Wake-on-LAN, or simply WoL. After configuring my motherboard and operating system, I was able to power on my machine remotely with this simple command:</p><pre><code>wakeonlan &lt;MAC_ADDRESS&gt;</code></pre><p>Because of how WoL works, it sends a “magic packet” over the local network  meaning you need to be on the same LAN to wake the machine. That’s fine, one less problem. Now I could turn the machine on remotely, which led to the next question: when do I need to power it on? The answer was simple whenever I needed to access services running on it, like Ollama or any other self-hosted service.</p><h1>Intercepting Traffic</h1><p>Most services use a specific port, such as 11434 for Ollama (where it opens a TCP connection). I thought of using a reverse proxy to intercept the traffic and, when necessary, wake the server. Once the server was online, the proxy could redirect the traffic to it. Perfect! Now we’d have the ability to wake the server remotely only when needed.</p><pre><code>sequenceDiagram    participant User as User    participant Proxy as Reverse Proxy (Wakezilla)    participant Server as Server (Ollama - port 11434)    User-&gt;&gt;Proxy: TCP Request (port 11434)    Proxy-&gt;&gt;Server: Check if online    alt Server OFF        Proxy-&gt;&gt;Server: Send Wake-on-LAN (power on server)        Server--&gt;&gt;Proxy: Server initialized    end    Proxy-&gt;&gt;Server: Redirect traffic    Server--&gt;&gt;Proxy: Response    Proxy--&gt;&gt;User: Return data</code></pre><h1>When to Shut Down the Server?</h1><p>Now that we can remotely power on the server, we also need to decide when to shut it down. I don’t want it running 24/7, so I thought, since we’re already intercepting traffic, why not monitor it? When no more requests come in, the server can be shut down. By adding a requests-per-minute threshold, if no requests are made, the server can be turned off.</p><h1>How to Do This?</h1><p>After some research, I didn’t find many tools that did exactly what I wanted, so I decided to build my own solution. Since the target machine would need some software anyway to receive the shutdown command, I kept it simple: a CLI that starts a small web server. When it receives an unauthenticated HTTP request (for now), it shuts down the machine. I also added a health check so the reverse proxy can verify whether the machine is online.</p><h1>Wakezilla</h1><p>With that in mind, I built Wakezilla, a simple tool that does exactly this: it intercepts traffic, wakes the server with WoL when needed, and powers it down when there’s no more traffic. All of this in a straightforward way, written in Rust, packaged as a single binary with no external dependencies, making it easy to use anywhere.</p><h1>Open Source Project</h1><p>The project is available on GitHub, and contributions are welcome, whether to add new features or improve documentation. If you’d like to try it out, just follow the instructions in the project’s README. If you have any questions, feel free to open an issue, and I’ll be happy to help. Here’s the project link: <a href="https://github.com/guibeira/wakezilla">Wakezilla</a></p><p>Originally posted on :<br/><a href="https://guibeira.dev/wakezilla-en.html">https://guibeira.dev/wakezilla-en.html</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 23:15:22 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nawkyn/selfhosted_ai_is_the_way_to_go/</link><title>Self-hosted AI is the way to go!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nawkyn/selfhosted_ai_is_the_way_to_go/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nawkyn/selfhosted_ai_is_the_way_to_go/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nawkyn/selfhosted_ai_is_the_way_to_go/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Yesterday I used my weekend to set up local, <a href="https://imgur.com/a/FCBEKP3">self-hosted AI</a>. I started out by installing <a href="https://ollama.com/">Ollama</a> on my Fedora (KDE Plasma DE) workstation with a Ryzen 7 5800X CPU, Radeon 6700XT GPU, and 32GB of RAM. </p><p>Initially, I had to add the following to the systemd ollama.service file to get GPU compute working properly: </p><pre><code>[Service]Environment=&quot;HSA_OVERRIDE_GFX_VERSION=10.3.0&quot;</code></pre><p>Once I got that solved I was able to run the Deepseek-r1:latest model with 8-billion parameters with a pretty high level of performance. I was honestly quite surprised! </p><p>Next, I spun up an instance of Open WebUI in a podman container, and setup was very minimal. It even automatically found the local models running with Ollama. </p><p>Finally, the open-source Android app, Conduit gives me access from my smartphone. </p><p>As long as my workstation is powered on I can use my self-hosted AI from anywhere. Unfortunately, my NAS server doesn&#39;t have a GPU, so running it there is not an option for me. I think the privacy benefit of having a self-hosted AI is great. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 21:15:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</link><title>Welcome to /r/SelfHosted! Please Read This First</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><h1>Welcome to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">/r/selfhosted</a>!</h1><p>We thank you for taking the time to check out the subreddit here! </p><h2>Self-Hosting</h2><p>The concept in which you host your own applications, data, and more. Taking away the &quot;unknown&quot; factor in how your data is managed and stored, this provides those with the willingness to learn and the mind to do so to take control of their data without losing the functionality of services they otherwise use frequently. </p><h2>Some Examples</h2><p>For instance, if you use dropbox, but are not fond of having your most sensitive data stored in a data-storage container that you do not have direct control over, you may consider NextCloud</p><p>Or let&#39;s say you&#39;re used to hosting a blog out of a Blogger platform, but would rather have your own customization and flexibility of controlling your updates? Why not give WordPress a go. </p><p>The possibilities are endless and it all starts here with a server. </p><h2>Subreddit Wiki</h2><p>There have been varying forms of a wiki to take place. While currently, there is no <em>officially</em> hosted wiki, we do have a <a href="https://github.com/r-selfhosted/wiki">github repository</a>. There is also at least one unofficial mirror that showcases the live version of that repo, listed on the index of the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki">reddit-based wiki</a></p><h2>Since You&#39;re Here...</h2><p>While you&#39;re here, take a moment to get acquainted with our few but important <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki/rules">rules</a></strong></p><p>And if you&#39;re into Discord, <a href="https://discord.gg/UrZKzYZfcS">join here</a></p><p>When posting, please apply an appropriate flair to your post. If an appropriate flair is not found, please let us know! If it suits the sub and doesn&#39;t fit in another category, we will get it added! <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fselfhosted">Message the Mods</a></strong> to get that started.</p><p>If you&#39;re brand new to the sub, we highly recommend taking a moment to browse a couple of our awesome self-hosted and system admin tools lists.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/Kickball/awesome-selfhosted">Awesome Self-Hosted App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/n1trux/awesome-sysadmin">Awesome Sys-Admin App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/veggiemonk/awesome-docker">Awesome Docker App List</a></p><p>In any case, lot&#39;s to take in, lot&#39;s to learn. Don&#39;t be disappointed if you don&#39;t catch on to any given aspect of self-hosting right away. We&#39;re available to help! </p><p>As always, happy (self)hosting!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 06:59:15 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
