<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 05:47:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/bill-gates-trump-ice-signature-aviation_n_68acd96fe4b0d17ae21e7ec4</link><title>Donald Trump's Mass Deportation Agenda Has A Surprising Stakeholder: Bill Gates (huffpost.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncg8xr/donald_trumps_mass_deportation_agenda_has_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncg8xr/donald_trumps_mass_deportation_agenda_has_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 54 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncg8xr/donald_trumps_mass_deportation_agenda_has_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bf094a1800004c3f8c75c3.jpg?ops=1200_630' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><section><p>President <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/news/topic/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a>&rsquo;s mass deportation agenda has a surprising stakeholder: Bill Gates. </p><p>The multibillionaire tech mogul and philanthropist owns a large portion of a key service provider for immigration flights. </p><p>And now, with new funding from Congress and an aggressive push from the White House, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/13/politics/ice-flights-locations-tracking-maps">more </a>and <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5e221cacff87ba2d2833cf54/t/6890c72c36915023d86b61a2/1754318642276/ICE+Air+JulTHCPDF.pdf">more</a> immigration flights are taking off, transporting immigration detainees both within the United States and to their home countries &mdash; or, in some cases, to places <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/us-trump-administration-third-country-deportations_n_6877b467e4b0cc43a0bf1473">they&rsquo;ve never been before</a>.</p><p>Gates&rsquo; connection to the U.S. detention and deportation machine is a company called Signature Aviation. Signature <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/">calls</a> <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/news/signature-aviation-celebrates-modernized-terminal-in-winston-salem/">itself</a> &ldquo;the world&rsquo;s largest network of private aviation terminals,&rdquo; and it&rsquo;s a linchpin in the day-to-day machinery of Trump&rsquo;s immigration enforcement apparatus. </p><div><blockquote><p><em><strong>For two decades, HuffPost has been fearless, unflinching, and relentless in pursuit of the truth. <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/support?utm_campaign=in-text-support-member">Support our mission</a> to keep us around for the next 20 &mdash; we can&rsquo;t do this without you.</strong></em></p></blockquote></div><p>Private <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/airlines/avelo-airlines-ice-deportation-flights-f5f150db?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAj1SzI2kI1CRzURQ_WyA4mcDpyIzkB4u6f82FXR4SWdhHu5IyqQtLihhYn_1jc%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68ac9721&amp;gaa_sig=HtxI3-vjIq5Ad6GG3oLKbC4fg0EZyid4wTeVtZxLSo1IqolawfD1fu5Zz6aeA-I46yNp0JOF_c6YVBo2yUplAA%3D%3D">charter</a> <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/inside-ice-air-deportation-flights">carriers</a> subcontracted for Immigration and Customs Enforcement to transport immigration detainees &mdash; part of a network known as &ldquo;ICE Air,&rdquo; a reference to the Department of Homeland Security&rsquo;s ICE Air Operations &mdash; use Signature&rsquo;s services daily. As a fixed-base operator, or FBO, Signature supplies ground crews, aviation fuel, boarding stairs, and airplane hangar space at hundreds of airports around the world, mostly in the United States. </p><p>The private firm that holds Gates&rsquo; and the Gates Foundation Trust&rsquo;s assets, Cascade Investment, increased its stake in the company to 30% in 2021, when it and two partners bought Signature outright for $4.7 billion. Human rights advocates &mdash; plane trackers and activists who <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/seattle-boeing-field-ice-deportation-flights">keep tabs on deportation flights</a>, as well as the aviation and logistics companies profiting from them &mdash; say Gates&rsquo; stake in Signature is at odds with his humanitarian work, including the Gates Foundation&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/about/committed-grants?q=immigration">support</a> of a plethora of immigration-focused nonprofits. Without FBOs like Signature, they say, Trump&rsquo;s mass deportation agenda would be stuck on the ground.</p><p>Gates himself has not publicly commented on Signature Aviation&rsquo;s crucial role in servicing ICE Air flights. Neither the Gates Foundation nor Cascade Asset Management Company, which oversees Cascade Investment, responded to multiple requests for comment. </p><p>At one airport, Signature appears to have worked to make its branding less visibly associated with immigration flights. Last month, a set of Signature boarding stairs in Seattle &mdash; where the county government set up cameras in 2023 to keep an eye on immigration flights &mdash; got a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jjindc.bsky.social/post/3lwrlthymck2w">new accessory</a>: two sheets of cardboard, taped over the company&rsquo;s logos. </p><figure><picture><source srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale&amp;format=webp 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560&amp;format=webp 2x"><img alt="A worker in a mask walks off a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement flight departing from King County International Airport-Boeing Field in Seattle on Aug. 23." src="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale" srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560 2x"></source></picture><div><figcaption>A worker in a mask walks off a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement flight departing from King County International Airport-Boeing Field in Seattle on Aug. 23.</figcaption><div><p><span>Lindsey Wasson/Associated Press</span></p></div></div></figure><p><span>FBOs &ldquo;are critical, obviously, because they provide fuel and other services while the plane makes its stops,&rdquo; said Tom Cartwright, a retired financial executive who has tracked ICE flights for nearly six years. </span></p><p><span>Cartwright estimated that through the end of June, 95% of the ICE Air flights he&rsquo;d tracked were operated by charter companies, with military and Coast Guard planes being used for the remainder. That doesn&rsquo;t include a tally of commercial flights used to deport people, he said &mdash; but in fiscal year 2017, ICE Air used charter flights to remove or transfer 181,317 people, compared with just 8,288 who were removed on commercial flights, </span><a href="https://www.oig.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/assets/2019-03/OIG-19-28-Mar19.pdf"><span>according to a 2019 DHS inspector general report</span></a><span>. </span></p><p><span>&ldquo;In this case, when they&rsquo;re doing 1,100 flights a month, that&rsquo;s a pretty significant piece of the operation &mdash; so they&rsquo;re absolutely critical,&rdquo; he said of the planes carrying immigration detainees. &ldquo;Without a fixed-base operator, I&rsquo;m not sure this system really operates.&rdquo; </span></p><p><span>In a </span><a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2025/08/21/gross-human-rights-violations-in-washington-state-enforced-disappearance-and-refoulement/"><span>recent report</span></a><span> covering local connections to alleged human rights violations stemming from the Trump administration&rsquo;s immigration enforcement agenda, the University of Washington Center for Human Rights (UWCHR), which has studied ICE Air flights </span><a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air/"><span>for years</span></a><span>, called out Gates&rsquo; Signature Aviation investment specifically. </span><em></em></p><p><span>&ldquo;In Washington, our most famous philanthropist grows his investments in part by supporting a company complicit in gross human rights abuses, potentially ascending to the level of crimes against humanity,&rdquo; the report alleged.</span></p><h2><strong>Signature At Work</strong></h2><p><span>To report this story, HuffPost scoured government records and plane location data, collected plane-spotting reports from activists on the ground, and matched aviation photographs to planes known to ferry ICE detainees. Still, ICE Air operates largely in the shadows, and many key players, including Signature Aviation, did not answer detailed questions about their operations. </span></p><p><span>So we wanted to see the process for ourselves. On Aug. 31, HuffPost witnessed Signature Aviation in action. On the tarmac of Newark Liberty International Airport, a couple hundred yards from Signature&rsquo;s private terminal, a Signature-branded set of boarding stairs and fuel tanker met a Boeing 737 belonging to Avelo Airlines, the low-cost carrier that has faced </span><a href="https://www.wbaltv.com/article/avelo-airlines-protest-bwi-marshall-ice-deportation-flights/65943086"><span>protests</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://www.change.org/p/we-won-t-fly-avelo-until-they-stop-ice-flights-no-volaremos-con-avelo"><span>a boycott</span></a><span> from potential passengers over </span><a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/airlines/avelo-airlines-ice-deportation-flights-f5f150db?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAj1SzI2kI1CRzURQ_WyA4mcDpyIzkB4u6f82FXR4SWdhHu5IyqQtLihhYn_1jc%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68ac9721&amp;gaa_sig=HtxI3-vjIq5Ad6GG3oLKbC4fg0EZyid4wTeVtZxLSo1IqolawfD1fu5Zz6aeA-I46yNp0JOF_c6YVBo2yUplAA%3D%3D"><span>its work with ICE Air</span></a><span>. Like other </span><a href="https://www.jetphotos.com/photo/keyword/N804VL"><span>Avelo</span></a> <a href="https://www.jetphotos.com/photo/keyword/N805VL"><span>planes</span></a><span> working ICE Air flights, this plane, with the tail number N801XT, was recently painted completely white, erasing any </span><a href="https://www.jetphotos.com/showphotos.php?aircraft=all&amp;airline=all&amp;country-location=all&amp;photographer-group=all&amp;category=all&amp;keywords-type=all&amp;keywords-contain=1&amp;keywords=n801xt&amp;photo-year=all&amp;genre=all&amp;search-type=Advanced&amp;sort-order=2"><span>prominent Avelo branding</span></a><span>. </span></p><p><span>One by one, 16 people dressed in white and gray, and shackled at the wrists, waist and ankles, hobbled off the plane and onto Signature Aviation&rsquo;s boarding stairs, unable to reach the handrail on the stairs. On the tarmac, the second man in line shuffled his feet slightly, taking uneven steps as his head drooped, making him look older than the rest. The plane had just finished a </span><a href="https://www.flightaware.com/live/flight/VXP55/history/20250831/1530Z/KAEX/KEWR"><span>two-and-a-half-hour flight</span></a><span> from Alexandria, Louisiana, a </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/07/31/us/ice-deportation-hub-alexandria-louisiana.html"><span>central hub</span></a><span> for ICE Air flights, meaning the men had </span><a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/inside-ice-air-deportation-flights"><span>likely</span></a><span> been shackled for several hours straight. The detainees waited on the tarmac as they were processed into sprinter vans with flashing police lights. A Signature-branded fuel tanker sidled up to the plane, and personnel on the ground hauled plastic mesh bags </span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/north-america-us-news-ap-top-news-az-state-wire-immigration-a1d44854cd134333b2cb85de853056c9"><span>known</span></a><span> to be used for detainees&rsquo; personal belongings. Eventually, accompanied by Port Authority police vehicles, the caravan left the tarmac, likely heading to nearby ICE detention facilities. </span></p><p><span>Two weeks prior, HuffPost saw a similar scene play out, when a plane operated by Eastern Air Express &mdash; the same aircraft CNN recently </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AlRypvEB76Q"><span>spotted</span></a><span> ferrying people in ICE custody &mdash; was met with similar fanfare at Newark. Law enforcement vehicles with flashing lights approached that plane as well, including one that looked similar to a shuttle bus previously </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wSIL0wpxUyc"><span>filmed</span></a><span> transporting detainees out of Delaney Hall, the </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/14/nyregion/newark-ice-detainees-escape.html"><span>infamous</span></a><span> immigration jail. </span></p><p><span>In both cases, after about an hour on the ground, the planes continued on their way around the country, ferrying people in ICE custody to other detention facilities, and for some, onto their ultimate deportation, according to one activist plane spotter who goes by the moniker &ldquo;JJ in DC&rdquo; on Bluesky and who helped HuffPost track the aircraft.</span></p><blockquote><div><p>&ldquo;In Washington, our most famous philanthropist grows his investments in part by supporting a company complicit in gross human rights abuses, potentially ascending to the level of crimes against humanity.&rdquo;</p><p>- Recent report from the University of Washington Center for Human Rights</p></div></blockquote><p>Such scenes are now commonplace throughout the country. But they are not new. For over a decade, private aviation contractors have handled tens of thousands of ICE Air flights, according to Cartwright&rsquo;s count, which can collectively <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air/">transfer or remove</a> hundreds of thousands of people <a href="https://www.oig.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/assets/2019-03/OIG-19-28-Mar19.pdf">annually</a>.</p><p>Recent video from King County&rsquo;s cameras at Boeing Field-King County International Airport in Seattle shows a grim parade of detainees. One climbs a set of boarding stairs while <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DKc3-uPhNVD/">shackled and holding a cane</a>. Another, also shackled &mdash; detainees generally are, including during flights &mdash; is <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/lalabote.bsky.social/post/3ltun6dwqos2e">manhandled by several guards</a> who run him onto the plane; a few feet before Signature&rsquo;s staircase, the group stumbles and the man falls onto the tarmac.</p><p>&ldquo;The use of restraints on detainees during deportation flights is a standard ICE protocol and an essential measure to ensure the safety and well-being of both detainees and the officers/agents accompanying them,&rdquo; an unidentified DHS spokesperson told HuffPost in a statement. &ldquo;Our practices align with those followed by other relevant authorities and is fully in line with established legal standards.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;ICE takes its commitment to promoting safe, secure, humane environments for those in our custody very seriously,&rdquo; the statement added. &ldquo;ICE Air Operations flights are law enforcement sensitive. ICE conducts flights throughout the U.S. on a daily basis. For operational security purposes, ICE does not discuss ongoing or future operations.&rdquo; </p><figure><picture><source srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale&amp;format=webp 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560&amp;format=webp 2x"><img alt="U.S. and Signature Aviation flags fly outside Signature Aviation's Newark Liberty International Airport terminal." src="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale" srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560 2x"></source></picture><div><figcaption>U.S. and Signature Aviation flags fly outside Signature Aviation's Newark Liberty International Airport terminal.</figcaption><div><p><span>Illustration: HuffPost; Photo: Will Tooke/HuffPost</span></p></div></div></figure><p>Activists working to end ICE Air&rsquo;s presence in Seattle have zeroed in on Signature&rsquo;s work as a service provider for charter flights. </p><p>&ldquo;The presence of Signature is essential for ICE to be within the airport, because without having a fixed-base operator to service the planes, they can&rsquo;t land there, and no one else is doing this type of work,&rdquo; said Guadalupe Gonzalez, flight monitoring coordinator for La Resistencia, an immigrant-led activist group in Washington state that seeks to end immigrant detention and deportation. &ldquo;Signature Aviation specifically are the ones responsible for servicing ICE at Boeing Field.&rdquo; </p><p>Gonzalez said La Resistencia volunteers, who observe ICE Air transfers in person at Boeing Field, have in recent years reported seeing detainees bound in the &ldquo;WRAP&rdquo; restraint system, a type of full-body restraint device that has come <a href="https://capitalandmain.com/police-restraint-system-adopted-nationwide-despite-lawsuits-allegations">under</a> scrutiny in the past. More commonly, Gonzalez said, people with mobility issues were made to walk up Signature&rsquo;s stairs to a waiting ICE Air flight. </p><p>Not having a presence at Boeing Field, Gonzalez said, &ldquo;would impair [ICE&rsquo;s] efforts to deport as many people as possible &mdash; or, at the very minimum, make it more costly.&rdquo; </p><p>Signature Aviation did not answer a lengthy list of questions about its practices, including its involvement with ICE Air. Instead, the company sent a one-sentence statement.</p><p>&ldquo;Our FBOs must accept flight operations that comply with the law, FAA regulations and contract requirements at federally funded airports,&rdquo; said Rosanna Fiske, the company&rsquo;s global head of corporate affairs.</p><p>Fiske did not respond to follow-up questions about the nature of Signature&rsquo;s obligations, including the terms of contracts it may have signed with ICE Air charter operators.</p><h2><strong>&lsquo;Don&rsquo;t Want Bill&rsquo;s Name In The Headlines&rsquo;</strong></h2><p>Gates is a significant shareholder in Signature Aviation. Cascade Investment LLC, the holding company for Gates&rsquo; and the Gates Foundation&rsquo;s assets, first bought a piece of the company&rsquo;s predecessor, <a href="https://www.ainonline.com/aviation-news/business-aviation/2020-02-07/bba-aviation-rebrands-signature-aviation">BBA Aviation</a>, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/airlines/bill-gates-joins-private-equity-firms-in-4-7-billion-deal-for-private-jet-company-11612534767">in 2009</a>. In 2021, a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jan/09/bill-gates-joins-blackstone-in-bid-to-buy-british-private-jet-firm">bidding war</a> broke out over the company, and Gates&rsquo; Cascade &mdash; then Signature&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/blackstone-gates-team-up-signature-aviation-bid-carlyle-circles-2021-01-08/">largest</a> individual shareholder, with a 19% stake &mdash; joined forces with Blackstone Group and Global Infrastructure Partners to <a href="https://www.ainonline.com/aviation-news/business-aviation/2021-06-08/signature-aviation-now-under-new-ownership">buy it outright</a>. (Global Infrastructure Partners was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/blackrock-quarterly-profit-rises-strong-assets-under-management-2024-01-12/">acquired</a> by BlackRock in 2024.)</p><p>Working together, the three firms bought Signature for $4.7 billion, with Cascade winding up with 30% of the company. </p><p>Cascade Investment LLC is <a href="https://cascadeassetmanagement.com/faqs/">overseen</a> by Cascade Asset Management Company. That firm&rsquo;s chief investment officer is Michael Larson, who has Gates&rsquo; &ldquo;complete trust and faith,&rdquo; Gates said in 2014, at a party he threw celebrating the 20th anniversary of Larson managing his assets. <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/this-mans-job-make-bill-gates-richer-1411093811">The Wall Street Journal reported</a> at the time that their arrangement was &ldquo;simple: Mr. Larson makes money, and Mr. Gates gives it away.&rdquo; Cascade Investment is located in the same Kirkland, Washington, office park as Gates&rsquo; personal office, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/26/business/bill-gates-cascade-michael-larson.html">The New York Times noted</a> in a 2021 story. Cascade&rsquo;s mandate, one unnamed former employee told the Times for the same story, was: &ldquo;We don&rsquo;t want Bill&rsquo;s name in the headlines.&rdquo; </p><p>Cascade&rsquo;s work on Gates&rsquo; behalf has come up in the news before. </p><p>For example, when <a href="https://landreport.com/farmer-bill-gates">The Land Report revealed</a> in 2021 that Gates was &ldquo;America&rsquo;s largest private farmland owner,&rdquo; what they were really talking about, as <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/mcdonald-s-french-fries-carrots-onions-all-foods-come-bill-n1270033">NBC News later described it</a>, was farmland &ldquo;purchased through a constellation of companies that all link back to [Bill and Melinda Gates&rsquo;] investment group, Cascade Investments, based in Kirkland, Washington.&rdquo; When Gates was asked about his farmland purchases, which made national news, he <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/m8n4vt/comment/grid8pt/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">said</a>, &ldquo;My investment group chose to do this&rdquo; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/109eze3/comment/j3xyx6r/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">and</a> &ldquo;all these decisions are made by a professional investment team.&rdquo; </p><p>The same might apply to Signature Aviation. It&rsquo;s unclear how much Gates knows about his stake in the company, or whether he knows that Signature plays such a crucial role in Trump&rsquo;s mass deportation operation. </p><p>Still, &ldquo;it would be surprising if Gates couldn&rsquo;t influence a decision to disinvest of this particular investment,&rdquo; said Cartwright, who before his retirement <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/ice-flight-tracker-deportations/682226/">spent decades at J.P. Morgan</a>, including as chief financial officer of one division that covered 5,000 bank branches. </p><p>The foundation has previously addressed concerns about its money being invested in Signature Aviation. One complaint recently filed through EthicsPoint, a public-facing portal to submit ethical concerns to the foundation, and later shared with HuffPost, accused the foundation of &ldquo;providing material support for U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement&rdquo; through its investment in Signature.</p><p>In response, the foundation said it did not &ldquo;control or participate in the activities of the Gates Foundation Trust.&rdquo; Instead, the foundation said, the trust&rsquo;s assets were &ldquo;independently managed by Cascade Asset Management Company.&rdquo; </p><h2><strong>Signature&rsquo;s Footprint</strong></h2><p>Look closely and you&rsquo;ll see Signature Aviation popping up across Trump&rsquo;s mass deportation pipeline. </p><p>In fact, the company is part of perhaps the most infamous footage of Trump&rsquo;s second term so far: an <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/white-house-deportation-asmr_n_67b59e2ce4b04083cc996831">&ldquo;ASMR&rdquo;</a> <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/white-house-asmr-deportation-video_l_67b7a45ce4b05145b9c4f94f">video</a> that glorifies shackling and transporting immigration detainees. The video was <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/white-houses-gleeful-video-shows-chained-deportees-at-boeing-field/">filmed at Boeing Field</a>, where the number of contracted ICE flights, all serviced by Signature Aviation, has <a href="https://washingtonstatestandard.com/2025/07/15/deportation-flights-at-wa-airport-up-dramatically-this-year-advocates-say/">shot up</a> this year. It also happens to be a 20-minute drive from the Gates Foundation&rsquo;s offices. </p><p>Signature&rsquo;s <a href="https://brandfetch.com/signatureaviation.com">distinct logo</a> is visible at the top of a set of boarding stairs about five seconds into the clip: </p><p>Signature did not answer HuffPost&rsquo;s inquiry about where it serviced ICE Air flights, but the company has had a significant footprint in servicing aviation contractors hired by ICE. In 2019, one <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/wp-content/uploads/sites/22/2025/08/IAO-AEX2-Schedule-20190711.pdf">internal ICE document</a> listed Signature as the designated FBO for contracted ICE flights at 12 major domestic airports: Atlanta, Dallas, Newark, Houston, Laredo, Kansas City, Memphis, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/minnesota/comments/1k69i6t/weekly_ice_flight_at_msp_this_morning/">Minneapolis-Saint Paul</a>, Chicago, San Diego, San Antonio, and Denver, where HuffPost recently spotted a set of Signature boarding stairs pulled up to another <a href="https://www.planespotters.net/airframe/boeing-737-800-n804vl-avelo-air/eg9gq1">all-white Avelo Air plane</a>.</p><p>And while it&rsquo;s not clear whether ICE Air still uses every airport on the 2019 list, the list also doesn&rsquo;t include airports where Signature has recently been spotted servicing ICE Air flights. For example, the 2019 document doesn&rsquo;t include Seattle&rsquo;s Boeing Field. Signature now <a href="https://kingcounty.gov/en/dept/executive-services/transit-transportation-roads/airport/about/ice-flights">frequently</a> services ICE flights there, and detainees picked up at the airport have ended up in El Salvador&rsquo;s CECOT prison, Guant&aacute;namo Bay, and South Sudan, according to the <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2025/08/21/gross-human-rights-violations-in-washington-state-enforced-disappearance-and-refoulement/">recent report</a> from UWCHR. The human rights center previously obtained the 2019 list of airports that listed FBOs servicing the ICE flights pursuant to a public records request to ICE. </p><p>Signature also appears to be servicing immigration flights out of Jacksonville, Florida. One March email with the subject line &ldquo;ICE Schedule This Week&rdquo; notes several charter flights landing at Jacksonville International Airport. The activist group Ground ICE &mdash; which <a href="https://groundice.org/our-mission">aims</a> to &ldquo;limit the rate at which I.C.E. can transport and remove its detainees&rdquo; &mdash; obtained the document through a public records request and shared it with HuffPost. Recipients of the email included Signature Aviation&rsquo;s Jacksonville manager as well as several email accounts associated with GEO Group, a private prison contractor.</p><p>In July, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kPg8Z8hx2OQ">Fox 13 News Utah captured video</a> of apparent immigration detainees climbing a set of Signature boarding stairs at Salt Lake City International Airport. </p><p>And <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/trump-ice-coast-guard-planes-immigrants-detention-1235414267/">Rolling Stone recently spotted</a> a Coast Guard plane refueling and boarding ICE detainees at Baltimore/Washington International Airport. Independent journalist Gillian Brockell, who wrote the Rolling Stone story, told HuffPost that Signature Aviation refueled the plane.</p><p>Signature is also the <a href="https://www.buffaloairport.com/flight-info/air-carriers/fixed-base-operator">only FBO</a> at Buffalo Niagara International Airport, Ground ICE has noted. Planes carrying immigration detainees pass through that airport once or twice a week, according to Cartwright, who is currently transitioning <a href="https://humanrightsfirst.org/ice-flight-monitor/">his work</a> over to the group <a href="https://humanrightsfirst.org/library/ice-flight-tracking-project-now-officially-housed-at-human-rights-first/">Human Rights First</a>.</p><h2><strong>&lsquo;Dehumanizing To A Lot Of Degrees&rsquo;</strong></h2><p>Various entities involved with Gates&rsquo; ICE Air investment proclaim their commitment to human rights. </p><p>Signature Aviation itself <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/about/policies-terms-and-conditions/signature-aviation-bba-aviation-disclosures/signature-aviation-ethics/">says</a> it is committed to &ldquo;refraining from coercion and never deliberately causing harm to anyone&rdquo; and that it takes steps &ldquo;to confirm that our businesses and supply chains are free from modern slavery and human trafficking.&rdquo; Another company policy requires that suppliers &ldquo;never use, support, or engage in forced or indentured labor, or practices involving coercion, deception, or abuse of power &mdash; including human trafficking, slavery and child labor.&rdquo; As part of its efforts to combat human trafficking, it says it <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/news/signature-aviation-taking-steps-to-end-human-trafficking/">works with</a> the Department of Homeland Security. (ICE falls under the purview of DHS.) </p><p>Cascade <a href="https://cascadeassetmanagement.com/investment-approaches/">says</a> it takes &ldquo;a value-oriented approach&rdquo; to investing money for Gates and the Gates Foundation Trust, and that one of its objectives is to &ldquo;protect Bill and the Trust by acting lawfully, honestly, ethically, and with integrity, safeguarding their assets and information.&rdquo; It <a href="https://cascadeassetmanagement.com/">notes</a> that &ldquo;neither Cascade nor the Trust play a role in the grantmaking or operations of the foundation&rdquo; and that the foundation &ldquo;does not control or participate in the Trust&rsquo;s investment activities.&rdquo;</p><p>The Gates Foundation <a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/about">says</a> its mission is to &ldquo;create a world where every person has the opportunity to live a healthy, productive life,&rdquo; and the foundation has <a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/about/committed-grants?q=immigration">awarded grants</a> to multiple prominent immigration-focused nonprofits. </p><figure><picture><source srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale&amp;format=webp 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560&amp;format=webp 2x"><img alt="Immigration and Customs Enforcement detainees disembark from an " src="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale" srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560 2x"></source></picture><div><figcaption>Immigration and Customs Enforcement detainees disembark from an "ICE Air" flight at Newark Liberty International Airport using a set of Signature Aviation boarding stairs.</figcaption><div><p><span>Photo: Matt Shuham/HuffPost</span></p></div></div></figure><p>The experiences of immigration detainees traveling on ICE Air &mdash; particularly ICE&rsquo;s use of shackles, which bind their wrists and ankles &mdash; seemingly stand in contrast to those commitments. </p><p>The shackles &ldquo;felt very disrespectful, dehumanizing to a lot of degrees,&rdquo; Mahmoud Khalil, the Palestinian activist jailed and threatened with deportation for his beliefs, <a href="https://zeteo.com/p/exclusive-mahmoud-khalil-talks-to">recalled to Zeteo</a> after his release from ICE custody in June. </p><p>After more than a day of travel, &ldquo;by the time I arrived in Jena, [Louisiana, home to an infamous ICE jail,] I couldn&rsquo;t walk because my leg was swollen from the shackles,&rdquo; Khalil added.</p><p>Deportation flight passengers have alleged &ldquo;the use of racist epithets and insults, and rough physical treatment upon boarding,&rdquo; as well as, in more isolated cases, &ldquo;beatings, the use of straitjackets, verbal abuse and threats, and the denial of access to restrooms,&rdquo; according to a UWCHR <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air/">summary</a> of <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/08/16/ice-air-deportation-flight-complaints/">public records</a> it received detailing the complaints. </p><p>In one case, a Somalia-bound deportation flight sat on a tarmac in Senegal for a full day due to technical issues, while detainees remained shackled inside and the plane&rsquo;s toilets &ldquo;overfilled with human waste,&rdquo; according to a <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/meet-the-ice-contractor-running-deportation-flights">subsequent lawsuit</a>. The plane eventually returned all of the detainees to the United States. (The suit was ultimately <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.518509/gov.uscourts.flsd.518509.215.0.pdf">dismissed</a> for jurisdictional reasons, and many of the people on the ill-fated flight <a href="https://theintercept.com/2019/04/09/somalis-ice-deportation-flights/">continued to face deportation proceedings</a>.)</p><h2><strong>Seattle Shows Vulnerabilities Of Private System</strong></h2><p>Relying on private contractors at every stage of the deportation process creates major vulnerabilities for ICE &mdash; which may be why the Trump administration is <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/immigration/kristi-noem-pushing-ice-buy-operate-fleet-deportation-planes-sources-s-rcna217149?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;taid=68a633abd3e93400010d65da&amp;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=bluesky">reportedly</a> considering purchasing its own fleet of deportation planes. </p><p>While giant private prison companies like CoreCivic and GEO Group are dependent on federal contracts to survive, FBOs work in different economic conditions. Most rely on business from corporate and private jet travel, and they&rsquo;re often subject to local political pressure. For example, Ground ICE has <a href="https://groundice.org/the-pilots-boycott">encouraged pilots</a> to write to Signature Aviation and &ldquo;let them know you will not be buying fuel from them&rdquo; due to their work for ICE. </p><p>More than anywhere else, Seattle&rsquo;s Boeing Field represents how local anti-deportation sentiment can affect FBOs and seriously slow down ICE&rsquo;s work. </p><p>In 2019, amid <a href="https://inthesetimes.com/article/ice-deportation-boeing-field-airport-washington-immigrant-rights">pressure</a> from local activist groups and an <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air-king-county/">impactful</a> report from UWCHR concerning &ldquo;King County Collaboration with ICE Air Deportation Flights at Boeing Field,&rdquo; then-King County executive Dow Constantine <a href="https://kingcounty.gov/about/policies/executive/PFCeo/~/media/0B00DFDD9114472BB8C596234A2C631D.ashx?la=en#:~:text=King%20County%20International%20Airport%20shall,United%20States%20or%20its%20territories.">ordered</a>, among other things, that future leases at Boeing Field contain a prohibition against the private transport of immigration detainees. The FBO for those flights at the time, Modern Aviation, stopped servicing them soon after that executive order, even though the order was ultimately blocked in court. Two other FBOs at the airport, including Signature, also said they &ldquo;will not take over from Modern in servicing ICE flights,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/ice-flights-will-no-longer-use-boeing-field/">The Seattle Times reported at the time</a>, citing the airport&rsquo;s director. (Matt Dill, general manager at Modern Aviation&rsquo;s location at Boeing Field, declined to comment.)</p><p>&ldquo;Without the help of such companies,&rdquo; the paper reported, &ldquo;flights cannot operate at the airport. Though they can technically take off and land, [airport director John] Parrott said, flights need a company to open gates, to provide stairs to get passengers on and off planes, and to offer fuel.&rdquo; </p><p>Without an FBO in Seattle, ICE was forced to <a href="https://www.nwpb.org/2019/05/20/yakima-and-king-county-airports-risk-funding-loss-if-they-dont-cooperate-with-ice/">route planes through Yakima</a> &mdash; where the airport was smaller, more remote, and hours inland. <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.283169/gov.uscourts.wawd.283169.62.1_2.pdf">In a court filing</a>, the Trump administration said it only landed on the remote airport after approaching three others &ldquo;without success.&rdquo; </p><p>The Trump administration also acknowledged at the time that this shift jammed the gears of its deportation machinery, particularly when it came to people detained at the Northwest Detention Center in Tacoma. </p><p>&ldquo;Transporting detainees from Tacoma to Yakima, as compared to Tacoma to Boeing Field, adds, at a minimum, six hours of travel time to the process of executing an ICE Air flight,&rdquo; the filing read.</p><p>&ldquo;Additionally,&rdquo; it continued, &ldquo;the transport to Yakima and back frequently requires the use of an additional bus and two additional officers, as well as additional meal and fuel costs. This takes resources away from federal law enforcement tasks that would otherwise be performed if the ICE Air flights were flying out of Boeing Field. Relocation of the ICE Air flights to Yakima also impacts ICE operations in Yakima, requiring ICE to utilize staffing of at least two officers from its Yakima sub-office to facilitate the flight processing in Yakima. Additionally, travel over the mountain passes in winter is hazardous, and frequently either slowed significantly by road conditions or suspended altogether, as was the case on January 14, 2020, when an ICE Air flight had to be cancelled due to road conditions prohibiting transport.&rdquo; </p><p>On March 30, 2023, a federal judge <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/politics/federal-judge-allows-deportation-flights-to-resume-at-boeing-field/">ruled against</a> the county&rsquo;s executive order requiring future FBO leases to prohibit work on deportation flights. </p><p>&ldquo;At that time, Signature Aviation said, &lsquo;OK, we&rsquo;ll do that business,&rsquo;&rdquo; recalled Angelina Snodgrass Godoy, the director of UWCHR. &ldquo;Ever since then, the ICE flights have resumed at Boeing Field, and they&rsquo;re being served by Signature Aviation.&rdquo; </p><p>Local public radio station KNKX <a href="https://www.knkx.org/social-justice/2023-05-10/ice-deportation-flights-resume-at-king-countys-boeing-field">described Signature</a> at the time as &ldquo;the fixed-base operator that agreed to service ICE flights at Boeing Field.&rdquo; </p><p>By May 2, four years after ICE Air flights stopped at Boeing Field, they resumed again, according to <a href="https://kingcounty.gov/en/dept/executive-services/transit-transportation-roads/airport/about/ice-flights">records of the flights</a> kept by the county. Signature has been their sole service provider ever since, according to the same records. </p><blockquote><div><p>&ldquo;Without a fixed-base operator, I&rsquo;m not sure this system really operates.&rdquo;</p><p>- Tom Cartwright, a retired financial executive who has tracked ICE flights for nearly six years</p></div></blockquote><p>For Godoy, the years-long absence of deportation flights running through Seattle shows just how important FBOs like Signature Aviation are.</p><p>&ldquo;Here in Seattle, what we saw in 2019 and to this date, was that when there was enough local concern, and people expressing local outrage about it, that the other FBOs also didn&rsquo;t want to do it,&rdquo; she said. </p><p>&ldquo;There are businesses who will say, &lsquo;No, we don&rsquo;t want this, we don&rsquo;t want to be associated with this.&rsquo;&rdquo; </p><p>Local pressure also may have recently disrupted ICE Air operations on the other side of the country. Last month, after <a href="https://www.wbur.org/news/2025/06/17/plymouth-county-sheriff-ice-immigration-detentions-flights">media attention</a> and local protest over the spike in immigration flights from Hanscom Field in Bedford, Massachusetts &mdash; including specific attention <a href="https://lexobserver.org/2025/07/22/ice-flights-move-from-hanscom-to-portsmouth/">on Signature Aviation</a> for servicing the flights &mdash; the ICE Air flights to that airport <a href="https://concordbridge.org/index.php/2025/07/18/breaking-ice-no-longer-using-hanscom-field-spokesperson/">stopped</a>, <a href="https://www.wbur.org/news/2025/07/31/immigration-hanscom-portsmouth-flights-airport">instead going through</a> Portsmouth International Airport at Pease in Portsmouth, New Hampshire, where Signature does not have a presence.</p><p>&ldquo;It was because the activists were so annoying, basically, to that airfield, and they were so focused on Signature, that they decided to shift to [Portsmouth International Airport] as the hub for New England,&rdquo; JJ in DC posited to HuffPost, referring to the shift from Massachusetts to New Hampshire.</p><p>Godoy also speculated that the shift came in response to protest. </p><p>&ldquo;My impression is that, for Signature, the ICE flights are only a portion of their business, and not the majority of their business &mdash; and when the ICE flights become sufficiently notorious, that threatens Signature&rsquo;s overall business, and then they say &lsquo;no thanks,&rsquo;&rdquo; she said.</p><p>&ldquo;And it looks to me &mdash; this is speculation, because I&rsquo;m not privy to the discussions between ICE and Signature &mdash; like that&rsquo;s what happened at Hanscom Field,&rdquo; Godoy added. &ldquo;So now, ICE is going to be using a more far-away airport, which is more inconvenient for them. And they haven&rsquo;t said why.&rdquo; </p><p>Still, even apparent route changes may not last: Two flights from Avelo Airlines planes landed at Hanscom Field on Friday and Saturday, flight records show. The airline, ICE, and Signature Aviation did not respond to questions about the purpose of the flights.</p><h2><strong>It&rsquo;s Not Just Bill</strong></h2><p>The financial backing behind Signature Aviation doesn&rsquo;t stop with Bill Gates and the Gates Foundation. </p><p>Annual financial reports reviewed by HuffPost show several large public pension funds are also stakeholders in Signature.</p><p>Institutional investors Blackstone and BlackRock (via Global Infrastructure Partners) own the remainder of the company that Gates does not. And those massive asset management firms often invest money in various funds on behalf of public pensions, nonprofits and university endowments.</p><p>One such fund, a BlackRock product called Global Infrastructure Partners Fund IV, has 68 such limited partners, according to data from PitchBook, a private-equity market database.</p><p>That includes the California Public Employees&rsquo; Retirement System, a public pension that in 2023 held more than $350 million of the fund; the New York State Common Retirement Fund; the Utah State University endowment; the Oregon Public Employees Retirement System; the Washington State Investment Board; <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1HfRYzWYIZ7kBAnyRsDMT5ixTNpDWqaAefiF4LeM-OdE/edit?usp=sharing">and more than 60 others</a>.</p><p>BlackRock and the California Public Employees&rsquo; Retirement System declined to comment. The New York State Common Retirement Fund, Oregon Investment Council (which manages OPERS&rsquo; investments) and the Utah State University endowment didn&rsquo;t respond. A spokesperson for WSIB told HuffPost that, as a policy, it does not comment on individual holdings.</p><p>Washington&rsquo;s stake was flagged by UWCHR, which <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2025/08/21/gross-human-rights-violations-in-washington-state-enforced-disappearance-and-refoulement/#_ftn155">warned in its recent report</a> that &ldquo;public workers&rsquo; retirements are being financed in part through investments in organizations that profit from the detention and deportation of our neighbors.&rdquo;</p><p>A handful of public pension funds are also invested in a similar offering from Blackstone, called Blackstone Infrastructure Partners. They include the New Mexico State Investment Council, the Orange County Employees&rsquo; Retirement System, Pennsylvania Public School Employees&rsquo; Retirement System, and the Teacher Retirement System of Texas, according to the PitchBook data.</p><p>Blackstone didn&rsquo;t respond to a request for comment, nor did the New Mexico State Investment Council. A spokesperson for the Teacher Retirement System of Texas declined to comment, citing a Texas law that prohibits discussing specific investments. The Orange County Employees&rsquo; Retirement System and Pennsylvania Public School Employees Retirement System similarly declined to comment.</p><p>Azani Creeks, a senior campaign and research coordinator at PESP, a nonprofit watchdog organization focused on the private equity industry, told HuffPost that people whose pensions rely on these investments are entitled to have a say in their composition.</p><p>&ldquo;You can contact pension fund staff and trustees by email to schedule a meeting, and often, pension funds have regular meetings with public comment periods in which you can communicate your concerns,&rdquo; Creeks said. </p><p>&ldquo;A handful of private equity firms, drawing on capital from pension funds, foundations, endowments, insurance companies, and other institutional investors, exert major influence through investments in companies providing services to immigrant detention facilities and migrant shelters around the United States.&rdquo;</p><p>JJ in DC noted that in his work tracking immigration flights, he&rsquo;s been struck by just how opaque the process is. The Department of Homeland Security <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/meet-the-ice-contractor-running-deportation-flights">contracts with its main broker</a>, CSI Aviation, which works with a network of subcontractors including GlobalX, Avelo and Eastern Air Express. Those firms in turn work with FBOs like Signature Aviation. Along the way, airplanes have been made harder to spot &mdash; with some losing all of their external branding or being <a href="https://www.levernews.com/ice-is-using-taylor-swifts-loophole-to-hide-deportation-flights/">taken off public flight trackers</a>, though their information is still available on crowdsourced networks like <a href="https://www.adsbexchange.com/">ADS-B Exchange</a>. (Anyone with <a href="https://www.adsbexchange.com/ways-to-join-the-exchange/">the correct receiver</a> can contribute to the site, which presents location information <a href="https://www.adsbexchange.com/how-it-works/">broadcast by individual aircraft over radio waves</a> as an interactive and real-time, though not always complete, <a href="https://globe.adsbexchange.com/">map</a> of global aviation traffic.) </p><p>The result, in the end, are taxpayer dollars quietly contributing to the portfolios of people like Gates and the Gates Foundation Trust. </p><p>&ldquo;This is a big pressure point,&rdquo; JJ in DC told HuffPost. &ldquo;And if more people apply pressure, it&rsquo;s going to hurt their operations, and they&rsquo;re going to have to adjust.&rdquo; </p><p><em>Matt Shuham reported from New York. Ryan Grenoble reported from Denver. </em></p></section></section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:55:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/job-market-hell/684133/?gift=Vowm9zXD_VpjYJtYApIfy6iqYdFY6568omVJ07mz1tc</link><title>The Job Market Is Hell: Young people are using ChatGPT to write their applications; HR is using AI to read them; no one is getting hired. (theatlantic.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/J-0rMrIxnE3yFSvDEPugUb2U1Zk=/0x43:2000x1085/1200x625/media/img/mt/2025/09/2025_6_7_Impossible_To_Get_A_Job/original.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Listen to more stories on the <a href="https://newsoveraudio.com/?offerId=atl_reader_exclusive_jks1kjl"> Noa</a> app.</p></div><section><p>Harris started looking for his first real job months before his graduation from UC Davis this spring. He had a solid r&eacute;sum&eacute;, he thought: a paid internship at a civic-consulting firm, years of volunteering at environmental-defense organizations, experience working on farms and in parks as well as in offices, a close-to-perfect GPA, strong letters of recommendation. He would move anywhere on the West Coast, living out of his car if he had to. He would accept a temporary, part-time, or seasonal gig, not just a full-time position. He would do anything&mdash;filing paperwork, digging trenches&mdash;to build his dream career protecting California&rsquo;s wildlife and public lands.</p><p>He applied to 200 jobs. He got rejected 200 times. Actually, he clarified, he &ldquo;didn&rsquo;t get <em>rejected</em> 200 times.&rdquo; A lot of businesses never responded.</p><p>Right now, millions of would-be workers find themselves in a similar position. Corporate profits <a href="https://www.bea.gov/data/income-saving/corporate-profits">are strong</a>, the jobless rate is 4.3 percent, and wages are <a href="https://www.atlantafed.org/chcs/wage-growth-tracker">climbing in turn</a>. But payrolls have been essentially frozen for the past four months. The hiring rate has declined to <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/JTSHIR">its lowest point</a> since the jobless recovery following the Great Recession. Four years ago, employers were adding four or five workers for every 100 they had on the books, month in and month out. Now they are adding three.</p><p>At the same time, the process of getting a job has become a late-capitalist nightmare. Online hiring platforms have made it easier to find an opening but harder to secure one: Applicants send out thousands of AI-crafted r&eacute;sum&eacute;s, and businesses use AI to sift through them. What Bumble and Hinge did to the dating market, contemporary human-resources practices have done to the job market. People are swiping like crazy and getting nothing back.</p><p>Every time Harris logged in to LinkedIn or Indeed, he would see scores of gigs that seemed like they might be a good fit. He would read a posting carefully, scrub his r&eacute;sum&eacute;, tailor an introductory note, answer the company&rsquo;s screening questions, hit &ldquo;Send,&rdquo; hope for the best, and hear nothing in response&mdash;again and again and again.</p><p>Other job seekers described similar experiences. In suburban Virginia, a paralegal named Martine got laid off by a government contractor in April. (Like Harris, she did not want to dim her employment prospects by providing her full name.) She saw plenty of jobs being advertised at nonprofits, law firms, consultancies, and universities. She sent out dozens of applications. She even got to the second round a few times. But she never came close to being hired. &ldquo;I have 10 years of experience,&rdquo; she told me. &ldquo;I would be happy if a person told me no at this point.&rdquo;</p><p>For employers, the job market is working differently too. Businesses receive countless ill-fitting applications, along with a few good ones, for each open position. Rather than poring over the submissions by hand, they use machines. In a recent survey, chief HR officers told the Boston Consulting Group that they are <a href="https://www.bcg.com/publications/2025/ai-changing-recruitment">using AI</a> to write job descriptions, assess candidates, schedule introductory meetings, and evaluate applications. In some cases, firms are using chatbots to interview candidates, too. Prospective hires log in to a Zoom-like system and field questions from an avatar. Their performance is taped, and an algorithm searches for keywords and evaluates their tone.</p><p>Priya Rathod, a career-trends expert at Indeed, told me she understands why job seekers feel as if their r&eacute;sum&eacute;s are &ldquo;going into a void.&rdquo; But she argued that the online platforms make it easier for people to find open positions and that AI can &ldquo;get them to the next stage of the interview quicker,&rdquo; if their applications fit an employer&rsquo;s needs.</p><p>Still, a lot of job applicants never end up in a human-to-human process. The impossibility of getting to the interview stage spurs jobless workers to submit more applications, which pushes them to rely on ChatGPT to build their r&eacute;sum&eacute;s and respond to screening prompts. (Harris told me he does this; he used ChatGPT pretty much every day in college, and finds its writing to be more &ldquo;professional&rdquo; than his own.) And so the cycle continues: The surge in same-same AI-authored applications prompts employers to use robot filters to manage the flow. Everyone ends up in Tinderized job-search hell.</p><p>For months, the economy has been in a low-hire, low-fire equilibrium; virtually every sector of the labor market except for health care has been frozen. The amount of time a worker has spent looking for a job has climbed to an average of <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNU03008276">10 weeks</a>, meaning that Americans are spending two weeks longer on the job market than they were a few years ago. The share of American workers quitting a job has fallen to its lowest <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/JTSQUR">level in a decade</a>, because of concerns about rising prices and jitters about slowing growth.</p><p>The equilibrium now seems to be falling apart, and a full-on recession looks likely. Black workers have experienced a dramatic <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNS14000006">surge in joblessness</a>, in part because of the Trump administration&rsquo;s mass layoffs of federal employees. (The 154,000 civil servants who took the White House&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">&ldquo;</a><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">Fork in the Road</a><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">&rdquo;</a> deferred-resignation offer will receive their last <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/07/31/federal-workers-doge-buyout-paid/">paycheck this month</a>.) More than 10 percent of workers under the age of 24 are searching for <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNS14024887">a job</a>. &ldquo;Performance-based and strategic layoffs are increasing,&rdquo; Lydia Boussour of the consultancy EY-Parthenon wrote in a note to clients last week. &ldquo;Cracks are increasingly showing.&rdquo;</p><p>What is a worker supposed to do? Martine and Harris and millions like them are still trying to figure that out; she keeps on applying, whereas he is doing landscaping and volunteering. Rathod said that she recommends old-fashioned networking: asking recruiters out for coffee, going to in-person job events, and surveying friends and former employers for leads.</p><p>Such strategies might work if employers begin hiring again. But if not, millions more people might be left pitching their CVs into the void.</p></section><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/G3J3fAQrlILC_OcsAGs76IWlZmo=/438x0:1563x1125/80x80/media/img/mt/2025/09/2025_6_7_Impossible_To_Get_A_Job/original.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:25:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ft.com/content/97e42e98-46ee-4752-b80e-ea0ca947c813</link><title>Donald Trump warns multinationals to respect immigration laws after Hyundai raid -- We encourage you to LEGALLY bring your very smart people, with great technical talent, to build World Class products, stated the president (ft.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbnnbj/donald_trump_warns_multinationals_to_respect/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbnnbj/donald_trump_warns_multinationals_to_respect/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbnnbj/donald_trump_warns_multinationals_to_respect/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><div><p><span></span><span>Subscribe to unlock this article</span></p></div><div><h2><span><span>Try unlimited access</span></span></h2><h2><span><span>Only </span><span>Rs100</span><span> for 4 weeks</span></span></h2><p><span><span>Then </span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month. Complete digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Cancel anytime during your trial.</span></span></p></div></div><div><h2>Explore more offers.</h2><div><div><div><p><img src="https://images.ft.com/v3/image/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fbarrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fassets%2Ficons%2Fprimary_product_icon_ftedit.svg?format=svg&amp;source=next-barrier-page" alt></p><h3>FT Edit</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4490</span><span> per year</span></span></p><p><span><span>Access to eight surprising articles a day, hand-picked by FT editors. For seamless reading, access content via the FT Edit page on FT.com and receive the FT Edit newsletter.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Standard Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs2850</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Essential digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Premium Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Complete digital access to quality FT journalism with expert analysis from industry leaders. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div></div></div><div><h2>Explore our full range of subscriptions.</h2><div><div><div><h3>For individuals</h3></div><p>Discover all the plans currently available in your country</p></div><div><div><h3> For multiple readers</h3></div><p>Digital access for organisations. Includes exclusive features and content.</p></div></div></div><div><div><h2>Why the FT?</h2><p>See why over a million readers pay to read the Financial Times.</p></div><p><a href="https://subs.ft.com/whytheft?ft-content-uuid=97e42e98-46ee-4752-b80e-ea0ca947c813">Find out why</a></p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://images.ft.com/v3/image/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fbarrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fassets%2Ficons%2Fprimary_product_icon_standard.svg?format=svg&amp;source=next-barrier-page"></p><p><img src="https://images.ft.com/v3/image/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fbarrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fassets%2Ficons%2Fprimary_product_icon_premium.svg?format=svg&amp;source=next-barrier-page"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:53:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.techspot.com/news/109365-biden-era-noncompete-ban-collapses-ftc-withdraws-appeal.html</link><title>Biden-era noncompete ban collapses as FTC withdraws appeal | The FTC reversal leaves millions of workers still bound by noncompetes (techspot.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbmkqp/bidenera_noncompete_ban_collapses_as_ftc/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbmkqp/bidenera_noncompete_ban_collapses_as_ftc/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbmkqp/bidenera_noncompete_ban_collapses_as_ftc/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:07:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3324637/top-harvard-mathematician-liu-jun-leaves-us-china</link><title>Top Harvard mathematician Liu Jun leaves US for China (scmp.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb87bl/top_harvard_mathematician_liu_jun_leaves_us_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb87bl/top_harvard_mathematician_liu_jun_leaves_us_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb87bl/top_harvard_mathematician_liu_jun_leaves_us_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/09/07/45fcea36-18e9-4c9b-84ca-2f6143efce05_5ad33423.jpg?itok=9gU6RQL7&v=1757218100' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><p>Liu Jun, one of the world&rsquo;s leading statisticians and a long-time professor at Harvard, has returned to China full-time, accepting a prestigious chair at Tsinghua University last month.</p><p>The move marks the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3309548/wanted-china-born-researchers-leave-us-work-china-attractive-pay?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>homecoming of an academic</span></a> whose career has spanned research in data science, biostatistics and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>artificial intelligence</span></a> &ndash; and whose early life reflected the complex interplay between intellectual pursuit and political engagement.</p><p>In 1988, Liu Jun transferred from Rutgers University in New Jersey to the University of Chicago, studying under statistician Wing Hung Wong.</p><p>While there, he became deeply interested in human rights issues and spent a considerable amount of time <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3201760/inspired-rare-protests-mainland-chinese-students-north-america-organise-and-speak-out?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>taking part in student protests</span></a>.</p><p>The student movement he supported did not occur in Chicago, but in Beijing.</p><p>In 1989, students held a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiananmen-square-crackdown?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>massive demonstration in Tiananmen Square</span></a> and overseas student groups have organised events in support of the cause. Liu was so actively involved in student activities in the United States that his mentor asked him if he wanted to be &ldquo;a politician or a mathematician?&rdquo;</p><p>This question was a turning point for Liu. After careful consideration, he decided to pursue a career in maths.</p></section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 04:57:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/gen-z-laughing-face-ai-123000930.html</link><title>Gen Z is laughing in the face of the AI jobs apocalypse. I see it in my classroom every day (yahoo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb75et/gen_z_is_laughing_in_the_face_of_the_ai_jobs/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb75et/gen_z_is_laughing_in_the_face_of_the_ai_jobs/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb75et/gen_z_is_laughing_in_the_face_of_the_ai_jobs/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/OXXk4G_Z0xF8yIpq2xr_rQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/fortune_175/98bce0b897220e2a353181756b6cdcc1' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><header><div><p>Jeff LeBlanc</p><div><p><time>Sat, September 6, 2025 at 12:30 PM UTC</time></p><p>4 min read</p></div></div></header><div><figure><figcaption><p>I've seen that laugh many times.</p></figcaption></figure></div></div><div><p>In my strategy class this spring, a student leaned back during a discussion about automation and quipped, &ldquo;Well, we aren&rsquo;t going to get a job anyway because of AI, so who cares?&rdquo; Laughter rippled across the room. It was quick, light&mdash;even comforting. But beneath the jokes lay a tense reality. This feeling is the elephant in the room for many young people: they sense the job market evolving under AI&rsquo;s influence, and they&rsquo;re not sure where they&rsquo;ll fit.</p><p>When I asked several students if they ever talk seriously about AI replacing jobs, one replied, &ldquo;Not really. If you think about it too much, it feels hopeless.&rdquo; Another said, &ldquo;We just figure something else will come along. Or maybe we&rsquo;ll figure out how to work with it.&rdquo; Humor has become a coping tool&mdash;a way to acknowledge the threat without dwelling on it.</p><p>This sentiment is grounded in data.&nbsp;A <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/08/06/goldman-sachs-economist-gen-z-tech-jobs-ai-labor-market/">Goldman Sachs analysis</a> shows that Gen Z tech workers are experiencing higher unemployment than older generations, with rates among 20-to-30-year-olds up nearly 3 percentage points since early 2024&mdash;over four times the national average increase. Joseph Briggs, a senior economist at Goldman Sachs, warns that&nbsp;<a href="https://observenow.com/2025/08/goldman-sachs-economist-warns-gen-z-tech-workers-could-be-first-to-lose-jobs-to-ai/?utm_source=chatgpt.com">&ldquo;those performing the most easily automated tasks&mdash;often the most junior employees&mdash;are naturally the most vulnerable.&rdquo;</a> Yet even among this landscape, roughly 42% of Gen Z workers have used AI to inform career decisions&mdash;the highest of any generation&mdash;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1mll0dp/goldman_sachs_economist_warns_gen_z_tech_workers/?utm_source=chatgpt.com">one in five say AI suggested a career path they hadn&rsquo;t considered before</a>.</p><p>Gen Z isn&rsquo;t the first generation shaped by turbulence. Millennials faced the 2008 recession, Gen <a href="https://fortune.com/company/twitter/">X</a> experienced offshoring, and Boomers watched industries automate. But AI&rsquo;s rapid scope and reach set this moment apart. A&nbsp;2025 SHRM survey found that 80% of employers expect entry-level job descriptions to shift significantly within three years because of AI.</p><p>Some students are already hedging: gravitating toward fields that seem more human-centric&mdash;mental health, skilled trades, education&mdash;and others are diving into AI skills, hoping to stay ahead. A few are building side gigs early: freelancing, tutoring, and part-time creative work. One student captured it best: &ldquo;If AI really changes everything, we can&rsquo;t control it. So I&rsquo;d rather focus on what I can do now.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a blend of pragmatism and fatalism that feels uniquely Gen Z.</p><p>But the risk is that humor can mask passivity. Laughing off the threat may ease the moment but doesn&rsquo;t set up long-term preparedness. These same laughs surface in TikToks about job interview awkwardness, tales of the &ldquo;Gen Z stare&rdquo; in service roles, and viral &ldquo;workplace hacks&rdquo; like CC-ing fake lawyers to protect oneself from bad bosses&mdash;shared because they make real work anxieties feel relatable.</p><p>Is that enough? According to economist Tyler <a href="https://fortune.com/company/cowen/">Cowen</a> of George Mason University, not entirely. He argues that college curricula are overfocused on routine skills&mdash;content that AI can now handle better&mdash;and recommends dedicating up to <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/economist-tyler-cowen-college-students-trained-jobs-ai-work-2025-8?utm_source=chatgpt.com">one-third of higher education to teaching students how to use AI</a>, understand its limits, and cultivate critical thinking and mentorship capacities that AI can&rsquo;t replicate.</p><p>The challenge is for educators, employers, and policymakers to build on Gen Z&rsquo;s humor, adaptability, and intelligence&mdash;not shy away from it. Laughter is part of their cultural toolkit, a way to defuse tension and build connection, but it should be paired with clear-eyed preparation. Laughing through uncertainty isn&rsquo;t inherently harmful; in fact, it can signal resilience. Yet if humor becomes the only response, it risks leaving deeper concerns unaddressed.</p><p>Helping this generation see beyond the joke means showing them how to translate quick wit into strategic thinking. That might involve embedding AI literacy into every discipline, encouraging students to treat emerging tools as collaborators rather than threats, or designing workplace mentorship programs that help young employees connect short-term problem-solving with long-term career planning. It also means rewarding adaptability not just when things go wrong, but when it&rsquo;s used proactively to anticipate change.</p><p>AI will reshape work in unexpected ways, touching industries from creative arts to healthcare logistics. It may introduce entirely new career categories, while making others obsolete faster than any previous wave of automation. The real question is whether Gen Z&rsquo;s combination of humor, adaptability, and caution will help them ride that wave&mdash;or whether they will find themselves reacting too late, caught in its undertow. For now, the laughter continues. The work ahead lies in making sure it is paired with the skills and foresight to turn uncertainty into opportunity.</p><div><h2>More in Technology</h2></div><p><em><em>The opinions expressed in Fortune.com commentary pieces are solely the views of their authors and do not necessarily reflect the opinions and beliefs of&nbsp;</em>Fortune<em>.</em></em></p><p>This story was originally featured on <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/09/06/gen-z-is-laughing-in-the-face-of-the-ai-jobs-apocalypse/">Fortune.com</a></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/om8Xf1Ur6UC7bnS6lpBibQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2MDtoPTYwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/2b82d430-3567-11eb-be1f-26e8c03de24e"></p><p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/BkcvsRYihaoBF986onW3RQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2MDtoPTYwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/4a8cb0d0-3567-11eb-9bbd-46eddb1d0973"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 04:10:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.npr.org/2025/09/02/nx-s1-5521384/energy-report-scientists-climate-change</link><title>Dozens of scientists find errors in a new Department of Energy climate report (npr.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb04u5/dozens_of_scientists_find_errors_in_a_new/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb04u5/dozens_of_scientists_find_errors_in_a_new/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb04u5/dozens_of_scientists_find_errors_in_a_new/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 23:32:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wsj.com/politics/trump-tech-ceo-rose-garden-dinner-1fee2de3?st=LbJtjB</link><title>Tech CEOs Take Turns Praising Trump at White House Dinner (wsj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1naw5hz/tech_ceos_take_turns_praising_trump_at_white/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1naw5hz/tech_ceos_take_turns_praising_trump_at_white/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1naw5hz/tech_ceos_take_turns_praising_trump_at_white/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 20:58:33 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
