<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=explainlikeimfive&amp;averagePostsPerDay=9&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/explainlikeimfive</title><description>Hot posts in /r/explainlikeimfive (roughly 9 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 18:13:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/a-thumbs-redditmedia-com-KZESzgF91cP3KEAR29JhCFmX0zxsPgY1sYhv7XCtiW0-144x400.png</url><title>/r/explainlikeimfive</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/</link><title>ELI5 What is diplomatic immunity for?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Diplomats handle disputes between countries. If I am a diplomat in the US from Norway, and there is a conflict between the US and Norway, I want to have some sort of immunity while I am in the US. If not, I wouldn&#39;t want to do that kind of work. The US could harass me and hold me hostage, and I could be put in danger.</p><p>Immunity for diplomats is an agreement between states that have diplomatic relations, because it is seen as necessary for the system to function.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/nf86lan/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>To prevent the harassment of diplomats &amp; ensure the free-flow of negotiations between countries...</p><p>If the US and China have a dispute, and the US sends an ambassador to China whom the Chinese throw in prison for unpaid parking tickets, that just might prevent the dispute from being negotiated away.... It further might prevent the US from sending diplomats to China in the first-place....</p><p>So the countries of the world made a rule that diplomats may only be expelled from host countries, not arrested/fined/punished under host-country law.</p><p>That way any country that wishes to send diplomats to other countries can do so, without fear that their people will end up in prison.</p><p>This also gets abused for espionage, but there-again, the understanding that spies with diplomatic-immunity (official-cover) are untouchable beyond kicking-them-out if you catch them gets universally respected, so your spies are as safe as your enemy&#39;s.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/nf88rbi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s an extension of “Don’t shoot the messenger” into modern times</p><p>The diplomats need to be able to be present in a country to facilitate talks with them. If a war breaks out and you instantly kill off all the diplomats there’s no going back because you can no longer talk. So an agreement to make the diplomats immune from the decisions of their home country is needed. They’re not immune from laws, just can’t be held responsible for their governments actions since, they’re just a messenger</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/nf875ta/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Diplomatic immunity is a principle of international law, established by the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations (1961), that protects foreign diplomats from arrest, prosecution, or interference by the host country, ensuring they can carry out their duties without fear of intimidation or political pressure. It safeguards secure communication between states, promotes reciprocity (since countries want their own envoys protected abroad), and prevents host nations from exploiting legal systems to obstruct diplomacy.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/nf86tpy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In movies, it seems to be used for spy work and to get criminals off the hook for things. I wonder if that means diplomats can get away with murder literally</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/nf8dpug/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s rooted in the idea of &quot;not shooting the messenger&quot; and &quot;don&#39;t shoot my messenger and I won&#39;t shoot your messenger&quot;. Otherwise, it becomes very difficult to send diplomats anywhere except friendly countries. But diplomats are probably the most important when sent to less than perfectly friendly countries.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/nf8egym/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Diplomats are there so that they can talk to other governments even when they are at war etc. so peace deals etc. can be worked out. If an ambassador or their staff could just be arrested and thrown in jail at the whim of the government all of that is put at risk, it is impossible to separate what is a political motivated charge  and what is a legitimate criminal charge, especially when dealing with dictatorships, so the easiest way is to make the ambassador and a small team immune. In normal circumstances they don&#39;t commit crimes (other than spying) any one with immunity caught doing anything wrong is normally sent home in disgrace and won&#39;t get any further posting and may even face charges in their home country.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlv6q1/eli5_what_is_diplomatic_immunity_for/nf8l39b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 16:28:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/</link><title>ELI5: How do humans breed dogs to have specific behaviors?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I came across this message:</p><p>&quot;Boarder Collies were bred to work with a human to herd livestock. They play by structured rules and abhor the chaos of a scattered herd.</p><p>Huskies were bred to use their own judgement. When pulling a sled, they may detect something the human doesn&#39;t notice and will refuse to follow an order against their judgement. This makes them more likely to be stubborn.&quot;</p><p>Do dogs need to be born with a behavior to pass it on to their offspring, or can a trained behavior increase the chance their puppies inherit it?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s the result of hundreds of years of selective breeding, if not thousands for some species. You need a dog born with a strong drive to run after cattle, you take it, breed it with a similar dog. Repeat until you get a border collie some hundreds of years down the line.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/nf7f6rz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Well, when they find a dog good at a certain thing, and another dog good at a certain thing, they have put them together in heat, and puppies are formed!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/nf7f3z2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Herding is just part of wolves instinctual hunting behavior.  They&#39;ll coral prey to exhaust them.  The tricky part was training/breeding the dogs so the herding didn&#39;t escalate to them killing.  Most working dog behaviors, pointing, herding, retrieving, are all based in instinctual wolf behaviors.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/nf7h7to/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We find a dog with the behavior traits the we want, and breed it with another dog that has those same traits. Rinse and repeat. It&#39;s no different than breeding a dog for physical characteristics.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/nf7irzu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Puppies can not inherit a trained behavior, it does not work that way.<br/>It&#39;s just like breeding for physical characteristics, except you&#39;re breeding for behavior traits.<br/>Regardless of the trait, you simply find a male and female that come as close as he desired characteristic you can find and breed them together.  The hope is that some of the offspring will inherit those traits, and you then again  take the ones that come closest to what is desired and breed those... over and over and over again.</p><p>So let&#39;s say you would like an all black beagle.  The coat of the typical beagle is a mixture of white, brown and black.  So find a male and female that each have more black in their coat than the average beagle.  Breed them and the hope is that some of the puppies have more black in their coat than their parents had.  From the puppies (perhaps across a few litter of puppies) you take the male and female that have the largest percentage of black fur and breed them.  You continue the cycle until you either get the desired trait or give up because you&#39;re not making progress with each generation.</p><p>Now simply substitute &quot;black fur beagle&quot; with &quot;some behavioral trait&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/nf7mobe/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Born with the behaviour. Or at least have a propensity for it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/nf7eyg0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s called selective breeding, and it happens with more than just dogs, all domesticated animals, and even plants are subjected to selective breeding. </p><p>It’s exactly what it sounds like, you select a trait you like, and you breed that animal with another animal to make more animals with that trait.</p><p>Let’s say you wanted to breed grizzly bears to have a new breed of grizzly bears that will instinctually break trees down for you. For the sake of argument, let’s just start from scratch. The first thing you need is a bunch of wild grizzly bears, so you capture 100 wild grizzly bears. You release them into a field that has trees in it and see which ones like to scratch the trees the most. You keep the best tree scratching boy, and best tree scratching girl bear, and let the rest go. You let the two bears you kept make babies, preferably as many as possible. Of all the offspring, you see which two like going after them trees them most, then you breed them together (yes, selective breeding often involves inbreeding, often lots of inbreeding). The others you let go. If you do this generation after generation, and you keep only letting the bears that like ripping on them trees reproduce, after a few dozen generations, all the baby bear cubs just instinctually love clawing up trees. It’s not a learned behavior, it’s one that was partially instinctual in their great great great grandparents, but you kept forcing that instinct into all the kids, stronger, and stronger, until it’s so strong that all bears with this gene reinforcement make new bears that also have this gene reinforcement… now boom, you have grizzly bears that have a genetic distinction from normal wild grizzly bears. Now you can name them, Treezly Bears, it’s a new breed of bear that just really love ripping up trees. </p><p>The thing about selective breeding, is that DNA is complicated, and genes are really close together, so sometimes when you select one trait, you are inadvertently selecting at least 1 other gene. Let’s say the gene that makes them like scratching trees is right next to a gene that makes them have big ears. That’s how visual distinctions end up happening when selecting for behavioral traits. Your Treezly Bears just happen to have big ears, and that’s how you know you got a Treezly Bear, it’s just a side effect.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlqv5y/eli5_how_do_humans_breed_dogs_to_have_specific/nf7mrv7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:00:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/</link><title>ELI5 If there was a live video feed between us on earth and a ship traveling at light speed, what would we see?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Would they see us age rapidly? Would we see them stay young? How would that even work, assuming it was possible?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>You couldn&#39;t have a &quot;live&quot; feed in this scenario because the feed itself is traveling to us at the speed of light; as the ship travels away from us, each successive frame of the video takes longer to get to us because it has to travel a greater distance than the frame before it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/nf6cbvf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Fun thought experiment. Here&#39;s how I think about it: </p><ol><li><p>Imagine the ship is flying to Jupiter at its closest approach. That&#39;s 33 light minutes away. </p></li><li><p>Let&#39;s say the ship is flying so close to the speed of light that it only takes 1 minute to get there from the earth. </p></li><li><p>The ship starts its broadcast and then accelerates to near lightspeed. It broadcasts the message for the entire time it&#39;s travelling. </p></li></ol><p>From the ship&#39;s perspective, they only broadcast a message for 1 minute before they reach Jupiter.</p><p>From our perspective, that same message was 33 minutes long. To us, that one-minute broadcast would appear like it was very, very slow and stretched out. If the first words of the broadcast were one of the crew members saying, &quot;one Mississippi, two Mississippi,&quot; it would take an entire minute (and more) for them to finish speaking those first few words. </p><p>But of course, to them it feels like they&#39;re speaking perfectly normally, and the fact is that they ARE speaking perfectly normally, just not from your perspective.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/nf6x0gi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You wouldn’t see anything, because the time dilation would be too great.</p><p>But if it were traveling at 99% of light speed, you’d see an extremely red-shifted signal that looked like slow motion.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/nf6c592/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You can&#39;t travel <em>at</em> the speed of light, but as a thought experiment let&#39;s imagine you are so close to the speed of light it doesn&#39;t matter.</p><p>Whatever is transmitting the video signal is traveling at the speed of light. Because the ship is going light speed away from earth they don&#39;t receive new signals, so the earth looks frozen in time to the ship.</p><p>The ship is under huge amounts of time dilation and time runs incredibly slowly for them, so the ship looks frozen in time to the earth. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/nf6csex/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They would appear frozen as they moved along, if you could see them.</p><p>But if they are traveling away from you, the signal would be so stretched that each video frame would take longer and longer to get here. </p><p>60 frames per second.   First frame is as they left.   Second frame is 10,000kms away.   It will arrive in 1 minute. The next frame in 2 minutes, etc. </p><p>Worst stop -motion video ever.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/nf6gp15/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If it were a magic live feed of a magic ship that defied the laws of physics, you&#39;d see the people on board the ship frozen in time. At light speed, time stops.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/nf6j3bg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A broadcast advertising <em>Milliways</em>, probably.*</p><p>Objects with mass cannot travel at the speed of light as seen frrom any inertial frame. So the only way that your hypothesised ship can &quot;travel at the speed of light&quot; is for it to become massless.</p><p><em>&quot;(This is, of course, impossible.)&quot;</em></p><p>Objects travelling at the speed of light do not experience time. So IF we were to find a loophole in the laws of physics that would somehow allow us to make our ship massless, we would need to send it to a given destination and have it recover its mass at a precise location relative to us, despite its having no time in which to distinguish between its different spatial locations.</p><p><em>&quot;(This is, of course, impossible.)&quot;</em></p><p>We would then need to find a way of monitoring its state at those different points in a sequential manner from our perspective, despite the fact that no time is passing from its perspective.</p><p><em>&quot;(This is, of course, impossible.)&quot;</em></p><p><em>&quot;(Which is why the advertising executives of the star system of Bastablon came up with this slogan: :&quot;If you&#39;ve done six impossible things this morning, why not round it off with breakfast at Milliways, the Restaurant at the End of the Universe?&quot;)&quot;</em></p><p>*The other answer, ignoring all the physical impossibilities involved, is that, for us, it would be very, very boring - because no time is passing for the ship. So there wouldn&#39;t be any change between the moment (from our perspective) it departed and the moment it arrived. And the crew of the ship wouldn&#39;t have any opportunity to form any opinion about what was happening to us, because at the precise moment (from their perspective) that they set off, they would arrive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nllfwj/eli5_if_there_was_a_live_video_feed_between_us_on/nf7l007/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 07:04:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/</link><title>ELI5 why are road fatalities per capita in the US so high?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>According to the Wikipedia page, the US is 111 out of 191 in the world for road fatalities per capita, lower numbers being better: <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_traffic-related_death_rate">https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_traffic-related_death_rate</a></p><p>This is  <em>way</em> worse than basically all Western nations. It&#39;s worse than even the poorest European countries, and at the same level as Bangladesh and Syria. (China, Brazil and South Africa are still worse, however)</p><p>Maybe the US is more car dependent, and more people own cars? But Canada is probably similar enough and it is in 32nd place.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Just because the US is a car reliant country doesn&#39;t mean most of us know how to actually drive properly</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5e0ie/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The metric you are looking at is deaths per capita, this means any country with a high rate of driving will have high results. </p><p>In your same link you can look at deaths per kilometer driven. The only problem with that data is it only lists 23 countries of which the US is #8. Slightly better than countries like Mexico, South Korea, and New Zealand, and slight worse than countries like France, Australia, and Canada.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5fu2k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>More people driving in general is the easiest answer, but it has a lot of cultural elements that affect how we approach driving and road infrastructure.</p><p>In my opinion, the biggest issues informing how policy is shaped around driving is that <strong>people need to drive to get to work, and drive to buy things</strong>. These two issues are critical to our economy, meaning the barrier to entry for driving has to be relatively low to not impede people&#39;s ability to act as consumers and a workforce. </p><p>Directly connected to this, we allow many people who probably should not be driving to drive. The very old and the very young stick out in particular. Because cars are required to get to work, there is pressure for people to continue to drive without a license if it is suspended or they don&#39;t have one to begin with. </p><p>Downstream of this, roads have to be designed to let people with cars get from point a to point b expidently. Many stretches of roads have relatively high speed limits for the type of traffic traversing it. This inherently makes changing lanes and attempting to turn dangerous.</p><p>Further down from that, we also have to think about suburban sprawl.  Many suburban and suburbanizing-rural areas are covered in Stroads. Stroads are extremely dangerous for pedestrians and drivers. They have very high collision rates for both parties as they are high speed but designed for local areas rather than traveling between distant places.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5ga98/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because the US is built around cars and driving everywhere. There is very little public transportation,  mostly located in the biggest cities.  And even there a lot of people still choose to drive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5emrq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s our culture. </p><ul><li>we drive more</li><li>we drive faster</li><li>we let ourselves be more distracted </li><li>we drive under the influence of more substances</li><li>we believe ourselves to be more skilled drivers than we actually are, so we blame the problem on other drivers instead of prioritizing safety</li></ul></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5fe79/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You are looking at fatalities, not accidents. The US has a lot of dumb drivers (everywhere does), but the high speed limits and relatively less traffic mean people drive faster and if an accident happens, speed kills.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5eqwk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A lot of it has to do with the size of the vehicles as well. Not many places will allow the super compensator 350 with dual axles and a semi on the road.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5f393/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 03:42:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/</link><title>ELI5. Why don't brain biopsies kill you?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>ELI5. Basically the title. How do brain biopsies not further damage people? How does it not hurt people more? Does the brain grow back if missing small piece?</p><p>Thanks!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Hi there.  Person who has received a brain biopsy here. The truth is they only need a handful of cells to confirm a diagnosis, and typically the cells they need to biopsy are not brain cells but tumor cells, so the potential for harm is already greatly reduced. </p><p>Put it this way; if you can DNA test cells from your cheek with a cotton swab it ought to be similarly easy to get tumor cells surgically on a probe.  The difficulty isn’t in collecting the cells but in getting there safely.  In my case the tumor was in my midbrain so they had to tunnel through brain matter to get there.  They use a very thin needle and CT scans to get a 3D image of the brain then map out the least destructive path avoiding critical regions and blood vessels. The brain can withstand such micro punctures with little to no damage.  So they find the best approach to the target tissue and slowly insert the probe/needle using stereotactic (precise, 3D modeling based) guidance and remotely controlled robotic equipment.  </p><p>To further protect the brain, they attach a metal frame to the patient’s skull, completely immobilizing it to the operating table so there is no chance for movement.  In my personal experience, that’s the worst part, because they literally screw the frame into the bone of your skull to keep it still.  Sorry for the graphic explanation, but it’s the truth.</p><p>Granted, it’s still brain surgery, but it’s not like they’re excising portions of the brain.  </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf2zsrd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s a tiny bit that&#39;s taken, think like having a scrape on your knee. And yes, it is not without risk. But if it&#39;s being done, risk of not doing it is much higher. No, it doesn&#39;t grow back.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf2xxu4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m a neuropathologist, meaning my job is to look at brain biopsies all day long.</p><p>Saying &quot;brain biopsies are small,&quot; while true, isn&#39;t really the answer.</p><p>Saying &quot;the tissue they take is diseased&quot; also isn&#39;t really the answer. Many biopsies, by the nature of brain tumors, also take some normal brain with them.</p><p>The main reason is, simply, there are large areas of the brain that can be removed without causing serious problems. The brain has a lot of redundancy and interconnectedness.</p><p>There are some distinct areas of the brain that, when damaged, will kill you. In general, these are in the deeper regions of the brain that control things like consciousness, breathing, etc. Surgeons like to stay away from these areas.</p><p>There are other large areas of the brain that, if damaged, can cause severe consequences like paralysis, memory loss, language impairment, etc., but will not kill you. Surgeons also like to avoid these.</p><p>The main risk of a brain biopsy is hitting a critical structure that will cause a neurologic deficit. Typically, the main risk of death during brain surgery is damage to a vessel that causes a bleed or a stroke.</p><p>Some surgeries, especially in young people, can remove enormous parts of the brain with little consequence. In the past, neurosurgeons have attempted to remove an entire half of the brain to treat certain tumors. Although very morbid, patients could still live with half a brain.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf5p81v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Pretty much every surgery is a controlled wound. The big thing that makes a surgery special is the number of specialized tools and experience needed to make sure the wound is as small and controlled as possible while still doing whatever the surgeon is trying to do.</p><p>A brain biopsy is a perfect example. Whatever is damaging / afflicting the brain is <em>probably</em> worse than the surgery on its own, so by doing a biopsy you can minimize the amount  of damage for the full treatment.</p><p>The biopsy itself is small enough that it doesn&#39;t destroy the brain to a degree where you would die -- but, it&#39;s also really important to consider <em>where</em> a biopsy might be taking place, because that will impact the net effect of the surgery to the brain, surrounding skull, and general tissue.</p><p>Asking &quot;why don&#39;t brain biopsies kill you&quot; is similar to asking &quot;why wouldn&#39;t a blood draw take all your blood?&quot; The answer is always that the damage isn&#39;t enough to be lethal, and blood loss &amp; tissue damage are controlled as much as reasonably possible.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf2ydr2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As long as no vital parts are damaged you&#39;d be surprised what kind of trauma to the brain people can survive. Hell we used to stick ice picks into people&#39;s brains as a mental health remedy lol.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf36dm4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Surgeons take a rice-grain sized sample through a tiny hole using image guidance (not a big chunk). Beforehand they map the brain with MRI or CT and plan a path that dodges speech, movement and major blood vessels. During the biopsy a rigid frame or camera guidance keeps the needle on that safe path. The brain itself doesn&#39;t feel pain, so with the scalp and skull numbed or under anesthesia the procedure isn&#39;t felt the way you&#39;d expect.</p><p>Removing a tiny bit doesn&#39;t make a hollow that &quot;kills&quot; tissue around it. The spot bleeds a little then seals, immune cells clean up and scar tissue fills in. Neurons don&#39;t grow back like skin or liver, but the brain has redundancy and can usually compensate for such a small sample. There are risks like bleeding or seizures, which is why it&#39;s only done when the benefit of getting a diagnosis outweights those risks.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf3gls9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Neurosurgeon here.Most of the brain is considered “non-eloquent” which means that when parts of them are removed there is no obvious outward neurological deficit or stroke-like symptom that results. There are two types of biopsies - one uses a small needle that’s inserted to suck up a little rice grain sized piece of brain and the other is a surgery that drills a piece of your bone off through a bigger incision to sample a piece of the brain. Sometimes these biopsies actually involve sampling the bone or the covering of the brain which doesn’t damage the brain at all.</p><p>When we do a biopsy we tend to aim for safer areas of the brain that are “non-eloquent” such as the right frontal lobe or the very front parts of the left frontal lobe. We try to avoid places that would mess up vision, movement, sensation, and language.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf6rd0h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:19:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/</link><title>ELI5: How do TSA/customs agents open our luggage with their special keys? What's stopping thieves or criminals from making the same keys?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Nothing. You can buy TSA master keys on ebay. This is why many people consider TSA approved locks to be inherently insecure.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2pyqy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Short answer: nothing. You can get TSA keys from eBay and people have been using those to loot luggage.</p><p>This is the same as “back doors for good guys” in encryption - except that it is much easier for bad guys to peek into data packages than into suitcases.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2q7qc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The reality is that thieves or criminals don&#39;t need a TSA key to open your luggage because zippers are extremely unsecure. Any piece of luggage with a zipper can be popped open in seconds with a standard ball point pen. Just push the pen through the zipper and pull apart the gap that it created.</p><p>Those padlocks do add a little bit of security in that they prevent people from quickly rifling through your luggage and then zipping it back up with no outward signs of tampering.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2r3q0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>What&#39;s stopping thieves or criminals from making the same keys?</p></blockquote><p>Absolutely nothing. </p><p>Good luck. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2qjbz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You can buy the keys online for a couple of bucks. There’s 7 TSA master keys.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2pys5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The only real difference is access to your luggage. </p><p>Most people dont use the locks unless they are travelling. And when you&#39;re travelling, the only people who really have access are yourself and airline/airport workers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2qkiv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you really want your luggage secured, you need to pack a gun in a hard well locked case, you can pack valuables in the same case.<a href="https://www.tsa.gov/travel/transporting-firearms-and-ammunition">https://www.tsa.gov/travel/transporting-firearms-and-ammunition</a>No really. They will inspect your firearm, and all contents of your luggage in front of you. Then it needs to be securely locked without a TSA lock. And they put a special label on it as well. It will not be opened during transport. If it, report it, as there are heavy penalties.</p><p>I&#39;ve heard a starter pistol will work for this as well, if you don&#39;t want to own a real gun.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2vt4k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:45:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/</link><title>ELI5 how do factories take feathers off the chicken?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>When people mass produce chicken how do they efficiently take all the feathers out?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>They use a specialized machine called a chicken defeathering machine which is basically a drum that spins to create friction that rubs the feathers off.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/nf1zsv1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They soak the chicken in warm water to loosen the feathers and then put the carcass in a device like a washing machine that spin-rubs the feathers off.</p><p>You can see a mini version of this for 3 chickens:</p><p>Relevant section starts at 12.45</p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/irtfnJ4QekQ?si=8HlJQO33aOpbWcs8">https://youtu.be/irtfnJ4QekQ?si=8HlJQO33aOpbWcs8</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/nf289dz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Got an old washing machine?  You’re welcome.</p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/mS-8outVilc?si=aoye4LbMRs2mVQuf">https://youtu.be/mS-8outVilc?si=aoye4LbMRs2mVQuf</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/nf2ej1r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Violently, but seriously, factories first dip the chickens in hot water to loosen the feathers, then run them through big rotating machines with rubber fingers that rub and pull the feathers off quickly. </p><p>It can look pretty violent.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/nf1zq98/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Homesteaders and farmers do it as well. </p><p>Not just factories. </p><p>There are plenty of youtube videos, lol, you know, if watching a dead chicken be spun around inside a drum is your Friday morning kind of thing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/nf21trl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>throw them in boiling water then a giant cylinder brush removes the feathers</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/nf2fqxt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Worked in chicken plant that rhymed with bison fixing those for a while. They would leave the kill line hanging from their paws, dipped into really hot water, then conveyed through what looked like a really really long rectangular metal box. Inside that box was rotating large rubber “fingers” that just violently slapped the feathers off the chickens</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl1crz/eli5_how_do_factories_take_feathers_off_the/nf3lxcf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 17:17:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/</link><title>ELI5: Can satellites in space detect the B-2 bomber?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>On the ground? Sure. I&#39;d be surprised if China and Russia don&#39;t have eyes on US airfields. Mid flight? Probably, but with a big asterisk. Like you can find them on pictures taken since they are not invisible, but tracking them is probably going to be very difficult.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/nf1l99n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Former satellite imagery analyst here. If you’re talking about detecting one in flight then you should know that catching a moving aircraft via satellite imagery is essentially always incidental. Most imaging satellites follow what’s known as a “<del>geosynchronous</del> sun-synchronous orbit”, meaning they circle the earth on a predictable path over a 24 hour period. This means you have limited time span and a limited area in which satellites can capture an image at any given point in time. This is why we have “constellations” of many satellites to ensure more frequent coverage over broader areas on a daily basis.</p><p>In order to “task” imagery over a specified location you need to already know area where you want the satellite to take a picture ahead of time (usually hours, in rare cases I’ve seen successful tasking within half an hour if the priority is high enough and everything happens to line up correctly). If you knew the aircraft’s predetermined flight plan AND the flight actually adhered to that plan AND a satellite was going to be over that area at that exact time then it would be theoretically possible, but if you already know all that information from other sources or sensors then there probably wouldn’t be much point in taking a satellite image anyway. There’s also the processing time for the image itself so even if you did capture it by the time you get the image back and have someone look at it the aircraft would probably be over a hundred miles away at least.</p><p>Imagery also has a limited area you can capture and the larger the area the lower the resolution, so blindly taking images over large areas would be painstaking and probably not worth the effort. Ships, however, often ARE tracked via imaging satellites as they move much slower and you can cross reference their navigational path with other sources, plus there is more value in taking an image since there are other details about the ship you might want to try and see (cargo load, structural damage, etc.).</p><p>I’m simplifying this quite a bit since there are multiple types of sensors (including infrared and radar imagery). I’m also talking about the most common types of imaging satellites and not signals-based sensors, which operate very differently.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/nf25oa5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Depends. If one&#39;s taking photos of the ground, and a B-2 is in frame, it will be visible whenever someone looks at the photos, same as it would to the eye. If you mean recognize and notify someone as it enters frame, if that capability exists it&#39;s going to be classified. A harder problem at night. </p><p>The bigger issue with satellites is that they move on predictable orbits, you need thousands for consistent coverage, so unless one of the recent commercial LEO  constellations is secretly doing double duty as spy satellites, any coverage that exists is going to be sporadic, and can be avoided at the flight planning stage.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/nf1lyjw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If they are using regular optics (IE just looking at stuff) then yes.  But then again so can you or I.  The stealth is only stealthy to radar and to an extent, infrared (heat vision).  So anything.outside of those two can easily see it.  </p><p>Question though, how do you look for something you don&#39;t know is there?</p><p>Radar tells us something is out there but if you can&#39;t track it by radar, your eyes are useless.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/nf1vn0h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Using optics...meh, not really. </p><p>However.....</p><p>Using a satellite in conjunction with signal detection on the ground.  Yes.</p><p>If the satellite sends out a signal, it will be blocked by the aircraft, creating a &quot;hole&quot; in the signal that can be tracked. More or less like a shadow. </p><p>Some researchers already showed it can be done from the signals/frequencies that Starlink is constantly beaming down. </p><p>If one were to build a more dedicated detection system it would be able to detect any stealth aircraft.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/nf3a5o6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Absolutely! Stealthy aircraft are usually designed to have a low radar cross section from certain angles (usually from the front) and aren&#39;t usually designed to be stealthy from the top.</p><p>So if you have a NRO radar imaging satellite in geostationary orbit, it can definitely detect a B-2 or other stealthy jet from overhead.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/nf737j6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They can, in low orbit using regular matrix sensor and optics like in your phone and cameras.</p><p>Usual observation/photo satellites are just sweeping with a big line of photo sensors and count on their orbit to make actual pictures by sweeping (it explains the distortion you can see on moving objects), making it impossible to track a plane as it can only take a picture each time it passes over it during its orbit.</p><p>So yeah, if you made satellites dedicated to it. Also would need multiple to have no dark zones. And using a matrix is really limited in range and resolution</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkz8n7/eli5_can_satellites_in_space_detect_the_b2_bomber/nf1xpfm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:18:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/</link><title>ELI5 how rice-cookers make better rice than just boiling the rice in a pan?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I understand the benefit of the rice cooker to keep rice warm after it’s cooked, but I just fail to see how the <em>cooking</em> differs between a rice-cooker and a basic pan.</p><p>Rice + boiling water (in a pan) = Rice + boiling water (in a rice-cooker)</p><p>What am I missing? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>A rice cooker automatically stops the heat once the rice is done (by detecting the temperature raising above 100C, meaning all water has been absorbed and boiled)</p><p>This is all done without lifting the lid, which means the steam doesn&#39;t escape and the rice can cook with it</p><p>You can do all the same things in a pan, it&#39;s just less consistent</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1favo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A rice cooker uses the fact that when there is water in the pot, the temperature of the pot cannot rise above boiling point.</p><p>Once the water is fully absorbed by the rice, the temperature rises again, a thermostat detects the rise (usually using a special magnet), and it stops cooking.</p><p>This is the difference.</p><p>A pot on a stove you can do the same, just not as accurately. So you may have almost cooked rice with gloopy water at the bottom, or overcooked rice without water but starting to catch and burn.</p><p>A rice cooker is simple (one moving part) and reliable (using physics to stop cooking) for perfect rice every time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1hc13/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://youtu.be/RSTNhvDGbYI?si=nbQWI4vZRjRk40Rv">https://youtu.be/RSTNhvDGbYI?si=nbQWI4vZRjRk40Rv</a></p><p>Tech Connections has a great video on how they work</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1ieqx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Basic rice cookers don&#39;t make better rice than just boiling in a pan, as long as we&#39;re comparing apples to apples: same rice/water ratio, same heat output to the pan/pot, <strong>same distribution of heat</strong>.</p><p>That last one is particularly important. Boiling something over a gas stove puts a <strong>lot</strong> of energy into the bottom of the pot (and usually around the sides) very quickly. A good rice cooker will have a heating element that heats the bottom and sides of the pot a bit more evenly, and a bit more slowly. This prevents rice at the bottom of the pan from receiving too much heat energy too quickly, which would cause it to dry out and become hard. A good rice cooker excels at producing cooked rice with a consistent texture.</p><p>I&#39;m sure fancier rice cookers go even further with heat cycles / cooking times, but the basics remain the same. The more evenly distributed the heat in your rice/water is, the more evenly the rice will cook.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1ftmv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m not sure it makes better rice, but it is foolproof. Set it and forget it</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1gldl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In addition to making consistent rice and being able to keep it warm for hours, to me the number one advantage of a rice cooker is you start it and walk away. You’re not standing at the stove watching it, you can do something else. Some fancy ones even let you do things like load it up in the morning and set so that rice is ready (not start, but ready) at a specific time, like right at dinner time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf2dwvn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Rice cookers use a very simple system to detect when the moisture has dropped enough and the rice is cooked, but not overcooked. This switches the heat down to a low level that keeps it warm. </p><p>Between perfect timing and tight temperature control, this can make better rice (and defiantly easier rice) then most people can make in a pan.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1foti/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:22:04 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/</link><title>ELI5: What does "Be there or be square" even mean??</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Maybe it&#39;s because English isn&#39;t my first language, but what does this phrase even mean?</p><p>is it a threat? You be there or i&#39;ll turn you into a square? like rectangle cube??</p><p>what? it doesn&#39;t make sense what be square even means?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Square means not cool, not hip. Be there or be square means you can either be there or you can be boring and uncool and not be there.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/nf0vl9a/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In the US, in the 1950’s, being a “square” was the slang for someone who was not hip or part of the counter culture. The rhyme and rhyme of the phrase sounds good in English, which is why it persists.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/nf0wbam/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Square is another term for lame/no fun/fun ruiner/party pooper kinda thing, be there or be no fun basically</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/nf0vm3f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>According to wikipedia, </p><blockquote><p>Square is slang for a person who is conventional and old-fashioned, similar to a fuddy-duddy. This sense of the word &quot;square&quot; originated with the American jazz community in the 1940s in reference to people out of touch with musical trends</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_(slang">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_(slang)</a>)</p><p>---</p><p>I thought it was an insult like &quot;nerd&quot;, but it sounds like it wasn&#39;t quite like that.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/nf0xjrz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Square is a US English slang term for uncool or lame. It&#39;s a way of inviting you somewhere and deeming you uncool if you don&#39;t go (in a lighthearted joking manner, nothing to be taken seriously tbh). Plus, it rhymes.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/nf0vuax/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>“Square” is outdated slang for an uncool person. So they’re saying that if you don’t go to the event, everyone will think you’re uncool and boring.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/nf0whcf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In the 80s, being a &#39;Square&#39; meant similar to being a nerd, but also had the added characteristic of being a goody-two-shoes - sucking up to teachers, for example.</p><p>So if you were invited to a party, and someone said &#39;Be there or be square&quot; it was slight peer pressure to attend as to not be seen as uncool.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkvfur/eli5_what_does_be_there_or_be_square_even_mean/nf17k22/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 11:17:25 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/</link><title>ELI5 Why we cannot swallow fast?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>If you try to swallow multiple times your body simply cannot do it, you have like a small cooldown to be able to swallow, why does that happen?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Swallowing happens by muscles contracting. Now they&#39;re contracted, so they have to relax before they can contract again. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/nexx50s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>you are clenching successive &#39;rings&#39; of muscles to squeeze the bolus of food down, where it goes through a sphincter into the actual stomach. SO effectively, call it [random number because my anat/phys days were 40 years ago] 12muscle rings that have to clench in order and relax so your esophagus is more or less programed to ripple down, then you swallow again, another ripple down ...</p><p>does that make sense? I am on a couple gummies as it is a bad body day .</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/nexx9vw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>When you swallow, you go through five different stages. You can only start this process, not speed it up. Even if you do swallow really hard, your body will compensate to keep the rhythm.</p><p>You can trick this, notice how you swallow liquids faster than food, and that people can engulf a drink in one go.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/nexyacd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Did anyone else just try to swallow quickly multiple times in a row? 😂</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/neyow2h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Swallowing is actually pretty complicated, and requires concerted action by a bunch of different muscles squeezing and relaxing in the right order. If you started swallowing again too quickly, that would mess up that sequence, potentially causing you to aspirate stuff into your lungs, or getting stuff stuck in your trachea and choking. So, part of the swallowing process is reflexes keeping you from doing that.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/ney3oxf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Have you ever chugged a beer?  You can swallow quite quickly, you just need liquid in your mouth first.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/nexxe1q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Mostly because you don&#39;t have control over most of your esophagus. You only control when you start swallowing, but the whole system past like, the epiglottis is automated. If you try to go faster than the rest of the system, things are gonna lose coordination, and you&#39;re just gonna hurt yourself, or throw up.</p><p>That said, there is a faster way of drinking liquid: don&#39;t swallow. You can train yourself to not engage your swallowing reflex, and effectively just pour a liquid directly down into your stomach. It&#39;s a bizarre ability, very unnatural at first, but it&#39;s a neat party trick to make a lot of liquid disappear very quickly. WARNING: DOES NOT WORK WITH ANYTHING THICKER THAN WATER.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkhoj5/eli5_why_we_cannot_swallow_fast/neyfznc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:53:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/</link><title>ELI5: why is Saffron so expensive in the modern age?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I just came back from a supermarket and i saw that Saffron was ~26,000 USD per Pound(~57,000 USD per KG). I did a quick comparison against gold, and it&#39;s almost half the value(~58,000 USD per Pound or ~128,000 USD per KG). I can understand how, in the past, it may have been expensive with spice trade stuff. </p><p>Why is it so absurdly expensive in this day and age? Even more important, what&#39;s keeping it from being mass-produced like other spices? Thanks!</p><p>Edit: wow! Lots of responses really quick, thank you all! </p><p>As a Tldr; for people who just want to read and go, basically it is a very fragile crocus flower that requires very specific environmental conditions and produces a significantly small yield per plant. Automation is virtually impossible because of damage and expensive residue. There&#39;s a lot of cool info in the comments about the specifics.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>One flower produces 3 threads of saffron and needs to be taken by hand. It is a delicate long process. I just looked it up and it would take 75,000 flowers to make one lb. That is a huge amount of land and time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqyq1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It can&#39;t be machine farmed, so people have to individually pick the stigmas of the saffron flower. Human labour still costs the same as in the past.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqhuh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Saffron is the dried stigma and styles of the saffron crocus flower. The only way to harvest it is by hand, and you get very little saffron from each plant. Therefore, it is hard to produce and harvest in large quantities and very valuable by weight. </p><p>But practically speaking, recipes don&#39;t use very much saffron, so it isn&#39;t really as expensive as it seems. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexr0ij/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Its a flower, and of the flower the red stigma from the flower is the actual saffron.  Each flower has 3(?) stigma im pretty sure.   So 1 flower, produces 3 very small, very light, very fragile things that we call saffron the spice.  Its just super hard to grow a lot of it....</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqrz7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because it takes a ridiculous number of crocus plants to make a tiny amount, and its such a small amount that we can&#39;t really make a system to automate it much because even the amount that would be left on the machine itself would be worth a fortune.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqtx6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s not that it is a particularly hard crop to produce. The problem is on the manual labor required to process it.</p><p>The saffron strands you see are actualy the stigma from the crocus flower. They have to be handpicked from a flower, then dried, then they are graded (yes, there are saffron grades, and they are differents based on place of origin... Spain has its own grades and middle eastern countries have another. They are somewhat aligned)</p><p>When you take into consideration that a gram of saffron requires MANY stigmas, and that they have to be handpicked, the labor costs is what makes the final product so expensive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexsnnl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s because saffron only grows in specific conditions and is astoundingly labor intensive to harvest.</p><p>Saffron the spice is the <a href="https://cdn.britannica.com/25/203625-050-64EDAEEE/Saffron-crocus-bloom-stigmas-flower-saffron-spice.jpg">stigma</a> of the saffron flower. Saffron flowers are difficult to grow, and they only bloom once per year. Each flower only produces three stigma, known as threads, of saffron. It takes approximately 150 to 170 saffron flowers to produce a single gram, and a pound (just over 450 grams) requires approximately <em>70,000 to 75,000</em> saffron flowers.</p><p>Saffron is also very delicate, it must be picked by hand. That means that one gram of saffron requires a person to carefully and individually hand pick the threads from 150 flowers. It is also incredibly sensitive to temperature, even the heat of the sun causes the flowers to wilt and the saffron to die. This means that all of this harvesting has to occur early in the morning.</p><p>This makes it a very labor intensive spice to grow, and makes it essentially impossible to mass produce like other spices.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/next77r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:22:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/</link><title>ELI5, what does it mean when something is radioactive?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>And while I appreciate simplified versions for the layperson, I would love if someone can actually explain it as if talking to a five year old.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s like a rock that doesn&#39;t want to exist cuz it has too much energy, and it throws that energy around in a form of some very small bullets until it got rid of all the extra energy and can exist again as a simple rock, not a spicy rock.</p><p>Or when you&#39;re really angry and start yelling to get rid of your anger so you can feel calm again.</p><p>They are angry rocks screaming until they calm down.<br/>Just that their scream makes cancer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/nex88qg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I could use cutesy words but real five year olds don’t need them. </p><p>Something is radioactive because it shoots out radiation. Radiation is invisible and dangerous and can hurt your body badly, like poison, just by being close to it. </p><p>Everything is made of tiny atoms and the radioactive atoms shoot off parts of themselves. Those parts hit other atoms that cause them to break. Your body is made of atoms too and even if only a little bit of them are broken you can get very sick because your body stops working right. </p><p>Most radioactive atoms are buried and spread out so far apart they aren’t dangerous to us. But when people dig them up and pile them up together they do become very dangerous. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/nexeo7l/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There are a few types and forms of radiation.</p><p>Alpha, Beta, and Neutrons are fast moving particles. XRays which are high energy photons and Gamma which is a <em>higher</em> energy photon. These are the main ones that people are referring to when we think of potentially harmful radiation.</p><p>Something is radioactive when it emits a form of radiation either via natural occurrences or via man made means.</p><p>The danger is that these particles are moving fast enough that they sometimes smash DNA when the collide with you. This can cause all kinds of health problems up to and including cancer.</p><p>As many radioactive substances are heavy metals which can take the form of a fine dust, breathing in heavy metal dust that emits DNA damaging particles is a really bad time.</p><p>Edit: high to higher based on comment response.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/nex9g84/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So, some types of atoms just don&#39;t want to exist. We call those atoms &quot;unstable&quot;.  As time goes by, those atoms break down into smaller atoms. This process happens randomly, so any time you have a sample of these atoms, some of them are breaking down all the time. </p><p>When atoms break apart in this way, they can shoot out either particles or energy at extremely high speeds.  This is what we call &quot;radiation&quot;. These individual particles are far too tiny to be seen, or even felt when they hit you (and the energy can&#39;t be seen with human eyes), but they can still do damage. Some of that damage is immediate and obvious, and some is more subtle. The most insidious part is that it can mess with your DNA, without actually killing the cells involved, which can cause everything from cancer to birth defects in the next generation. </p><p>The more unstable atoms you have, and the more unstable they are, the more radiation gets fired out in every direction, and the greater the odds that it will do serious damage. That&#39;s why the dosage of radiation is so important: the more you get the more you&#39;re damaged. At certain levels, your body is so damaged, on a cellular level, that it&#39;s unlikely you&#39;ll survive. </p><p>Now, radiation goes in straight lines, so standing right in front of the radioactive material is a major danger.  If there&#39;s enough shielding between you and the radioactive source, you&#39;re not in danger (there are different types of radiation, and some are either to block than others, but all of them can be blocked with enough shielding).  Where things can get really dangerous is if these unstable atoms get spread around, and become dust in the air. That dust can get breathed into your lungs or embedded in your skin. And if that happens, it continues to send out radiation until all of the unstable atoms have broken down.  If the radiation source is inside your body, you&#39;re going to be continually dosed with radiation, making things much more dangerous for you.  And the worst thing is that there&#39;s no way to neutralize radioactive material. It&#39;s going to keep radiating and radiating until it&#39;s all gone. That&#39;s what makes nuclear material so very tricky to deal with: you have to contain everything for a very long time before it&#39;s going to be safe.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/nexg6fj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Radioactive things are like turds except they shoot off radiation instead of being stinky. Just like smell isn&#39;t something we can see, radiation is also invisible to our eyes.</p><p>The longer the radioactive thing  / turd sits around, the more of the radioactivity / smell leaves. </p><p>Once they are old, they give off less of that stuff, because most of it already left. Eventually so much has left that its no longer quite the same thing as it was when it started, because that stuff left, leaving only non-radioactive / non-stinky stuff behind.</p><p>And by left I mean, gone away somewhere else, blown away by the wind.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/nexh1do/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s like it’s hot. You know how when you touch something hot it hurts, and sometimes burns you? Something that’s radioactive can be like that but it can also hurt you in ways you don’t feel right away, can even make you sick in ways that don’t show up until a long time from now. And it can take a really really long time for it to stop being dangerous in this way.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/nexaojz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Being radioactive means that some of the atoms in a thing are unstable and slowly falling apart. Each time one of these atoms breaks down, it radiates (emits, gives off) a bunch of energy and a tiny piece of itself. That energy is what makes radioactive material so dangerous. It&#39;s very good at going through things, and if it goes through you it can cause serious damage.</p><p>If you wait long enough, a radioactive thing will destroy itself. Unfortunately, &quot;long enough&quot; could be anywhere from minutes to billions of years depending on the exact element, and many radioactive elements decay into other things at are still unstable and radioactive. It can be a long chain of self destruction before it becomes something stable like lead.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkejku/eli5_what_does_it_mean_when_something_is/nexh9du/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 22:55:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/</link><title>ELI5: why do horses get shot once they have a broken leg? Or is this just a joke?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>There&#39;s no humane way to keep a horse&#39;s weight off a broken leg so it can heal. They can&#39;t lay down for that long without damaging their internal organs, and a sling or cast is a struggle when you can&#39;t explain to the animal what&#39;s going on.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0cud/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Horse&#39;s legs do not really recover from breaks.  Sadly, it&#39;s better to end their suffering.  A prize winning horse broke his leg and they supported him in a sling so they could still collect semen, but that&#39;s no life.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/newzszz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Typically horses are euthanized, not shot, but before humane euthanasia was common, shooting was the way too quickly and suffering of an animal. </p><p>Because of their anatomy, horses generally do not do well healing from a broken leg.  Horses are built to be on their feet the vast majority of the time, they only lay down for short periods for deep sleep.  It is damaging to their body to lay down for a long period of time.  Horses also carry 70% of their body weight on their front legs, so if you have one broken leg, the rest of that weight gets shifted to the other leg which it is not equipped to handle.  In the famous case of Barbaro, he had to be put down because he developed lameness in the supporting leg despite their attempts to save him. It is also extremely mentally damaging for a horse to be kept confined for long periods of time that it would take to heal a broken leg. They are a prey animal whose main defense is to run away and being unable to do so causes them extreme stress.  They also do not have any muscle below the knee, which means less blood supply and slower healing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0ngz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>ELI5: <a href="https://thunderdungeon.com/2025/06/15/fun">Horses are incredibly fragile creatures who exist despite God’s grace.</a> Horses are often put down after a broken leg for a number of reasons. The bigs are that</p><p>A) horse bones are comparatively light for such a heavy creature. Sometimes when a horse’s legs break it just <em>shatters</em> to the point that it can’t be set.</p><p>B) horses can’t support the weight on the other three legs while the horse recovers. The horse can develop laminitis, which damages the other three legs immensely, so now you have an even more injured horse. </p><p>C) horses can’t really lay down for long periods of time since they’re so heavy (they develop basically bed sores) so you can’t even put a horse to rest while the legs recover.</p><p>Essentially, horses are often euthanized because once a leg is broken you can’t guarantee them a quality of life.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex15l8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Horses depend on movement for all kinds of things like proper sleep, circulation, digestion, etc. if you try to immobilize a horse for a protracted period of time, all kinds of other health problems start happening, including life-threatening conditions.</p><p>You can&#39;t explain to a horse that it has to lie down and not move around for the next several weeks, so the only option is to tranquilize it, which incurs other risks.</p><p>It is possible to suspend a horse in a sling, and this has been done, mostly for stallions that the owners want to wring breeding fees from, but it&#39;s not always successful and it&#39;s hard to argue that it&#39;s humane.</p><p>TLDR: Horses are supposed to move around almost constantly and all kinds of things stop working when they don&#39;t.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0ucr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because horses aren&#39;t built to not be on their feet for long periods of time. While you can force them in a sling to holds them up off the ground that has other issues with it.</p><p>I&#39;m the end it&#39;s just easier on the horse to end it&#39;s life then make it suffer for the rest of it with a leg that isn&#39;t as well of as the other</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0f1f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I haven&#39;t seen this mentioned yet, so:</p><p>Horse legs are evolved from fingers. Like actually. Instead of developing longer arms, they got longer fingers to walk on. Their hoof is a fingernail. Or toenail. This is part of why they are so delicate compared to other animals.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex3wtm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 22:15:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/</link><title>Eli5:what exactly is the Bose-Einstein Condensate and does it count as a state of matter</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>God, how do you ELI5 the Bose-Einstein Condensate…</p><p>Okay, so at really small scales, there’s this weird property of matter where it kind of acts like it’s made of a bunch of particles and kind of acts like it’s made of a bunch of waves. We can see this in things like the double-slit experiment, where a singular electron can act like a particle passing through a hole in some instances or it can interfere with itself like a wave in others. </p><p>Well when you cool down certain matter (specifically bosons, named for Satyendra Bose, same as in the condensate), to REALLY cold temperatures like bordering on absolute zero, those wave-like patterns can start to collectively combine into basically acting like one really big wave, instead of a bunch of small waves. This is distinctly different than a solid, but it kind of acts more like a solid than usual. It’s its own unique thing that only really happens at very specific temperatures to very specific matter. </p><p>You’ll get different responses on whether it’s a state of matter based on who you ask. Depends how exactly we define “state of matter”, which is not perfectly defined yet. <del>Personally, I don’t consider it one, since most of the stuff we’re looking at for states of matter is made of protons/neutrons/electrons, which can’t make a B-E condensate. But you’ll find people who will happily call it a state of matter, too.</del></p><p>Hopefully I didn’t say anything egregiously wrong, it’s been like 8 years since I took physics courses and I supplemented with Wikipedia. Hopefully if I’m way off about anything, a more recent physicist can chime in.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/newrybf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So, sub-atomic particles are broadly sorted into two types; fermions and bosons. Bosons have whole-number quantum spin, and fermions have non-whole-number quantum spin (I won&#39;t go into what quantum spin <em>is</em> as it&#39;s a huge subject which isn&#39;t entirely germane to explaining BEC).</p><p>Fermions include most of the stuff we traditionally think of as &quot;matter&quot; - protos, neutrons, and electrons. Bosons include things we tradtionally think of as &quot;not matter&quot; - photos, gluons, the Higgs boson, and more.</p><p>But because the quantum spin of an atom is equal to the sum of the spins of its constituent parts, sometimes an atom can be a boson, despite being made out of fermions. Any atomic nucleus with an even number of protons &amp; neutrons will be a boson, since protons and neutrons both have a spin of 1/2.</p><p>Why is this important? Well, fermions and bosons obey very different laws of physics. Two identical fermions cannot occupy the same quantum state; you can&#39;t have more than one particle in the same place at the same time with the same amount of energy (this is an oversimplification of the Pauli exclusion principle).</p><p>Bosons do not obey this rule. Two bosons can occupy the same state at the same time. And when you cool bosons down a <em>lot</em> (which simply means removing energy from them), they essentially have no choice by to merge and occupy the same state, because they lack the energy to be in other states. Hence, they <strong>condense</strong> together into a <strong>Bose-Einstein condensate</strong>.</p><p>Things get weird when this happens. The particles cease to be observable as particles, and instead become better described as waveforms in space. And these waveforms increasingly overlap, and interfere with each other. This happens all the time at the extremely-tiny quantum scale (the double slit experiment is a demonstration of this happening with photons), but in a BEC it&#39;s on a larger scale which alters the physical properties of the substance on an observable, macro level. This is what qualifies it as a separate state of matter - it has distinct properties not found outside other conditions.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/newsdbv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Some materials, if you cool them <em>all the way down</em>, basically stop being solid and enter a super secret <em>double solid</em> sort of a state. The particles literally clip into each other like video game sprites, it&#39;s totally bizarre. Then just like a multiboxer in an MMO or something, they have strange properties based on all pretty much overlapping each other. </p><p>As to what these properties exactly <em>are</em>: imagine it like, the particles formed a union. They work together, they refuse to split up, they act like one big thing rather than a lot of little things. Some properties like viscosity or electrical resistance sometimes become <em>literally</em> zero depending on the exact kind of stuff that condensed. And if I recall correctly they do things like resist being heated up because they won&#39;t accept any energy unless everybody can have some.</p><p>As for whether it&#39;s a different <em>state of matter</em> - states of matter are just a model, that is, a simplified idea to help us understand the universe. A given particle doesn&#39;t exactly have a little dial on the side with solid/liquid/gas settings. At a certain point a BEC is just a BEC.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/newuiyi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The Bose-Einstein condensate is super cooled bosons.</p><p>Bosons are particles with integer spin. The fundamental particles are photons, gluons, the weak bosons and the Higgs. You can also produce larger, composite bosons as long as there are an even amount of half-spin particles. So Helium-4 or Carbon-12 are composite bosons.</p><p>They have to be integer spin because half spin particles follow the fermi-exclusion principle, where no two particles can occupy the same quantum state. In Bose-Einstein Condensate, the bosons all collapse down into the same low energy state, and this causes quantum effects to show macroscopically.</p><p>It is a new state of matter because you have new behaviour, not indicative of solids.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/newr27p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Quantum physicist here.<br/>A Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC) is a state, where particles behave in unison such that can be described with a single (wave-) function, in contrast to thermal atoms, which behave randomly.<br/>More precisely, this means that the particles in a BEC have a common phase. That means, if you split the BEC in half and recombine it, you will see interference fringes. </p><p>Usually, this state is achieved by cooling the matter to pretty low temperatures, but Einstein discovered this state by increasing the density of a gas. </p><p>It is **DEFINITELY** a state of matter, because it has very different properties than what we consider a gas, liquid or a solid. The mentioned appearance of fringes is such a property, but also super fluidity (no drag resistance) and formation of vortices when you stirr the BEC. </p><p>Let me know if you want to have more details</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkbwwk/eli5what_exactly_is_the_boseeinstein_condensate/nf1jkcg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:17:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/</link><title>ELI5: Why don't we feel our blood moving?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>You lack nerves to pick up the movement and there is minimal temperature variation. You can however sense the movement through your pulse.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/new7pkj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>To sense that, you need nerves. Most blood vessels have very few sensory nerves in them. Also, even if we did feel it, we would feel it constantly. It would likely be similar to tactile adaptation (where you become desensitized to a constant stimulus like the clothes you’re wearing so your brain can focus on more important things)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/new7su3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Your brain filters what you perceive a shit ton. If it&#39;s a constant your brain is probably cancelling it out </p><p>Seeing your nose. Gone.</p><p>Hearing your blood. Nope</p><p>The sound of your eyes moving. Not registered.</p><p>Be happy you don&#39;t as some poor people don&#39;t have this luxury and do hear their own blood, the movement of their eyes ect.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/new8v3c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Have you never felt your head pounding?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/new7741/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Get on a treadmill and switch it up to max, now run on the treadmill for 15 minutes (picturing you ex running after you might help , so would a lion, or your mom with sandal in her hand ).</p><p>After 15 mins get off and sit in a quiet corner, now while you are contemplating your life decisions you will hear and feel your blood flowing every which way.</p><p>Cheerio.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/new8msb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Brother I have insane anxiety, I can feel and hear my blood moving all. the. time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/new7bds/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We don’t usually feel our blood because our nerves are tuned to notice changes, not constant background stuff. If we felt it all the time, it would be overwhelming. That’s why it only stands out in certain situations, like when your heart’s pounding after exercise, during anxiety, when you receive a cut, or when you feel your pulse in your head/ears.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk9uea/eli5_why_dont_we_feel_our_blood_moving/new7u2q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:59:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/</link><title>ELI5 Is 20km/hr the top pace a human can run at distance?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Watching world athletics championship and was wondering..if marathon runners can run at approx 20km/hr for 2 hours why is pace for the 5000m only about 21-23 km hour (13-14 mins) ? Given the huge difference in distance I would expect that for the much shorter distance they could run faster than that. At what distance does human speed start to exponentially taper off? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>At about 400m.  Thats about the limit of anaerobic running.  </p><p>Below that your muscles can operate at an unsustainable level of oxygen consumption.  </p><p>Above that your lungs and blood need to be able to keep up with the oxygen consumption rate of your muscles.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevah1x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Two things.</p><p>First, a 5k is still mostly aerobic. Once you&#39;re past a couple of minutes, speed is capped by how much oxygen you can deliver and how efficiently you run, not by raw sprint power. Elites can hold roughly 80-85% of their max aerobic output for a marathon and about 95-100% for a 5k, so the 5k ends up only a bit faster. That&#39;s why world-best speeds are around 21km/h for the marathon and about 24km/h for 5000m, not double.</p><p>Second, championship 5ks are tactical. Packs jog-and-surge and then kick, so the average pace looks closer to marathon pace than a flat-out record attempt.</p><p>There isn&#39;t a single distance where speed suddenly falls off. Human speed follows a smooth power-duration curve. It drops quickly from sprints to the first minute or two, then eases down more gradually from 1500m through 10k to the marathon as you move deeper into purely aerobic territory.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevajuf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I know for Athletics training the furthest the sprinters ever ran was 600m. And even over 400m you will be ever so slightly slower in the second half of the race. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevayd6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s hard to put a hard cap on a biological benchmark but seeing as how world class athletes are meant to be the best functioning humans in their fields, those numbers can be safely considered as the closest to it.</p><p>Worth mentioning that our strength isn&#39;t that we can run fast (many animals can reach much higher speeds), it&#39;s that we can run continuously. Sweating is an absolutely broken mechanic that allowed us to maintain those relatively slow speeds for <em>hours</em>, which is uniquely a human thing because most animals can only sprint in short bursts.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevaxgm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Muscles need energy. This energy cam come in two main ways.</p><p>1) Breathing energy (aerobic), which is limited by the sugar your body can supply and your overall fitness.</p><p>2) Hold-your-breath energy (anaerobic), which can last for just about a minute and is limited by how strong your muscles, tendons and bones are.</p><p>So if the exercise is short enough for you to hold your breath the whole time, you can do a LOT more.</p><p>But even the best athletes can&#39;t break the laws of physics. Having 2 legs is great for running efficiently, but terrible for max speed. We&#39;re just not springy enough to get too much faster.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevz14w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>By that logic, at 30 meters they should be able to run at about 700km/h? Speed doesn’t really scale with distance - the limitations of muscle/bone/metabolism applies whatever the distance</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/neva8b3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The answers mentioning oxygen levels are all great but you also have to consider that human speed is biomechanically limited so far at about 45km/h (a bit less was peak speed for Usain Bolt when setting his 100m WR). </p><p>Oxygen levels explain how that scales down on other distances. At 200m in 19’’19  it’s about 41/42 km/h. At 400 is more like 37. At 800 30/31. You see how that goes down relatively quick. These are average speed rather than peak speeds but the longer the race the closer those are.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevdm7x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:51:56 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/</link><title>ELI5: why do athletes specifically eat bananas for quick fuel?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Why bananas and not oranges or a watermelon?</p><p>Or a chocolate chip cookie?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Bananas are full of potassium along with some other nutrients. They are quite nicely wrapped in a non messy container that does not need tools to open.<br/>I work as a medic for cycling events and anytime I stop for a rider with issues I hand them a banana and a bottle of water. Even if the issue is a chain problem, they still need the banana.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4m0u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As my college wrestling coach said</p><p>&#39;Bananas are the best pre-workout food. They taste the same going down as when they come back up. &quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nevblxy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Imagine trying to eat a banana compared to an orange or watermelon, from scratch.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4g3u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>banana:<br/>doesn&#39;t make a mess with all the juices like both your fruit options<br/>doesn&#39;t need a knife to eat/prepare like a watermelon<br/>doesn&#39;t take a long time to peel like an orange<br/>doesn&#39;t melt in the sun like the cookie</p><p>another snack in this same category would be an apple, but if you need to eat fast because your break is short, you would probably be faster with a banana.</p><p>I don&#39;t know much about the nutritional benefits of a banana, my arguments are all based on practicality.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev5baz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s a good mix of easily digestible energy (carbs) and potassium (electrolyte for muscle function) plus it&#39;s weiner shaped making them a little horny which can help athletes like me at least.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4o2w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Have you ever seen a monkey get a cramp? No?</p><p>Do you know why? Because they eat banana.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev5yvz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Bananas have both simple and complex carbohydrates which give you both the quick energy of simple sugars with longer lasting burn of starches.  Add in <del>Vitamins K,</del> potassium and the vitamins C and B6 and they&#39;re quite good for rejuvenating strained muscles as well.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4slm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:09:11 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/</link><title>ELI5: Why does rocking a baby soothe them?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Holding them tight and rocking them makes them nostalgic for the old days they spent in the womb.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/netm8a9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’m sure it is reminiscent of the womb as others have stated but it also activates your parasympathetic nervous system which is responsible for the “rest and digest” as opposed to the “flight or flight” sympathetic nervous system. It communicates that you are safe. There are no enemies nearby. You can rest. </p><p>When the parasympathetic nervous system is activated it slows the heart rate, stabilizes breathing, and reduces cortisol which is the “stress hormone”. </p><p>You can replicate this yourself by laying down on your back with your feet against a firm and stable surface (such as a headboard, a wall, the arm of a sturdy couch) and bounce your feet in a rhythm that feels comfortable. You should “bounce” strong enough to get movement all through your body and your head but in a gentle wave motion. If you breathe slowly and deeply while doing so for a few minutes you will feel that same sensation of calm and safety. </p><p>Also, a Thai style massage is wonderful at engaging the parasympathetic nervous system through compression, rocking, jostling, and stretching. It can be a great way to rebalance your default setting to a more relaxed state.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/netxucw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Artificial aids aside, the only way a baby can be rocked is by an attending adult doing so.  Evolutionarily, babies that demand adult attention are safer from prey.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/netudwm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>everything that soothes a baby on the outside is just recreating what they felt on the inside</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/netoa1k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While womb like conditions is partly true. There are a few other reasons. Infants can&#39;t self regulate. So, holding them close and rocking them consistently when they are disregulated provides predictability and comfort  that their bodies can sync with. Consistently doing this  allows them to internalize the external regulation, allowing them to become more self regulated. </p><p>Also, the rocking stimulates the inner ear, which has a calming effect on the brain that controls other regulatory systems like  heartbeat, breathing and muscle relaxation--I&#39;m an infant specialist</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/nevsz7c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>sometimes the simplest inputs, sway, warmth, touch unlock the deepest calm.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/neuap2w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because they get rocked by the parent moving and walking while they&#39;re in the womb</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njwz4q/eli5_why_does_rocking_a_baby_soothe_them/netmxpb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:19:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/</link><title>ELI5- Why do a lot of kids start out blonde and then become brunettes as they get older?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>This is pretty common but why?! </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Kids are often born with lighter hair because their bodies aren’t producing much melanin (the pigment that gives hair its colour) yet. As they grow, the genes that control melanin production kick in more strongly, so their hair gradually darkens. That’s why a lot of blond kids turn into brunettes as they get older, it’s basically genetics catching up</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/nesg5k4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They have the instructions to build the melanin molecule but they don’t actually start production until they are older. Then later in life they’ll stop producing melanin and their hair will go gray.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/neslnib/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Just a note, this happens with eye color as well. A lot of babies born with blue eyes end up with other colors once they age a bit. I can imagine a lot of brown-eyed, brunette couples out there freaking out a bit when they get a little Aryan surprise.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/nessyf8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And why does the reverse happen too, but rarer? Example: Pewdiepie’s son Björn came out with brown hair just for a bit, now blonde</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/net04f2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So just like your skin, your hair contains melanin.  You know the stuff that dictates your skin color.  </p><p>So when you&#39;re young, you produce less melanin.  When you get older, you produce more.</p><p>Your genes also dictate how much melanin you produce and when it changes.  </p><p>Environmental factors also play into this.  Sun exposure can cause an overproduction of melanin.  As well as exposure to hard water, chemicals and product buildup.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/neshkyy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>My son, as I expected from his genetics, was born with a thick head of black hair. It...lightened. He was a redhead briefly as a one year old and now he&#39;s a kindergartener with auburn hair. Very odd. Every other kid I know started light and darkened as they grew!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/netjn3q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I have some blonde streaks in my hair that never turned brown. They are now turning grey.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/netln33/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:13:28 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/</link><title>ELI5: How does my phone know where I am even without GPS turned on?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Sometimes my phone shows my location on apps like maps or weather, even when I’ve got GPS off. How’s it figuring out where I am? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Triangulating between 3 nearest cell towers if not on wifi.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqib5y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Your phone&#39;s data works by contacting nearby cell towers. By measuring the signal strength from nearby towers, it can place you at a certain distance from those towers. If there&#39;s three or more towers in range, then it can use triangulation to provide a rough estimate of your location.</p><p>If you&#39;re on wifi, then the IP address assigned to the wifi can give a rough estimate of your location; some networks have more-precisely identified wifi, like a store.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqihm7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It can use several network methods: Wi-Fi positioning, cell tower triangulation or Bluetooth beacons.</p><p>But without those it works it out using two things: your last GPS signal and internal hardware.</p><p>Most modern smartphones come equipped with two pieces of hardware: an accelerometer and a gyroscope. Using that, your phone knows which direction you&#39;re going (gyroscope) and the distance you&#39;ve travelled based on your acceleration (accelerometer).</p><p>Knowing that and your initial position, it will do the math and give you an approximate location.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqj203/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Cell towers and triangulation. WiFi and triangulation. I bet you could point the camera and it could work it out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqihog/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Assuming you can turn off the actual GPS chip, and not just toggle “Location Services” which should disable location for all or selected app…</p><p>Location services in phones use GPS, Bluetooth, WiFi, and cellular networks to triangulate your position.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqisrx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Phones that have their GPS on will find local WIFI networks and send the routers MAC address to the company (Apple, Google) to be added to a database. </p><p>Then when a phone without GPS enabled is near it can get the router’s MAC address and query the database to see where it is at.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqjirn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Your phone can take a good stab at where you are based on where it last knew you were and use things like the accelerometer to figure out where you have moved since then.  It can also use various network devices, which it knows the location of, to get an estimate of where you are.</p><p>From a network perspective, I used to work for a company that could locate any given phone provided it could talk to enough towers. Using the difference in time it took a signal to reach each given tower, you can draw some parabolas and they&#39;d all intersect at your position.  This is called UTDOA.  It was used primarily for E911 implementation for providers that didn&#39;t want to rely on the phone reporting its location.  It was <em>expensive</em> though, and last I knew, most companies had drop using the technology.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqj9rv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 22:32:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/</link><title>ELI5 Why did audio jack never change through the years when all other cables for consumer electronics changed a lot?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Bought new expensive headphones and it came with same cable as most basic stuff from 20 years ago</p><p>Meanwhile all other cables changes. Had vga and dvi and the 3 color a/v cables. Now it’s all hdmi. </p><p>Old mice and keyboards cables had special variants too that I don’t know the name of until changing to usb and then going through 3 variants of usb. </p><p>Charging went through similar stuff, with non standard every manufacturer different stuff until usb came along and then finally usb type c standardization. </p><p>Soundbars had a phase with optical cables before hdmi arc.</p><p>But for headphones, it’s been same cable for decades. Why?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It does not need to deliver power or data beyond a simple electrical wave.  So really no need to.  It was robust and had a low impedance (added by the connector) and had zero issues with crosstalk.  No need to reinvent the wheel unless it can’t move the new truck anymore basically.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1gmw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The only thing a headphone cable needs to transmit is an audio signal and what we got didn&#39;t need improving. </p><p>Video cables transmitted data differently or at high bitrates/ data rates, etc... Headphone jacks didn&#39;t need any of that. </p><p>Otherwise, there are many variants of headphone jacks. Though, most of them are for add-ons like an inline controller or microphone.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1k3t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It did change.</p><p>The first ones (which I believe were first used in telephone exchange facilities in the late 1800s) were 1/4” (6.35mm) jacks.</p><p>These are still often used in pro audio because they are stronger.</p><p>The 1/8” (3.5mm) jack was developed about a century later in the 1950s as devices got smaller and the big jacks were too big to fit.</p><p>They still persist because they do the job and most devices are still thicker than 1/8”.</p><p>Anything smaller (or just as another option) can use Bluetooth anyway. </p><p>You can deliver audio on anything, usb, wireless, jack, lighting cable.</p><p>Standards are just fashion basically, and the jack is an “old reliable” like blue jeans.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo49c7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>1) It&#39;s inexpensive.</p><p>2) most other connections are intended to be digital, whereas a headphone jack is typically analog, going to analog headphones. If the cable transmitted a digital signal, then the DAC would have to be in the headphones, making them heavier, more expensive, and needing power (which could be transmitted through the same data cable, but it&#39;s just not needed with the headphone jack.</p><p>3) It&#39;s ultra-low latency.</p><p>4) It&#39;s durable as heck.</p><p>5) A good percentage of people who buy expensive headphones want them to work with high-end gear, including vintage high-end gear. And they all used analog headphone jacks.</p><p>The things that you&#39;d gain by switching to other technologies wouldn&#39;t really benefit a headphone user.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1vzu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Brah, 20 years?</p><p>Musical instrument cables have not changed in almost 100 years. There has basically only been one design.</p><p>Why? Because it just has to work, and musicians don&#39;t want to fuck around with a new cable every 5 years. </p><p>It&#39;s pretty awesome. They pretty much perfected the electric guitar seventy years ago, and you can still take one from 1955 and plug it into a new amp or whatever.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo7vmq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The jack now includes the microphone which used to require a separate plug. So while the jack looks the same it isn&#39;t. Also, audio is now available through Bluetooth, Wifi or USB cable, so the technology has not stood still.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1ntg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It did change but not on most consumer grade headphones. There&#39;s XLR, Pentaconn, 5 pin din, 6.35mm, 3.5mm and others. The difference in headphone cables and your examples is that those are digital connections being used for digital audio transfer, headphones are analogue. </p><p>If you look at a pair of headphones that can use a cable for digital audio you&#39;ll find they changed over the years too. Micro USB, USB C, Lightning, etc. </p><p>Perhaps a useful comparison is looking at a wall outlet or cigarette lighter plug in a car. They&#39;ve largely been unchanged in decades.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo38o2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:01:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/</link><title>ELI5 How do they remove Metal particles from water/drinking water?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>For example:</p><p>People tend to sharpen their Knife/Knives then wipe it down and rinse it off.</p><p>Or rinse it off then wipe it down... How does the city remove all of these particles that are going down the drain</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>several things, first, its very uncommon for a city to re-process sewage as drinking water.  (it does happen, but rarely), so knife sharpening shavings arent really going into the drinking supply</p><p>Now there are metals in water when collected, so there is that issue.  But for MOST metals, there is not a max safe level, you can just eat them if you want (but dont, just because something isnt toxic doesnt mean its a good idea to eat).  Very few metals dissolve much in water, and they are heavier than water, so normally you can just filter or settle them out.</p><p>So mostly, they dont bother, not as much as you seem to be thinking they would.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/nenyq21/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Water_treatment">water treatment</a> plants </p><p>Generally speaking, we aren’t just pulling water out of rivers, lakes, or the ground, we’re running it through multiple filters to catch particulate matter, cleaning out the bacteria, and adding beneficial chemicals like fluoride, before it gets sent out to people’s homes.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/nenydf8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The obvious answer is magnets, but that&#39;s not going to capture everything, by any means.</p><p>Typically local water treatment goes through a bunch of steps such as coagulation (actually adding things like salt or iron or other things to the water to bind contaminants together), flocculation (with more additives) to clump the loose particulates together into larger blobs, sedimentation to separate out the heavier blobs, filtration which can remove very, very small particles including bacteria and such, and lastly disinfection to kill anything harmful in the water.</p><p>It&#39;s quite an involved process.</p><p>I had to look up the etymology of &quot;flocculation&quot;... Latin every time. A <em>floccus</em> is a tuft of wool, so I imagine the gathering of that is where we get the word and makes some sense in the context of cleaning water.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/nenzagr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Waste water in treatment plants goes into settling tanks and heavy stuff falls to the bottom.</p><p>A look at the process for making water safe for human consumption. the filtering and chemical processes used, including activated carbon and chlorine and at what stages the various dangerous substances in water are removed. <a href="https://youtu.be/8vmebqvdEL4">https://youtu.be/8vmebqvdEL4</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/neo59qu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You could do it two ways, if the metal is magnetic you could use a magnet. If not, you could do it in the way you do with another suspended things, let them sink (they are heavier than water)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/nenyedo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They will settle out as soon as they reach somewhere water isn&#39;t moving very fast, same with any other solid waste that&#39;s denser than water. </p><p>It&#39;s also not a huge problem if you eat or drink a tiny particle of iron, even if it didn&#39;t get removed.  What do you think happens to all the bits of metal that used to be the sharp edge of the knife, as it gets dull over time? The concentration of metal particles from that that you ingest is way higher than whatever goes down your drain, diluted over the whole water supply by the time it gets to the next town.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/neo73c4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There&#39;s a great episode where someone liquidates Cheerios cereal and shows how the iron supplement is added.  It&#39;s iron bits, magnetic and all 🧲.  Same with knife shavings, no problem, eat away.  Lead is more problematic!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj66me/eli5_how_do_they_remove_metal_particles_from/neo821g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 12:31:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/</link><title>ELI5: how does Ozempic (or other weight loss jabs) work?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Is it that they just suppress appetite? Or do they help in another way to lose weight? </p><p>Say someone who is not on ozempic (A) makes sure to eat the exact same amount as someone who is taking it (B), would it achieve the same results had A been taking the jab? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>A lot of good answers so far but a lot of people are ignoring your specific question about comparing two people with the same caloric intake.</p><p>From what I’ve researched and understand, more or less they’d look the same if they at the same thing with one person using ozempic to curb the appetite.</p><p>It’s just that for someone who’s used to eating a lot more, having to eat that low caloric intake is suddenly is unbearable. Like constant anger, pain in the stomach levels of hunger. It takes so much willpower to go from eating 3000+ calories a day to &lt;1200 calories a day.</p><p>Ozempic makes it almost effortless. You can eat a third of your normal helpings each meal and just be totally fine all day. The reporting of ozempic face and stuff is because the person drops weight so fast that you notice it more versus dropping that weight over the course of a year. If someone lost weight from caloric restriction from sheer willpower, they’d get that drastic face change too, but they’re gonna be in agony while doing it because it’s such major diet change.</p><p>Same with the muscle mass loss. You get the same muscle mass loss from caloric restriction. However, it could be pointed out that if the weight was lost more slowly, you could exercise and keep the muscle mass from losing by building it up faster than you lose it from losing weight.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/nendbp3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It doesn&#39;t significantly affect metabolism. </p><p>So if you took two similar people like a pair of identical twins, they have the exact same food intake, but one is taking ozempic and the other is not - they would have the same outcomes. </p><p>Ozempic (and similar drugs) effectively suppresses hunger. People taking them in appropriate doses still feel hunger, but it is satisfied with relatively small quantities of food, and they do not get hungry again for longer periods of time. </p><p>People say it turns off &quot;food noise&quot; - that little voice in your head that encourages you to eat when you&#39;re not really hungry. </p><p>My partner is taking Mounjaro, a drug similar to Ozempic. She still eats normal meals, but towards the end of a meal she starts feeling a little nauseous, which maker her want to stop eating. It also makes her much less prone to cravings and snacking. Within a couple of days of her first dose, the difference was obvious.</p><p>She has previously struggled with extreme cravings and a compulsion to binge-eat. Now she doesn&#39;t really think about food until our regular meal times, and isn&#39;t really interested in snacking between meals.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neoeole/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Pretty much, they mimic a hormone (GLP-1) that helps regulate appetite and slows digestion. So yeah, part of it is feeling full sooner, but there’s also an effect on blood sugar and insulin that helps with weight loss. If two people ate the exact same calories, the one on Ozempic might still have an edge because of how their body processes food differently. ucofo. com has a plain breakdown of how GLP-1s work if you want a quick read.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neoqxnm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I see you&#39;re in the UK. Ozempic is not licensed for weight loss in the UK and is a T2DM medication. If interested, consider wegovy (cheaper) or mounjaro (more effective).</p><p>Source: Weight management specialist dietitian</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neoke38/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>More than suppressing hunger, ozempic has done wonders fo my blood sugar.  I never thought I&#39;d see the day when my blood sugar hit below 100 mg/dl</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neox45r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So, I have a food addiction. My A1C was high, so my doctor prescribed me Ozempic along with my Metformin to get it down. Being a food addict, I normally never get hungry because (surprise) I&#39;m usually eating a lot. While Ozempic hasn&#39;t totally killed the desire to eat, it has made me feel full faster. I think it&#39;s doing it&#39;s job. lol. </p><p>Not a medical person by any stretch of the imagination, just giving my input as someone who uses it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/nen9kn6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>GLP1’s help with insulin resistance and lower blood sugar levels in diabetics.  Insulin resistance is associated with PCOS and other hormone issues like gestational diabetes or liver issues </p><p>If a person with insulin resistance ate the same reduced calories as some with no insulin resistance they would lose less weight</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neorz9x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:02:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/</link><title>ELI5: How do artists who make money off fanart not get sued/taken down?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’ve heard that for example, attempting to make money via writing fanfiction of existing characters is dangerous as you can be hit by copyright laws.</p><p>However, there are lots of digital artists with a strong online presence who draw fanart/fan animations, put them behind a paywall etc. but they have been going on strong for a long while. Some of these artists+animators are popular and make a LOT of money. </p><p>So how come these artists are not being taken down for making money via existing content/characters?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The short answer is they are too small to be worth suing.</p><p>Disney for example is unlikely to go after an artist that sells a couple Mickey theme prints at a convention, but you have to be careful regardless.</p><p>They often check art sites and issue take downs. If you attract to much attention or show up on a casual check you might end up with an &#39;angry lawyer letter&#39; aka a cease and desist.</p><p>Basically you have to be doing it on a small enough scale to not get noticed.</p><p>There&#39;s also a degree of fair use, parody work, etc that can protect you, but you still have to be careful because the big corps will threaten you regardless.</p><p>Put a version of Mickey in your webcomic once as a joke it will probably be fine. Put it on a T-shirt and you&#39;ll get sued.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/nemx6l5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;ve heard several commission artists refer to it as a &quot;gentlemen&#39;s agreement.&quot; Publishers turn a blind eye to their artists profiting off of commissions because they want to preserve a good working relationship with the talent. In return, the artists behave themselves by not talking smack about the publishers, not disparaging the characters, and, most important of all, not attempting to publish collected volumes of their commissions.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/nemx09c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Some IP holders expressly allow it, or offer $0 licenses.</p><p>Matt Dinniman, author of the series Dungeon Crawler Carl, is this way.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/nen0k0j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Suing people costs money and generates negative publicity. There&#39;s also a risk for some family friendly companies that a lawsuit will draw a lot of attention to adult content news companies will lavaciously show that would better stay in shadow. So, most companies don&#39;t bother to enforce things as stringently as the law allows.</p><p>Some agents, such as Nintendo, Anne McCaffery, and the band Metallica are notable more litigious than average and tend to sue anyone they can.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/nemwkov/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Fan artists can be and have been sued/taken down many times before.</p><p>But they will have to be big enough and/or making something that the company feels like directly affecting their profits.</p><p>While fan art is a lucrative industry, most fan artists are freelancing individuals, the company can&#39;t spend resources going after all of them, especially when each making meager money in the grand scheme of things.</p><p>Fan arts also benefit companies, they gain good publicity and free marketing from the community in a field almost all of them will not engage in. The financial loss, if there&#39;s any, is negligible.</p><p>That&#39;s why Japan has a giant con dedicated to fan artists.</p><p>It&#39;s more like a &quot;Don&#39;t cross the line and we&#39;re cool&quot; kind of thing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/nenqlmz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The difference between technically illegal and illegal in practice is enforcement. If you break a law and no one comes after you for it, well, you’re basically free to keep doing it.</p><p>For fanart, lots of publishers see it as either not worth pursuing, or actually in their best interest to maintain good relationships with the fanart community. Not only is it free advertising and community goodwill, some will literally go to conventions and offer good fanartists jobs. Of course, some companies disagree, and <em>will</em> go after you for minor infringements.</p><p>For both fanart and fanfiction, it depends a lot on scale. Doing individual commissions and selling a few prints at a con is one thing. Doing large scale unlicensed merch runs is more likely to draw attention.</p><p>With fanfiction, there’s not as much you can do in the “small scale” range. If you’re publishing a book, you’re publishing a book. Even if it’s an ebook, it’s still on the marketplace for anyone to buy, and potentially competing with the original work. The fanfiction equivalent of “commissions or prints at a con” is… I mean I’m sure there’s some equivalent stuff you could do, but it’s not as common or large a space. Though I’m pretty sure I’ve heard of some fanfiction writers getting commissions to write a story about such and such, and I’m pretty sure those mostly fly under the radar, same as fanart commissions.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/nen4bgq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In reference to fan art versus fanfic, I&#39;ve heard it explained this way: if someone sees a cool piece of fan art, they&#39;re likely to seek the original media to consume (book, game, etc) and are more likely to pay for it.</p><p>If they read a cool fanfiction, which may have more depth/content than the max twenty seconds spent looking at an image, say, spending half an hour or more reading it, they might feel satiated and not bother looking for the original media. The fanfiction was plenty, thanks, plus it was free.</p><p>Fanart = more likely to draw in new business. Fanfiction = more likely to siphon away business</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj0rio/eli5_how_do_artists_who_make_money_off_fanart_not/nen205g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 07:37:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/</link><title>ELI5: How did people clip their fingernails 1000 years ago?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Did they just chew them off every time?</p><p>Did pretty much every man have a beard at all times? When did it become normal to shave your face down to the skin?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>1000 years ago? There were plenty of advanced societies with steel and iron tools. You can shave just fine with a sharp knife though it&#39;s trickier, hence barbers existing as well as specialized blades. In fact clean shaven faces were popular throughout history, greeks and romans shaved during different periods. But other cultures may have not. It became a military need during ww1 due to gas masks not sealing properly but otherwise it&#39;s been about fashion not lack of tools</p><p>As for fingernails, same thing. Manicures for higher classes have been a thing for a good 5000 years. You can make decent small shears or specialty tools out of hard stones and bronze. Not as convenient or fast as nail clippers, but they didn&#39;t have much going on.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemo69z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Chimpanzees and other primates also have fingernails. They typically trim their fingernails by biting them off when they get too long or damaged, a behavior that can be a natural part of their grooming routine. Their active daily lives, which involve climbing and digging, also contribute to natural nail wear and tear that keeps them short. </p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1mylf6/how_do_chimps_take_care_of_their_nails/">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1mylf6/how_do_chimps_take_care_of_their_nails/</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemtxjq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>we have had steel/iron blades for 3000 years, bronze blades for 4700 years, and flint blades for <del>5500</del> 3.3 Million years.  </p><p>1000 years they just used a knife (or a kinda sheer shaped scissor (or even a special nail clipper like thing, good history section on the wikipedia <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nail_clipper">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nail_clipper</a> ))  and razor.</p><p>Shaving has been common for centuries, the ancient Egyptians would use shaving to separate classes as you would need money and time to get a good shave.</p><p>Now before that, say 10,000 years ago, yah long hair and beards.  as for fingernails, if you actually do hard work every day they are mostly self maintaining, and you can just chew them as you noted.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemodin/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>1000 years ago was medieval times. Humans had small scissors and tools which they used to trim nails, but also many people bit/chewed them as well.</p><p>If you’re wondering about pre-tool eras of human society, it was a combo of biting/chewing, wear and tear and occasionally scraping on rocks and rough surfaces - similar to what apes do today.</p><p>As for being fully shaven, that depends on the civilization and their cultural norms - but Ancient Egyptians have been shaving since almost 3000 BC.</p><p>In Ancient Rome it became fashionable to shave during the times of Christ - around 0 AD - (you often see ancient Roman statues depicting young men with clean shaven faces).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nempq1q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The first spring scissors were found in ancient Egypt 4000 years ago. The first two bladed pivot style scissors were a Roman invention around 100AD. </p><p>so how did people cut hair and nails 1000 or even 2000 years ago? Pretty much the same way we do. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nenh1qn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’m the only person I know that does this, but I peel my fingernails off</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/neou6gu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You don’t have to clip your nails, you can file them down with a rock. Trimming a beard can be accomplished with a sharp rock. You’re not going to shave yourself down to the skin with a rock, but you can definitely trim your beard.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemoatr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 06:44:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/</link><title>ELI5 Why do humans live so much longer than other mammals?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Mammals under our care typically live longer than their wild counterparts parts too. </p><p>The wild isn’t easy. Animals eat anything mildly palatable good or bad for them because they need calories for survival. </p><p>Humans are smart. We constantly learn more about what is good or bad for our health, develop healthcare and ways to treat ailments, etc. </p><p>If another species gained our level of intelligence and development we would also most likely see their lifespans significantly increase in a similar way. Being smart lets us optimize our bodies</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/neldo1k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A cat can reproduce when it&#39;s 4 months old. Animals generally live at a minimum long enough until they can have grandchildren (so the species can survive). That takes 30 years or so for humans.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nelg19o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>because we grow slowly, have big brains that help us solve problems, protect ourselves from predators, and invent medicine and technology. We also live in groups and take care of each other, which makes it easier to survive into old age.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/neld3ck/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because when we get old and slow, we sit down and play bingo while a nursing home takes care of us.</p><p>When animals get old and slow, they get eaten</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nelf3fn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We don’t. </p><p>Relatively speaking. Other great apes have similar lifespans. Comparing us to rodents or ungulates or whatever else is apples to oranges.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nem4psc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The big ones are modern medicine, vaccines, antibiotics and people who are wiling to feed you while you are healing. In the modern era: over 99% of people born in an advanced economy make it to puberty. For the entire world 95% born make it to puberty.</p><p>For comparison purposes:</p><p>Before modern medicine, the fatality rate for children was ruthlessly high: 1/3 of all live birth children died by age one. And 50% were dead by age 10. Less than half made it to puberty. And by age 40 only a third of each generation was still alive. </p><p>Brett Devereuax (a roman historian with a very good blog) has been working on a series about how peasants lived before the modern era. I am linking to his section on death. It is worth the read and expands on the comments I made above.</p><p><a href="https://acoup.blog/2025/07/18/collections-life-work-death-and-the-peasant-part-ii-starting-at-the-end/">https://acoup.blog/2025/07/18/collections-life-work-death-and-the-peasant-part-ii-starting-at-the-end/</a></p><p>I am only linking to one part of the series, but please take the time to read the rest of it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nen6as4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn&#39;t the speed of metabolism some how dictates how long we can live?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nelvgc7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 02:25:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/</link><title>ELI5: Why do phones and EVs say to keep the battery around 20-80%? What's physically happening at the extremes that wears batteries faster?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I often see tips to avoid 0% and 100% on lithium batteries to make them last longer. Can you explain, in simple terms, what’s going on inside the battery near empty and near full that makes those levels rough on it?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Take a deep breath. Super deep, keep trying to breath in more and you can even take a teeny tiny breath on top of your big one, but it’s really hard to do.<br/>That’s why charging over 80% is bad, it takes a lot more effort to cram in those last electrons into the battery because it’s so full, and that causes more wear on the battery.</p><p>Now let’s slowly exhale that breath. Keep breathing out steadily. Once you run out of air keep trying to blow. That last bit of air is really hard to push out.<br/>That is why discharging below 20% is bad, it takes a lot more effort to squeeze out those last electrons from the battery because there are so few, and that causes more wear on the battery.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejriyt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>may I ask: is this still valid. with today&#39;s technology?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nek2jzc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While I understand the concept,</p><p>Why can’t manufacturers just claim a 3000mah battery is only 2,400mah (80% of 3000mah). With a software limitation of only charging up to 2,400mah and representing that as the ‘100%’ and also presenting 600mah (20% of 3000mah) as the battery being at ‘0%’ ?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejtnzb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Why don’t they just change the percentage of the battery to keep them where they need to be?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejvkd5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Above 80%, further charging probably causes a small amount of electrolyte breakdown, and the products start forming a film on one of the terminals.  The effect is more pronounced when hot, so charging above 80% while hot is probably the worst thing to reduce battery life. </p><p>Below 20% is not inherently damaging, but batteries self discharge over time even if unused.  If it gets too low, your typical smart chargers may not see enough voltage on the battery to recognize it and start charging it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejsrav/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Think of a Li-ion battery cell like a ballon. If it gets too full, it can pop. If it gets too empty, it can stick together and make it hard to fill up again. Also, the process of going from 0% to 100% and back down to 0% puts a lot of stress on the cell, meaning it can&#39;t hold as much in future.</p><p>If you stick between 20% and 80%, it puts less stress on the battery so it can retain the max charge capacity for longer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejqna3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Every time you sit on a chair or stand up - it rubs the fabric on the chair and &#39;wears&#39; it out a bit.</p><p>Charging a battery causes electrons to &#39;attach&#39; themselves to plates.</p><p>Using a battery causes the electrons to &#39;detach&#39; themselves to plates.</p><p>This causes wear or &#39;degradation&#39; of the plates in the battery.  Very similar to people sitting up/down/up/down on chairs in say an airplane.</p><p>With me so far?</p><p>A &#39;high state of charge&#39; battery has electrons over most of the surface.  Like magnets - these electrons repel each other and as temp changes or just sitting there - the charged electrons &#39;get up&#39; and move to some less dense place.</p><p>A &#39;low state of charge&#39; battery also has electrons that decide to get up and move around.</p><p>A battery with a 50% charge tends to have less spontaneous movement of electrons. This results in less wear just sitting there.</p><p>Hope this helps.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejsvcm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:43:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/</link><title>ELI5: Why do athletes from different track  field events all run in a specific way, unique to their discipline?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Watching the Athletics world championships and noticed you can identify which discipline the athlete is competing in solely based on their running technique. For example, a high jump run-up starts with some long jumpy steps and then transitions into some normal ones... And a long jump run up has very pronounced high knees &amp; arms? Almost all of the unique disciplines have their own styles that all the athletes seem to use.</p><p>Is there a performance related reason for this? Or did one world-beater just do it once and everyone copied?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s performance-related. Every jumping discipline requires your body to be in a particular position when you make the leap, so you run with the twin goals of 1) being at the right speed at the right time, and 2) having your body be in the right position at the right time. </p><p>For example, for a long jump, you basically want to be going as fast as possible, except that you have to be able to leep slightly upward. A sprinter can lean forward toward the end and thus go slightly faster, but as the jumper, you have to get your center of gravity a little more under you. Thus, you run differently so you don&#39;t lean too far and are unable to get the elevation that allows you to translate speed into distance.</p><p>For high jumps, you aren&#39;t direclty translating speed into height, so you run to get the right level of momentum while maintaining your body lean such that you can maximize your vertical power and jump as high as possible. If you ran too fast, you&#39;d end up out of position and be able to jump lower (but probably farther). </p><p>Etc for each sport.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/neic52o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It has been learned over time that is the most effective way to do it.  When I was in middle school we were doing few Olympic events in P.E. and one of them was the standing broad jump.  I had just watched that event a couple of days before and copied what the athletes were doing.  It looked goofy and people were laughing, until I jumped and was about a foot farther than everyone else.  </p><p>I was not the most athletic person in the class but by imitating the moves of the athletes I was able to jump much further than I otherwise would.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/neiipgq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Of course it&#39;s performance related. They have experimented with all the techniques and optimised to current knowledge. If you didn&#39;t optimise, then you didn&#39;t qualify.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/neiim78/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I went to a running camp and they taught this very studied, mechanically sound technique. </p><p>When I incorporated it into playing basketball with my friends, they teased me and called me “T-1000” so I stopped. Shame, it was effective.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/nek7hqa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Retired professional track athlete here. It&#39;s about optimization for speed/power in certain events (sprints) and efficiency in others (distance events). The middle distance athletes are the universally recognized freaks as they can generally over distance and under distance respectably well too.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/nejrj9o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There is the occasional athlete who visibly moves differently and wins, eg Usain Bolt &amp; Michael Johnson</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/nekfsoj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because the best way to be successful in their discipline is to run “unique to their discipline”. </p><p>Not being cheeky, but you answer your own question here. At least in an ELI5 sense</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nif6wn/eli5_why_do_athletes_from_different_track_field/nerixdn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 17:17:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/</link><title>ELI5: Why does it take forever for hot water to reach the shower?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Every morning I turn on the shower and wait like two minutes before the water is hot. It’s the same with the sink. Honestly, those two minutes aren’t the worst though I usually just check my phone or play some slots on grizzly’s quest while I’m waiting. Where is the water “waiting” in those two minutes? Why can’t it just be hot right away?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The water in the hot water heater is hot.  The water in the pipes in between the hot water heater and your shower has cooled down since the last time you used it.  It takes time for the hot water to push all that cold water out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7kzv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You can add a circulation pump to your hot water line to so the hot water slowly circulates through the house and back into the water heater so the hot water gets to the faucet quicker.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/neiasth/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you have a mixer style tap, try setting the mix to 100% hot until the water gets hot otherwise you aren&#39;t allowing the existing cold water in the hot pipe to clear at full flow rate. You are also just wasting the water from the cold pipe while you wait for the hot to come through.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei8npc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How far away is your shower from the water heater and do you have a tank or tankless system ? </p><p>If you have a tank the hot water is literally waiting there until you turn on a hot water source.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7jr2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Depends on your plumbing setup. In many homes there&#39;s a hot water tank. That&#39;s where the water is waiting. There are pipes between the tank and your fixtures. Water cools off it out sits in the pipes. If those pipes are long and/or large diameter, you have to clear out a whole bunch of cold water from the pipes until the hot can get to you.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7pqf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You know when you drink Coke with a straw, it takes a moment of sucking before it reaches your mouth? The longer the straw, the longer it takes.</p><p>Getting hot water in the shower is similar: long pipe, long wait. And if the system needs time to heat (depends on heating setup), the first water coming through won’t be warm anyway.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nejlnd6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How far away from your water heater is your shower? The water has to travel that distance… on a low flow shower head, it can take a while to use up the cold water sitting in the pipes.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7oqk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:47:53 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/</link><title>ELI5: why does creamer have such a long expiration date vs regular milk?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Similar ingredients (milk, cream, sugar vs just milk) but a much longer life. My current creamer has a “use by” date of Feb 26, while my regular milk is usually 2-3 weeks.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It will be <del>Ultra Heat Treated</del> Ultra High Temperature (UHT) which gives milk (or in this case &#39;creamer&#39;) a much longer shelf life. From personal experience it does this at the cost of taste, but considering creamer has already been doctored with sugar and is solely designed to go into hot drinks such as coffee, it&#39;s likely less noticeable, plus it&#39;s worth it for the increased shelf life, ease of storage and shipping.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/nei94p8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s the fat content - you can actually see the numbers jump from 2,% to whole to half and half to heavy cream (though the speed wr which the heavy cream sells makes that harder to realize)</p><p>This is also why butter can be left mostly room temperature and folks store bacon grease next to their stove.   Most bacteria need water.  Fat displaces water, so the more fat there is, the less bacteria can grow.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/neio6je/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Almost all liquid creamers use oil instead of milk/heavy cream</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/neki195/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Most coffee creamer like international delight are oil based, not dairy</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/nej2zf9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thought it was the density of the protein.  Why different meat needs to be cooked to certain temperatures.</p><p>Been wrong before.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/neiormv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because no one in their right mind would use creamer (for coffee) - so it has to sit on the shelf longer 😉</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/nej63au/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Also organic whole milk lasts way longer than regular whole milk.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nielgw/eli5_why_does_creamer_have_such_a_long_expiration/nej9m8u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:46:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/</link><title>ELI5: Why do forces like gravity or electromagnetism only propagate at the speed of light?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>do not think of it as &quot;<em>the speed of light</em>&quot;, but &quot;<em>the speed at which A makes B happen</em>&quot;, or &quot;<em>the speed of causality</em>&quot;. It&#39;s a hardcoded value of our universe and nothing goes faster.</p><p>Light happens to go very fast, so we say &quot;<em>speed of light</em>&quot;, but it&#39;s as if we called 80kmh/50mph the &quot;<em>speed of bus</em>&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/nehhb91/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is being asked a lot right now for some reason. </p><p>First let&#39;s start by calling it speed of causality. It&#39;s a better name, esp because we&#39;re no longer talking about just light. </p><p>My favorite explanation is: the speed of causality is the default speed of any event in the universe. As you add mass to a thing, it slows down. That&#39;s it, that&#39;s the rule. </p><p>So light/gravity travel at the speed of causality because they have no mass. That&#39;s how fast things with no mass travel. It&#39;s just a universal speed setting.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/nei2ohb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because no information can travel through spacetime faster than the ultimate speed limit, <em>c</em>. That includes gravitational and electromagnetic information, especially since light <em>is</em> an electromagnetic wave, just one we can detect with our eyes.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/nehgxmq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah, the speed of light or speed of causality, as it includes more than just light, is the default speed for propagation of massless particles/waves and gravity, whatever the latter is caused by.</p><p>The speed of causality appears so random to us because it is this odd, seemingly very specific number, and we and everything else with mass are so much slower than it. However, we are the outliers, the speed of causality is the true constant of the universe. We, with mass, just exchange speed of causality for speed of time.</p><p>And it is that odd number because we invented kilometers and miles as a measure of distance humans can process. Its just odd from our point of view.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/nehhqgb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There are 2 types of &quot;objects&quot; in the universe. Objects with mass, and objects without mass.For objects with mass, they resist acceleration more and more as they speed up. To get to the speed of light they need infinite energy. </p><p>For objects without mass  they HAVE to travel at the speed of light. </p><p>Why specifically that speed? It&#39;s more complex but the number comes out of Maxwell&#39;s equation that relate space and time. It seems like a specific number but it is essentially arbitrary- for every number it would be we will ask &quot;why that specific figure&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/nehitew/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The laws of physics must be the same for everyone no matter how fast they are moving relative to someone else. For that to be true, there must be a speed limit to how fast things travel.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/nehpg0p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Light <em>just so happens to be</em> one of the myriad things that travel at that speed because photons have zero weight, but the speed of light is just &quot;the universe&#39;s top speed&quot; and we called it that because the first time we measured it was using light.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niagkm/eli5_why_do_forces_like_gravity_or/nei0q1b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 12:28:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/</link><title>ELI5 How does light always travel at a constant speed?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>How does light travel at a constant speed? Isn’t speed relative to the observer always? How can I understand this fact without breaking everything I understand about speed intuitively? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Isn’t speed relative to the observer always?</p></blockquote><p>Nope! Surprisingly. Light travels at the speed of light, relative to all observers, even those that are moving relative to each other. This results in unintuitive effects, like if you are on a speeding train and shine a flashlight forwards, the light form the flashlight isn&#39;t accelerated by the train like any other object would be. An observer not on the train just sees it moving at the same speed you do, the speed of light. </p><blockquote><p>How can I understand this fact without breaking everything I understand about speed intuitively? </p></blockquote><p>That&#39;s the fun part, you don&#39;t. It was the troublesome nature of the speed of light which prompted the development of special relativity, revolutionizing physics and leading to many more surprising and unintuitive conclusions. </p><p>I think one way to think about it, though, is to realize that while we call the speed of light that name, it isn&#39;t just the speed of light. Gravitational waves, for example, also propagate at the speed of light. It is more that the speed of light is simply the speed of causality in our universe: it is the fastest that phenomena are allowed to propagate through reality at. Light has no mass, so it is allowed to go as fast as is possible. Things with mass are prevented from moving as fast as possible. This is also why the speed of light shows up in equations like E=mc<sup>2</sup> - it isn&#39;t that the relationship between mass and energy in our universe is governed by the speed of light, but that the number &#39;c&#39; is a fundamental property of the relationship between mass and energy in our universe, and as a result it is the speed which light can move at in a vacuum, among other important things</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/neh84bb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I love how you stated this question:</p><blockquote><p>How can I understand this fact without breaking everything I understand about speed intuitively? </p></blockquote><p>You cannot because you have to do exactly that.</p><p>That&#39;s the whole idea about both of Einstein&#39;s Relativities. There&#39;s nothing that&#39;s <em>meant to be</em> intuitive about it, but it is how the world works.</p><p>There is a maximum immutable speed called c (or speed of light), and all massless particles (which light is) travel exclusively at that speed, no slower no faster.</p><p>It actually gets a bit simpler to imagine when you realise that the world isn&#39;t 3D with time, it&#39;s 4D space-time.</p><p>In that 4D space there is only one speed. The speed of light c. Everything travels through the 4D space-time at that speed and that speed only. There is no other speed than The Speed.</p><p>The difference is how much of The Speed is in the direction of space, and how much is in the direction of time.</p><p>Light, and other massless particles, have 0 (zero) speed through time. They do not perceive time. All their speed is through space. All of the The Speed.</p><p>Anything with mass is forced to travel in the direction of time at least a bit. The more speed you dedicate to space, the less is left for time, but it is never 0. The slower you move through space, the faster you koce through time.</p><p>That&#39;s the source of all the time and space bending in Relativities.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/nehk72c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You cannot understand it without breaking everything you understand about speed intuitively. It&#39;s the very fact it is unintuitive, breaks everyday reality, and not at all what you would expect that makes it fascinating.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/nehlayh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How I see it, it&#39;s perhaps more intuitive the other way: everything is energy, and energy traveling at the speed of light is the natural state of everything in the universe. </p><p>So everything always moves, and everything moves at the speed of light. Except for stuff that has a property called mass. Saying like this is a bit misleading. Mass can be thought as a specific configuration of energy, very tightly packed together so that there&#39;s a lot of it in very small volume. That the organization of things changes their property it&#39;s fairly intuitive to us: metal organized into a key can open your house door, but the same metal organized as a ring can&#39;t. Organization matters, for stuff with mass. The same - I think - for energy, and ultimately it&#39;s the same effect.</p><p>Being in that densely packed state seems to change the way energy interacts with the bit of universe it is in, in a way that the stuff made up by that energy is decelerated (there&#39;s lots of ideas on why, it seems that such tightly packed energy can interact with other energy that is part of universe, while less packed energy can more easily slip thru). That&#39;s why we can call it a property.. but in reality mass seems to me just a specific state of energy.</p><p>But in any case, mass actively prevents stuff to be at its natural speed: it has a deceleration effect. </p><p>Mass also seems to change the universe in its vicinity in a way that it affects other stuff - both stuff &quot;with mass&quot; and stuff &quot;without&quot;, changing their directions and (for other stuff &quot;with mass&quot;) creating further acceleration. </p><p>In the universe there are also other forces that can try and accelerate stuff (so it&#39;s not always at constant speed) but the more something is accelerated, the more energy it has (in the same volume), so the more mass it has, so the more the mass-induced deceleration increases; ultimately, when the something is very near the speed of light, the mass-induced brakes are so strong that no &quot;other force&quot; can make it reach it (the only way would probably be to unpack the mass and distribute its energy in a much larger volume, effectively changing that energy organization so it&#39;s no longer massive). Perhaps the universe can support only so much energy in a certain volume, who knows.</p><p>Time is created (locally) only for stuff with mass, as a consequence of its own mass-induced deceleration from the speed of light and the acceleration induced by other stuff with mass in its vicinity. </p><p>Stuff traveling at the speed of light sees no passing of time. Time depends on how much slower than the speed of light something is going because of the mass/induced brakes and the effect of other stuff with mass in the vicinity. </p><p>For things with mass which are very near to each other, the effect is very similar, so they all see give or take the same &quot;time&quot;. But if they start looking at things which are enough far away, their time as seen from each other&#39;s point of view will be quite different. </p><p>Your intuition is used only to a rather small volume of universe, and is built for stuff with mass (since you have mass); so it breaks down when you try to apply it to things with mass which are far away from each other. It also breaks when you try to apply to stuff without mass.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/nei2ity/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Basically, it’s the same as multiplying a number by 0. It doesn’t matter how high or low a number is, multiplying it by 0 is always going to be 0. 0 also happens to be light’s speed traveling through time, so no matter what your speed through time (and thus your speed through space) is, light, because it’s going 0, will always been the same for you. Any attempt to convert its speed over time to match your flow of time is going run into a multiplying or dividing by 0 issue.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/nekb4uq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><strong>DISCLAIMER: BIG WRONG MATH IN SERVICE OF CONCEPT EXPLENATION</strong></p><p>Ok, let&#39;s start from the other end that physicists don&#39;t like to do, for some reason.</p><p>If you are on a planet and send a rocket moving at 1/2 the speed of the light to a destination 1 lightyear away, it will arrive at that destination in 2 years. Period. Doesn&#39;t matter what the pilot or passengers are experiencing, you will use up two full calendars by the time they arrive. If you wait for them to come back at the same speed, it will make it a 4 year round trip, total. The distance is the distance and the speed is the speed, as we classically understand it.</p><p>As a person waiting back on the home planet, you will expel 4 full calendars waiting for them to reach their destination and return if they are moving at half the speed of light over a distance of 1 light year away and back.</p><p>Now that we have established this, we can use that fact as an anchor to understand that &quot;relative&quot; part of the speed of light.</p><p>From the perspective of the people inside the ship moving at 1/2 the speed of light, they arrived at their destination one lightyear away, in <strong>6 months</strong>. Meaning if the crew remains constant through a round trip at half the speed of light to and from a destination 1 lightyear away, the entire round trip will feel like it took <strong>1 year</strong>.</p><p>That&#39;s the practical consequence of relativistic speeds. But why does it do this?</p><p>Well, first The Speed of Light is not what sets the speed limit of matter in the universe. That&#39;s simply what we humans use to quickly reference it since light just <em>happens</em> to move at that speed through a void, or empty space.</p><p>What sets that limit is the Speed of <em>Causality</em>. The maximum speed of Cause and Effect in the universe. No matter, energy, or even information can surpass this speed. This includes the energy and information moving around in our human brains. The movements in our muscles, the sound in the air, <em>everything</em>. </p><p>So when we&#39;re inside the spaceship moving at 1/2 the speed of causality, all of the energy inside that <em>ship</em> is moving at 1/2 speed to compensate. That means if we shine a flashlight forward, those light photons are moving at half the speed light normally does <em>within</em> and <em>from</em> that ship. When added to the speed the ship was already going, that adds up to the light moving at its full energy and, thus, speed! (relative to the rest of this hypothetical still universe). </p><p>And to the people inside the ship, because the energy in their brains and bodies are all moving at half speed, they <em>perceive</em> everything in the ship to be moving at &quot;normal&quot; speed and time.</p><p>Now this is all specifically about relativity due to speed. Gravitational relativity is something else entirely. And we know relativity is real, because if we don&#39;t compensate the internal clocks of our satellites for relativity, their program clocks run too fast or too slow depending on which we are ignoring.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/nejpgrq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Oh boy.</p><p>Relativity is going to break everything you know about speed intuitively.</p><p>(Also, we talk about Newtonian mechanics and general relativity like they are two separate things… both are just models we use to describe the world around us) </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni938j/eli5_how_does_light_always_travel_at_a_constant/neh978e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:04:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/</link><title>ELI5: Why is our solar system organized the way it is?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Like we have<br/>-Sun<br/>-All Terrestrial Planets<br/>-Asteroid Belt<br/>-All Gaseous Giants<br/>-Asteroid Belt</p><p>and then like the gas giants are organized in descending order. like is there a physics explanation or is it just weird serendipity?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>When the solar system formed it was a lot hotter.</p><p>Only materials that could withstand the intense heat were able to form within the first asteroid belt</p><p>Beyond the first belt it was cool enough that gasses could gather without being obliterated by the sun</p><p>As the sun has cooled down over a bazillion years, gasses have been able to exist closer to the sun which is why we can have an atmosphere that isn&#39;t actively ripped away by the sun.**</p><p>(** Yes, the sun does take some of our lighter gasses with it but thats beyond the scope of an ELI5 comment)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/negaxo1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There is actually a cool reason, it is not a coincidence. </p><p>When the Solar System formed, the sun blew all the gas out, leaving only dust and small rocks left. This is why the 4 inner planets are rocky, and why we have an asteroid belt. The remaining gas (coupled with a small amount of rocks) clumped together to form the outer gas planets. And the reason they are in descending order is pretty simple, there would be less gas the further you travel outwards, which is less gas for planets to take and grow.</p><p>And for the Kuiper belt, I imagine that there were still rocks left outwards to form a belt.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/negbac4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Our solar system is organized the way it is because it formed from a spinning cloud of gas and dust, with the Sun forming in the center and the planets forming from the leftover material orbiting in the same plane and direction. The <a href="https://www.google.com/search?sca_esv=cdd4458fa27f824d&amp;sxsrf=AE3TifNCuW6T7GXjoNSOO-zS8ezsWszJOA%3A1757987329552&amp;q=nebular+hypothesis&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiewbCSldyPAxUd7DQHHdYhH00QxccNegQIORAB&amp;mstk=AUtExfAs3Wctjx8SwUhLjRXB6xCLQEKBjYzt5WhODlnv1mLlc6OZv1-7VdwHFpQlX_y8gKI1lUl3wHUvbQJwMTC7zuEgrcFxj9aPFAlSDy85yZ160CFV9CPXKOPLqrsAtS_1mSSxBJBFzq1gv4Ug3WMSpaqtFEzVtPblw2ZEYDFMqnGFj6SAWNXeN-uAnRZDosJpKVGFhxY2gFISZnxHD_0TRbU5Jo4Ji0iHVRxkA1E39QtotThZG0ZjRaqo3saY8eWPFohZ4eCg0XqqdQFCQRe24NFG&amp;csui=3">nebular hypothesis</a> explains that the heat from the young Sun pushed lighter gases outward, leading to rocky planets near the Sun and gas giants farther away, while early <a href="https://www.google.com/search?sca_esv=cdd4458fa27f824d&amp;sxsrf=AE3TifNCuW6T7GXjoNSOO-zS8ezsWszJOA%3A1757987329552&amp;q=planetary+migration&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiewbCSldyPAxUd7DQHHdYhH00QxccNegQIORAC&amp;mstk=AUtExfAs3Wctjx8SwUhLjRXB6xCLQEKBjYzt5WhODlnv1mLlc6OZv1-7VdwHFpQlX_y8gKI1lUl3wHUvbQJwMTC7zuEgrcFxj9aPFAlSDy85yZ160CFV9CPXKOPLqrsAtS_1mSSxBJBFzq1gv4Ug3WMSpaqtFEzVtPblw2ZEYDFMqnGFj6SAWNXeN-uAnRZDosJpKVGFhxY2gFISZnxHD_0TRbU5Jo4Ji0iHVRxkA1E39QtotThZG0ZjRaqo3saY8eWPFohZ4eCg0XqqdQFCQRe24NFG&amp;csui=3">planetary migration</a> further shaped the orbits of the giant planets into their current positions.   </p><p>Mods feel free to delete this as its the first answer in Google</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/negax39/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Jupiter formed first. Started moving inwards towards the sun. Sucked up a lot of the stuff. When Saturn formed, it pulled Jupiter back out. Left over inner material that Jupiter didn’t acquire formed inner planets. Outer gas giants formed from available material out there.  </p><p>At least according to Brian Cox.</p><p>Something, something, late heavy bombardment</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/neiofwn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Going off of what I remember from the way my professor explained it a couple years ago:</p><p>Most of space, especially early on, was really basic elements like Hydrogen and Helium. These are what end up primarily making up the gas giants (and iirc, it&#39;s expected that most planets are gas giants from the same logic). It&#39;s also what primarily makes up the sun, which is big enough to keep all those gas giants around it in the first place. Jupiter, being the big boy it is, has a strong enough gravitational pull to clear the orbits for the terrestrial planets/suck up anything big from hitting that area (though I forget which came first, the rocky bits that make up the terrestrial planets or the gas giants). That&#39;s primarily all the junk in the asteroid belt. The outer edge of the solar system is basically all the stuff that is too far to be cleared out by the gravity of the other gas giants, but still being pulled by the sun. That&#39;s also what makes it hard for there to be any other planets after the gas giants: they don&#39;t have a mechanism to help clear their orbits the way the inner terrestrial planets do.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/negm7l4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s possible that all explanations here are backwards.  In solar systems with inner gas giants there are forces that cause life to be unlikely.  Passing giants peel off atmosphere, or give off radiation or slowly spiral into their sun.  Or are plain too far away to give enough energy for life</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/negrcfq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>With the asteroid belt specifically, a large part of it is explained by Jupiter&#39;s gravity. There&#39;s two big &quot;bulges&quot; in the belt trailing and leading Jupiter, called the Trojans. There&#39;s a few of these stable orbital resonances and 60⁰ before and after a planet in its orbit are 2 of them</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni4l0a/eli5_why_is_our_solar_system_organized_the_way_it/neh0uj5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 07:12:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/</link><title>ELI5: How are cured meats, like sausages made from raw meat safe to eat?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>How come those are safe to eat even though they&#39;re made from raw meat? Like, at what point of its making depending on the sausage, do all the bacteria die and how?</p><p>edit: Solved. Thank y&#39;all.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>They use a curing agent of some sort, and often involve the removal of most or all of the moisture from the meat, thus making it a hostile environment for harmful bacteria. </p><p>Essentially, they turn the meat too salty and dry for anything harmful to survive.  Kind of like a meat desert.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg0q87/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>if you think that&#39;s crazy, look up edible mold on sausages and cheeses. Basically mold that&#39;s not harmful to us, and makes food tastier, is out competing other molds that would be harmful to us</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg1w36/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>the curing process.</p><p>in general, you add &quot;curing salt&quot; which is regular table salt plus some amount of potassium or sodium nitrate (KNO3/NaNO3) and potassium or sodium nitrite (KNO2/NaNO2). the nitrite wards off <em>C. botulinum</em> (causes botulism) and other bacteria, then lactic acid bacteria reduce nitrate to nitrite over time to give you a time-released dose of anti-microbial action. nitrite also gets reduced further to nitric oxide (NO) which permanently binds myoglobin, preventing discoloration which is why cured meats stay nice and pink instead of turning brown.</p><p>the salt itself also removes moisture. once the water activity of the meat is below a certain point, it&#39;s shelf-stable, so the curing salts are just to prevent pathogen growth in the mean time while the meat dries. some styles like salami also use bacterial and fungal cultures similar to cheesemaking to add stability and flavor as well.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg3q76/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They use a lot of salt, the salt dries the meat and germs can’t survive due to the low moisture environment.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg0u2x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Low moisture and high salt.</p><p>This is why drying stuff is effective at preserving. Bacteria need water to survive. And when you add salt, it sucks the water out of bacteria, it creates this double hostile environment.</p><p>Raw meat&#39;s danger comes from the pathogen like bacteria and parasite. The longer they stay out, the more of them there is from multiplying.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg0ywi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You don&#39;t always need heat to make meat safe.  Anything like salt or acid can kill the microorganisms and prevent them from growing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg18cs/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Prague powder, a pink salt, is mixed in with the rest of the salt when you&#39;re getting ready to cure some meat/fish. It contains some sodium nitrite, which kills a lot of bacteria. Whether the nitrites themselves have downsides health-wise is a point of contention, I think it&#39;s a tiny amount and the government generally says it&#39;s safe to eat.</p><p>Curing salmon and then smoking it to make lox is fun and surprisingly easy. Just make gravlax once, which is like the laziest process, and then next time add a cold smoking step. Fun.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/negdfak/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 06:16:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhx0gh/eli5_how_can_backneck_muscles_get_so_tweaked/</link><title>Eli5 how can back/neck muscles get so tweaked while sleeping</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhx0gh/eli5_how_can_backneck_muscles_get_so_tweaked/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhx0gh/eli5_how_can_backneck_muscles_get_so_tweaked/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhx0gh/eli5_how_can_backneck_muscles_get_so_tweaked/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>The amount of muscle tightness and pain after “sleeping wrong” seems beyond what someone should be able to do while lying still and sleeping. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Your neck muscles are really weak, so when they get into a position where your body feels that it’s in danger of hurting itself, those muscles clamp down hard to try and avoid injury. That is pretty painful. Stretching and massage can help temporarily, but the way to actually fix the problem is training your neck muscles.</p><p>This video is about the lower back, but all the same principles apply. <a href="https://youtu.be/mzIgrFwhjPc">https://youtu.be/mzIgrFwhjPc</a></p><p>Basic neck training exercises like lying face down on a bench and lifting your head, and the same thing face up and sideways, will make the muscles strong enough that your body doesn’t feel like your neck will snap while sleeping!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhx0gh/eli5_how_can_backneck_muscles_get_so_tweaked/neeqdcg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Put a camera on yourself for a few nights while you are asleep.  You will be shocked at how much moving most people do.  Twisting, turning. Etc</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhx0gh/eli5_how_can_backneck_muscles_get_so_tweaked/neeth06/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 01:52:28 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/</link><title>ELI5: In the Copenhagen interpretation of quantum mechanics, do particles really not exist fully until we observe them?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’ve been reading about the Copenhagen interpretation, and it says that a particle’s wave function “collapses” when we measure it. Does this mean that the particle isn’t fully real until someone looks at it, or is it just a way of describing our uncertainty? I’m not looking for heavy math, just a simple explanation or analogy that makes sense to a non-physicist.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Observing means to measure. To measure it you&#39;ve got to touch it. When you touch it, you affect it. </p><p>You can&#39;t know what state it was in before you measure it. Experiments show that before you measure it it really is in multiple states at once.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/neeihjt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s not that they don’t exist, it’s more that for certain properties, they don’t have a specific “value” until an interaction with something in the environment forces it to. </p><p>In electron exists in a superposition of a bunch of possible states around an atom when it’s just doing its thing on its own, but when the atom interacts with something in a way that affects the electron, it can“collapse” to a particular location.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/neel7yo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The particle is fully real before you measure it, but your measurement changed its wavefunction. That&#39;s what the collapse is. But it was real. We&#39;re not in the matrix.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/nefgxlp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I believe the founders of the Copenhagen interpretation would argue that the interpretation isn’t a representation of reality it is just a very good probabilistic model of how nature actually works.  There are scientists who believe that the wave function collapse is an actual process that takes place in reality. If that is correct the particle would be existing in a superposition all possible locations until the collapse of the function. Those who don’t believe it is a representation of reality would argue that the science is incomplete. There are arguments such as pilot wave theory that could explain the nature we see today with the particle existing at all times but the science isn’t there yet to explain everything so it’s just a theory at the moment.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/nefbib2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Imagine you are looking at a door. On the other side of the door is a person running (somewhat) randomly around a room. They can be anywhere in the room but more likely they&#39;ll be in the middle area and not like, a corner or something. You open and close the door quickly, just fast enough to see where the person is in the room. Then you do it again and they&#39;re somewhere else. With the door closed there&#39;s no way to know where in the room they are, and the brief glimpse doesn&#39;t tell you where they will be after you close the door. The person was in the room but without looking you don&#39;t know where exactly. The map of where they could run in the room is the wavefunction</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/neexjpq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>All of these answers so far are incorrect or severely incomplete. The real answer is that the Copenhagen interpretation is not ontological. That is, it does not attempt to tell you what a particle “is” when you don’t measure it. It just says that there is some math you can do, which involves pretending that the particle is described by a wave function that can, indeed, be spread out throughout space, and when you measure the particle you will find that its actual position is predicted with a high degree of accuracy by this math. </p><p>Importantly, we know that the math by itself cannot be the full story. Due to something called the EPR paradox and Bell’s theorem (outside of the scope of this answer), there are experiments we have done that show definitively that the math is not consistent with what we know about reality. Something has to change, which is what leads to all the other interpretations after Copenhagen.</p><p>However, in every situation we can come up with the math is still very, very good. So ascribing to the Copenhagen interpretation is just choosing not to care too much about this one weird contradiction and just use the math to do otherwise amazing things with physics.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/nefakz4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>When particles are unobserved (not collapsed via the Copenhagen interpretation) they can occupy special states that are combinations of observable states. Like 1/4 in state one and 3/4ths in state 2.  If you were to measure (observe) it, you would only ever find it in a single state.  </p><p>The cat business tries to explains this somewhat.  The cat is in a superposition of the states of dead or alive before it is observed.  When you observe it, you collapse the wave function into only one of those options.  </p><p>A lot of weird phenomena in quantum physics occurs between particles in the superposition states.  This is what produces quantum interference or entanglement.  They really do occupy these strange combinations of states, but if you try to catch them in that state, (according to Copenhagen interpretation) they collapse into a single allowable state.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhw20q/eli5_in_the_copenhagen_interpretation_of_quantum/nek5mo4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 01:17:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/</link><title>ELI5: Why is bread harder after heating it up and cooling it down than after doing nothing ?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The heat drives the moisture out of the bread. This makes it feel softer while it&#39;s warm, but once it cools back down to room temperature, it&#39;s now back where it started but with even less moisture.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/nedablc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Heat bread up = take water out of bread.</p><p>Cool bread down = do not put water back in bread.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/nedbma6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It gets dehydrated and dries up. Dry bread no longer contains softness of moist bread</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/nedanj5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Heating it up releases more moisture, which continues until cool. Leads to hard, dry bread</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/nedaqqn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Dry bread ist harder than bread that is still fresh and not dry. If you make bread hot, it dries out quickly. Just like when your mommy uses her electric hair dryer to make your hair warm and dry after your bath time. So when you do this, the bread becomes hard quickly. If you leave bread out in the open where it can dry out without getting icky mold on it, it will get just as hard. But it takes longer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/nedbql5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Fast tip to prevent that: wrap a napkin around the bread, and then heat it up. It will be soft after cooling.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/nedhhvv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I thought that said &quot;breed&quot; and was really confused for a more than a second.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhqadw/eli5_why_is_bread_harder_after_heating_it_up_and/nee9hhf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 21:46:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/</link><title>Eli5 Why don't we just drill really deep holes to let extra floodwater soak back into the ground?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Edit: Thank you all so much for taking the time to reply. I really appreciate the way you explained so simply and clearly and I truly learned from your responses. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>We kind of do, these are called &quot;sumps&quot;, and depending on where you live, you might actually have lots of them around - they usually look like 1/2 acre sized fields that are slightly lower than surrounding areas and usually fenced off. Where I grew up they are very common, easily 1 per neighborhood. </p><p>There are two goals here - A. letting surface water drain into the Earth which is much better ecologically than polluting near by streams, lakes, and oceans. B. recharging local aquifers (underground water sources), though this takes much more time than human-scale changes will effect (thousands and thousands of years).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necbo1p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We dig really wide holes instead (retention ponds) because that&#39;s a bit easier, less dangerous (people won&#39;t accidentally fall in), and looks better.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necbwe0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In regions prone to flooding, groundwater can often be found at as little as 10m underground.</p><p>If you wanted to clear 30cm of water from 1km square of flooded land, you&#39;d need a 1x1m hole that&#39;s 300m deep, which couldn&#39;t work becaude of aforementioned groundwater level.</p><p>Much easier to do what we already do: Dig big, wide ponds for runoff to let it drain into the groundwater.</p><p>Edit: Listen to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/Malcopticon">/u/Malcopticon</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necclz5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That is basically what storm drains and similar systems are. Japan has some very extensive flood management systems with huge underground tunnels.</p><p>The problem with just digging holes straight down is that then all the runoff and other pollutants the floodwaters pick up along the way go straight into the groundwater without being filtered by the ground itself. Then there&#39;s also the difficulty of maintaining however many huge holes you&#39;d need safely.</p><p>Edit: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metropolitan_Area_Outer_Underground_Discharge_Channel">This is one of the tunnels in Japan to which I referred.</a> It very much evokes the Mines of Moria to me.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necbu42/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Lots of good points about ground saturation - another is that groundwater (aquifiers) are commonly clean water sources. This naturally occurs as water percolates though the soil and rock which filters out contaminants. You do not want surface water to directly feed into groundwater.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necfd8p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because the soil is already saturated with water, and because you wouldn&#39;t be able to drill a hole large enough or deep enough to handle a tremendous amount of water that makes up a flood. I mean, you&#39;re talking about millions and millions of gallons of water.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necc0o2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There are 2 possible issues with flood water. The first one, is that it is not absorbed because the ground is already saturated and the water line is above ground. So digging a hole would change nothing as this hole is already full of water. The second one is that the ground can has properties that makes it hard to absorb water (either super dry, made of clay/rocks that absorb water super slowly, etc...). So digging a hole would only allow this hole to be filled quickly but the ground would not absorb that water more quickly. So you would need to dig a shit ton of holes to even be able to displace a very tiny amount of floodwater. If the ground was not saturated and can absorb water quickly, floodwater would disappear almost at the same speed with deep holes or not.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necc0vn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 18:49:24 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
