<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=science&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;comments=3&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/science</title><description>Hot posts in /r/science (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:37:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_mouw-styles-communityIcon_xtjipkhhefi41-144x400.png</url><title>/r/science</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://newatlas.com/cancer/vitamin-b3-skin-cancer-risk/</link><title>Daily vitamin B3 dose cuts skin cancer risk by up to 54%: A common, over-the-counter form of vitamin B3 has emerged as an inexpensive ally in protecting us from skin cancer, lowering the risk by an average of 14% and increasing to a massive 54% for anyone who has previously had a positive diagnosis. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/1af8b4f/2147483647/strip/true/crop/4807x2524+0+338/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fb6%2Fe0%2Fc6a9f7274eeda16a860f6100725d%2Fdepositphotos-102779586-xl.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A common, over-the-counter form of vitamin B3 has emerged as an inexpensive ally in protecting us from skin cancer, lowering the risk by an average of 14% and increasing to a massive 54% for anyone who has previously had a positive diagnosis. This latest study of more than 33,000 patients supports earlier evidence that emerged in a 2015 Australian trial.</p><p>Researchers from Vanderbilt University Medical Center conducted a large real-world analysis of US veterans, which looked at the health records of 33,822 individuals, comparing those prescribed niacinamide (typically 500 mg twice daily for more than 30 days) with matched patients who didn&rsquo;t take it.</p><p>Overall, niacinamide &ndash; also known as nicotinamide, a vitamin B3 form found in food and supplements that supports cellular energy, DNA repair and healthy skin &ndash; was associated with a 14% lower risk of developing skin cancer. When people began nicotinamide after having earlier received a positive skin cancer diagnosis, the reduction in risk was 54%. What's more, the effect was seen in both basal cell carcinoma and cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, with the largest drop in squamous cell cancers.</p><p>&ldquo;There are no guidelines for when to start treatment with nicotinamide for skin cancer prevention in the general population," said corresponding author Lee Wheless, M.D., assistant professor of Dermatology and Medicine at Vanderbilt University Medical Center. "These results would really shift our practice from starting it once patients have developed numerous skin cancers to starting it earlier. We still need to do a better job of identifying who will actually benefit, as roughly only half of patients will develop multiple skin cancers."</p><p>While basal cell carcinoma, which generally affects areas of the skin that have endured longterm exposure to the Sun, develops slowly, they can be easily missed for some time and surgery can be significant. (In 2024, I had surgery to remove one measuring 0.4 cm in diameter, which required a deep and wide excision, and around 20 subcutaneous and surface stitches.) Cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, meanwhile, are cancerous growths on a more surface layer of skin. These, along with melanoma, make up the three malignant skin cancers.</p><p>People tend to underestimate the impact and seriousness of non-melanoma cancers. The US spends more than <a href="https://www.skincancer.org/skin-cancer-information/skin-cancer-facts/">US$8 billion each year</a> in treating skin cancer &ndash; and a majority of that cost ($4.8 billion) is to address non-melanoma types.</p><p>In general, niacinamide has been shown to help skin cells repair UV-induced DNA damage, and it blunts some of the immunosuppressive effects of sunlight. While observational, so causation can't be proven, this study is by far the biggest dataset yet on niacinamide's everyday performance outside of controlled clinical trials. The veteran cohort also skews older and male (average age 77 and predominantly white men), and the researchers caution that studies on a more diverse demographic are needed to see if these results can be replicated more broadly.</p><p>However, it does echo the findings of the groundbreaking <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa1506197">2015 ONTRAC phase-3 trial in Australia</a>, which demonstrated that 500 mg of niacinamide twice daily lowered the incidence of new non-melanoma skin cancers by about 23% over 12 months in 386 high-risk adults with prior skin cancers. And this protective factor diminished once the individuals discontinued the treatment. </p><p>While the researchers urge that this is no replacement for covering up and applying sunscreen to exposed skin, for people who&rsquo;ve had a first basal or squamous cell carcinoma removed, a daily niacinamide regimen is emerging as a practical, inexpensive way to lower the odds of a recurrence. And this study gives clinicians and patients more real-world numbers to weigh when deciding whether these supplements could be of benefit.</p><p>"The results of this cohort study suggest that there is a decreased risk of skin cancer among patients treated with nicotinamide, with the greatest effect seen when initiated after the first skin cancer," noted the researchers.</p><p>"<a href="https://newatlas.com/medical/vitamin-b3-chronic-pain/">Nicotinamide</a>, a simple vitamin B3 derivative, is showing real promise as a practical tool for skin cancer prevention," said Dr Yousuf Mohammed, a Senior Research Fellow at the University of Queensland. "These findings highlight that timing matters; starting earlier may be the key to stronger protection. For clinicians, the appeal of nicotinamide lies in its accessibility, safety, and tolerability. Unlike systemic retinoids or invasive field therapies, nicotinamide is inexpensive, over-the-counter, and free from significant side effects.</p><p>"Overall, these results reinforce what many dermatologists have long suspected, nicotinamide is an underutilized, low-risk intervention that can make a difference in reducing skin cancer burden, especially for patients with an early history of disease," he added.</p><p>The research was published in the journal <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2838591"><i>JAMA Dermatology</i></a><i>.</i></p><p>Source: <a href="https://news.vumc.org/2025/09/17/study-reveals-efficacy-of-nicotinamide-for-skin-cancer-prevention/">Vanderbilt University Medical Center</a><br></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>My dad has Gorlin syndrome. Approximately 10years ago he commenced treatment with larger doses of B3. Instead of having 20-30 BCCs removed every ~6 months, the number has reduced to 8-12 removed every  12months.</p><p>When growing up it always confused me why he wore his hat in buildings with skylights etc. - he has always been extremely careful.</p><p>B3 has been a game changer for him.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf1qva2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the news release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article: </p><p><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2838591">https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2838591</a></p><p>From the linked article: </p><p><strong>Daily vitamin B3 dose cuts skin cancer risk by up to 54%</strong></p><p><strong>A common, over-the-counter form of vitamin B3 has emerged as an inexpensive ally in protecting us from skin cancer, lowering the risk by an average of 14% and increasing to a massive 54% for anyone who has previously had a positive diagnosis</strong>. This latest study of more than 33,000 patients supports earlier evidence that emerged in a 2015 Australian trial.</p><p>Researchers from Vanderbilt University Medical Center conducted a large real-world analysis of US veterans, which looked at the health records of 33,822 individuals, comparing those prescribed niacinamide (typically 500 mg twice daily for more than 30 days) with matched patients who didn’t take it.</p><p>Overall, niacinamide – also known as nicotinamide, a vitamin B3 form found in food and supplements that supports cellular energy, DNA repair and healthy skin – was associated with a 14% lower risk of developing skin cancer. When people began nicotinamide after having earlier received a positive skin cancer diagnosis, the reduction in risk was 54%. What&#39;s more, the effect was seen in both basal cell carcinoma and cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, with the largest drop in squamous cell cancers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf1p5i8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sounds like Australia should maybe introduce it into their food supply like iodine</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf27b4z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:58:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://now.tufts.edu/2025/09/18/one-three-young-adults-skip-dentist-and-thats-problem</link><title>1 in 3 young adults skip the dentist, putting young adults at greater risk for future health problems. Dental care in the United States is still excluded from medical health insurance coverage and usually not integrated with public health initiatives that promote preventative care. (now.tufts.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://now.tufts.edu/sites/default/files/uploaded-assets/images/2025-09/dental_care_young_people.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><p><span>Regular dental checkups are vital for overall health. Yet dental care in the United States is still excluded from medical health insurance coverage and usually not integrated with public health initiatives that promote preventative care. A new study from a researcher at </span><a href="https://dental.tufts.edu/"><span>Tufts University School of Dental Medicine</span></a><span> found that nearly one in three young adults skipped visits to the dentist in the past year&mdash;and pointed to wider health and access problems that could affect the nation&rsquo;s future workforce and health systems.</span></p><p><span>Published recently in </span><em><span>Frontiers in Oral Health</span></em><span>, the </span><a href="https://doi.org/10.3389/froh.2025.1619983"><span>study</span></a><span> is the first to compare people&rsquo;s social and economic circumstances, access to dental care, and self-reported health challenges across different ages. The study builds on past research about cost and access barriers to dental care, but it provides new insights by showing that young adults are especially likely to miss out on care&mdash;and that factors like mental health and housing problems also play a role.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;Young adults, aged 18 to 35 years old, were the most likely to report not having visited a dentist within the past 12 months,&rdquo; says </span><a href="https://dental.tufts.edu/people/faculty/yau-hua-yu"><span>Yau-Hua Yu, D20</span></a><span>, the study&rsquo;s author and an associate professor of periodontology at the School of Dental Medicine. &ldquo;This is very troubling.&rdquo;&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Her </span><a href="https://now.tufts.edu/2024/03/04/study-shows-correlation-between-self-reported-oral-health-and-systemic-health-outcomes"><span>earlier research</span></a><span> suggested that poor oral health is linked to shortened life expectancy and other negative health outcomes.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>For this study, Yu analyzed health, demographic, and dental-care data from nearly 128,000 adults in the </span><span>National Institutes of Health</span><span>&rsquo;s All of Us program, one of the world&rsquo;s largest biomedical databases. Yu used the data to examine how physical challenges and mental health issues reported by individuals from different socioeconomic backgrounds varied depending on three factors: whether they had visited a dentist in the past year, their income level, and their age.</span></p><figure><p>The study found that nearly one in three young adults skipped visits to the dentist in the past year.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></figure><p><span>&ldquo;Across all ages, people generally managed to see a doctor,&rdquo; says Yu. &ldquo;But those who skipped dental care most often pointed to cost and lack of insurance coverage.&rdquo; She says this finding reinforces the need to address the persistent policy gap in dental coverage, especially for those not covered by employer-based insurance or public programs.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Young adults who missed dental visits were also more likely to skip medical care, struggle with copays, rely on emergency care, and report poor mental health or memory problems. Yu found that this group of study participants were more likely to be renters, uninsured, and racially diverse&mdash;and that unstable housing added financial and emotional strain.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The study&rsquo;s age-based analysis revealed other important generational contrasts. While adults aged 66 years or older were more likely to have insurance and own a home, they also reported more disabilities. Individuals who reported difficulty walking, bathing, running errands, or concentrating were more likely to skip dental care, particularly among these older adults.&nbsp;</span></p></div><div><p><span>&ldquo;Our findings show the urgent need to integrate dental care into overall health care,&rdquo; Yu says. &ldquo;They also suggest that interventions must be tailored not only to income, but to life stage and cumulative disadvantage. The desperate need to bring routine preventative dental care to younger adults&mdash;who will be our prime source for societal productivity&mdash;should not be ignored.&rdquo;&nbsp;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This may include expanding public dental insurance and integrating oral health equity goals into public health surveillance and primary care frameworks, Yu says.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>For older adults, barriers like transportation and mobility point to the need for home-based or mobile dental programs.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>For young adults, Yu adds that community organizations and faith-based health systems could be key partners in expanding access, as they already offer models of integrated affordable dental care.&nbsp;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;When dental care is rooted in trusted community spaces, it feels more familiar and supportive,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;That lowers the barriers of fear, inconvenience, and cost uncertainty that may keep some young adults away&mdash;and it helps them shift from waiting until there&rsquo;s an emergency to hopefully seeking regular, preventive care.&rdquo;</span></p></div></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn’t help that in the U.S., dental insurance is basically a coupon. If you have anything major, you’ll hit your limit and be paying out of pocket for most of the procedure.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez0i39/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s insane really. That somehow the government was convinced that eyes and mouth just don’t count as part of your body and you need a separate plan. And all we’re doing it finding out how the more we neglect the more harm we do to other parts of our body.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez11cr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I hate to break it to the researchers, but ALL ages are skipping dental visits or self limiting care. The cost of dental work to a fixed income senor means you &quot;might&quot; get one problem fixed per year and as your older, you have lots more problems than one per year and they only get worse.</p><p>I get $400 a quarter from my Advantage Medicare+ insurance. To cover <em>any</em> dental needs. I have two painful, abscessed, fractured teeth and I&#39;m struggling to figure out what necessity I can give up this next year to afford to have them pulled. Not fixed, not implanted, not even bridged. Just yank them out and give up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez63wd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:55:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/women-tend-to-feel-more-fearful-in-nature-especially-when-social-threats-are-present/</link><title>Women tend to feel more fearful in nature, especially when social threats are present | Study found women consistently expressed more fear, perceived higher risk, and were less inclined to explore wooded environments when potential dangers were present. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/woman-and-bear.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Women are more likely than men to feel unsafe in nature, particularly in areas with dense vegetation or when social threats are implied, according to a new study published in the <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvp.2025.102722">Journal of Environmental Psychology</a></em>. Across three experiments involving hundreds of adults in the United Kingdom, women consistently expressed more fear, perceived higher risk, and were less inclined to explore wooded environments when potential dangers were present.</p><p>The study was partially inspired by a viral social media trend that captured public attention in 2024. The &ldquo;Man or bear&rdquo; debate asked users whether they would rather encounter a man or a bear while alone in the woods. Many women chose the bear, suggesting that they perceived a greater threat from an unknown man than from a wild animal. This phenomenon sparked a broader discussion about women&rsquo;s experiences of safety in natural environments and highlighted how social fears can shape engagement with nature.</p><p>Although earlier studies have shown that environmental features like vegetation density can influence feelings of safety, relatively few had examined how those effects may vary by gender, especially when different types of threats &mdash; such as social, animal, or physical dangers &mdash; are involved. The researchers sought to fill this gap using experimental methods that allowed them to systematically vary environmental cues and measure psychological responses.</p><p>&ldquo;I became interested in women&rsquo;s experiences in forests and greenspaces because I had a few experiences in nature myself when I didn&rsquo;t feel entirely safe, and as a consequence the visit was not as enjoyable as I hoped,&rdquo; explained study author <a href="https://abornioli.wixsite.com/annabornioli">Anna Bornioli</a>, a Marie Sk&#322;odowska-Curie Postdoctoral Fellow at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health and an associate researcher at the Environmental Psychology Research Group at the University of Surrey, where this study was conducted.</p><p>&ldquo;When chatting with my friends about this, I realised that many female friends empathized, having had similarly bad experiences. On the other hand, many male friends had no idea of what we were talking about. So I started to wonder if gender has anything to do with how we experience nature, and reflected on how gender stereotypes, the way we are brought up, and safety concerns can affect nature experiences. This specific study focuses on safety perceptions.&rdquo;</p><p>The research involved three separate studies, each using online simulations to present participants with images or videos of natural settings. These settings varied in the density of vegetation and the presence of different types of danger signals. In all three studies, participants were asked to imagine walking through the environment and to report their levels of fear, perceived risk, perceived danger (such as social or physical threats), aesthetic appraisal of the setting, and intention to engage with it.</p><p>In the first study, 269 university students viewed slideshows depicting nature settings categorized as open, medium, or dense. Participants imagined taking a walk through these environments after a stressful day and then completed a series of rating scales. The researchers found that women reported significantly more fear and perceived risk than men. They were also more likely to anticipate social dangers, such as being followed or assaulted. Men, by contrast, did not report significantly different levels of fear across the different settings.</p><p>&ldquo;I was surprised that men&rsquo;s experiences were largely unaffected by danger threats,&rdquo; Bornioli told PsyPost. &ldquo;The possible presence of wild animals or of a dangerous attacker did not trigger fear among men, compared to the control scenario that had no dangers at all. This could mean that men are less affected by possible threats, or that they are reluctant to express fear and concerns.&rdquo;</p><p>In terms of how vegetation density affected perceptions, both men and women viewed dense environments as more dangerous and less aesthetically appealing than open settings. However, the effect of density on fear and behavioral intentions &mdash; such as wanting to explore or leave the area quickly &mdash; tended to be stronger for women.</p><p>The second study replicated the first with a larger and more balanced sample of 414 adults, including both students and participants recruited online. This replication largely confirmed the previous findings. Again, women expressed more fear, rated the risk of encountering danger as higher, and were especially concerned about social threats. The effect of vegetation density was once more more pronounced for women, with denser settings amplifying their perceptions of risk and decreasing their willingness to engage with the environment.</p><p>The third study added a new layer by directly manipulating the type of danger sign participants saw before watching a video of a nature setting. These signs warned of different dangers: social threats (such as an assault warning), physical threats (like tripping hazards), animal threats (such as wild boars), getting lost, or no danger at all. This allowed the researchers to examine how specific threat types influenced fear and behavioral responses.</p><p>Across the board, women again reported higher levels of fear and lower willingness to explore the environments. This was especially true when the danger was social in nature. In fact, the presence of a social threat produced the strongest gender differences. Women&rsquo;s fear scores spiked significantly in these conditions, while men&rsquo;s responses remained largely unaffected. This pattern was not seen when the danger was physical or animal-related.</p><p>&ldquo;There are three important takeaways,&rdquo; Bornioli explained. &ldquo;1). Women consistently reported higher levels of fear and felt more at risk in natural environments than men. This was always the case, independently from the type of greenspace and from the presence or absence of danger threats. 2). &lrm;Gender differences were particularly pronounced in dense, heavily vegetated areas. There, women felt especially scared and unsafe. 3). Social threats were a key concern for women. When shown scenarios involving social dangers (a potential assaulter spotted in the same greenspace), women&rsquo;s feelings of fear increased significantly. This concern was much more impactful than other dangers, including wild animal threats (which is somehow in line with the social media trend &ldquo;man or bear&rdquo;).</p><p>&ldquo;All of this is problematic because spending time in natural spaces can offer important benefits for health and wellbeing, such as conducting exercise or restoring from stress. But a poor sense of safety can discourage people to visit greenspaces. If women don&rsquo;t feel safe in nature, this can perpetuate a form of gender inequality in nature access and enjoyment.&rdquo;</p><p>As with all research, there are some limitations. The experimental stimuli were videos and slideshows rather than real-world nature experiences. While these formats allowed for better experimental control, they could not fully replicate the sensory experience of being outdoors.</p><p>&ldquo;The studies are based on virtual experiments rather than on actual nature visits,&rdquo; Bornioli noted. &ldquo;Participants watched videos filmed in nature and were asked to image being there. In addition, when showing the videos we did not give instructions to participants on whether they were alone or in company. This is a factor that is likely to affect perceptions of safety.&rdquo;</p><p>Despite these limitations, the study offers consistent evidence across multiple experiments that women tend to perceive nature settings as more dangerous than men do, particularly when social dangers are implied. These findings have important implications for environmental design, public safety messaging, and efforts to promote equitable access to nature. Parks and natural reserves may benefit from interventions aimed at improving perceived safety, such as clear signage, regular maintenance to reduce dense overgrowth, or community programming that fosters a stronger sense of collective presence and care.</p><p>&ldquo;I am interested in understanding the reason behind these gender differences, and what can be done to improve perception of safety among women,&rdquo; Bornioli said. &ldquo;Are these concerns entirely due to the fact that women are more likely to be sexually harassed in public spaces? Or are they also related to cultural ideas on nature, and how girls and boys are brought up (other studies indicate that boys are generally encouraged to &ldquo;be brave&rdquo; and explore the outdoor, while girls get discouraged to be independent and are often warned about the dangers of nature)?&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;There could be several elements playing a role &ndash; for example, dense vegetation did contribute to fear perceptions among women. However, it is clear that in order to improve women&rsquo;s (and everyone else&rsquo;s) sense of safety in nature, the solution is not cutting down trees. The key is to address crime in natural and public spaces &ndash; and gender-based violence.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvp.2025.102722">Gender differences in safety perceptions and experiences of natural environments: The role of vegetation density and danger threats</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Alice Bornioli and Birgitta Gatersleben.</p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>As a woman who loves being in nature, I don’t feel secure if there’re no people around and I would be an easy target for a potential attacker.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nex701x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They buried the important bit in the article.</p><p>&#39;Across the board, women again reported higher levels of fear and lower willingness to explore the environments. This was especially true when the danger was social in nature. In fact, the presence of a social threat produced the strongest gender differences. Women’s fear scores spiked significantly in these conditions, while men’s responses remained largely unaffected. This pattern was not seen when the danger was physical or animal-related.&quot;</p><p>So it appears its all social threat  though the wording of the article is not that clear and im not going to examine the paper. The women were not more fearful or deterred by other threats. Which is interesting.</p><p>Though I wouldn&#39;t overly trust the results given the methodology.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nexjxqx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That&#39;s because of the implications...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/newwkdd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:32:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496879-vitamin-d-supplements-may-lower-your-level-of-one-type-of-vitamin-d/</link><title>Vitamin D supplements may lower your level of one type of vitamin D (newscientist.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/17203014/SEI_266529911.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section> <figure><figcaption><div><p>Vitamin D supplements are recommended during the darker months in many countries</p><p>Olga Pankova/Getty Images</p></div></figcaption></figure><p>Taking one type of vitamin D supplement seems to cut the levels of another type that is more easily used by the body, which could affect our <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article-topic/immune-system/">immune system</a>.</p><p>Our bodies create vitamin D when ultraviolet rays in sunlight convert a protein called 7-dehydrocholesterol in the skin into a type of vitamin D known as vitamin D3. When sunlight is sparse during autumn and winter, countries like the UK <a href="https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/media/5a749fece5274a44083b82d8/government_dietary_recommendations.pdf">recommend people take supplements</a>.</p><p>Two forms of these supplements are available: vitamin D3, or cholecalciferol &ndash; which normally comes from lanolin, a waxy substance on sheep&rsquo;s wool &ndash; and vitamin D2, or ergocalciferol, which mainly comes from mushrooms. It was thought that it didn&rsquo;t really matter which one you took.</p><p>But now, <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Emily_Brown54">Emily Brown</a> at the University of Surrey, UK, and her colleagues have performed a meta-analysis of 11 previously published randomised-controlled trials on vitamin D supplements, with a total of 655 participants.</p><p>They found taking vitamin D2 supplements can lead to a drop in the body&rsquo;s concentration of vitamin D3. Why this happens, or if vitamin D3 supplements reduce vitamin D2 levels, isn&rsquo;t entirely clear.</p><p>Furthermore, in many of the studies, the vitamin D3 levels were lower in people taking vitamin D2 than they were in control groups not taking any vitamin D supplements. &ldquo;This is a previously unknown effect,&rdquo; says Brown.</p><p>A 2022 study suggests <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/immunology/articles/10.3389/fimmu.2022.790444/full">vitamin D2 and D3 have overlapping but different roles in supporting immune function</a>. Only vitamin D3 seems to stimulate the type-I interferon signalling system, for instance, which provides a first line of defence against bacteria and viruses.</p><p>Brown says the findings suggest vitamin D3 supplements may be more beneficial for most individuals than vitamin D2, but adds personal considerations need to be taken into account, such as wanting to avoid animal products.</p><p>They also don&rsquo;t mean people should just stop taking vitamin D2, she says. &ldquo;Your total vitamin D level will still be sufficient if you are taking vitamin D2 supplements, but you might find that it&rsquo;s less effective and you might lose out on those additional functions in terms of immune support.&rdquo;</p><p><a href="https://ehe.osu.edu/human-sciences/directory?id=ziouzenkova.1">Ouliana Ziouzenkova</a> at The Ohio State University points out studies have shown that among older people, <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36287374/">the conversion of vitamin D3 to its active form called calcitriol can be less efficient</a>, so D2 supplementation may be particularly beneficial in this population.</p><p>&ldquo;In the absence of any evidence for negative effects, if someone who is vegan is deficient in vitamin D, opting for a D2 supplement over no supplement remains the likely prudent choice,&rdquo; says <a href="https://www.liverpool.ac.uk/people/bernadette-moore">Bernadette Moore</a> at the University of Liverpool in the UK.</p><p>Plant-based vitamin D3 has started to become more accessible. For instance, a <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41477-022-01154-6">tomato has been gene-edited to produce vitamin D3</a>, but trials are ongoing.</p><p>Team member <a href="https://www.surrey.ac.uk/people/susan-lanham-new">Susan Lanham-New</a>, also at the University of Surrey, hopes the research will remind people of the importance of vitamin D supplements. &ldquo;There are many people in the United Kingdom and other areas of northern latitude who in winter get mild osteomalacia [known as rickets in children], caused by lack of vitamin D &ndash; which presents itself in lethargy, bone pain, muscle ache, susceptibility to infection, tiredness &ndash; and don&rsquo;t realise,&rdquo; she says.</p></section> </section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;They found taking vitamin D2 supplements can lead to a drop in the body’s concentration of vitamin D3. Why this happens, or if vitamin D3 supplements reduce vitamin D2 levels, isn’t entirely clear.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/new609t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The headline is misleading, the study actually shows that D2 suplements lower your levels of D3, but there isn&#39;t evidence that supplementing with D3 affects your D2 levels. It doesn&#39;t recommend stopping supplementing with either, just suggests that D3 is probably more effective.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/new6y7k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While you should always double-check, I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve ever come across a supplement which wasn&#39;t D3.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/newadju/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:54:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/au/blog/the-asymmetric-brain/202509/is-this-the-end-of-the-growth-mindset-theory</link><title>Growth mindset interventions are often used to improve academic performance of students. But a new study found that growth mindset interventions do not improve academic achievements of students. Just by telling somebody that their intelligence can grow if they work hard, it does not actually grow. (psychologytoday.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn2.psychologytoday.com/assets/styles/manual_crop_1_91_1_1528x800/public/teaser_image/blog_entry/2025-09/pexels-olly-3808057.jpg?itok=fdOH-tql' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><article><div><div><h3>Key points</h3> <ul> <li>Growth mindset interventions are often used to improve the academic performance of students</li> <li>A new study investigated the effectiveness of growth mindset interventions focussing on high quality data.</li> <li>Growth mindset interventions have little to no effect on academic performance.</li> </ul> </div><div><h2><strong>Can a growth mindset help improve academic performance?</strong></h2><p>There are many ideas about how students&rsquo; academic performance can be improved. A widely popular group of measures is <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/au/basics/growth-mindset" title="Psychology Today looks at growth mindset">growth mindset</a> interventions. The basic idea behind this is that students can have either a &ldquo;fixed mindset&rdquo; about their abilities (thinking they are born with a certain level of <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/au/basics/intelligence" title="Psychology Today looks at intelligence">intelligence</a> which cannot be changed over the course of their life) or a &ldquo;growth mindset&rdquo; (thinking their intelligence can be improved by hard work). It is assumed that having a growth mindset has a positive effect on academic achievement. Therefore, schools and universities often offer interventions that should help student develop a &ldquo;growth mindset,&rdquo; thinking this would improve their academic achievement. Some psychological studies indeed show this association, but does the effect hold when the findings of the most trustworthy high-quality studies on growth mindset interventions are integrated?</p><h2><strong>A new structured review of the studies on the effectiveness of growth mindset interventions</strong></h2><p>To answer this question, researcher Carolina Gazmuri from Durham University in the UK conducted a new structured review on studies about the effectiveness of growth mindset interventions (<a href="https://bera-journals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/rev3.70066">Gazmuri, 2025</a>). After screening the relevant literature, she included 24 studies. Importantly, the review did not include all types of studies but specifically focused on so-called randomized controlled trials. This is a type of study that yields especially high-quality data. Randomized controlled trials are the gold standard to determine whether a psychological intervention is effective or not. In a randomized controlled trial, volunteers are tested in two groups: an experimental group that receives the treatment (a growth mindset training) and a control group without the intervention. Importantly, volunteers are assigned at random to the two groups, minimizing the effects of potential individual differences between volunteers. To further assess study quality, all studies were rated on several indicators of scientific quality, such as data quality. This was done to identify the highest quality studies on growth mindset interventions.</p><h2><strong>What were the results of the study?</strong></h2><p>Overall, 14 different growth mindset study outcomes got the highest quality rating in the review. The findings were quite interesting: The lowest quality studies reported the biggest effects for growth mindset interventions. The higher the study quality was, the lower the effect was. Importantly, when only the 14 study outcomes with the highest quality rating were considered, the effect of growth mindset interventions was around zero. Thus, there was no effect at all. This discrepancy between low-quality and high-quality studies suggests that the effects observed in low-quality studies are more likely caused by problems in study designs (such as expectation effects of researchers that may <a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/au/basics/bias" title="Psychology Today looks at bias">bias</a> the findings) than an actual effect of the intervention.</p><h2><strong>Take Away: Growth mindset interventions do not help much in improving academic performance</strong></h2><p>The conclusions of the paper were clear: Growth mindset interventions do not improve the academic achievements of students. Just by telling somebody that their intelligence can grow if they work hard, it does not actually grow. Other interventions to improve performance in schools or universities should be developed.</p></div><div><p>References</p><div><p>Gazmuri, Carolina. (2025). Can growth mindset interventions improve academic achievement? A structured review of the existing evidence. <em>Review of Education</em>. 13. 10.1002/rev3.70066. </p></div></div></div></article> </div><div><div><p>More from Sebastian Ocklenburg, Ph.D.</p></div><div><p>More from Psychology Today</p></div></div></div><div><div><p>More from Sebastian Ocklenburg, Ph.D.</p></div><div><p>More from Psychology Today</p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://cdn2.psychologytoday.com/assets/styles/thumbnail_115x140/public/field_user_blogger_photo/e1_edited.jpg?itok=CsX9XRej"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This may suggest that you can&#39;t give them growth mindset training alone. If you&#39;re giving them that training but not also giving them the training how to study well, I could see this failing--you&#39;re telling them that they can do better without telling them how.</p><p>Moreover, what if you give them the training and they just don&#39;t care anyway?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev4on6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Telling someone about growth mindsets doesn&#39;t give them a growth mindset. And that&#39;s all these &#39;interventions&#39; ever are.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev64y8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you tell people to get over their depression, you&#39;ll probably get the same results.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev669x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/17/climate/national-academies-climate-trump.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mk8.H9nY.DT8PLhUIEux5</link><title>Top Scientists Find Growing Evidence That Greenhouse Gases Are, in Fact, a Danger (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.zinnedproject.org/news/tdih/coal-burning-co2-emissions-and-global-temperatures/">https://www.zinnedproject.org/news/tdih/coal-burning-co2-emissions-and-global-temperatures/</a></p><p>Evidence growing for 113 years and counting.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netmlom/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hasn&#39;t this been known for a while?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/net4jkv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Posting this salient paragraph cause zero people commenting  clicked on the link </p><p>&gt;The report, published by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, is significant because it could complicate the Trump administration’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/07/29/climate/epa-endangerment-finding-repeal-proposal.html">efforts to revoke a landmark scientific determination</a>, known as the endangerment finding, that underpins the federal government’s legal authority to control the pollution that is driving climate change.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/nettart/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:33:02 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.upi.com/Health_News/2025/09/17/circumcision-rates-decline-United-States-mistrust-doctors/5851758118319/</link><title>Study notes decrease in popularity of circumcision in United States (upi.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdnph.upi.com/sv/ph/og/upi/5851758118319/2025/1/3de2aadb4cd614145083d233757e67be/v1.5/Study-notes-decrease-in-popularity-of-circumcision-in-United-States.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>Circumcision rates have declined significantly in the United States, driven in part by parents' distrust of medical advice, researchers said in a new study. File Photo by Bill Greenblatt/UPI | <a href="https://www.upi.com/News_Photos/lp/3de2aadb4cd614145083d233757e67be/">License Photo</a></p><article><p>Circumcision rates have declined significantly in the United States, driven in part by parents' distrust of medical advice, a new study says.</p><p><a href="https://www.healthday.com/a-to-z-health/pregnancy/circumcision-643262.html">Circumcision</a> of newborn boys declined from 54% to 49% between 2012 and 2022, according to records from more than 1.5 million U.S. male births. </p><p>The trend flies in the face of doctors' advice, researchers said, noting that the World Health Organization, the American Academy of Pediatrics and the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention have all recommended that male babies be circumcised for lifelong health benefits.</p><p>The surgical removal of the foreskin from the penis is known to provide many health benefits, including better hygiene and a lower risk of <a href="https://www.healthday.com/a-to-z-health/infectious-disease/uti-2665938107.html">urinary tract infections</a> and sexually transmitted diseases. </p><p>"Based on our findings, we believe that multiple factors may contribute to the decline in the number of neonates circumcised," co-senior researcher <a href="https://profiles.hopkinsmedicine.org/provider/aaron-a-tobian/2703907">Dr. Aaron Tobian</a>, a professor of pathology at <a href="https://www.upi.com/topic/Johns_Hopkins/" title="Johns Hopkins">Johns Hopkins</a> University School of Medicine in Baltimore, said in a news release.</p><p>The sort of distrust that's led to vaccine skepticism and hesitancy is likely one of those factors, researchers said.</p><p>"Despite overwhelming evidence that neonatal male circumcisions provide health benefits, increasing public skepticism in the United States toward medical recommendations may be driving more parents to choose not to have their sons get circumcised," Tobian said. </p><p>The growth of America's Hispanic population also might play a role in this trend, Tobian said.</p><p>Circumcisions dropped by more than 5% among white male babies, from more than 65% in 2012 to 60% in 2022.</p><p>But rates remained relatively stable in Black, Asian and Hispanic infants, with rates hovering around 65%, 38% and 21% for each, researchers found.</p><p>"Hispanics -- the ethnic group that historically reports the lowest circumcision prevalence -- also is the largest growing population in the United States," Tobian said. "Therefore, the overall circumcision rate is skewed downward."</p><p>Changes in public health insurance also might have reduced circumcisions, researchers said.</p><p>"By 2011, one year before our study period began, 17 states had ended Medicaid coverage for routine neonatal male circumcisions," Tobian said. "This likely created barriers to such services for families at low-income levels during the decade we analyzed."</p><p>For the study, researchers analyzed data from the Kids' Inpatient Database, a nationally representative dataset of U.S. childhood hospitalizations maintained by the federal Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.</p><p>The study was published Sept. 15 in <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapediatrics/fullarticle/2838312">JAMA Pediatrics</a>.</p><p><b>More information</b></p><p>The American Academy of Pediatrics has more on <a href="https://www.healthychildren.org/English/ages-stages/prenatal/decisions-to-make/Pages/Circumcision.aspx">circumcision</a>.</p><p>Copyright &copy; 2025 HealthDay. All rights reserved. </p></article><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.upi.com/img/healthday.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This article is misleading in how they represent the WHO. The WHO and UNAIDS only recommend male circumcision in their HIV prevention package which was geared towards areas with a high risk of HIV (namely Eastern and Southern Africa). This is <em>not</em> a universal recommendation.</p><p>I could not find any major medical bodies that recommend routine circumcisions in the West, and several bodies such as the AAP and Canadian Paediatric Society explicitly say that they do not recommend it. Some European bodies explicitly advise against routine circumcision for males unless medically necessary.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesskrx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>&quot;Based on our findings, we believe that multiple factors may contribute to the decline in the number of neonates circumcised,&quot; co-senior researcher Dr. Aaron Tobian, a professor of pathology at Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine in Baltimore, said in a news release.</p><p>The sort of distrust that&#39;s led to vaccine skepticism and hesitancy is likely one of those factors, researchers said.</p><p>&quot;Despite overwhelming evidence that neonatal male circumcisions provide health benefits, increasing public skepticism in the United States toward medical recommendations may be driving more parents to choose not to have their sons get circumcised,&quot; Tobian said.</p></blockquote><p>I really dislike this framing. I feel our decision to not circumcise was based on medical advice and recommendations from reputable, credible international and national organizations. Just not exclusively and entirely based on what a couple specific US based orgs and agencies may have recommended.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesqrak/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Disregarding the usual Reddit tilting about circumcision, it simply isn&#39;t medically necessary for most men, the history of circumcision in the US generally stems from religious purity culture, and decisions for elective surgeries should be left to the individual for when they&#39;re adults.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nessr46/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 05:05:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.unsw.edu.au/newsroom/news/2025/09/ai-reveals-gender-bias-in-family-courts?&amp;</link><title>The language chosen by judges in family courts reinforces gender biases, with mothers seen mainly as caregivers and fathers judged on their ability to provide financially. Fathers were also praised for even a limited involvement in childcare, whereas mothers’ efforts were expected (unsw.edu.au)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.unsw.edu.au/content/dam/images/unsw-wide/general/news/2025/2025-03-newsroom-assets/AdobeStock_436663059.cropimg.width=700.crop=landscape.jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span><div><p><span><div><p><span><div><p><span><div><p><span><strong>When parents separate in Australia, their futures &ndash; and their children&rsquo;s &ndash; often rely on the words chosen by judges in the Family Court. But those words aren&rsquo;t always neutral along gender lines, say a team of UNSW researchers.</strong></span></p><p>The language chosen by judges in the Australian family courts reflects and reinforces long-standing gender biases, according to a recent <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0331841">study</a>.</p><p>A team of UNSW Sydney data scientists and legal experts used artificial intelligence (AI) to analyse more than 2500 custody and parenting judgments across 4330 documents, handed down in the Australian family courts between 2001 and 2021. They looked at the way male and female judges spoke to, and about, male and female parties in relation to their capacity to care for their children.</p><p>&ldquo;We used AI to uncover the biases we knew existed in the legal system but remained &lsquo;hidden&rsquo;,&rdquo; says the study&rsquo;s lead author Associate Professor Mehera San Roque from the UNSW School of Law, Society &amp; Criminology.</p><p>The study applied a method called structural topic modelling &ndash; a statistical technique that groups words into clusters of themes.</p><p>The results show judgments reflect gender stereotypes &ndash; with mothers seen mainly as caregivers and fathers judged on their ability to financially provide. While trends indicate the latter gender gap is narrowing, the former isn't &ndash; fathers were also praised for even a limited involvement in childcare, whereas mothers&rsquo; efforts were expected.</p><p>A/Prof. San Roque says this pattern echoes decades of feminist legal scholarship, which applies a more traditional method of analysing the content of legal decisions case-by-case.</p><p>&ldquo;AI helped us take this beyond a manual analysis of decision-making to identify trends at a system-wide scale,&rdquo; A/Prof. San Roque says.</p><p>&ldquo;We found elements&nbsp;of stereotypical bias, with certain parties being talked about in different ways. For example, we see a conflation between financial capacity and actual capacity, especially when talking about fathers &ndash; and that replicates biases identified in earlier feminist work,&rdquo; she says.</p><p>"Another example &ndash; again, consistent with previous work &ndash; was when judges looked at whether a father has capacity to care for his child, he often received the benefit of his new partner&rsquo;s capacity. Where the court was satisfied the father could provide care for his children &lsquo;with the assistance of his present wife'.&rdquo;</p></div></span> </p></div></span></p></div></span></p></div></span></p><p><span><div><p><span>The study found gender diversity 'on the bench' makes a difference to how certain topics and ideas are thought of.</span> <span>Photo: Adobe Stock</span> </p></div></span> </p><p><span><div><h2><strong>Systems designed to repeat bias</strong></h2><p>The researchers focused on family court cases because they usually involve one male-identifying and one female-identifying parent &ndash; with both parents parties to the litigation.&nbsp;</p><p>This makes family law judgments a useful setting to study gender bias in this comparative way. Criminal cases, by contrast, involve the State, defendants and witnesses, rather than two competing parties.&nbsp;</p><p>The data reflected differences between the way presiding judges spoke. Female judges gave greater weight to the risks of harm to children and paid closer attention to the role of fathers in co-parenting. They also spoke more to financial matters than their male counterparts did.</p><p>Male judges, meanwhile, focused more on court procedures and processes, especially in relation to female parties. This included compliance with court orders, which was the most significant topic overall.</p><p>Across the two decades studied, male judges outnumbered female judges roughly two to one.</p><p>That imbalance, says A/Prof. San Roque, reflects the enduring legacy of exclusion of female judges from the profession. Women were barred from practicing law in Australia until the early 20th century &ndash; and the effects linger with a &lsquo;masculinist&rsquo; leaning legal profession.</p><p>&ldquo;The legal system is a precedent-based system, which means it&rsquo;s replicating biases because of its structure,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;In common law systems like Australia&rsquo;s, legal texts don&rsquo;t just reflect the law &ndash; they actively shape the frameworks for how future cases are decided.&rdquo;</p><p>The study notes other minority groups &ndash; including social and racial &ndash; also face a combination of formal and informal barriers to legal careers. While this has an impact on the diversity of the profession, no diversity data currently exists beyond gender.</p><p>&ldquo;So there&rsquo;s the ongoing question about judicial diversity and whether having a broad and more diverse bench that reflects social demographics makes a difference to decision making,&rdquo; A/Prof. San Roque says.</p><p>&ldquo;What our study shows is that gender diversity does make a difference to how certain topics and ideas are thought of.&rdquo;</p><p>For coauthor Professor Yanan Fan, from the UNSW School of Mathematics &amp; Statistics and UNSW Data Science Hub, the project also offers a reflection on the role of AI itself.</p><p>&ldquo;We know there&rsquo;s bias in AI too,&rdquo; Prof. Fan says.</p><p>&ldquo;A lot of AI systems just troll through existing documents and make their recommendations based on what they see,&rdquo; she says.</p><p>&ldquo;And if the existing documents have bias &ndash; like you see in this study &ndash; then they&rsquo;ll be perpetuating that bias.&rdquo;</p><p>An example could be asking a large language model for a picture of a nurse &ndash; it'll give you a woman. And if you ask for a picture of a doctor &ndash; it'll give you a man.</p><p>&ldquo;The perpetuation of bias with AI is similar to how bias is repeated within the legal system,&rdquo; Prof. Fan says.</p></div></span> </p><p><span> <blockquote><p>The perpetuation of bias with AI is similar to how bias is repeated within the legal system.</p><cite> </cite> </blockquote> </span> </p><p><span><div><h2><strong>Troubling trends</strong></h2><p>A/Prof. San Roque credits Prof. Fan&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.unsw.edu.au/newsroom/news/2019/02/gender-and-cultural-bias-exists-against-teachers-at-university-l">earlier work</a> for inspiration on how AI can be harnessed to highlight system-wide biases.</p><p>Prof. Fan had looked at university student evaluations of their lecturers. Applying AI across a large dataset of student feedback forms, Prof. Fan uncovered what staff had already been highlighting as issues &ndash; but with anecdotal evidence that was not yet statistically proven.</p><p>&ldquo;There were ways in which male lecturers were being evaluated when compared to female lecturers,&rdquo; Prof. Fan says.</p><p>&ldquo;Female lecturers were talked about in terms of their approachability, how caring they were and how nice they were,&rdquo; she says. &ldquo;Males were talked about in terms of how well they knew their subject and how authoritative they were.&rdquo;</p><p>A/Prof. San Roque says there are echoes of that study's findings when looking at the language used in the family courts.</p><p>&ldquo;It's totally the same in terms of what gets valued for each gender,&rdquo; says A/Prof. San Roque.</p><p>She says there is more to interrogate from the 20-year dataset.</p><p>While this study focused primarily on the capacity for care, A/Prof. San Roque says the same tools could shed light on another critical issue in family law: violence.</p><p>She says early findings suggest a pattern in language that minimises domestic violence.</p><p>Working alongside linguists, A/Prof. San Roque says across many judgments, violence is spoken about in a way that obscures the perpetrator and softens the impact.</p><p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s a particular use of the passive voice when talking about violence,&rdquo; she says.</p><p>Although they&rsquo;ve yet to run a large-scale analysis of violence-related decisions, A/Prof. San Roque says doing so could help expose how legal language shapes, and sometimes downplays, the experiences of vulnerable parties.</p><p>&ldquo;Because we can&rsquo;t manually read through thousands of judgments, AI lets us uncover system-wide patterns,&rdquo; A/Prof. San Roque says.</p><p>&ldquo;Words matter. So it&rsquo;s important that we do pick up these trends.&rdquo;</p><p><i>This project was funded under the UNSW Science Social Good Seed Fund and LexisNexis Australia and was undertaken by Elma Akand, Yanan Fan, Wayne Wobcke, Scott A. Sisson and Mehera San Roque.</i></p></div></span> </p><div><p><span><div><p><span> <h3> Related stories </h3> </span> </p></div></span></p></div></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Another example – again, consistent with previous work – was when judges looked at whether a father has capacity to care for his child, he often received the benefit of his new partner’s capacity. Where the court was satisfied the father could provide care for his children ‘with the assistance of his present wife&#39;.”</p><p>This would really piss me off as a mother.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/neu6g0j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This title kind of buries the lede here. Language that the judges use always matters, and fathers are often rewarded for limited involvement while mothers’ efforts are expected, but those are both fairly surface level observations that society has regardless. The precise language you use always matters, especially in court. Mothers are always expected to give everything while fathers are generally praised for giving anything at all. Genuine sociological norms in the American 21st century that I’d expect a high schooler to know. </p><p>What I find interesting is that there’s apparent gender differences with 2/3 of all judges being men, but this article doesn’t go into how that imbalance really affects court orders. The article says female judges prioritize the kids while male judges prioritize “court procedures and processes”? But it doesn’t go into what that means or how it affects the children. </p><p>I think it’s <em>really</em> interesting that the article points out that these were known, voiced, and discussed issues already. But it’s interesting that the conversation was only given weight once ai confirmed its (known) existence. </p><p>They discuss how male &amp; female lecturers were evaluated differently. Men were authoritative, women were approachable. That’s interesting.</p><p>They didn’t even factor in minorities! They had ai run this study on gender but supposedly weren’t able to have ai run racial studies. Odd. Interesting, even. I don’t know yall. Basically, ai confirmed known biases that we knew exist. It only ran gender biases. It only confirmed known &amp; proven stereotypes that exist in family court. It’s just another straw in the hay bale of proof that discrimination exists in our society. <strong>It’s not new. It’s been known for decades.</strong></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nespk9t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yea. This sucks. I was the stay at home dad, took care and nurtured my kids. Effing judge still gave them to my ex.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesfe6b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 03:46:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chimpanzees-alcohol-cocktails-fruit-research/</link><title>Wild chimpanzees consume the equivalent of 2 cocktails a day in the form of boozy fruit, research finds (cbsnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets3.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2025/09/17/c7c4c41d-ee6f-4534-8793-ed627d9b8420/thumbnail/1200x630/1a2e367751580a011c4ce668031445c6/tai-northerner-males-at-parinari-excelsa.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"> <article><div><header><div><p>By <span>Sarah Metz</span> </p><p><time>Updated on: September 17, 2025 / 7:56 PM EDT</time> / CBS News </p></div></header> </div><figure><div><div><div><svg> <use></use> </svg><p><span>Wild chimps consume alcohol via fruit, study says </span> </p></div></div></div><figcaption> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/video/wild-chimpanzees-eat-fermented-fruit-equivalent-to-2-alcoholic-drinks-per-day-research-finds/"> <span>Wild chimpanzees eat fermented fruit equivalent to 2 alcoholic drinks per day, research finds</span> <span>01:45</span> </a> </figcaption> </figure> <section><p>In the forests of Uganda and C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire, <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chimp-haven-the-worlds-largest-chimpanzee-sanctuary/">chimps</a></span> crowd into fig and plum trees, feasting on fruit that's sweet, soft and just a little boozy. A new study shows those daily snacks quietly add up to the equivalent of nearly two alcoholic beverages for humans.</p><p>A team of scientists at University of California Berkeley and other institutions tested the fruit chimps actually snack on: figs in Uganda's canopy and the plum-like fruits on the forest floor in C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire. Collecting the data wasn't easy &mdash; with little electricity beyond solar panels and constant humidity threatening the instruments, researchers spent three seasons hauling equipment and calibrating test kits to measure alcohol in many different tropical fruits.&nbsp;</p><p>In the end, they found that on average, the fruit's alcohol content came in at about .3% by weight. This is kombucha-level, but when chimpanzees eat 10 pounds of fruit a day and weigh around 90 pounds, it adds up to about 14 grams of ethanol, equating to about two cocktails for a human.&nbsp;</p><p>But don't picture chimps swinging drunkenly from the trees. To actually get drunk, they'd have to binge on fruit until their bellies ballooned, the researchers said. Instead, they're exposed to a steady low dose, a quiet buzz from nature's own fermentation process.</p><figure> <figcaption> <span>Researchers tested the fruit chimps snack on in Uganda and C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire, finding the alcohol content is about .3% by weight.</span> <span> Aleksey Maro/UC Berkeley </span> </figcaption> </figure><p>Senior author of the paper and UC Berkeley professor of integrative biology Robert Dudley first floated the "drunken monkey" hypothesis in 2000, arguing that our attraction to alcohol could come from ancestral fruit-eating habits. Dudley argued that it makes sense primates would be tuned to alcohol, since their diets have long revolved around ripe fruit.&nbsp;</p><p><em>"</em>Once you start eating, it acts as an aperitif," he said. "The pleasure of association with drinking alcohol increases feeding rates."</p><p>Other animals chase the same buzz too.&nbsp;</p><p>"Open a bottle of beer outside and a fruit fly appears almost instantly," Dudley said.&nbsp;</p><p><a href="https://news.berkeley.edu/2022/03/30/monkeys-routinely-eat-fruit-containing-alcohol-shedding-light-on-our-own-taste-for-booze/">Spider monkeys in Panama</a>, <a href="https://home.dartmouth.edu/news/2016/07/dartmouth-study-aye-ayes-and-slow-loris-finds-prosimians-prefer-alcohol">slow lorises in Malaysia</a> and even <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/ece3.6777">elephants</a> have been documented consuming naturally fermented fruit or nectar.&nbsp;</p><p>What makes this study different is that it provides the first direct chemical measurements of ethanol in the fruits that wild chimps routinely eat, and then connects those numbers to daily intake.</p><p>The open question is whether chimps are actually selecting fruit for its alcohol content or just chasing sugar and calories. Either way, Dudley says the story connects to us.&nbsp;</p><p>"We inherited the taste for alcohol," Dudley said. "Even though our diets have diversified &hellip; that bias to consume quickly when this molecule is present could still be a powerful force."</p><figure> <figcaption> <span>Wild chimpanzees in Uganda and C&ocirc;te d'Ivoire consume the equivalent of about two alcoholic beverages a day from eating fruit, new research finds.</span> <span> Aleksey Maro/UC Berkeley </span> </figcaption> </figure> <ul> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/uganda/">Uganda</a></li> </ul> </section> </article> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets1.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/2025/09/17/61e24bbc-14f6-4340-874d-7e540f650efe/cbsn-fusion-wild-chimpanzees-eat-fermented-fruit-equivalent-to-2-alcoholic-drinks-per-day-research-finds-thumbnail.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://assets2.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2025/09/17/7f8b09e7-a6ce-450a-abc9-2d914ef1878d/thumbnail/620x413/992ba9cf521aeabd7693f73d4a0358ce/ngogo-2018-hicks-in-ficus-mucuso.jpg#"></p><p><img src="https://assets2.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2025/09/17/c7c4c41d-ee6f-4534-8793-ed627d9b8420/thumbnail/620x357/0e24339fd9bc6eddc49bd88431159cbb/tai-northerner-males-at-parinari-excelsa.jpg#"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I knew of a place in Portland (OR) that had cherry trees in the back yard. Starlings would party like crazy on the cherries fermenting on the ground. Drunk, flopping birds on the ground, birds in the trees keeping watch and making loud bird laughing noises. Crazy scene would go on for days. Outrageous amounts of noise.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/ner3qt0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Am ape<br/>I too like being buzzed, chillen among the trees</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/neqysmw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And humans think they are so different…</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/neqxdz0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:41:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/autistic-individuals-and-those-with-social-anxiety-differ-in-how-they-experience-empathy-new-study-suggests/</link><title>Empathy may operate quite differently in individuals with autism spectrum condition compared to those with social anxiety. Both groups tended to report elevated levels of emotional distress in social situations, but only individuals with autism showed lower levels of emotional concern for others. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/brain-2.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in the journal <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/aur.70075">Autism Research</a></em> indicates that empathy may operate quite differently in individuals with autism spectrum condition compared to those with social anxiety. Both groups tended to report elevated levels of emotional distress in social situations, but only individuals with autism showed lower levels of emotional concern for others. The researchers also introduced a new way to distinguish between these overlapping conditions: a ratio of self-focused distress to other-oriented concern. This metric, they argue, could help improve diagnosis and support strategies.</p><p>Autism and social anxiety are both linked to social difficulties, but for different reasons. People with autism spectrum condition often struggle with understanding and responding to social cues. Social anxiety, on the other hand, involves intense fear of being judged or rejected in social situations. These overlapping traits often make it difficult to distinguish between the two in clinical settings, especially since many autistic people also experience high levels of social anxiety. This overlap has created a need for better tools to tease apart the similarities and differences in how these groups perceive and respond to others.</p><p>One of the key traits involved in social functioning is empathy, which can be broadly divided into two components. Cognitive empathy involves understanding another person&rsquo;s thoughts and feelings. Affective empathy relates to emotional responses to others, such as compassion or distress. Prior studies suggest that people with autism tend to show lower cognitive empathy and mixed patterns in emotional empathy, with some reports of heightened emotional distress. In contrast, individuals with social anxiety may show high emotional reactivity but impaired accuracy in interpreting others&rsquo; mental states. Yet few studies have directly compared these two groups on both forms of empathy, using tools that can separate the different aspects.</p><p>To address this gap, researchers at the Bruckner Autism Research Center at Ariel University recruited 105 university students and divided them into three groups. One group consisted of students with a confirmed autism diagnosis. A second group included students with high levels of social anxiety but no autism diagnosis. The third group served as a control sample, reporting neither autism nor elevated anxiety.</p><p>All participants completed several standardized assessments, including the Interpersonal Reactivity Index, which measures both cognitive and affective empathy, and the Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test, which evaluates the ability to infer emotions based on subtle facial cues.</p><p>The results suggested clear differences between the groups when it came to trait-based empathy. Individuals in the autism group scored lower on perspective taking and empathic concern compared to the control group. Their empathic concern scores were also lower than those in the social anxiety group. Both the autism and social anxiety groups reported significantly higher levels of personal distress in response to others&rsquo; emotions compared to the control group. This suggests that while both groups experience intense emotional reactions in social situations, only the autistic group showed a notable reduction in the ability to feel concern for others.</p><p>One of the study&rsquo;s key contributions was the introduction of a novel metric: the personal distress-to-empathic concern ratio. This ratio compares how much emotional discomfort a person feels in response to others&rsquo; distress (personal distress) to how much they feel for the person experiencing it (empathic concern). A higher ratio indicates a more self-focused, emotionally overwhelmed response.</p><p>The researchers found that the autism group had the highest average ratio, followed by the social anxiety group, and then the control group. This ratio was also positively linked to the severity of autistic traits and anxiety symptoms, but only in the autism group. In other words, higher emotional distress relative to empathic concern was particularly associated with autism.</p><p>Importantly, the researchers tested whether this ratio could help distinguish between autism and social anxiety. Using a statistical approach called receiver operating characteristic analysis, they identified a cutoff value of 0.83 on the ratio scale. This value demonstrated good sensitivity, meaning it could correctly identify many individuals with autism, though its specificity was moderate, indicating a moderate ability to rule out autism in those without it. This finding suggests that the PD/EC ratio, while not a standalone diagnostic tool, could serve as a useful screening measure in conjunction with other assessments.</p><p>When it came to the Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test, which provides a snapshot of a person&rsquo;s ability to recognize emotions from subtle visual cues, the groups performed similarly. All scored within the normal range, and no significant differences emerged. This suggests that state-based cognitive empathy, at least as measured by this task, may not differ meaningfully across these populations.</p><p>However, the researchers noted that the simplicity of the task might not fully capture the complexity of real-life social interactions, particularly for autistic individuals who may rely on compensatory strategies in structured testing environments.</p><p>&ldquo;We observed a significant difference in empathy levels between the autism and social anxiety groups,&rdquo; explained study author Esther Ben-Itzchak, the head of the Bruckner Autism Research Center. &ldquo;Both groups experienced higher personal distress compared to the control group; however, only the participants with autism showed significantly lower levels of empathic concern. This difference was effectively illustrated by a new ratio we developed, called the personal distress-to-empathic concern ratio (PD/EC). This ratio successfully distinguished between autism and social anxiety, conditions that frequently overlap in clinical settings, which was both surprising and exciting.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;We were also surprised that by using a well-known and widely applied measure, the Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI) in a new way, namely computing the ratio between personal distress and empathic concern, we could provide a fresh application for this classic tool.&rdquo;</p><p>The findings support a growing view that empathy is not a single, unified trait but a multidimensional construct, with different profiles emerging across psychological conditions. In the case of autism, the study suggests a combination of reduced perspective taking and empathic concern, coupled with heightened personal distress. For those with social anxiety, the pattern includes elevated distress without a corresponding drop in empathic concern. These distinctions have important implications for how we assess and support individuals facing social challenges.</p><p>The study also aligns with existing theories about emotional regulation in autism. One model suggests that autistic individuals may experience high levels of emotional arousal in social situations but lack the cognitive tools to manage those emotions effectively. This imbalance may lead to withdrawal or self-focused responses, which can be misinterpreted as a lack of empathy. The current findings add nuance to this picture by showing that lower levels of empathic concern are not necessarily universal but may interact with how individuals experience and regulate emotional distress.</p><p>Like all research, there are limitations. Most notably, the social anxiety group was identified using a self-report scale rather than clinical interviews, which means some participants may not meet formal diagnostic criteria. The sample also included a relatively small number of women, which limits generalizability across genders.</p><p>Another limitation involves the overlapping nature of autism and social anxiety. In this study, about three-quarters of the autistic group also scored high on the social anxiety measure. Although the authors ran additional analyses to control for this overlap, it remains difficult to completely disentangle the effects of each condition. A follow-up study with larger groups could compare autistic individuals with and without social anxiety, alongside a group with social anxiety but no autism, to better isolate the unique contributions of each condition to empathy profiles.</p><p>&ldquo;Incorporating experimental tasks or physiological measures of empathy in future work could enhance the validity and depth of the findings,&rdquo; Ben-Itzchak said.</p><p>Still, the current findings offer a compelling direction for future research and clinical practice. The PD/EC ratio provides a fresh application of a well-established empathy questionnaire and shows promise as a simple, scalable measure to support diagnostic differentiation. It may also help guide targeted interventions by highlighting specific empathy-related challenges, such as managing distress or building perspective-taking skills.</p><p>&ldquo;We see two main directions for extending this work,&rdquo; Ben-Itzchak explained. &ldquo;First, we plan to replicate the findings across different populations by including more women in similar young adult samples, as well as examining clinical populations and younger children. Second, we aim to integrate the behavioral questionnaires with physiological markers of emotional regulation (such as autonomic nervous system measures), which could enhance the clinical utility of empathy profiles.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;This is the first study to directly compare detailed empathy subcomponents in autism and social anxiety, while carefully screening the social anxiety group for autistic traits,&rdquo; she added. &ldquo;By doing so, we were able to reveal unique empathy profiles for each condition. Clinically, these insights could support more accurate differential diagnosis, and theoretically, they advance our understanding of empathy as a multidimensional construct. Importantly, our work underscores that while both groups experience elevated personal distress in social situations, the presence or absence of empathic concern may be a key factor that sets them apart.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/aur.70075">Distinct Empathy Profiles in Autism and Social Anxiety: A Comparative Study</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Sigal Tikochinsky, Esther Ben&#8208;Itzchak, and Gil Zukerman.</p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>The findings support a growing view that empathy is not a single, unified trait but a multidimensional construct, with different profiles emerging across psychological conditions. In the case of autism, the study suggests a combination of reduced perspective taking and empathic concern, coupled with heightened personal distress. For those with social anxiety, the pattern includes elevated distress without a corresponding drop in empathic concern. These distinctions have important implications for how we assess and support individuals facing social challenges.</p><p>The study also aligns with existing theories about emotional regulation in autism. One model suggests that autistic individuals may experience high levels of emotional arousal in social situations but lack the cognitive tools to manage those emotions effectively. This imbalance may lead to withdrawal or self-focused responses, which can be misinterpreted as a lack of empathy. The current findings add nuance to this picture by showing that lower levels of empathic concern are not necessarily universal but may interact with how individuals experience and regulate emotional distress.</p></blockquote><p>(Because people were asking about how this ties to other literature on autism &amp; empathy in the previous version of this post).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/neozs9u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>People use the word &quot;empathy&quot; for different concepts. Like reading/interpreting the emotional state of others but also for actually <em>caring about</em> the wellbeing of others when you do know.</p><p>As if not knowing and not caring are the same thing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nep2xuz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Neurotypicals have a specific way they measure empathy and it doesn’t track with how many neurodivergent people demonstrate  empathy.</p><p>If you’re looking for clear outward signs that are kind of performative, then you will miss a lot of it.</p><p>I’m autistic and unless I make the faces and use the tone of voice they’re looking for, it won’t be acknowledged. Even if I jump in to help a stranger or verbally acknowledge I can relate to the feelings of another, the tone and facial expressions have to be ‘right’.</p><p>I have witnessed people do this (‘oh no, I’m so sorry!’) and then walk away with no genuine offers of assistance and that is seen as more empathetic.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nepism1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:41:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2418257122</link><title>Sexlessness is associated with higher IQ, increased educational attainment, lower BMI and lower ADHD rates (pnas.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nj3vol/sexlessness_is_associated_with_higher_iq/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nj3vol/sexlessness_is_associated_with_higher_iq/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nj3vol/sexlessness_is_associated_with_higher_iq/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It is associated with a whole lotta things: </p><blockquote><p><em>Phenotypically, there were notable associations with indicators of poor mental well-being, especially for men. Sexless men tended to suffer more from nerves, unhappiness, loneliness, and were less likely to believe their life is meaningful.</em> </p><p><em>Throughout this discussion, the issue of causality is ever-present—the causal pathways underlying these cross-sectional associations are likely to be complex. In the case of the affective well-being indicators, one possibility is that never having had sex takes a toll on one’s happiness, given that sex is a fundamental human drive, deeply important in our evolutionary history.</em></p><p><em>Other results in our data point to indirect routes in the same direction — sexless individuals (especially men) were much more likely to live alone, have less frequent social visits, and lack a confiding relationship or anyone to confide in. There were corresponding genetic correlations with these social variables too.</em> </p><p><em>...  On the other hand, autistic spectrum disorder showed a substantial positive genetic correlation with sexlessness, consistent with the interpersonal difficulties characteristic of the spectrum; autistic individuals commonly report difficulties developing intimate relationships (</em><a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2418257122#core-collateral-r17"><em>17</em></a><em>).</em></p></blockquote><p>The authors are very careful not to oversell their findings.</p><blockquote><p><em>Box 1. Cautionary notes</em> </p><p><em>Associations between genetics and behavior can be misinterpreted, sometimes with nefarious consequences. To minimize misinterpretations, we want to emphasize the complex nature of these associations. The genetic associations we identified should not be presented as identification of “genes for late-life sexlessness” for several reasons outlined below.</em></p><p><em>Associations between genetic variants and behavioral traits likely reflect a culture-specific interplay between underlying heritable factors and environmental influences (</em><a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2418257122#core-collateral-r14"><em>14</em></a><em>). An association observed in a contemporary Western society should not be generalized as a universally applicable genetic effect on sexlessness. Therefore, our genetic and phenotypic associations may not apply to populations of different ancestries or cultural backgrounds.</em></p><p><em>Moreover, the polygenic scores derived from these genetic associations are not suited to predict individual-level outcomes regarding sexlessness. These polygenic scores are based on approximations of small effects within a large sample from a specific population. Therefore, it is inevitable that there will be many individuals who score high on such a polygenic score yet low on its target trait, and vice versa.</em></p><p><em>Overall, it is important to note that genetics is only one facet of the complex network of factors influencing behavior. Environmental, social, cultural, and individual factors all play significant roles, and their interactions with genetics further complicate the picture. This study points to possible avenues for investigation and should be seen as an exploration of correlations, not a claim of cause-and-effect relationships.</em></p></blockquote></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nj3vol/sexlessness_is_associated_with_higher_iq/nenkrvd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is specifically about people who are virgins at a late stage in life, not people who haven&#39;t had sex in a while.</p><p>This study is perhaps the most comprehensive one in a while since their sample size is over 400,000</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nj3vol/sexlessness_is_associated_with_higher_iq/neoi1nc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And lifelong sexlessness is also noted by the authors as  associated with loneliness and unhappiness.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nj3vol/sexlessness_is_associated_with_higher_iq/nenknot/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:15:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencealert.com/our-sun-is-becoming-more-active-and-nasa-doesnt-know-why</link><title>NASA scientists say our Sun's activity is on an escalating trajectory, outside the boundaries of the 11-year solar cycle. A new analysis suggests that the activity of the Sun has been gradually rising since 2008, for reasons we don't yet understand. (sciencealert.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><img width="642" height="260" src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-642x260.jpg" alt="Our Sun Is Becoming More Active And NASA Doesn't Know Why" srcset="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-642x260.jpg 642w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-768x311.jpg 768w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-600x243.jpg 600w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity.jpg 1024w"> <span> <span>A snapshot of solar activity captured by NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory in 2013.</span> <span><a href="https://science.nasa.gov/image-detail/amf-gsfc_20171208_archive_e001435/">(NASA/Goddard/SDO)</a></span> </span> </p><div><p>At the end of the last solar cycle in 2019, the official predictions were that the next cycle would be <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/news/solar-cycle-25-forecast-update">just as mild as its predecessor</a>.</p><p>Those predictions were wrong. The current Solar Cycle 25 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Solar_Cycle_25_prediction_and_progression.png">turned out far stronger</a> than NASA and NOAA expected. Now, scientists say that the Sun's activity is on an escalating trajectory, outside the boundaries of the 11-year solar cycle. In fact, a new analysis of the data suggests that the activity of the Sun has been gradually rising since 2008.</p><p>"All signs were pointing to the Sun going into a prolonged phase of low activity," <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasa-analysis-shows-suns-activity-ramping-up/">says plasma physicist Jamie Jasinski</a> of NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL). "So it was a surprise to see that trend reversed. The Sun is slowly waking up."</p><p><b>Related: </b><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/something-is-up-with-the-sun-and-it-could-mean-our-models-are-wrong"><b>The Sun Is Being Weird. It Could Be Because We're Looking at It All Wrong.</b></a></p><p>The Sun seems like a constant, reassuring presence day to day, but it's actually fairly tempestuous and changeable. One particular change it undergoes is what we call the solar cycle. Every 11 years or so, the Sun undergoes an increase in activity to <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/its-official-nasa-declares-the-solar-maximum-is-happening-now">solar maximum</a> before subsiding again down to solar minimum.</p><p>This activity manifests as a significant increase in sunspots, solar flares, and coronal mass ejections at solar maximum, at which point the Sun's poles reverse their polarity. It's all very normal; if the number didn't give it away, we're currently in the 25th solar cycle on record, which means scientists have been watching this happen for centuries now, using sunspots as a proxy to record solar activity.</p><p>However, even with this wealth of solar cycle data, predicting how the Sun is going to behave is an inexact art. There's a lot more going on inside the Sun than we are privy to, driving changes that scientists are still trying to explain.</p><p>For example, for <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/we-might-finally-be-able-to-find-out-why-the-sun-was-naked-for-70-years">a 70-year period from 1645 to 1715</a>, almost no sunspots appeared at all, a period known as the Maunder Minimum. A similar lull occurred between 1790 and 1830, known as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalton_Minimum">Dalton Minimum</a>.</p><figure><img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/solar-cycle-graph.jpg" alt width="642" height="266" srcset="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/solar-cycle-graph.jpg 642w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/solar-cycle-graph-600x249.jpg 600w"><figcaption>A graph showing sunspot activity since 1750. (<a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/products/solar-cycle-progression">NOAA SWPC</a>)</figcaption></figure><p>"We don't really know why the Sun went through a 40-year minimum starting in 1790," <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasa-analysis-shows-suns-activity-ramping-up/">Jasinski says</a>. "The longer-term trends are a lot less predictable and are something we don't completely understand yet."</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_solar_cycles">Solar cycles</a> 22 and 23, commencing in 1986 and 1996, respectively, were pretty average in terms of sunspot activity. In spite of this, the solar wind pressure steadily decreased over both cycles, leading scientists to believe that we might be headed towards something similar to the Maunder or Dalton events.</p><p>In 2008, Solar Cycle 24 commenced, becoming one of the weakest solar cycles on record in terms of sunspot and flare activity. Solar Cycle 25, scientists thought, was going to be more of the same, but its activity level turned out to be higher, more consistent with an average solar cycle.</p><p>Jasinski and his colleague, space physicist Marco Velli of JPL, have now analyzed <a href="https://omniweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/">long-term solar data</a> and found something surprising. In 2008, at the start of Solar Cycle 24, the solar wind began growing stronger and has continued to increase steadily since then.</p><div></div><p>That strength is measured in speed, density, temperature, thermal pressure, mass, momentum, energy, and magnetic field magnitude, all of which showed an increase.</p><p>Now, the Sun is an extraordinarily complex engine, and one thing that's crystal clear is that it's really difficult to predict what it's going to do next. Jasinski and Velli believe their findings indicate that we could see an uptick in rowdy space weather, with powerful winds, <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/geomagnetic-storms">solar storms</a>, flares, and coronal mass ejections.</p><p>Their results are also consistent with another aspect of the Sun's behavior: the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hale%27s_law">Hale cycle</a>. This is represented by pairs of solar cycles, with each Hale cycle lasting 22 years, ending when the magnetic poles swap back to their original polarities. A growing body of evidence suggests that the Hale cycle is the primary cycle, and each solar cycle is only half of the full cycle.</p><p>At the moment, the solar wind pressure is still lower than it was at the turn of the 20th century. The only way we will know what it does from this point is to continue observing to see whether it continues to increase or remains stable.</p><p>The findings also have much broader implications, adding to the mounting evidence that sunspot numbers present, at best, an incomplete picture. We need to study a much wider catalog of solar behavior if we wish to understand the dynamics of our wild, beautiful star.</p><p>The research has been published in <a href="https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/adf3a6"><i>The Astrophysical Journal Letters</i></a>.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/SungFXUsoqw/0.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/TWjtYSRlOUI/0.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It just means that the long term models aren’t good enough to make accurate predictions yet. They predicted low activity but we’re getting high activity. The sun is doing whatever it was always going to do.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/nemjyxk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Astronomer here! For those interested in actual data over puns, <a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/2041-8213/adf3a6">here</a> is the actual paper. I find this bit of the abstract worth highlighting:</p><blockquote><p>Furthermore, comparison of values from a fitted trend to data between 2008 and 2025 show the following increases in solar wind proton parameters: speed (~6%), density (~26%), temperature (~29%), thermal pressure (~45%), mass flux (~27%), momentum flux or dynamic pressure (~34%), energy flux (~40%), interplanetary magnetic field magnitude (~31%), and the radial component of the magnetic field (~33%).</p></blockquote><p>These are certainly not nothing, but right now it’s far too early to know where they will lead. Worth noting in the roughly two solar cycles I’ve followed of the sun in my lifetime btw that weird stuff always seems to happen in them. For example, the last solar cycle was especially <em>weak</em>, to the point where folks speculated we might be entering a new kind of solar minimum- I doubt anyone’s suggesting that now!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/nemxn52/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Global warming?! I&#39;ll show you global warming!!&quot; - The sun, probably</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/nemgmmw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 06:00:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/mental-health/hd-tdcs-brain-stimulation-precise-depression/</link><title>A new study shows that a personalized, precise form of brain stimulation, HD-tDCS, can rapidly ease depression symptoms – and even reduce anxiety – offering a promising drug-free alternative with only mild side effects. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nixx2j/a_new_study_shows_that_a_personalized_precise/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nixx2j/a_new_study_shows_that_a_personalized_precise/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nixx2j/a_new_study_shows_that_a_personalized_precise/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/15217a6/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F2e%2F89%2F7902b91b4d68a65a594a4a3b6516%2Fdepositphotos-638237544-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study shows that a personalized, precise form of brain stimulation, HD-tDCS, can rapidly ease depression symptoms &ndash; and even reduce anxiety &ndash; offering a promising drug-free alternative with only mild side effects.</p><p>We&rsquo;ve reported on research that used transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) to improve <a href="https://newatlas.com/medical/transcranial-direct-current-stimulation-alzheimers-plasticity-cognitive-functioning/">cognitive functioning</a> and <a href="https://newatlas.com/brain/brain-stimulation-home-depression/">treat depression</a>. tDCS involves delivering a low-intensity direct current via electrodes on the scalp to trigger changes in the excitability of neurons on the brain&rsquo;s surface or cortex.</p><p>In a new study, researchers from UCLA trialed a newer, more precise and more personalized version of tDCS, called high definition tDCS or HD-tDCS, as a way of treating depression.</p><p>&ldquo;By honing in on the precise brain regions affected by depression, we&rsquo;ve shown that stimulation can significantly improve mood and daily functioning,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s lead author, <a href="http://www.bmap.ucla.edu/about/peopledetails/mayank_jog/">Mayank Anant Jog</a>, PhD, assistant professor of neurology at UCLA Health. &ldquo;Our data indicates that HD-tDCS therapy may also be effective for treating anxiety disorders, though dedicated studies to investigate this possibility are needed.&rdquo;</p><p>HD-tDCS enables more precise targeting of specific cortical regions by using a combination of smaller electrodes in combination with neuroimaging to determine the optimal brain target. In the present trial, the researchers delivered mild electrical currents to a specific brain area, the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC), a region often linked to mood regulation.</p><p>Sixty-eight adults aged 18 to 65 with moderate to severe &ndash; but not treatment-resistant &ndash; depression were enrolled in the randomized, double-blind, sham-controlled trial (that is, neither participants nor assessors knew who received real vs. fake treatment). Participants were either taking a stable regimen of antidepressants or not taking them at all. People with bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, or neurological disorders were excluded.</p><p>Participants were randomized to receive either active HD-tDCS therapy (at a current of 2 mA) or sham therapy for 20 minutes every day for 12 consecutive working days. This setup was personalized for each participant, using MRI scans and <a href="https://www.modalis.com.au/tms-therapies/what-is-tms/what-is-neural-navigation/#:~:text=What%20is%20Neuronavigation?%20%2D%20Modalis,structure%20and%20external%20navigation%20points.">neuronavigation</a> to precisely target the DLPFC. The active group received a current of 2 mA with brief (30-second) periods of ramping, whereas the sham group got a ramp-up/ramp-down current that felt real but wasn&rsquo;t therapeutically active. The main outcome the researchers were testing for was a change in depression severity using the <a href="https://www.mdcalc.com/calc/10043/hamilton-depression-rating-scale-hamd">Hamilton Depression Rating Scale</a> (HAM-D). Secondary measures included remission and response rates, side effects, and exploratory tests for anxiety symptoms.</p><div><figure><div><figcaption>Anatomy of the prefrontal cortex</figcaption><p>Wikimedia Commons/Zahr &amp; Sullivan (Public Domain)</p></div></figure> </div><p>Depression scores dropped in both groups, but more so in the active HD-tDCS group. The average improvement in the active group was &ndash;7.8 points on HAM-D, and in the sham group, &ndash;5.6 points. This difference was statistically significant. Regarding remission rates, 39.5% of active participants went into remission (defined as a HAM-D score of &le; 7), compared to only 13.3% in the sham group.</p><p>Some benefits were seen halfway through treatment (day six), suggesting faster improvement than standard antidepressants or psychotherapy, which usually take weeks to produce an effect. Anxiety scores also improved more in the active group, hinting that HD-tDCS could help both depression and anxiety. The treatment was generally well-tolerated. Mild side effects included skin redness, itching, or burning sensations at the electrode site, but these were minimal. No serious adverse effects were reported.</p><p>&ldquo;Overall, the HD-tDCS therapy was effective and well-tolerated, with only mild to no side-effects observed in the study,&rdquo; said Katherine Narr, a professor in UCLA&rsquo;s Department of Neurology and the study&rsquo;s senior author. "Coupled with tDCS&rsquo;s potential for convenient at-home use, this approach may offer a new treatment option for those seeking alternatives to medication or talk therapy.&rdquo;</p><p>The sample size was smaller than planned, partly due to COVID-19-related recruitment issues. Further, the trial wasn&rsquo;t designed to examine how HD-tDCS interacted with antidepressants, so any combined effects remain unclear. While the sham group only received a very tiny current, it may not have been completely inert. Participants were only tracked for four weeks after treatment, so the long-term effectiveness of the treatment isn&rsquo;t known. It&rsquo;s unknown whether the effects fade without the administration of &ldquo;booster&rdquo; sessions. And, while treatment was individualized, the researchers didn&rsquo;t directly compare personalized vs. non-personalized HD-tDCS.</p><p>Despite these limitations, HD-tDCS could become a fast-acting, non-drug option for people with moderate to severe depression, especially those who can&rsquo;t tolerate medication side effects. If refined, this kind of treatment could be adapted for safe, at-home treatments in the future. It&rsquo;s promising that HD-tDCS also lowered anxiety.</p><p>Follow-up studies could test whether mood improvements continue during a longer treatment period with appropriate maintenance treatments.</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2838763?guestAccessKey=aef661b6-9a93-47b1-93ef-b6dd96c7a51c&amp;utm_source=for_the_media&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;utm_content=tfl&amp;utm_term=091125"><i>JAMA Network Open</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.uclahealth.org/news/release/personalized-brain-stimulation-shows-benefit-depression">UCLA Health</a></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/1133d76/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1854x1236+0+0/resize/1440x960!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F76%2F9d%2F3f081ee04d9e95582fe6258d72fd%2Fprefrontal-cortex-copy.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: A new <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2838763?guestAccessKey=aef661b6-9a93-47b1-93ef-b6dd96c7a51c&amp;utm_source=for_the_media&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;utm_content=tfl&amp;utm_term=091125">study</a> shows that a personalized, precise form of brain stimulation, HD-tDCS, can rapidly ease depression symptoms – and even reduce anxiety – offering a promising drug-free alternative with only mild side effects.</p><p>We’ve reported on research that used transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) to improve cognitive functioning and treat depression. tDCS involves delivering a low-intensity direct current via electrodes on the scalp to trigger changes in the excitability of neurons on the brain’s surface or cortex.</p><p>In a new study, researchers from UCLA trialed a newer, more precise and more personalized version of tDCS, called high definition tDCS or HD-tDCS, as a way of treating depression.</p><p>“By honing in on the precise brain regions affected by depression, we’ve shown that stimulation can significantly improve mood and daily functioning,” said the study’s lead author, Mayank Anant Jog, PhD, assistant professor of neurology at UCLA Health. “Our data indicates that HD-tDCS therapy may also be effective for treating anxiety disorders, though dedicated studies to investigate this possibility are needed.”</p><p>HD-tDCS enables more precise targeting of specific cortical regions by using a combination of smaller electrodes in combination with neuroimaging to determine the optimal brain target. In the present trial, the researchers delivered mild electrical currents to a specific brain area, the left dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC), a region often linked to mood regulation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nixx2j/a_new_study_shows_that_a_personalized_precise/nem9s0p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Unfortunately, there are some obvious red flags in this study that raise concerns about the validity of the conclusions beyond the obvious sample size/power considerations. </p><ul><li>the sham group showed similar reductions over time as the treatment group. </li><li>the lack of time series analysis, instead relying on post hoc t-tests in a study that clearly has time dependencies and confounders</li></ul><p>These factors require a profoundly different approach to the analysis and inferences drawn from the trends that are clearly in the data.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nixx2j/a_new_study_shows_that_a_personalized_precise/nenrf1e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I have treatment-resistant depression, and have been on over 9 different antidepressants over the past 20 years. I had magnetic cranial therapy or TMS sessions every day for almost 2 months a year or 2 ago. It did absolutely nothing to improve my depression. So I&#39;m very skeptical of any sort of brain stimulation outside of ECT.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nixx2j/a_new_study_shows_that_a_personalized_precise/nemdhqe/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 05:26:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/new-study-finds-strong-links-between-prejudice-and-support-for-political-violence-in-the-united-states/</link><title>New study finds strong links between prejudice and support for political violence in the United States. Racist beliefs were strongly endorsed by 19.5% of 9,385 Americans surveyed, 16.9% for transphobia, 9.8% for xenophobia, 7.7% for hostile sexist views, and 5% for strong Islamophobic attitudes. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niwcl1/new_study_finds_strong_links_between_prejudice/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niwcl1/new_study_finds_strong_links_between_prejudice/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 9 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niwcl1/new_study_finds_strong_links_between_prejudice/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/man-with-gun-entering-building.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in <em><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667193X25002455">The Lancet Regional Health &ndash; Americas</a></em> suggests that various forms of prejudice are strongly tied to the belief that political violence is justified in the United States. People who expressed the most intense agreement with these prejudiced views were also more likely to say they supported or would personally engage in violence to achieve political objectives. When these forms of bias were combined into a broader measure of generalized hostility, the association with violent attitudes became even more pronounced.</p><p>The research was conducted by a team at the University of California, Davis, as part of a larger project to track support for political violence in the U.S. over time. The researchers aimed to quantify how various types of bias contribute to a person&rsquo;s willingness to justify or commit acts of political violence. They used the term &ldquo;allophobia&rdquo; to describe a generalized fear or hatred of others&mdash;an umbrella category that includes racism, antisemitism, xenophobia, Islamophobia, transphobia, hostile sexism, and homonegativity.</p><p>Concerns about the potential for widespread political violence in the United States have increased in recent years, particularly following the January 6, 2021 attack on the U.S. Capitol, the attempted assassination of Donald Trump, the assassination of Democratic Minnesota state Rep. Melissa Hortman, and the assassination of conservative activist Charlie Kirk. While past research has suggested that individual forms of prejudice are linked to violent behavior, the new study is one of the first to quantify how these views relate to political violence specifically, and on a nationally representative scale.</p><p>The study&rsquo;s findings are drawn from the second wave of an annual, nationally representative longitudinal survey, conducted between May 18 and June 8, 2023. A total of 9,385 adults completed the questionnaire, reflecting an 84 percent completion rate. The survey sample was weighted to mirror national demographics, with respondents averaging nearly 49 years of age. Just over half were women, and more than 60 percent identified as white and non-Hispanic.</p><p>Participants were asked to respond to a series of statements aimed at measuring prejudice toward various groups, including immigrants, Muslims, Jewish people, women, sexual minorities, gender-diverse individuals, and racial minorities. These questions were adapted from validated psychological scales but presented in shortened formats.</p><p>For example, to assess homonegativity, respondents rated their agreement with statements such as &ldquo;Gay men and lesbian women should stop shoving their lifestyle down other people&rsquo;s throats&rdquo; and &ldquo;Celebrations such as Gay Pride Day are ridiculous.&rdquo; Racism was assessed with items like &ldquo;Discrimination against whites is as big a problem as discrimination against Blacks and other minorities.&rdquo;</p><p>Transphobia was evaluated through items including &ldquo;I think there is something wrong with a person who says they are neither a man nor a woman,&rdquo; and &ldquo;I avoid people on the street whose gender is unclear to me.&rdquo; Xenophobia was measured with statements such as &ldquo;Interacting with immigrants makes me uneasy&rdquo; and &ldquo;I am afraid that our own culture will be lost with an increase in immigration.&rdquo;</p><p>Islamophobia was probed with items like &ldquo;Most Muslims living in the United States are more prone to violence than other people,&rdquo; while antisemitism included agreement with the idea that &ldquo;Jewish people have too much power in the media&rdquo; or &ldquo;talk about the Holocaust just to further their political agenda.&rdquo; Hostile sexism was assessed using statements such as &ldquo;Women seek to gain power by getting control over men&rdquo; and &ldquo;When women lose to men in a fair competition, they typically complain about being discriminated against.&rdquo;</p><p>In addition to these measures, the survey included multiple questions about political violence. Respondents were asked how much they agreed with general statements such as, &ldquo;True American patriots may have to resort to violence in order to save our country,&rdquo; and &ldquo;The United States needs a civil war to set things right.&rdquo; They were also asked whether they thought violence was justified in specific scenarios, such as stopping an election from being stolen, preventing illegal immigration, or protecting an &ldquo;American way of life based on Western European traditions.&rdquo;</p><p>Those who endorsed the use of violence were then asked about their personal willingness to damage property, threaten or injure someone, or even kill someone to achieve a political objective. Another set of items gauged how likely they were to use a firearm in such a situation, including openly carrying a gun, threatening someone with it, or shooting someone.</p><p>Among the seven forms of prejudice measured, homonegativity was the most prevalent, with 26.6 percent of respondents strongly agreeing with at least one related statement. Racist beliefs were strongly endorsed by 19.5 percent of participants, followed by 16.9 percent for transphobia and 9.8 percent for xenophobia. Hostile sexist views were strongly endorsed by 7.7 percent of respondents, while 5.0 percent expressed strong Islamophobic attitudes. Antisemitism was the least commonly endorsed, but still present, with 2.9 percent of respondents expressing strong agreement.</p><p>The researchers found that strong agreement with each type of prejudice was consistently associated with higher support for political violence. People who strongly agreed with Islamophobic statements, for example, were over 50 percentage points more likely to say that political violence was usually or always justified in at least one scenario. They were also about 12.5 percentage points more likely to say they would be willing to kill someone to achieve a political objective.</p><p>While Islamophobia showed the strongest individual link to violent attitudes, similar patterns were found across all seven forms of prejudice. The least prevalent forms of prejudice&mdash;such as antisemitism&mdash;tended to have the strongest connections to support for violence. In contrast, more commonly held biases like homonegativity had smaller but still significant associations. This pattern suggests that people who strongly endorse rarer prejudices may hold more extreme views overall, which could make them more prone to violent beliefs or behavior.</p><p>When the researchers combined all seven forms of prejudice into a single measure of &ldquo;allophobia,&rdquo; the associations with support for violence became even more pronounced. People who strongly agreed with multiple types of bias were significantly more likely to endorse statements such as &ldquo;The United States needs a civil war to set things right&rdquo; or &ldquo;Our American way of life is disappearing so fast that we may have to use force to save it.&rdquo; These individuals were also more likely to say they would be armed with a gun or even use one against someone in the future, if they believed the political situation warranted it.</p><p>&ldquo;The vast majority of Americans reject these harmful beliefs, just as they reject political violence,&rdquo; said lead author Garen Wintemute. &ldquo;We cannot eradicate such beliefs, but we must work to prevent them from leading to acts of violence.&rdquo;</p><p>The results suggest that people who harbor multiple forms of group-based hostility may pose a particularly high risk for endorsing or engaging in political violence. The authors compare the size of these associations to <a href="https://www.psypost.org/pro-trump-maga-republicans-much-more-likely-to-endorse-delusional-and-pro-violence-statements-study-finds/">what they previously found</a> among supporters of extremist groups like the Proud Boys or QAnon, as well as among people who frequently carry firearms in public.</p><p>Notably, the study also found that phobias were moderately to strongly correlated with each other. For example, people who held xenophobic beliefs were also likely to endorse Islamophobia, while those who expressed transphobic views tended to also agree with hostile sexist statements. This clustering of biases aligns with theories suggesting that people who support group-based hierarchies often generalize their dislike across multiple marginalized groups.</p><p>While the study&rsquo;s findings are based on self-reported attitudes rather than actual behavior, the researchers suggest that such attitudes are meaningful indicators of risk. They argue that people who strongly endorse these prejudices should be considered high-risk not just for targeted hate crimes, but for political violence more broadly. The connection appears to extend beyond group-specific animosity and into a more general willingness to use force in the political realm.</p><p>The authors note that while deep-seated prejudices may be resistant to change, there may still be ways to reduce the risk that these beliefs lead to violence. One approach could be to &ldquo;uncouple&rdquo; hostile beliefs from violent behaviors, possibly by using social pressure or persuasion. For example, previous survey waves have shown that individuals who initially supported the idea of civil war were often willing to reconsider their stance if family members urged them to. In other cases, traditional threat assessment or law enforcement interventions might be necessary.</p><p>The researchers also point to potential policy implications. In particular, they suggest that firearm permitting processes and extreme risk protection orders could take into account evidence of hostility toward marginalized groups, especially when combined with prior threats or violent behavior. California has recently implemented such a policy for its gun violence restraining orders.</p><p>Still, the study has limitations. Because it is cross-sectional, it cannot establish causal relationships. The researchers acknowledge the potential for sampling error, response bias, and other issues common to survey research. Social desirability bias may have led some participants to underreport their support for violence or their prejudiced beliefs. The findings may also have shifted since the time of data collection, given recent events that may influence public opinion.</p><p>The researchers emphasize that their results reflect attitudes held at the population level, rather than predicting any one person&rsquo;s future actions. They argue that identifying clusters of beliefs associated with political violence can help inform prevention strategies and improve public safety.</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667193X25002455">Fear, loathing, and support for political violence in the United States: findings from a nationally representative survey</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Garen J. Wintemute, Bradley Velasquez, Aaron B. Shev, Elizabeth A. Tomsich, Mona A. Wright, Paul M. Reeping, Sonia L. Robinson, Daniel J. Tancredi, and Veronica A. Pear.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://sp-ao.shortpixel.ai/client/to_webp,q_glossy,ret_img,w_250,h_85/https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/follow-on-google-news-1.png"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Ok so did anyone else notice this article is dated in the future?…… should we be concerned about that……November 2025?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niwcl1/new_study_finds_strong_links_between_prejudice/nenfx1a/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the news release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article: </p><p><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667193X25002455">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2667193X25002455</a></p><p>From the linked article: </p><p><strong>New study finds strong links between prejudice and support for political violence in the United States</strong></p><p>A new study published in The Lancet Regional Health – Americas suggests that various forms of prejudice are strongly tied to the belief that political violence is justified in the United States. People who expressed the most intense agreement with these prejudiced views were also more likely to say they supported or would personally engage in violence to achieve political objectives. When these forms of bias were combined into a broader measure of generalized hostility, the association with violent attitudes became even more pronounced.</p><p>The research was conducted by a team at the University of California, Davis, as part of a larger project to track support for political violence in the U.S. over time. The researchers aimed to quantify how various types of bias contribute to a person’s willingness to justify or commit acts of political violence. They used the term “allophobia” to describe a generalized fear or hatred of others—an umbrella category that includes racism, antisemitism, xenophobia, Islamophobia, transphobia, hostile sexism, and homonegativity.</p><p>The study’s findings are drawn from the second wave of an annual, nationally representative longitudinal survey, conducted between May 18 and June 8, 2023. A total of 9,385 adults completed the questionnaire, reflecting an 84 percent completion rate. The survey sample was weighted to mirror national demographics, with respondents averaging nearly 49 years of age. Just over half were women, and more than 60 percent identified as white and non-Hispanic.</p><p>Among the seven forms of prejudice measured, homonegativity was the most prevalent, with 26.6 percent of respondents strongly agreeing with at least one related statement. <strong>Racist beliefs were strongly endorsed by 19.5 percent of participants, followed by 16.9 percent for transphobia and 9.8 percent for xenophobia. Hostile sexist views were strongly endorsed by 7.7 percent of respondents, while 5.0 percent expressed strong Islamophobic attitudes</strong>. Antisemitism was the least commonly endorsed, but still present, with 2.9 percent of respondents expressing strong agreement.</p><p>The researchers found that strong agreement with each type of prejudice was consistently associated with higher support for political violence. People who strongly agreed with Islamophobic statements, for example, were over 50 percentage points more likely to say that political violence was usually or always justified in at least one scenario. They were also about 12.5 percentage points more likely to say they would be willing to kill someone to achieve a political objective.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niwcl1/new_study_finds_strong_links_between_prejudice/nely3sf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>People need to start downloading these studies to external hard drives as often as possible. We live in an age with millions of people capable of downloading and maintaining the equivalent of the library of Alexandra each.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niwcl1/new_study_finds_strong_links_between_prejudice/nemnoxc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 04:18:25 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
