<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=economics&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/economics</title><description>Hot posts in /r/economics (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>https://www.redditstatic.com/mweb2x/favicon/76x76.png</url><title>/r/economics</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link></image><item><link>https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/a-jobs-slump-spurred-trump-to-sack-his-stats-boss-this-time-around-he-s-got-no-one-to-blame-20250906-p5msve.html</link><title>A jobs slump spurred Trump to sack his stats boss. This time around he’s got no one to blame (smh.com.au)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9nrme/a_jobs_slump_spurred_trump_to_sack_his_stats_boss/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9nrme/a_jobs_slump_spurred_trump_to_sack_his_stats_boss/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9nrme/a_jobs_slump_spurred_trump_to_sack_his_stats_boss/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.2111%2C$multiply_0.7554%2C$ratio_1.777778%2C$width_1059%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/t_smh_analysis_no_age_social_wm/f6cd6cc534b3b8949ad4afc3dc2524a956fa56af' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><article><header></header><div><div><p><strong>Washington: </strong>The latest employment report in the United States is bad news for a president whose agenda revolves around <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p5labn">returning America to a &ldquo;golden age&rdquo;</a>, driven largely by a resurgence in manufacturing.</p><p>It shows jobs growth continues to stagnate, with just 22,000 positions created in August &ndash; while job losses in manufacturing were 12,000 for the month, and 78,000 for the year to date.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>Manufacturing job losses totalled 78,000 for the year so far, despite the Trump administration&rsquo;s bid to restore US factories.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>Bloomberg</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Last time Donald Trump received a weaker than expected jobs report from the Bureau of Labour Statistics &ndash; a month ago &ndash; he <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p5ml53">ordered the sacking of the agency&rsquo;s commissioner</a>, economist Erika McEntarfer.</p><p>This time, there&rsquo;s no figurehead to blame. Trump&rsquo;s pick to replace McEntarfer is yet to be confirmed by the US Senate.</p></div><div><p>The bureau found total non-farm payrolls, a widely watched indicator of US economic health, rose just 22,000 in August &ldquo;and has shown little change since April&rdquo;. Job gains in the healthcare sector were partially offset by losses in the federal government and in mining, quarrying, and oil and gas extraction, it said.</p><p>The August report also made further revisions to earlier months&rsquo; data, finding that in June, the US economy actually lost 13,000 jobs, rather than gaining 14,000 (a number which had already been revised down from 147,000). The July jobs growth figure was revised upward slightly to 79,000.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>The jobs report was the first since Donald Trump sensationally sacked the head of the Bureau of Labour Statistics for announcing weak data.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>Bloomberg</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Kevin Hassett, the director of Trump&rsquo;s National Security Council, told CNBC that while the figures were &ldquo;a little bit disappointing&rdquo;, he expected them to be revised up later.</p><p>That&rsquo;s entirely possible. Survey completion rates have fallen markedly since the pandemic, making it difficult for the bureau to provide accurate data in a timely, monthly fashion. That was true when McEntarfer was sacked for revising figures down, and it&rsquo;s true today.</p></div></div><div><div><div><p>Overall, the unemployment rate ticked up to 4.3 per cent &ndash; the highest since September 2017, outside the COVID-19 spike, though still low.</p><p>Trump reacted to the latest data by repeating his calls for the Federal Reserve to cut interest rates. &ldquo;[Fed chair] <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p5mj6v">Jerome &lsquo;Too Late&rsquo; Powell</a> should have lowered rates long ago. As usual, he&rsquo;s &lsquo;Too Late!&rsquo;&rdquo; Trump posted on social media.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>US Federal Reserve chairman Jerome Powell in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, for the Fed&rsquo;s annual gathering of global central bankers.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>Bloomberg</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Speaking at the central bank&rsquo;s annual summit in Jackson Hole, Wyoming last month, Powell gave a strong signal that rate cuts are on the way, noting the risks to employment were rising and &ldquo;may warrant adjusting our policy stance&rdquo;.</p><p>Scott Paul, the president of the Alliance for American Manufacturing, agreed the new report ought to spur a rate cut. But he also warned that Trump needed to finalise his policies on tariffs and trade.</p></div><div><p>&ldquo;Concluding tariff actions and trade deals to provide businesses with the certainty they need to hire, invest in new capital equipment, and realign supply chains,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Manufacturing will be treading water until we see those changes.&rdquo;</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>Sacked BLS chief Erika McEntarfer.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>US Bureau of Labor Statistics</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Justin Wolfers, an Australian economics professor at the University of Michigan, said the data was worrying and indicated rosy assessments of the US economy&rsquo;s resilience were premature. &ldquo;Bad policy leads to bad outcomes, but the actual economy doesn&rsquo;t move at the pace of the political cycle,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Wolfers credited bureau staff for compiling the data &ldquo;despite the arbitrary firing of their boss, uninformed social media insults, and the prospect of being led by an unqualified ideologue&rdquo;.</p><p>Trump&rsquo;s pick for the job, E.J. Antoni, is the chief economist at the Heritage Foundation, a right-wing think tank that produced the conservative blueprint Project 2025. On Friday, CNN reported Antoni once ran a now-deleted Twitter account that contained sexually degrading attacks on Kamala Harris, conspiracy theories and anti-gay remarks.</p></div><div><p>Meanwhile, Trump is engaged in a different form of reality-denial. Hours before the employment data was released, he was asked whether he would accept the numbers. He dismissed the question, saying &ldquo;the real numbers&rdquo; would come out in a year or so, once his economic agenda was realised.</p><p>Life is more difficult when you can&rsquo;t just shoot the messenger.</p><p><b><i>Get a note directly from our foreign </i></b><b><i>correspondents </i></b><b><i>on what&rsquo;s making headlines around the world. </i></b><a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p56l7u"><b><i>Sign up for our weekly What in the World newsletter</i></b></a><b><i>.</i></b></p></div></div><div><section><header><h2>Most Viewed in World</h2></header><p><span><span>Loading</span></span></p></section></div></div></article><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.189%2C$multiply_0.7725%2C$ratio_1.5%2C$width_756%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/c0ac78b194c30249aa466dce98d35c8904cb6918"></p><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.378%2C$multiply_0.7725%2C$ratio_1.5%2C$width_756%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/98d6bda8b8730d5656ecea5ef1abceb81c48bfda"></p><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.378%2C$multiply_0.7725%2C$ratio_1.5%2C$width_756%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/79adde6be61b3428b7c0b148f8f8474f5b426859"></p><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.844%2C$multiply_0.7487%2C$ratio_1%2C$width_378%2C$x_0%2C$y_35/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/6e87f68ac53bafa298818989bda5b97cd9a306aa474f1bd273691b84f39c856e"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 07:41:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/economy-jobs-report-trump-agenda</link><title>Trump’s economy problem is threatening his entire agenda (cnn.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9fcuf/trumps_economy_problem_is_threatening_his_entire/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9fcuf/trumps_economy_problem_is_threatening_his_entire/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 11 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9fcuf/trumps_economy_problem_is_threatening_his_entire/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2230148969.jpg?c=16x9&q=w_800,c_fill' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>President Donald Trump came into office with massive plans to overhaul the way the US government operates and consolidate power in himself. </p><p>And he&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/11/politics/trump-blowback-looming-analysis">been largely successful</a> in implementing that vision, thanks to a cowed Congress, timid institutions and a languid judiciary. </p><p>But there are growing signs that his entire agenda could be undercut and his party could face massive political consequences because of his hubris on the single most important issue to Americans: the economy. </p><p>A new <a href="https://www.cnn.com/business/live-news/us-jobs-report-august-2025">Bureau of Labor Statistics report</a> Friday confirms some the worst fears about a worsening jobs market. A brief recap: </p><div><ul> <li> <span> Preliminary numbers show just 22,000 jobs added in August, a very low number for an economy that generally needs to create about 100,000 jobs every month to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/11/03/economy/jobs-report-october-final">keep up with population growth</a>. </span> </li> <li> <span> Revisions in other months mean the economy has created only an estimated 107,000 jobs over the last four months combined. Apart from recessions and their aftermaths, those are the worst numbers in decades. </span> </li> <li> <span> June&rsquo;s jobs numbers were revised into negative territory (13,000 jobs lost), making it the first negative month since December 2020. </span> </li> <li> <span> Despite Trump&rsquo;s promises of his tariffs revitalizing U.S. manufacturing boom, that industry has now lost 78,000 jobs this year. </span> </li> </ul> </div><p>The Trump administration has made pains to try to neutralize headlines about these jobs numbers, including last month by <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/04/business/bureau-of-labor-statistics-jobs-report-explainer-hnk">baselessly suggesting the numbers are being rigged</a> to make them look bad. (There is no evidence for this, and there are safeguards to prevent such manipulation.) After a bad July jobs report, Trump fired the head of BLS and now aims to replace her with <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/kfile-ej-antoni-bureau-of-labor-statistics-twitter-account-vis">a controversial loyalist</a>. </p><p>If Trump&rsquo;s past is predicate, such conspiracy theories are likely to be revisited. But on Friday morning, there was apparently only so much the administration could do to spin these numbers. </p><p>Trump himself took aim at Jerome Powell, re-upping a familiar attack on the Fed Chair over his not lowering interest rates. Others acknowledged the report wasn&rsquo;t what they were hoping for. </p><p>&ldquo;This jobs number was certainly a little bit of a disappointment right now,&rdquo; top White House economic adviser Kevin Hassett said on CNBC, while predicting some upward revisions. </p><p>Labor Secretary Lori Chavez-DeRemer acknowledged on Fox Business that the new report &ldquo;underperformed a bit,&rdquo; while emphasizing that it at least contained some jobs gains (a very low bar, to be sure). </p><p>And Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick seemed to plead for patience, asking people to judge Trump&rsquo;s jobs record not today but in 12 months. </p><p>&ldquo;You look at the unemployment rate numbers today &ndash; wait until a year from today,&rdquo; Lutnick said in CNBC. &ldquo;Wow. It will be amazing numbers.&rdquo; </p><p>But that&rsquo;s asking a lot. People are already judging Trump&rsquo;s stewardship of the economy more negatively than ever before. And while Trump arguably earned the benefit of the doubt when his tariffs didn&rsquo;t lead to immediate and crushing consequences, he still faces a deeply skeptical public and potentially disastrous political consequences. </p><p>A Quinnipiac University poll in late August showed Trump with his <a href="https://poll.qu.edu/poll-release?releaseid=3929">worst economic approval numbers to date</a>, in either of his two terms: 57% disapproving to 39% approving. </p><p><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/694370/trump-ratings-mood-stay-tepid-august.aspx">Gallup</a> pegged his economic approval rating at just 37%, after averaging 52% in his first term. Just 29% of independents approved. </p><p>A <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/910985644/Yahoo-YouGov-Crime-Poll-August-2025">Yahoo News-YouGov poll</a> showed Americans disapproved of Trump on the &ldquo;cost of living&rdquo; by more than a 2-to-1 margin, 62-29%, and by a large margin on trade and tariffs, 58-35%. </p><div><picture><source height="undefined" width="679" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_679,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="967" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_967,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill" alt="Customers enter a grocery store in Westminster, California, on August 7." height="1600" width="2399"></source></source></source></source></source></picture> </div><p>We&rsquo;re also seeing some real cracks even in Trump&rsquo;s ever-loyal base. The Yahoo poll showed 27% of Republicans disapproved of Trump on the cost of living. And a Pew Research Center poll last month showed <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2025/08/14/how-americans-view-the-trump-administrations-tariff-policies-and-the-gops-budget-and-tax-bill/">32% of Republican-leaning voters disapproved</a> of his tariffs strategy. </p><p>All of which suggests the patience of even Trump&rsquo;s loyal supporters has already been tested. Are they really going to give him a year to straighten it all out? </p><p>The danger for Trump is that the economic picture turns bad enough that it sours Americans on the entire enterprise. </p><p>Trump&rsquo;s power plays are largely built on acquiescence. People might not like his methods, but they don&rsquo;t necessarily want to fight him on it. As long as these things don&rsquo;t impact them directly, the backlash is limited. </p><p>Indeed, many of Trump&rsquo;s most controversial initiatives are pretty unpopular &ndash; things like deporting people without due process, putting troops on US soil, the Department of Government Efficiency cuts, and Trump&rsquo;s signature agenda bill that cut Medicaid. We&rsquo;ve already seen <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/07/17/politics/gop-malaise-trump-epstein-analysis">cracks in Trump&rsquo;s base on some of these issues</a> &ndash; along with, most pronouncedly, the administration&rsquo;s handling of the Jeffrey Epstein files. </p><p>But none of those issues has caused a real revolt by Congress or anyone who could impede his agenda. </p><p>The economy is perhaps the one thing that could change that rather quickly, and bring these readily apparent concerns about his presidency to the fore. </p><p>Should things continue to turn sour, Trump and Co. can blame BLS data and the Federal Reserve&rsquo;s interest rates all they want. But it won&rsquo;t be difficult for Americans to trace all of it to something that&rsquo;s much easier to grasp and attach to Trump: his economy-rocking moves to unilaterally implement huge tariffs. These are moves that he made without consulting Congress, after all, and despite the (gently expressed) reservations of congressional Republicans who spent decades hailing free trade. </p><p>Trump did this despite persistent inflation that still hadn&rsquo;t really abated. He voluntarily took ownership of an already-tenuous situation and injected it with a huge amount of uncertainty. </p><p>Trump invested gobs of political capital in this. It&rsquo;s looking more and more like a bad bet. </p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2025-09-05t135925z-374478399-rc2plga3zhi7-rtrmadp-3-usa-economy.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 01:29:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/squeezed-french-millennials-blame-boomers-backlash-over-soaring-deficit-2025-09-05/</link><title>Squeezed French millennials blame boomers in backlash over soaring deficit (reuters.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9akax/squeezed_french_millennials_blame_boomers_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9akax/squeezed_french_millennials_blame_boomers_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9akax/squeezed_french_millennials_blame_boomers_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 22:23:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/05/jobs-report-august-2025.html</link><title>Payrolls rose 22,000 in August, less than expected in further sign of hiring slowdown (cnbc.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n941b8/payrolls_rose_22000_in_august_less_than_expected/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n941b8/payrolls_rose_22000_in_august_less_than_expected/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n941b8/payrolls_rose_22000_in_august_less_than_expected/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108194186-1756986229072-gettyimages-2228223483-US_JOBS.jpeg?v=1756986317&w=1920&h=1080' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><p>Job creation sputtered in August, adding to recent signs of labor market weakening and likely keeping the Federal Reserve on track for a widely anticipated interest rate cut later this month.</p><p><a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.nr0.htm">Nonfarm payrolls</a> increased by just 22,000 for the month, while the unemployment rate rose to 4.3%, according to a Bureau of Labor Statistics report Friday. Economists surveyed by Dow Jones had been looking for payrolls to rise by 75,000.</p><p>The report showed a marked slowdown from the July increase of 79,000, which was revised up by 6,000. Revisions also showed a net loss of 13,000 in June after the prior estimate was lowered by 27,000.</p></div><div><p>"The job market is stalling short of the runway," said Daniel Zhao, chief economist at jobs site Glassdoor. "The labor market is losing lift, and August's report, along with downward revisions, suggests we're heading into turbulence without the soft landing achieved."</p><p>Markets largely disregarded the report, with <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/04/stock-market-today-live-updates-.html">stocks up at the open</a> and Treasury yields sharply lower. Traders in the futures markets raised the probability of a quarter percentage point Fed rate cut to 100% and went even further, pricing in a 12% probability of a half-point move, according to the CME Group's <a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/markets/interest-rates/cme-fedwatch-tool.html?redirect=/trading/interest-rates/countdown-to-fomc.html">FedWatc</a>h gauge.</p><p>The payrolls count was the first since President Donald <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/08/01/trump-erika-mcentarfer-jobs-report-fired.html">Trump fired former BLS Commissioner Erika McEntarfer</a> following the release of the July jobs report a month ago. The move came after the report showed not just a weak level of job creation but also dramatic reductions in previous months' totals.</p><p>In McEntarfer's place, the president nominated economist E.J. Antoni, a Trump loyalist from the Heritage Foundation who previously had criticized the BLS numbers as being politically distorted. William Wiatrowski is serving as acting BLS commissioner.</p><p>While the pace of hiring was slow, average hourly earnings increased 0.3% for the month, meeting the estimate, though the annual gain of 3.7% was slightly below the forecast for 3.8%.</p></div><div><p>Hiring was held back by a payroll reduction in the federal government, which reported a decline of 15,000.</p><p>Health care again led sectors, adding 31,000 jobs, while social assistance contributed 16,000. Wholesale trade and manufacturing both saw declines of 12,000 on the month.</p><p>The report comes as markets widely expect the Fed to lower its benchmark interest rate by a quarter percentage point when it releases its next decision Sept. 17. Fed Chair <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/jay-powell/">Jerome Powell</a> and his fellow policymakers also have been under heavy criticism from the president as they have been on hold since last cutting in December 2024.</p><p>Though most economic indicators indicate continued expansion, Fed officials have expressed concern about a slowdown in hiring even as layoffs have held fairly steady. At the same time, policymakers worry that <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/donald-trump/">Trump</a>'s tariffs could reignite inflation, with data indicating a slow but steady increase in prices over recent months.</p><p>"The warning bell that rang in the labor market a month ago just got louder. A weaker-than-expected jobs report all but seals a 25-basis-point rate cut later this month," said Olu Sonola, head of U.S. economic research at Fitch Ratings. "Four straight months of manufacturing job losses stand out. It's hard to argue that tariff uncertainty isn't a key driver of this weakness."</p><p>While the <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.b.htm">establishment survey</a> showed weak job creation, the more volatile <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.a.htm">household count</a>, used to calculate the unemployment rate, held better news.</p><p>That report showed an increase of 288,000 employed, though the ranks of the unemployed also rose by 148,000. The labor force participation rate edged higher to 62.3% while the labor force swelled by 436,000, accounting for the tick higher in the unemployment rate.</p></div><div><p>A broader measure of unemployment that includes discouraged workers and those holding part-time jobs for economic reasons climbed to 8.1%, a 0.2 percentage point increase and the highest level since October 2021.</p><p>Along with the jobs numbers tally, the BLS on Tuesday will release the initial estimate for annual benchmark revisions to the numbers dating back one year from March 2025.</p><p>Revisions have been a source of controversy, particularly in the post-Covid era as the response rate has declined, particularly for the headline establishment survey that asks businesses and government agencies to detail the pace of hiring.</p><p>The BLS typically releases its initial estimate with the first batch of survey responses it gets, then updates two times as it gets more information. However, Trump has accused the BLS of being politically biased. The firing of McEntarfer drew widespread criticism in the economics and markets community.</p><p>In a <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/05/jobs-hassett-trump-rates.html">CNBC interview</a>, National Economic Council Director Kevin Hassett said he expects the August payrolls count to get revised higher. In the past three years, the initial August count actually was revised lower from the initial estimate.</p><p><em>Correction: The BLS on Tuesday will release the initial estimate for annual benchmark revisions to the numbers dating back one year from March 2025. An earlier version misstated the timing.</em></p></div><div><h2>Don&rsquo;t miss these insights from CNBC PRO</h2></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108194833-17570757121757075709-41506113646-1080pnbcnews.jpg?v=1757075711&amp;w=750&amp;h=422&amp;vtcrop=y"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:03:40 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.redfin.com/news/sellers-vs-buyers-price-impact/</link><title>The U.S. Housing Market Has Nearly 500,000 More Sellers Than Buyers—the Most on Record. That Will Likely Cause Home Prices to Fall (redfin.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8l0wc/the_us_housing_market_has_nearly_500000_more/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8l0wc/the_us_housing_market_has_nearly_500000_more/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 28 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8l0wc/the_us_housing_market_has_nearly_500000_more/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.redfin.com/news/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/3513-Ashwood-Ave_Ext-1-scaled.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><main><div><div><div><ul> <li><strong><i>There are 34% more sellers in the market than buyers. At no other point in records dating back to 2013 have sellers outnumbered buyers this much. In other words, it&rsquo;s a buyer&rsquo;s market.</i></strong></li> </ul> <ul> <li><strong><i>Redfin expects home prices to drop 1% by the end of the year as a result. Prospective buyers may see their purchasing power increase, and prospective sellers should consider selling sooner rather than later.</i></strong></li> </ul> <ul> <li><strong><i>31 of the top 50 metros are buyer&rsquo;s markets. The strongest buyer&rsquo;s market is Miami, where sellers outnumber buyers roughly 3 to 1. The strongest seller&rsquo;s market is Newark, and the most balanced market is St. Louis.</i></strong></li> </ul> <ul> <li><strong><i>The condo market heavily favors buyers; there are 83% more condo sellers than buyers. By comparison, there are 28% more sellers than buyers in the single-family-home market.</i></strong></li> </ul><p><span>There are an estimated 1.9 million home sellers in the U.S. housing market and an estimated 1.5 million homebuyers. In other words, there are 33.7% more sellers than buyers (or 490,041 more, to be exact). At no other point in records dating back to 2013 have sellers outnumbered buyers by this large of a number or percentage. A year ago, sellers outnumbered buyers by just 6.5%, and two years ago, </span><i><span>buyers </span></i><span>outnumbered sellers.</span></p><p><span>There haven&rsquo;t been this many home sellers since March 2020. There haven&rsquo;t been this few buyers at any point in records dating back to 2013 aside from April 2020, when the onset of the coronavirus pandemic brought the housing market to a halt.</span></p><p><span>The most recent data point in this analysis is April 2025. The estimated number of sellers in the market is simply the number of active listings in the MLS. To estimate the number of buyers, we created a model that uses data on pending sales and </span><span>the typical time from a buyer&rsquo;s first tour to their purchase.</span><span> Scroll down for a full methodology and data on the 50 most populous U.S. metropolitan areas.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Redfin earlier this month </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/home-price-forecast-decline-2025"><span>predicted</span></a><span> that home prices will drop 1% year over year by the end of 2025, and the growing imbalance between buyers and sellers is the basis for that prediction. When sellers are competing for a small pool of buyers, that indicates a </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/buyers-market-february-2025/"><span>buyer&rsquo;s market</span></a><span>. And when it&rsquo;s a buyer&rsquo;s market, home prices can fall because buyers have negotiating power.&nbsp;</span> </p><p><b>Sellers outnumber buyers for several reasons:</b></p><ul> <li><b>It&rsquo;s expensive to buy a home:</b><span> High home prices and mortgage rates are scaring buyers off. The median home sale price rose 1.6% year over year to $431,931 in April. That&rsquo;s the slowest growth in nearly two years, but monthly housing payments still hit a </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/housing-market-update-record-high-housing-costs-sales-decline/"><span>record</span></a> <a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/housing-market-update-record-high-housing-costs-economic-uncertainty/"><span>high</span></a><span> last month because mortgage rates and prices remain elevated. The average 30-year-fixed mortgage rate was </span><a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=1bnGA"><span>6.73%</span></a><span> in April&mdash;more than double the record low hit during the pandemic.&nbsp;</span></li> <li><b>Economic uncertainty:</b> <span>Tariff talks, layoffs, and federal policy changes are among the other </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/19/business/fed-meeting-minutes-interest-rates.html"><span>factors</span></a><span> dampening homebuyer demand. A recent Redfin</span> <a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/survey-tariffs-major-purchase/"><span>survey</span></a> <span>found that nearly 1 in 4 Americans is scrapping plans to make a major purchase due to tariffs.&nbsp;</span></li> <li><b>The mortgage rate lock-in effect is easing:</b><span> Homeowners who have been sitting on ultra-low mortgage rates they scored during the pandemic are now </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/mortgage-rate-lock-in-effect-eases/"><span>giving up</span></a><span> those low rates and selling their homes. That&rsquo;s because for most people, it&rsquo;s not realistic to stay put forever; job changes, return to office mandates and divorce force people to move. The idea of taking on a higher mortgage rate also isn&rsquo;t as shocking as it was when rates first skyrocketed in 2022.&nbsp;</span></li> </ul><p><span>&ldquo;The balance of power in the U.S. housing market has shifted toward buyers, but a lot of sellers have yet to see or accept the writing on the wall. Many are still holding out hope that their home is the exception and will fetch top dollar,&rdquo; said Redfin Senior Economist </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/author/asad-khan/"><span>Asad Khan</span></a><span>. &ldquo;But as sellers see their homes sit longer on the market and notice fewer buyers coming through on tour, more of them will realize that the market has adjusted and reset their expectations accordingly.&rdquo;</span></p><p><span>Sellers are already gaining more data points on this front, and will likely face another reality&nbsp; check in the summer, when demand typically starts to slow. More than two of every five (44%) home listings in April had been on the market for 60 days or longer&mdash;the highest April share since 2020. Stale inventory is piling up in part because many sellers are overpricing their homes, using sky-high comps from the recent seller&rsquo;s market that aren&rsquo;t realistic today. In some cases, sellers are pricing high because they bought at the peak of the market and are trying to recoup their investment.&nbsp;</span></p><p><b>The takeaway for sellers:</b><span> Time is not on your side. If you are considering selling, do it sooner rather than later because home prices in your area may fall. If your home is already on the market and has been sitting for over a month, you may want to consider an improvement to your property or a reduction in price.</span></p><p><b>The takeaway for buyers: </b><span>Many Americans have already been and will remain priced out of the housing market, even if prices decline. But for those who are still in the game, don&rsquo;t get discouraged. Your purchasing power will increase if home prices fall, </span><a href="https://www.atlantafed.org/chcs/wage-growth-tracker"><span>wages</span></a><span> rise and mortgage rates remain steady as </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/home-price-forecast-decline-2025/"><span>expected</span></a><span>. Homes that would have been out of reach six months ago may come into reach as sellers entertain lower offers and concessions.</span></p><h3><b>History Shows That Home Prices Cool When Sellers Outnumber Buyers</b></h3><p><span><br> A change in the balance of buyers and sellers is a signal of what&rsquo;s to come with home prices. Aside from the onset of the pandemic, the last time sellers significantly outnumbered buyers was around the time mortgage rates jumped in 2018.</span></p><p><span>In November 2018, the average 30-year-fixed mortgage rate peaked at 4.87%, which was the highest level in nearly eight years and almost a full percentage point higher than a year earlier. One month later, sellers outnumbered buyers by 9.4%&mdash;the largest percentage since 2015 and a reversal from the prior year, when buyers outnumbered sellers. Three months later, home-price growth shrunk to the lowest level in at least six years, with prices rising 2% from a year earlier to $283,912.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>We saw a similar dynamic take hold in 2013-2014. As shown in the chart below, swings in the ratio of buyers to sellers are typically followed by similar swings in home-price growth.</span></p><p><span>Today, the imbalance between buyers and sellers is even greater, meaning there&rsquo;s more pressure on prices. Annual price growth has already slowed to 1.6% from 6.2% last spring, and we expect this trajectory to continue, ultimately causing prices to fall. The last time home prices posted a year-over-year decline was 2023.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Even as mortgage rates surged in 2022, buyers outnumbered sellers. Sellers most recently started outnumbering buyers in November 2023&mdash;the month after mortgage rates hit the highest level in over two decades, peaking at almost 8%. Homebuyer demand has been sluggish ever since, and is likely to remain so given widespread economic uncertainty and recession fears. What</span><i><span> has</span></i><span> changed recently is more sellers have started entering the market.&nbsp;</span></p><h3><b>Miami and West Palm Beach Are the Strongest Buyer&rsquo;s Markets, With Nearly Three Times More Sellers Than Buyers</b></h3><p><span><br> In </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/city/11458/FL/Miami"><span>Miami</span></a><span>, there are an estimated 21,672 home sellers and 7,280 homebuyers. That means there are 197.7% more sellers than buyers&mdash;the largest imbalance among the 50 most populous U.S. metropolitan areas. It&rsquo;s followed by </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/city/19373/FL/West-Palm-Beach"><span>West Palm Beach, FL</span></a><span> (182% more sellers than buyers), </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/city/6173/FL/Fort-Lauderdale"><span>Fort Lauderdale, FL</span></a><span> (179.3%), </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/city/30818/TX/Austin"><span>Austin, TX</span></a><span> (124.1%) and </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/city/8907/FL/Jacksonville"><span>Jacksonville, FL</span></a><span> (119.5%).</span></p><p><span>In this report, we define a market where there are over 10% more sellers than buyers as a buyer&rsquo;s market and a market where there are over 10% fewer sellers than buyers as a seller&rsquo;s market. A market where the gap is plus or minus 10% is considered a balanced market.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Overall, 31 of the 50 most populous metros are buyer&rsquo;s markets, 12 are balanced markets and seven are seller&rsquo;s markets. The buyer&rsquo;s markets are concentrated in the Sun Belt and on the West Coast, while balanced markets and seller&rsquo;s markets skew more toward the Midwest and East Coast. Scroll down for full metro-level data.</span></p><p><b>Top 10 Buyer&rsquo;s Markets: April 2025&nbsp;</b></p><table> <tbody> <tr> <td><b>U.S. metro area</b></td> <td><b>Sellers vs buyers: % difference</b></td> <td><b>Sellers</b></td> <td><b>Buyers</b></td> <td><b>Median home sale price</b></td> <td><b>Y/Y change in median home sale price</b></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Miami, FL&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>197.7%</span></td> <td><span>21,672</span></td> <td><span>7,280</span></td> <td><span>$574,696</span></td> <td><span>5.6%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>West Palm Beach, FL&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>182.0%</span></td> <td><span>18,075</span></td> <td><span>6,409</span></td> <td><span>$513,683</span></td> <td><span>2.7%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Fort Lauderdale, FL&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>179.3%</span></td> <td><span>21,018</span></td> <td><span>7,525</span></td> <td><span>$451,709</span></td> <td><span>1.2%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Austin, TX&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>124.1%</span></td> <td><span>17,386</span></td> <td><span>7,757</span></td> <td><span>$433,990</span></td> <td><span>-3.0%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Jacksonville, FL&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>119.5%</span></td> <td><span>14,479</span></td> <td><span>6,598</span></td> <td><span>$368,311</span></td> <td><span>-3.4%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Tampa, FL&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>118.6%</span></td> <td><span>26,917</span></td> <td><span>12,313</span></td> <td><span>$371,028</span></td> <td><span>-1.3%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Phoenix, AZ&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>100.6%</span></td> <td><span>32,418</span></td> <td><span>16,159</span></td> <td><span>$452,290</span></td> <td><span>-2.1%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Las Vegas, NV&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>92.1%</span></td> <td><span>13,814</span></td> <td><span>7,192</span></td> <td><span>$448,605</span></td> <td><span>2.4%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Orlando, FL&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>92.0%</span></td> <td><span>19,555</span></td> <td><span>10,184</span></td> <td><span>$407,411</span></td> <td><span>0.8%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Nashville, TN&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>90.0%</span></td> <td><span>14,935</span></td> <td><span>7,859</span></td> <td><span>$467,178</span></td> <td><span>0.0%</span></td> </tr> </tbody> </table><p><span>&ldquo;It has absolutely shifted to a buyer&rsquo;s market, which means house hunters have a lot more options&mdash;and room to negotiate,&rdquo; said </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/real-estate-agents/tim-harper"><span>Tim Harper</span></a><span>, a </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/premier"><span>Redfin Premier</span></a><span> real estate agent in </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/city/4302/FL/Daytona-Beach"><span>Daytona Beach, FL</span></a><span>. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s not uncommon for a buyer to get a home for 5% less than the list price and $10,000 in seller concessions. That&rsquo;s why it&rsquo;s important for sellers to make sure their home is in tip-top shape. </span><span>We&rsquo;re frequently recommending sellers do a lot of cosmetic repairs and maintenance to get buyers&rsquo; attention and stand out from the crowd. And of course, don&rsquo;t overprice.&rdquo;</span></p><p><span>The Sun Belt skyrocketed in popularity during the pandemic, when scores of homebuyers moved in from more expensive parts of the country, driving up housing costs and pricing many locals out of the market. To meet surging demand, homebuilders ramped up activity&mdash;especially in Florida and Texas&mdash;which is one reason there are now a lot more homes for sale than people who want to buy them.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Six of the top 10 buyer&rsquo;s markets are in Florida and one is in Texas (there are many more Texas markets in the top 20). Redfin </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/florida-homes-for-sale-record-high/"><span>reported</span></a><span> in February that Florida saw housing inventory hit the highest level on record, in part because it has been</span> <a href="https://www.census.gov/construction/bps/visualizations/datatool/index.html"><span>building</span></a> <span>more homes than any state but Texas. Florida is also grappling with intensifying natural disasters, which has caused home insurance costs to skyrocket and prompted some homeowners to leave the state. Plus, soaring HOA fees are prompting many Florida </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/florida-condo-prices-rise-inland/"><span>condo</span></a><span> owners to sell.</span></p><p><span>Parts of Florida and Texas are already seeing home prices fall. The median sale price in Jacksonville fell 3.4% year over year in April&mdash;the biggest decline in the country aside from </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/city/13654/CA/Oakland"><span>Oakland, CA</span></a><span> (also a buyer&rsquo;s market). Austin came in third place, with a 3% drop.</span></p><p><span>On average, home prices were roughly flat (+0.5%) from a year earlier across the top 10 buyer&rsquo;s markets in April. By comparison, prices rose an average of 4.5% in the 12 balanced markets and 6.9% in the seven seller&rsquo;s markets. These are weighted averages based on the number of homes sold by metro in April 2025.</span></p><h3><b>St. Louis Is the Most Balanced Market; Newark Is the Strongest Seller&rsquo;s Market</b></h3><p><span><br> In St. Louis, there are an estimated 9,327 home sellers in the market and 9,447 buyers. That means there are 1.3% fewer sellers than buyers, making St. Louis the most balanced housing market among the 50 most populous metros.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Next come Virginia Beach, VA (1.7% more sellers than buyers), Kansas City, MO (2.3% more sellers than buyers), Chicago (4.2% more sellers than buyers), and San Jose, CA (4.7% fewer sellers than buyers). The other balanced markets are Cincinnati, Boston, New York, Minneapolis, Philadelphia, Warren, MI and Washington, D.C.</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;Different markets are balanced for different reasons,&rdquo; Khan said. &ldquo;In Cincinnati, homebuyer demand is stronger than the national average, perhaps due to the relatively low cost of housing. At the same time, listings are rising, mirroring the national trend. Together, these forces are creating a balanced market. In Chicago, demand is weak, mirroring the national trend. But inventory is also weak, which creates balance in another way.&rdquo;</span></p><p><span>There are just seven seller&rsquo;s markets. Newark, NJ is the strongest seller&rsquo;s market, with an estimated 5,241 sellers and 9,899 buyers&mdash;or 47.1% fewer sellers than buyers. This imbalance helped Newark home sellers fetch record-high prices last month; the metro&rsquo;s median sale price rose 12.2% from a year earlier&mdash;the biggest gain among the top 50 metros.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The other seller&rsquo;s markets are Nassau County, NY (41.7% fewer sellers than buyers), Montgomery County, PA (38.4% fewer), Cleveland (24.8%), New Brunswick, NJ (18.6%), Providence, RI (16.1%) and Baltimore (11.8%).&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>New construction can have a significant influence on whether negotiating power lies with buyers or sellers because it impacts the balance of supply and demand. The South </span><a href="https://www.census.gov/construction/bps/current.html"><span>issues</span></a><span> the most single-unit building permits, followed by the West, the Midwest and the Northeast. As mentioned earlier, many of the nation&rsquo;s buyer&rsquo;s markets are in the South or on the West Coast, and many of the balanced markets and seller&rsquo;s markets are in the Midwest or on the East Coast.&nbsp;</span></p><p><b>The 7 Seller&rsquo;s Markets: April 2025&nbsp;</b></p><table> <tbody> <tr> <td><b>U.S. metro area</b></td> <td><b>Sellers vs buyers: % difference</b></td> <td><b>Sellers</b></td> <td><b>Buyers</b></td> <td><b>Median home sale price</b></td> <td><b>Y/Y change in median home sale price</b></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Newark, NJ&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>-47.1%</span></td> <td><span>5,241</span></td> <td><span>9,899</span></td> <td><span>$622,545</span></td> <td><span>12.2%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Nassau County, NY&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>-41.7%</span></td> <td><span>7,440</span></td> <td><span>12,763</span></td> <td><span>$717,506</span></td> <td><span>7.0%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Montgomery County, PA&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>-38.4%</span></td> <td><span>4,632</span></td> <td><span>7,513</span></td> <td><span>$501,422</span></td> <td><span>5.4%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Cleveland, OH&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>-24.8%</span></td> <td><span>6,659</span></td> <td><span>8,855</span></td> <td><span>$238,685</span></td> <td><span>11.6%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>New Brunswick, NJ&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>-18.6%</span></td> <td><span>8,628</span></td> <td><span>10,599</span></td> <td><span>$560,136</span></td> <td><span>5.7%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Providence, RI&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>-16.1%</span></td> <td><span>4,357</span></td> <td><span>5,196</span></td> <td><span>$489,974</span></td> <td><span>3.2%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><span>Baltimore, MD&nbsp;</span></td> <td><span>-11.8%</span></td> <td><span>9,251</span></td> <td><span>10,485</span></td> <td><span>$388,919</span></td> <td><span>4.0%</span></td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <h3><b>The Condo Market Is Tilted Strongly in Favor of Buyers</b></h3><p><span><br> There are an estimated 259,137 condo sellers in the U.S. housing market and an estimated 141,223 condo buyers. In other words, there are 83.5% more condo sellers than buyers.</span></p><p><span>By comparison, there are 27.8% more single-family-home sellers than single-family-home buyers, and 33% more townhouse sellers than buyers.</span></p><p><span>Many condo owners are trying to offload their properties because HOA fees and insurance costs have been soaring, and some homeowners associations are doling out hefty special assessments. Florida is the </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/florida-condo-prices-rise-inland/"><span>epicenter</span></a><span> of the condo slowdown, but condo markets in many other parts of the U.S. have also been cooling.&nbsp;</span></p><table> <tbody> <tr> <td></td> <td><b>Sellers vs buyers: % difference</b></td> <td><b>Sellers</b></td> <td><b>Buyers</b></td> <td><b>Median home sale price</b></td> <td><b>Y/Y change in median home sale price</b></td> </tr> <tr> <td><b>Condos</b></td> <td><span>83.5%</span></td> <td><span>259,137</span></td> <td><span>141,223</span></td> <td><span>$357,287</span></td> <td><span>0.4%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><b>Single-family homes</b></td> <td><span>27.8%</span></td> <td><span>1,442,867</span></td> <td><span>1,128,645</span></td> <td><span>$449,684</span></td> <td><span>1.5%</span></td> </tr> <tr> <td><b>Townhouses</b></td> <td><span>33.0%</span></td> <td><span>195,745</span></td> <td><span>147,192</span></td> <td><span>$376,213</span></td> <td><span>0.4%</span></td> </tr> </tbody> </table><p><span>Because there are so many more condo sellers than buyers, condo prices have been underperforming single-family home prices, and in some markets, falling or even plummeting (think </span><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/florida-condo-prices-rise-inland/"><span>Florida</span></a><span>). The median U.S. condo sale price rose 0.4% year over year in April, compared with a 1.5% gain in single-family-home prices.&nbsp;</span></p><h3><b>Metro-Level Summary: 50 Most Populous Metros (April 2025)</b></h3> <table> <thead> <tr> <th><strong>U.S. metro area</strong></th><th><strong>Balance of power</strong></th><th><strong>Sellers</strong></th><th><strong>Buyers</strong></th><th><strong>% difference: sellers vs buyers</strong></th><th><strong>Median sale price</strong></th><th><strong>Median sale price: Y/Y change</strong></th> </tr> </thead> <tbody> <tr> <td>Anaheim, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>6,685</td><td>4,821</td><td>38.7%</td><td>$1,182,683 </td><td>0.8%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Atlanta, GA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>36,862</td><td>22,651</td><td>62.7%</td><td>$396,150 </td><td>0.3%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Austin, TX&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>17,386</td><td>7,757</td><td>124.1%</td><td>$433,990 </td><td>-3.0%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Baltimore, MD&nbsp;</td><td>Seller's market</td><td>9,251</td><td>10,485</td><td>-11.8%</td><td>$388,919 </td><td>4.0%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Boston, MA&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>10,922</td><td>11,725</td><td>-6.9%</td><td>$742,377 </td><td>5.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Charlotte, NC&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>15,557</td><td>9,709</td><td>60.2%</td><td>$405,322 </td><td>2.1%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Chicago, IL&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>25,128</td><td>24,104</td><td>4.2%</td><td>$359,348 </td><td>6.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Cincinnati, OH&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>7,743</td><td>8,176</td><td>-5.3%</td><td>$294,351 </td><td>5.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Cleveland, OH&nbsp;</td><td>Seller's market</td><td>6,659</td><td>8,855</td><td>-24.8%</td><td>$238,685 </td><td>11.6%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Columbus, OH&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>8,308</td><td>7,147</td><td>16.2%</td><td>$333,968 </td><td>-0.7%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Dallas, TX&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>32,020</td><td>17,774</td><td>80.2%</td><td>$416,539 </td><td>-0.8%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Denver, CO&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>16,357</td><td>11,525</td><td>41.9%</td><td>$585,046 </td><td>-0.1%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Detroit, MI&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>6,526</td><td>5,580</td><td>16.9%</td><td>$195,920 </td><td>2.6%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Fort Lauderdale, FL&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>21,018</td><td>7,525</td><td>179.3%</td><td>$451,709 </td><td>1.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Fort Worth, TX&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>13,646</td><td>8,507</td><td>60.4%</td><td>$356,430 </td><td>-0.4%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Houston, TX&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>44,743</td><td>25,327</td><td>76.7%</td><td>$337,077 </td><td>0.3%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Indianapolis, IN&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>8,538</td><td>7,070</td><td>20.8%</td><td>$309,734 </td><td>3.5%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Jacksonville, FL&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>14,479</td><td>6,598</td><td>119.5%</td><td>$368,311 </td><td>-3.4%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Kansas City, MO&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>8,152</td><td>7,968</td><td>2.3%</td><td>$326,474 </td><td>0.8%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Las Vegas, NV&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>13,814</td><td>7,192</td><td>92.1%</td><td>$448,605 </td><td>2.4%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Los Angeles, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>20,189</td><td>13,941</td><td>44.8%</td><td>$899,032 </td><td>0.7%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Miami, FL&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>21,672</td><td>7,280</td><td>197.7%</td><td>$574,696 </td><td>5.6%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Milwaukee, WI&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>4,600</td><td>4,171</td><td>10.3%</td><td>$342,322 </td><td>10.0%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Minneapolis, MN&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>12,842</td><td>13,994</td><td>-8.2%</td><td>$390,029 </td><td>3.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Montgomery County, PA&nbsp;</td><td>Seller's market</td><td>4,632</td><td>7,513</td><td>-38.4%</td><td>$501,422 </td><td>5.4%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Nashville, TN&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>14,935</td><td>7,859</td><td>90.0%</td><td>$467,178 </td><td>0.0%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Nassau County, NY&nbsp;</td><td>Seller's market</td><td>7,440</td><td>12,763</td><td>-41.7%</td><td>$717,506 </td><td>7.0%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>New Brunswick, NJ&nbsp;</td><td>Seller's market</td><td>8,628</td><td>10,599</td><td>-18.6%</td><td>$560,136 </td><td>5.7%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>New York, NY&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>27,564</td><td>29,854</td><td>-7.7%</td><td>$765,736 </td><td>4.9%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Newark, NJ&nbsp;</td><td>Seller's market</td><td>5,241</td><td>9,899</td><td>-47.1%</td><td>$622,545 </td><td>12.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Oakland, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>6,565</td><td>4,820</td><td>36.2%</td><td>$904,023 </td><td>-5.6%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Orlando, FL&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>19,555</td><td>10,184</td><td>92.0%</td><td>$407,411 </td><td>0.8%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Philadelphia, PA&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>8,077</td><td>7,439</td><td>8.6%</td><td>$285,456 </td><td>4.9%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Phoenix, AZ&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>32,418</td><td>16,159</td><td>100.6%</td><td>$452,290 </td><td>-2.1%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Pittsburgh, PA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>9,116</td><td>8,072</td><td>12.9%</td><td>$249,303 </td><td>8.7%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Portland, OR&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>9,963</td><td>7,526</td><td>32.4%</td><td>$552,734 </td><td>0.4%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Providence, RI&nbsp;</td><td>Seller's market</td><td>4,357</td><td>5,196</td><td>-16.1%</td><td>$489,974 </td><td>3.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Riverside, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>17,991</td><td>11,151</td><td>61.3%</td><td>$590,354 </td><td>1.5%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Sacramento, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>7,014</td><td>4,841</td><td>44.9%</td><td>$590,619 </td><td>0.5%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>San Antonio, TX&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>17,915</td><td>9,687</td><td>84.9%</td><td>$309,290 </td><td>0.0%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>San Diego, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>7,728</td><td>6,772</td><td>14.1%</td><td>$901,022 </td><td>-0.5%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>San Francisco, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>3,188</td><td>2,432</td><td>31.1%</td><td>$1,494,441 </td><td>-0.7%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>San Jose, CA&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>3,030</td><td>3,180</td><td>-4.7%</td><td>$1,601,398 </td><td>3.0%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Seattle, WA&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>9,052</td><td>8,170</td><td>10.8%</td><td>$821,991 </td><td>0.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>St. Louis, MO&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>9,327</td><td>9,447</td><td>-1.3%</td><td>$272,314 </td><td>6.8%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Tampa, FL&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>26,917</td><td>12,313</td><td>118.6%</td><td>$371,028 </td><td>-1.3%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Virginia Beach, VA&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>7,077</td><td>6,961</td><td>1.7%</td><td>$351,589 </td><td>1.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Warren, MI&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>8,333</td><td>9,133</td><td>-8.8%</td><td>$317,350 </td><td>6.2%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>Washington, DC&nbsp;</td><td>Balanced market</td><td>16,881</td><td>15,405</td><td>9.6%</td><td>$574,913 </td><td>3.6%</td> </tr> <tr> <td>West Palm Beach, FL&nbsp;</td><td>Buyer's market</td><td>18,075</td><td>6,409</td><td>182.0%</td><td>$513,683 </td><td>2.7%</td> </tr> <tr> <td><strong>National&mdash;U.S.A.</strong></td><td><strong>Buyer&rsquo;s market</strong></td><td><strong>1,943,669</strong></td><td><strong>1,453,628</strong></td><td><strong>33.7%</strong></td><td><strong>$431,931 </strong></td><td><strong>1.6%</strong></td> </tr> </tbody> </table> <h3><b>Methodology</b></h3><p><span><br> The number of sellers in the market is simply active listings, or the total number of homes actively for sale at any point during a given month. Active listings data come from the MLS.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Because there is not a similar metric measuring how many buyers are actively in the market, we developed one. </span><span>We took active listings and pending sales from the MLS to estimate what fraction of homes on the market will sell within a given month. Analogously, we estimated what fraction of buyers on the market will find a home within a given month using Redfin data on the typical time from first tour to purchase. The ratio of these two data points approximates the ratio of buyers to sellers in the market. We then multiplied that ratio by the number of active listings to get the estimated total number of buyers in the market. Note that our estimate of buyers is not based on Redfin traffic or customer acquisition data, and the purpose of this analysis is to measure the number of buyers and sellers in the housing market as a whole. All metrics that go into our calculation of the number of buyers and sellers in the market are seasonally adjusted.</span></p><p><span>References:</span><span><br> </span><span>Anenberg, Elliot and Daniel Ringo, &ldquo;Volatility in home sales and prices: supply or demand?&rdquo; Journal of Urban Economics, Vol. 139, January 2024, 103610.</span><span><br> </span><span>Genesove, David and Lu Han, &ldquo;Search and matching in the housing market,&rdquo; Journal of Urban Economics, Vol. 72, Issue 1, July 2012, pp. 21-45.</span></p></div><div><figure><img src="https://www.redfin.com/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/Lily_Katz-300x300.jpg" alt="Lily Katz"></figure><div><h4><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/author/lily-katzredfin-com/">Lily Katz</a></h4><p>As a data journalist, Lily is passionate about helping readers understand complex facets of the housing market. She is particularly interested in the issues of climate change, race and gender equality and housing affordability. Prior to working at Redfin, Lily spent four years as a reporter at Bloomberg News in New York City.</p><p><a href="https://www.redfin.commailto:lily.katz@redfin.com"><i></i> Email Lily</a></p></div><figure><img src="https://www.redfin.com/news/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/Asad-Khan-300x300.jpg" alt="Asad Khan"></figure><div><h4><a href="https://www.redfin.com/news/author/asad-khan/">Asad Khan</a></h4><p>Asad Khan studies housing market trends and the forces behind them as a senior economist at Redfin. Previously, he was an economic consultant at Analysis Group where he worked on antitrust and valuation matters. Asad taught urban economics as a Research Fellow at the University of Wisconsin-Madison and earned a PhD in economics from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. His research has focused on the economics of city structure and zoning policy.</p><p><a href="https://www.redfin.commailto:asad.khan@redfin.com"><i></i> Email Asad</a></p></div></div></div><div><div><h3> Get a home loan <br> that helps you win </h3> </div><div><p><span>Join us on X for more<br>#housingmarket updates</span></p></div><div><h3>You Might Also Like</h3> </div></div></div></main> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.redfin.com/news/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/FINAL-CHART-2-1024x709.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 01:50:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.kait8.com/2025/09/02/i-have-never-been-worried-i-am-now-arkansas-farmers-gather-share-concerns/</link><title>‘I have never been as worried as I am now’: Arkansas farmers gather to share concerns (kait8.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jxd8/i_have_never_been_as_worried_as_i_am_now_arkansas/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jxd8/i_have_never_been_as_worried_as_i_am_now_arkansas/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jxd8/i_have_never_been_as_worried_as_i_am_now_arkansas/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://gray-kait-prod.gtv-cdn.com/resizer/v2/2R3NXX24ANA2TPFFIJHCPVSAFQ.bmp?auth=3c22d1b6c780110f89cc36a24b7fd2933358e9d0ef586723d7eaddf594b333cb&width=1200&height=600&smart=true' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><article><div><p>BROOKLAND, Ark. (KAIT) - Farmers from across the state are asking for help before it&rsquo;s too late.</p><p>Hundreds of farmers gathered in Brookland to speak with representatives of Arkansas leaders to share with them their urgent plight: the difficulties they face in farming today.</p><p>Many farmers spoke out at the meeting.</p><p>Their message was straightforward: We need help, and we need it now.</p><p>&ldquo;Mr. Trump, you looked at me and said, &lsquo;I love you,&rsquo;&rdquo; Woodruff County farmer Chris King said. &ldquo;Mr. Trump, I need to see the fruit of your love.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;You are going to lose 25 to 30% of the farmers in this country if they don&rsquo;t do something,&rdquo; said Scott Brown, a farmer from Biggers, Arkansas. &ldquo;It has to be done, and it&rsquo;s not just here; it&rsquo;s everywhere.&rdquo;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Hundreds of farmers gathered in Brookland to speak with representatives of Arkansas leaders to share with them their urgent plight: the difficulties they face in farming today.</span><span>(kait)</span></figcaption></figure><h3>Hundreds of farmers gather to share their concerns</h3><p>The line to get into the meeting place, the Woods Chapel Baptist Church, went out the door. Countless farmers from across the state came to voice their concerns about the current state of farming.</p><p>Representatives from U.S. Congressman Rick Crawford, Sen. Tom Cotton, and Sen. John Boozman&rsquo;s offices attended the gathering to hear concerns.</p><p>One of the farmers in attendance, Chris King, spoke about his harvest difficulties.</p><p>He told us this was his 39th harvest, and he has never seen it this bad before. </p><p>&ldquo;I have never been as worried as I am now about whether or not my kids and grandkids will be able to carry on,&rdquo; said Chris King.</p><h3>Lack of profit, export difficulties, and high costs</h3><p>Chris King said the main problem is that they can&rsquo;t sell for profit. </p><p>&ldquo;I just would like to see somebody help us get our markets back,&rdquo; said Chris King. &ldquo;We need our exports, and we just need to be paid for what we do, and that&rsquo;s not happening, and we&rsquo;re in real trouble.&rdquo;</p><p>But this is not the only issue.</p><p>Chris King&rsquo;s wife, Melissa King, and farmer Scott Brown said they are struggling to afford the bare minimum cost to maintain their farms.</p><p>&ldquo;Prices that we are getting now are prices like they were when we were children, and what it costs for us to farm is astronomical now. The price of a combine when we were kids was in the 20,000s, and now it&rsquo;s 100,000,&rdquo; said Melissa King.</p><p>&ldquo;I farm 800 acres by myself, I can&rsquo;t afford any help, I farm with paid-for equipment, all my tractors are 50 years old, and I can&rsquo;t hardly make this deal work,&rdquo; said Brown. &ldquo;How are the guys farming 5 and 10 thousand with 20 hands and million-dollar combines and million-dollar drills going to make it work?&rdquo;</p><h3>Tariffs are hurting farmers</h3><p>Brown said one issue that rounds out all the problems farmers are facing: tariffs.</p><p>&ldquo;I think the tariffs are the ice cream on the cake of a perfect storm,&rdquo; said Brown. &ldquo;When you try and sell a product, okay, U.S. soybeans leaving New Orleans without the tariff to China are cheaper than Brazilian soybeans, at the current market. But when you put the tariff on top of them, Brazilian beans are cheaper.&rdquo; </p><p>What can be done to help farmers? </p><p>&ldquo;In the short term, they have no choice but to mail us a check,&rdquo; said Brown. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know a farmer that likes the check program. Nobody wants to take the taxpayer dollars, but nobody wants to go broke, nobody wants to lose everything. Long term, we have to have options, markets, and places to sell our product.&rdquo; </p><p>The political representatives who attended said they will take these concerns to Washington to share with government leaders and find a way to solve this problem before it&rsquo;s too late.</p><p><i>To report a typo or correction, please </i><a href="https://www.kait8.com/page/tips/"><i>click here</i></a><i>.</i></p><p><i>Copyright 2025 KAIT. All rights reserved.</i></p></div></article><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://gray-kait-prod.gtv-cdn.com/resizer/v2/2R3NXX24ANA2TPFFIJHCPVSAFQ.bmp?auth=3c22d1b6c780110f89cc36a24b7fd2933358e9d0ef586723d7eaddf594b333cb&amp;width=980&amp;height=551&amp;smart=true"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 01:07:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://katv.com/news/local/hundreds-of-struggling-arkansas-farmers-ask-federal-government-to-save-them-agriculture-ag-economy-farm-bill-commodity-prices-safety-net-big-beautiful-bill-derek-haigwood-brookland-farming-delta-farm-bankruptcy-closure-sale-trump-boozman-crawford</link><title>Hundreds of struggling Arkansas farmers ask federal government to save them (katv.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jcvg/hundreds_of_struggling_arkansas_farmers_ask/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jcvg/hundreds_of_struggling_arkansas_farmers_ask/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jcvg/hundreds_of_struggling_arkansas_farmers_ask/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://katv.com/resources/media2/16x9/1280/986/center/90/6f6132c4-2f52-49ec-96cb-30051f776380-PFARMERBANKRUPTCIES.transfer_frame_5123.jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>NEWPORT, Ark. (KATV) &mdash; </span>Hundreds of struggling Arkansas farmers are pleading with the federal government to provide emergency funding amid a farm economy crisis.</p><p>Almost everything that could go wrong for Arkansas farmers went wrong this year, leaving many facing bankruptcy or even the closure of farms that have been passed down for generations.</p><p>A dismal global market and plunging commodity prices mean there&rsquo;s little hope of breaking even, even as input costs soar because of inflation and tariffs&mdash;on top of bad weather earlier in the year.</p><p>&ldquo;This time last year, the rice price was about 40 percent higher than it is now. Inputs costs have gone up, fertilizer has gone up, commodity prices have gotten worse. So, after a horrible year last year where most farmers in Arkansas, Delta, lost money, this year is going to be worse,&rdquo; said Derek Haigwood, a farmer from Independence and Jackson county.</p><p>Though President Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;Big, Beautiful Bill&rdquo; provided a much-needed update to safety net subsidies for farmers, they won&rsquo;t see those federal dollars until late next year. By then, some have projected that as many as one-fourth&mdash;or even one-third&mdash;of Arkansas farmers could face bankruptcy or be forced out of business.</p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m a sixth-generation farmer from Newport, and we made the decision to go out this year, in the spring. So, my son will not be the seventh generation on our farm,&rdquo; said one Newport farmer.</p><p>&ldquo;In the last 14 months, five of my customers have committed suicide. That&rsquo;s how serious this is,&rdquo; said another Arkansas farmer who also works as an ag equipment financier.</p><p>On Tuesday, farmers gathered in Brookland to share their struggles with staffers from Arkansas&rsquo; congressional delegation, asking the state's representatives on Capitol Hill and the governor to convince the president to provide emergency aid to see them through to next year.</p><p>&ldquo;We have to have ad hoc payments right now to make it through this year,&rdquo; Haigwood said.</p><p>&ldquo;If there&rsquo;s no emergency funding this year, there will be one out of three farmers who will file bankruptcy,&rdquo; said Chris King, a Woodruff County farmer.</p><p>Their cries for help did not appear to fall on deaf ears.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to take your message. We&rsquo;re going to get it back to D.C. and we&rsquo;re going to do everything we can to get you the help you need,&rdquo; said Gene Higginbotham, district director for Congressman Rick Crawford.</p><p>Until then, farmers have no one to turn to but God.</p><p>&ldquo;Farmers, in my opinion, dear Lord, they&rsquo;re closer to you than anyone else on this earth because we deal with your earth every day. Dear Lord, we&rsquo;re hurting, dear Lord. We can&rsquo;t help what&rsquo;s happened to us. We need help, dear Lord,&rdquo; prayed one farmer at Tuesday's meeting.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:45:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://apnews.com/article/conocophillips-layoffs-job-cuts-2025-f35528aad7d8c02895853d73bb12842e?&amp;&amp;&amp;</link><title>ConocoPhillips says it will lay off up to 25% of its workforce, impacting thousands of jobs (apnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n7vzsa/conocophillips_says_it_will_lay_off_up_to_25_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n7vzsa/conocophillips_says_it_will_lay_off_up_to_25_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n7vzsa/conocophillips_says_it_will_lay_off_up_to_25_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/152a20c/2147483647/strip/true/crop/5184x2916+0+270/resize/1440x810!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2F38%2F20%2F15c9e8af8101f627af72d167469a%2Fac3927b5b5c040128dafa8340892b868' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><div><p></p></div><bsp-page-actions> </bsp-page-actions> </div><div xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><p>NEW YORK (AP) &mdash; Oil giant ConocoPhillips is planning to lay off up to a quarter of its workforce, amounting to thousands of jobs, as part of broader efforts from the company to cut costs.</p><p>A spokesperson for ConocoPhillips confirmed the layoffs on Wednesday, noting that 20% to 25% of the company&rsquo;s employees and contractors would be impacted worldwide. ConocoPhillips currently has a global headcount of about 13,000 &mdash; meaning that the cuts would impact between 2,600 and 3,250 workers.</p><p>&ldquo;We are always looking at how we can be more efficient with the resources we have,&rdquo; a ConocoPhillips&rsquo; spokesperson said via email, adding that the company expects the &ldquo;majority of these reductions&rdquo; to take place before the end of 2025.</p><p>ConocoPhillips&rsquo; shares fell 4.3% Wednesday. The Houston-based company&rsquo;s stock now sits at under $95 per share, down nearly 14% from a year ago.</p><div><bsp-figure> <figure> <a></a><picture> <source width="800" height="493" srcset="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/00ee838/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/800x493!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 1x,https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/ab67471/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/1600x986!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 2x"> <source width="800" height="493" srcset="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/c26b15d/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/800x493!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 1x,https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/9dac53d/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/1600x986!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 2x"> <source width="767" height="473" srcset="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/d474bb5/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/767x473!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 1x,https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/d3c82f6/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/1534x946!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 2x"> <source width="767" height="473" srcset="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/6b89796/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/767x473!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 1x,https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/d0aa56e/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/1534x946!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 2x"> <source width="599" height="369" srcset="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/9026153/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/599x369!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 1x,https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/6eb1d57/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/1198x738!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 2x"> <source width="599" height="369" srcset="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/fc2c78b/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/599x369!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 1x,https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/a3e0431/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/1198x738!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 2x"> <img alt="An ice-covered ConocoPhillips sign is displayed at the Colville-Delta 5, more commonly known as CD5, drilling site on Alaska's North Slope, Feb. 9, 2016. (AP Photo/Mark Thiessen, File)" srcset="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/fc2c78b/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/599x369!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 1x,https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/a3e0431/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/1198x738!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e 2x" width="599" height="369" src="https://dims.apnews.com/dims4/default/fc2c78b/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1850+0+0/resize/599x369!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.apnews.com%2Fce%2F3e%2F12162cce91dd3ee9fc60e36dcda7%2Fae573eb135b14ed78feaefd7a5fdb75e"> </source></source></source></source></source></source></picture><div><bsp-read-more> <figcaption><p>An ice-covered ConocoPhillips sign is displayed at the Colville-Delta 5, more commonly known as CD5, drilling site on Alaska&rsquo;s North Slope, Feb. 9, 2016. (AP Photo/Mark Thiessen, File)</p></figcaption> </bsp-read-more></div></figure> <template><div><bsp-carousel-read-more><p>An ice-covered ConocoPhillips sign is displayed at the Colville-Delta 5, more commonly known as CD5, drilling site on Alaska&rsquo;s North Slope, Feb. 9, 2016. (AP Photo/Mark Thiessen, File)</p></bsp-carousel-read-more> </div></template> </bsp-figure> </div><p>News of the coming layoffs was first reported <span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/world-at-work/conocophillips-says-it-will-cut-workforce-by-20-25-shares-fall-2025-09-03/">by Reuters</a></span>, with anonymous sources telling the outlet that CEO Ryan Lance detailed the plans in a video message earlier Wednesday. In that video, Reuters reported, Lance said the company needed &ldquo;fewer roles&rdquo; while he cited rising costs.</p><p>Last month, ConocoPhillips reported second-quarter earnings of $1.97 billion. That beat Wall Street expectations, but was down from the nearly $2.33 billion the company reported for the same period last year. </p><p>In its latest earnings, reported on Aug. 7, ConocoPhillips continued to point to cost cutting efforts &mdash; noting that it had identified more than $1 billion in cost reductions and margin optimization. The company also said it had agreed to sell its Anadarko Basin assets for $1.3 billion.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 06:08:25 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/03/economy/us-jolts-job-openings-layoffs-july</link><title>Confirmed: America is in a serious jobs slump (edition.cnn.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n7j3m2/confirmed_america_is_in_a_serious_jobs_slump/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n7j3m2/confirmed_america_is_in_a_serious_jobs_slump/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n7j3m2/confirmed_america_is_in_a_serious_jobs_slump/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2231677154.jpg?c=16x9&q=w_800,c_fill' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Employment gains were <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/01/economy/us-jobs-report-july">so weak in the July</a> jobs report that President Donald Trump <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/01/business/trump-job-report-number-fire">fired the head of the bureau</a> charged with collecting the data, baselessly claiming it was <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/08/business/bls-commissioner-pick">rigged</a>. </p><p>But fresh figures out Wednesday show that those meager job totals weren&rsquo;t an anomaly: For the first time in more than four years, there are fewer open jobs than there are job seekers. </p><p>&ldquo;This is a turning point for the labor market,&rdquo; Heather Long, chief economist at Navy Federal Credit Union, wrote Wednesday. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s yet another crack.&rdquo; </p><p>The number of job openings was an estimated 7.18 million at the end of July, falling from a downwardly revised 7.36 million the month before, according to Bureau of Labor Statistics data released Wednesday. </p><p>Job openings are now not only at their lowest level in 10 months, but they&rsquo;re also below the number of unemployed workers (at 7.2 million) for the first time since April 2021. </p><p>Economists were expecting that openings would shrink slightly from June and land at 7.37 million for July, according to FactSet consensus estimates. </p><p>The labor turnover activity reported in the JOLTS reports comes from a different survey than the monthly jobs report, so the figures aren&rsquo;t meant to match up exactly. However, it can still provide a good sense of underlying trends: Like most economic metrics, JOLTS is meant to be viewed and analyzed in concert with other data. </p><p>Wednesday&rsquo;s JOLTS report is the first of several major labor market data releases due out in this holiday-abbreviated week, culminating with the August jobs report on Friday. Economists expect job gains to remain fairly tepid, at 80,000, and the unemployment rate to hold steady at 4.2%, according to FactSet estimates. </p><p>&ldquo;What I was really looking for (in the JOLTS data) was for any revisions, because we had those huge revisions<strong> </strong>[to the May and June jobs reports]<strong> </strong>but that was not the case,&rdquo; Dan North, senior economist for North America at Allianz Trade, told CNN in an interview. &ldquo;Certainly, I think the employment report on Friday is the more important number. We&rsquo;ll be looking for what the revisions are, because those last two months were pretty shocking, and we expect this month to be light again, similar to what we had last month.&rdquo; </p><p>Wednesday&rsquo;s data is yet another sign that the labor market isn&rsquo;t just cooling, it has grown stale: Hiring remained stagnant, workers stayed put and layoffs remained low. </p><p>The all-important turnover needed for a healthy labor market has become all but nonexistent. </p><p>The July JOLTS data &ldquo;offers a good reminder of why labor market churn matters: It can help drive up wages, create more opportunities for a broader range of workers to enter the market, and support innovation,&rdquo; Allison Shrivastava, an economist at employment site Indeed, wrote Wednesday. &ldquo;For the past few months, the opposite has largely held true.&rdquo; </p><p>In addition to being less dynamic, the job market has become increasingly reliant upon a select few industries &mdash; primarily health care, with leisure and hospitality to a lesser extent &mdash; to drive overall employment growth. However, even opportunities within those industries appear to be shrinking. </p><p>Job openings fell the most in health care and social assistance in July and also dipped somewhat in leisure and hospitality, Wednesday&rsquo;s data showed. </p><p>Openings picked up the most in wholesale trade, construction and the federal government (where areas such as immigration enforcement are on a hiring spree while other agencies are trying to claw back workers after the Trump administration&rsquo;s deep workforce cuts). </p><p>Wednesday&rsquo;s report also showed that hiring was flat across most sectors (including health care and the federal government). The biggest hiring gains were in &ldquo;other services&rdquo; (a catch-all category that includes jobs such as repair, maintenance, pet care, etc.) and wholesale trade. </p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 21:42:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wsj.com/economy/wsj-norc-economic-poll-73bce003?st=5FPFcR&amp;reflink=article_copyURL_share</link><title>70% believe the American dream—that if you work hard, you will get ahead—no longer holds true or never did, the highest level in 15 years. (wsj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n79f5h/70_believe_the_american_dreamthat_if_you_work/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n79f5h/70_believe_the_american_dreamthat_if_you_work/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n79f5h/70_believe_the_american_dreamthat_if_you_work/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:09:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://thedailyadda.com/2025/09/02/economy/us-economy-on-the-brink-of-recession-by-year-end-moodys-chief-warns-as-job-growth-slows-and-inflation-rises/</link><title>U.S. Economy ‘On the Brink’ of Recession by Year-End, Moody’s Chief Warns as Job Growth Slows and Inflation Rises (thedailyadda.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n6h2dv/us_economy_on_the_brink_of_recession_by_yearend/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n6h2dv/us_economy_on_the_brink_of_recession_by_yearend/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n6h2dv/us_economy_on_the_brink_of_recession_by_yearend/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://thedailyadda.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Moodys-Analytics-Chief-Economist-Mark-Zandi-warns-that-the-U.S.-economy-could-slip-into-recession-by-the-end-of-2025-amid-slowing-job-growth-and-rising-inflation.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Moody&rsquo;s Chief Economist Mark Zandi warns the U.S. is &lsquo;on the edge of recession.&rsquo; Photo: Bloomberg via Getty Images</p></div><div><p>President Donald Trump often highlights strong <a href="https://www.bea.gov/data/gdp/gross-domestic-product">GDP</a> growth, high foreign investment, and low inflation as proof the economy is booming under his leadership. The administration credits <a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-economy-idUSKBN2A10Z">tariffs</a> for the economic success and says only cautious policymakers prevent further growth.</p><p>However, Mark Zandi, chief economist at Moody&rsquo;s Analytics, warns that multiple warning signs point to a potential recession by the end of 2025. In an interview with <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/economy-brink-recession-mark-zandi-2122414">Newsweek</a>, he said the U.S. economy feels &ldquo;on the brink, on the precipice of this recession.&rdquo;</p><p>Zandi gained recognition for predicting the 2008 financial crisis. He has recently raised concerns about the consequences of trade policies and federal job cuts. He believes these factors could combine to weaken the U.S. economy significantly.</p><p>One of Zandi&rsquo;s top concerns is employment. Job growth has slowed to a &ldquo;virtual standstill,&rdquo; he said, and businesses are reluctant to expand payrolls. Low layoffs have so far prevented a full downturn, but that may not last.</p><p>&ldquo;As soon as you see negative employment, that&rsquo;s when alarm bells should start going off,&rdquo; Zandi said. He predicts that negative payroll numbers could emerge soon, signaling a growing risk of recession.</p><p>Other economic indicators also worry Zandi. GDP growth for the first half of the year was just over 1 percent annualized. Consumer spending has stagnated, manufacturing is contracting, and construction activity shows weakness despite a boom in data centers.</p><p>Tariffs have not immediately raised consumer prices as Zandi initially predicted. Companies have delayed price hikes due to policy uncertainty and political concerns. Nevertheless, he expects inflation, now 2.7 percent, to climb above three percent and approach four percent by next year.</p><p>&ldquo;Prices are already rising, but soon they&rsquo;ll be impossible to ignore,&rdquo; Zandi said. He added that higher prices and layoffs could trigger a self-reinforcing cycle of reduced consumer spending and further job cuts.</p><p>States representing about one-third of U.S. GDP are either near recession or already in contraction, according to Zandi. California and New York are key indicators because they collectively account for over a fifth of the national economy.</p><p>&ldquo;If California and New York weaken, the national economy is going to go into recession,&rdquo; Zandi said. Conversely, if they hold steady, the broader U.S. economy could avoid contraction. He emphasized these states are bellwethers for national trends.</p><p>Zandi said the economy retains structural strengths despite current weaknesses. The rise of <a href="https://www.britannica.com/technology/artificial-intelligence">artificial intelligence</a> and technology provides positive economic consequences. He believes these long-term forces could offset the negative effects of tariffs and restrictive immigration policies.</p><p>The Moody&rsquo;s machine-learning model places the probability of a recession at 49 percent, nearly even odds. However, Zandi cautioned that the risks are increasing rapidly, and the U.S. economy is vulnerable to further shocks.</p><p>In monitoring economic signals, Zandi focuses on three primary areas. First, inflation is critical, as tariffs pass through to consumer prices. Second, consumer spending will show how households respond to higher costs. Third, layoffs will indicate whether businesses adjust to changing demand.</p><p>&ldquo;Historically, recessions begin and end with payroll employment,&rdquo; Zandi said. Consistent negative employment numbers over several months would indicate the start of a recession according to National Bureau of Economic Research standards.</p><p>Zandi challenged the common &ldquo;two quarters of GDP contraction&rdquo; rule for defining a recession. He argued that a persistent decline in economic activity, even without consecutive GDP drops, can signal a true recession. Jobs and payrolls, he said, are a more reliable indicator.</p><p>The Trump administration attributes strong economic performance to tariffs, job growth, and investment. Zandi countered that first-half GDP growth at just over 1 percent is below historical potential growth of around 2 percent. He said the economy is struggling rather than booming.</p><p>Policy choices, including tariffs and restrictive immigration measures, are central to Zandi&rsquo;s concerns. He believes these policies have caused uncertainty that limits hiring and investment. This uncertainty could soon translate into higher prices, lower spending, and job reductions.</p><p>Housing is another troubling sector. Rising mortgage rates have depressed sales, and homebuilding is expected to slow sharply. Inventories of unsold homes are at levels not seen since before the 2008 financial crisis, highlighting risks to economic stability.</p><p>Zandi emphasized that the next few months will be critical. Employment data from September and potential revisions could reveal whether the economy begins to lose jobs consistently. These figures may determine whether a recession officially begins.</p><p>Other economists have highlighted systemic risks, such as national debt and a contracting money supply. Zandi acknowledged these challenges but emphasized that the U.S. economy also has strong structural foundations. Technology and AI provide positive growth that could stabilize the economy over time.</p><p>He also expressed concern over staffing cuts and funding reductions at key government agencies. The <a href="https://www.bls.gov/">Bureau of Labor Statistics</a>, responsible for critical data such as the consumer price index, may face delays or data quality issues. Accurate reporting is crucial for monitoring recession risks.</p><p>Zandi stressed that while policy choices are currently a primary factor weakening the economy, long-term structural problems should not be ignored. Fiscal deficits and debt will need attention eventually, but immediate risks stem from tariffs, immigration restrictions, and their effects on jobs and prices.</p><p>&ldquo;Policy errors are often an element of all recessions,&rdquo; Zandi said. Historically, both the Federal Reserve and administration policies have influenced downturns. However, he noted that current policies stand out because they are intentional and directly affect economic activity.</p><p>Looking ahead, California and New York will serve as early indicators. Technology and professional services currently provide support, but continued strength is essential. If these states falter, the risk of a nationwide recession increases significantly.</p><p>In conclusion, Zandi highlighted that the economy is fundamentally sound but vulnerable. Rising prices, stagnant spending, and potential layoffs could combine to trigger a recession. Policymakers and consumers will be watching closely in the coming months.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://thedailyadda.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Moodys-Analytics-Chief-Economist-Mark-Zandi-warns-that-the-U.S.-economy-could-slip-into-recession-by-the-end-of-2025-amid-slowing-job-growth-and-rising-inflation-1170x658.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:05:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/2025/08/30/rural-america-economic-crisis-farmers-agriculture-exports-trump-trade-war-china/</link><title>Rural America is suffering an economic crisis as crop prices plunge — ‘U.S. soybean farmers cannot survive a prolonged trade dispute’ (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n5ub2o/rural_america_is_suffering_an_economic_crisis_as/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n5ub2o/rural_america_is_suffering_an_economic_crisis_as/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n5ub2o/rural_america_is_suffering_an_economic_crisis_as/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://fortune.com/img-assets/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/GettyImages-200010069-001-e1756582439345.jpg?resize=1200,600' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>U.S. producers of corn and soybeans have sent dire warnings as prices for their crops have crashed in recent years while President Donald Trump&rsquo;s trade war whipsaws farmers.</p><div><p>On Thursday,&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://ncga.com/stay-informed/media/the-corn-economy/article/2025/08/the-corn-economy-ncga-highlights-high-production-costs-amidst-economic-crisis">National Corn Growers Association raised alarms</a> about &ldquo;the economic crisis hitting rural America, as commodity prices drop at a time when input costs remain at near-record highs.&rdquo; </p><p>Corn prices have plunged more than 50% from their 2022 peak, while production costs are down just 3% in that span, translating to a loss of 85 cents per bushel, the NCGA said, adding that the outlook for next year is worse with even lower prices and higher costs. </p><p>The NCGA called on Congress and the Trump administration to boost demand, including via higher blends of ethanol and increased foreign market access. </p><p>A week before that, <a href="https://soygrowers.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/08/8-19-25-ASA-Letter-to-President-Trump-on-China-FINAL-1.pdf">the American Soybean Association sent a letter</a> to Trump, warning that &ldquo;U.S. soybean farmers are standing at a trade and financial precipice.&rdquo;</p><p>The group asked that Trump prioritize soybeans in trade talks with China, seeking major purchase commitments as well as the removal of Beijing&rsquo;s duties on the U.S. </p><p>&ldquo;Historically, the U.S. was the provider of choice for Chinese customers,&rdquo; the letter said. &ldquo;However, due to ongoing tariff retaliation, our longstanding customers in China have and will continue to turn to our competitors in South America to meet their demand, a demand Brazil can meet due to significantly increased production since the previous trade war with China.&rdquo; </p><p>With harvest season fast approaching, the association added that China hasn&rsquo;t purchased any U.S. soybeans for the months ahead. </p><p>The longer negotiations with China drag on without a trade deal&mdash;and the deeper farmers go into the fall&mdash; the more pain they will feel, it said. </p><p>Like the corn growers, the soybean growers also cited sharply lower prices and high costs. Since peaking in 2022, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/%40S.1?qsearchterm=soybean">soybean prices</a> have fallen about 40%.</p><p>&ldquo;Soybean farmers are under extreme financial stress,&rdquo; the group said. &ldquo;Prices continue to drop and at the same time our farmers are paying significantly more for inputs and equipment. U.S. soybean farmers cannot survive a prolonged trade dispute with our largest customer.&rdquo; </p><h2>Farm incomes, credit conditions deteriorate</h2><p>The bleak picture of the agricultural economy was echoed by the <a href="https://www.kansascityfed.org/agriculture/agfinance-updates/weakness-in-crop-sector-weighs-further-on-farm-finances/">Federal Reserve&rsquo;s latest survey</a> of farm financial conditions. It found that weaker income has reduced liquidity for farmers, boosting demand for financing. </p><p>At the same time, credit conditions deteriorated with roughly 30% of respondents in the Chicago Fed and Kansas City Fed districts reporting lower repayment rates versus a year ago, while the Minneapolis Fed region&rsquo;s share was around 40% and the St. Louis Fed&rsquo;s was 50%. </p><p>To be sure, U.S. farmers are set to receive substantial help. After Trump launched his latest trade war earlier this year, the administration and lawmakers began talking about a <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/04/06/farmer-bailout-trump-trade-war-tariffs-china-canada-agriculture-secretary-brooke-rollins/">bailout for farmers in April</a>, similar to how they received a bailout during Trump&rsquo;s first term, when he waged a trade war against China. </p><p>The One Big Beautiful Bill Act that was signed in July included about $66 billion in agriculture-focused spending. The vast majority, about $59 billion, is earmarked for farm safety-net enhancements, <a href="https://www.fb.org/market-intel/one-big-beautiful-bill-act-final-agricultural-provisions">according to the American Farm Bureau Federation</a>. </p><p>In addition, other trade deals Trump has negotiated should see countries elsewhere in Asia step up purchases of U.S. crops. </p><p>For example&nbsp;Indonesia and Bangladesh have agreed to boost buying under their agreements, and <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/analysis-asias-pledge-boost-us-035317236.html">sources told Reuters</a> this past week that Vietnam, the Philippines and Thailand may increase feed grain purchases. </p><p>&ldquo;There have been productive trade discussions which present an opportunity for the U.S. to strengthen its access to markets in our region,&rdquo; said Timothy Loh, the U.S. Soybean Export Council&rsquo;s regional director for Southeast Asia &amp; Oceania, told Reuters. </p><p>&ldquo;We are anticipating higher demand for U.S. products such as soymeal and other U.S. agricultural exports into Southeast Asia.&rdquo; </p></div><p><strong>Fortune Global Forum</strong> returns Oct. 26&ndash;27, 2025 in Riyadh. CEOs and global leaders will gather for a dynamic, invitation-only event shaping the future of business. <a href="https://conferences.fortune.com/event/global-forum-2025/summary">Apply for an invitation.</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 22:33:24 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
