<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=singularity&amp;averagePostsPerDay=4&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/singularity</title><description>Hot posts in /r/singularity (roughly 4 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 09:37:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh8m-styles-communityIcon_hmujz61wdga81-144x400.jpg</url><title>/r/singularity</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.scmp.com/tech/big-tech/article/3325058/bytedance-unveils-new-ai-image-model-rival-google-deepminds-nano-banana</link><title>ByteDance claims Seedream 4.0 beats Google's "nano banana" on aesthetics and alignment (scmp.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndkl18/bytedance_claims_seedream_40_beats_googles_nano/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndkl18/bytedance_claims_seedream_40_beats_googles_nano/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndkl18/bytedance_claims_seedream_40_beats_googles_nano/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><p>TikTok-owner ByteDance has launched its latest image generation artificial intelligence tool Seedream 4.0, which it said surpasses Google DeepMind&rsquo;s viral &ldquo;Nano Banana&rdquo; AI image editor across several key indicators.</p><p>ByteDance&rsquo;s Seed department, which oversees the tech unicorn&rsquo;s AI development efforts, said on Tuesday that Seedream 4.0 had strong image editing capabilities, putting it in direct competition with Nano Banana, officially known as Gemini 2.5 Flash Image.</p><p>The US model has received wide acclaim since its release in late August for the consistency and accuracy of its image editing abilities, which have been a challenge for AI image generators until now.</p><p>ByteDance claims that Seedream 4.0 beat Gemini 2.5 Flash Image for image generation and editing on its internal evaluation benchmark MagicBench, with stronger performance in prompt adherence, alignment and aesthetics.</p><p>However, these results were not published as part of an official technical report.</p><p>According to Artificial Analysis, a leading AI benchmark firm, Seedream 4.0 represented a &ldquo;significant evolution&rdquo; from previous ByteDance tools because it combined the text-to-image capabilities of Seedream 3.0 with the image editing capabilities of SeedEdit 3.0, while still being priced the same as the former at US$30 per 1,000 generations.</p><div><figure><figcaption>Nano banana produced this image with the prompt, &lsquo;Turn the Star Ferry into a spacecraft traversing a wormhole in space&rsquo;. Photo: Nano Banana</figcaption></figure></div></section><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://img.i-scmp.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=contain,width=1024,format=auto/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2025/09/10/87dba758-b040-459b-ac8e-c03a0893eb68_bfef6415.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 22:56:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/kebsisuo1dof1</link><title>Legal technology expert's reaction to realizing GPT-4 could replace his professional writing (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndid36/legal_technology_experts_reaction_to_realizing/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndid36/legal_technology_experts_reaction_to_realizing/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndid36/legal_technology_experts_reaction_to_realizing/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Legal technology expert Richard Susskind describes his experience testing ChatGPT initially, then trying GPT-4 six months later and the moment he realized it could genuinely replace his professional writing. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/kebsisuo1dof1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2CZWRiMWM1ZmUyMTZjMjhjNDdhZjBjMDA2MjFiNzRkNzE0ZmMyMDFjMDRlODdlYThkYmExMmYyZGE0MjYxOTY4ZA%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1920' height='1080'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 21:35:56 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/07/ai-entry-level-jobs-hiring-careers.html</link><title>AI is not just ending entry-level jobs. It's the end of the career ladder as we know it (cnbc.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndfnso/ai_is_not_just_ending_entrylevel_jobs_its_the_end/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndfnso/ai_is_not_just_ending_entrylevel_jobs_its_the_end/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ndfnso/ai_is_not_just_ending_entrylevel_jobs_its_the_end/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108195282-1757251791575-gettyimages-950612854-noah_apr5_2018-21543.jpeg?v=1757251806&w=1920&h=1080' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Current CEO of Hewlett Packard Enterprise Antonio Neri rose from call center agent at the company to chief executive officer. Doug McMillon, Walmart CEO, started off with a summer gig helping to unload trucks. It's a similar story for GM CEO Mary Barra, who began on the assembly line at the automaker as an 18-year old. Those are the kinds of career ladder success arcs that have inspired workers, and Hollywood, but as AI is set to replace many entry-level jobs, it may also write that corporate character out of the plot. </p><p>The rise of AI has coincided with considerable <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/15/amazon-and-the-endangered-future-of-the-middle-manager.html">organizational flattening</a>, especially among middle management ranks. At the same time, Anthropic CEO Dario Amodei is among those who forecast 50% of entry-level jobs may be wiped out by AI as the technology improves, including <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/06/03/ai-jobs-work-anthropic-human-replacement.html">being able to work eight-hour shifts without a break</a>. </p><p>All the uncertainty in the corporate org chart introduced by AI &mdash; occurring at a time when <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/06/09/job-market-is-trash-right-now-career-coach-says-heres-why.html">college graduates are struggling to find roles</a> &mdash; raises the question of whether the career ladder is about to be broken, and the current generation of corporate leaders' tales of ascent that have always made up an important part of the corporate American ethos set to become a thing of the past. If the notion of going from the bottom to the top has always been more the exception than the rule, it has helped pump the heart of America's corporations. In the least, removing the first rung on the ladder raises important questions about the transfer of institutional knowledge and upward advancement in organizations.</p><p>Looking at data between 2019 and 2024 for the biggest public tech firms and maturing venture-capital funded startups, venture capital firm SignalFire found in <a href="https://www.signalfire.com/blog/signalfire-state-of-talent-report-2025">a study</a> there was a 50% decline in new role starts by people with less than one year of post-graduate work experience: "Hiring is intrinsically volatile year on year, but 50% is an accurate representation of the hiring delta for this experience category over the considered timespan," said Asher Bantock, head of research at SignalFire. The data ranged across core business functions &mdash; sales, marketing, engineering, recruiting/HR, operations, design, finance and legal &mdash; with the 50% decline consistent across the board. </p><p>But Heather Doshay, partner at SignalFire, says the data should not lead job seekers to lose hope. "The loss of clear entry points doesn't just shrink opportunities for new grads &mdash; it reshapes how organizations grow talent from within," she said. </p><p>If, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7LNyUbii0zw">as Amodei told</a> CNBC earlier this year, "At some point, we are going to get to AI systems that are better than almost all humans at almost all tasks," the critical question for workers is how the idea of an entry-level job can evolve as AI continues to.</p><p>Flatter organizations seem certain. "The ladder isn't broken &mdash; it's just being replaced with something that looks a lot flatter," Doshay said. In her view, the classic notion of a CEO rising from the mailroom is a perfect example since at many company's it's been a long time since anyone worked in an actual mailroom. "The bottom rung is disappearing," she said, "but that has the potential to uplevel everyone."</p><p>The new "entry level" might be a more advanced or skilled role, but with the upskilling of the bottom rung, pressure is being created for new grads to acquire these job skills on their own, rather than being able to learn them while already on a job they can't land today. That should not be a career killer, though, according to Doshay.</p><p>"When the internet and email came on the scene as common corporate required skills, new grads were well-positioned to become experts by using them in school, and the same absolutely applies here with how accessible AI is," she said. "The key will be in how new grads harness their capabilities to become experts so they are seen as desirable tech-savvy workers who are at the forefront of AI's advances," she said.</p><p>But she concedes that may not offer much comfort to the current crop of recent grads looking for jobs right now. "My heart goes out to the new grads of 2024, 2025, and 2026, as they are entering during a time of uncertainty," Doshay said, describing it is a much more vulnerable group entering the workforce than ones further into the future.</p><p>Universities are turning their schools into<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/07/technology/chatgpt-openai-colleges.html"> AI training grounds</a>, with several institutions<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/04/03/openai-anthropic-target-college-students-with-education-ai-services.html"> striking major deals</a> with companies like Anthropic and OpenAI.</p><div><p>"Historically, technological advancements have not harmed employment rates in the long run, but there are short-term impacts along the way," Doshay said. "The entry-level careers of recent graduates are most affected, which could have lasting effects as they continue to grow their careers with less experience while finding fewer job opportunities," she added.</p><p>Anders Humlum, assistant professor of economics at the University of Chicago, says predictions about AI's long-term labor market impact remain highly speculative, and firms are only<a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w33777"> just beginning</a> to adjust to the new generative AI landscape. "We now have two and a half years of experience with generative AI chatbots diffusing widely throughout the economy," Humlum said, adding "these tools have really not made a significant difference for employment or earnings in any occupation thus far."</p></div><p>Looking at the history of labor and technology, he says even the most transformative technologies, such as steam power, electricity, and computers took decades to generate large-scale economic effects. As a result, any reshaping of the corporate structure and culture will take time to become clear.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>"Even if Amodei is correct that AI tools will eventually match the technical capabilities of many entry-level white-collar workers, I believe his forecast underestimates both the time required for workflow adjustments and the human ability to adapt to the new opportunities these tools create," Humlum said.</p><p>But a key challenge for businesses is ensuring that the benefits of these tools are broadly shared across the workforce. In particular, Humlum said, his research shows a substantial gender gap in the use of generative AI. "Employers can significantly reduce this gap by actively encouraging adoption and offering training programs to support effective use," he said.</p><p>Other AI researchers worry that the biggest issue won't be the career ladder at the lowest rung, but ultimately, the stability of any rung at all, all the way to the top. </p><p>If predictions about AI advancements ultimately leading to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/06/10/meta-scale-ai-alex-wang.html">superintelligence</a> are proven correct, Max Tegmark, president of the Future of Life Institute, says the issue isn't going to be about whether the 50% entry-level jobs being wiped out is accurate, but that percentage growing to 100% for all careers, "since superintelligence can by definition do all jobs better than us," he said.</p><p>In that world, even if you were the last call center, distribution center or assembly line worker to make it to the CEO desk, your days of success might be numbered. "If we continue racing ahead with totally unregulated AI, we'll first see a massive wealth and power concentration from workers to those who control the AI, and then to the machines themselves as their owners lose control over them," Tegmark said.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 19:55:25 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1nddcnv</link><title>SeeDream 4 turns learned noise into something we mistake for truth (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nddcnv/seedream_4_turns_learned_noise_into_something_we/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nddcnv/seedream_4_turns_learned_noise_into_something_we/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nddcnv/seedream_4_turns_learned_noise_into_something_we/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/5ak8gl1j3cof1.jpg?width=3072&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=13c62b8092585b25bcef940c6634aa76809026d5" height="4096" width="3072" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/unch522k3cof1.jpg?width=1920&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=9546d5a799f72b25cff420f58c18ee605ca77ff5" height="2560" width="1920" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/vi09sddk3cof1.jpg?width=3072&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=62e1c046bc584bb90797ae460316cf02ed6b9e15" height="4096" width="3072" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/g6rwch4l3cof1.jpg?width=3072&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=640895038c2d638c42a80062ef63702b094471ab" height="4096" width="3072" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/qske2s2m3cof1.jpg?width=3072&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=20a42f552273dcb3d7bbe2754e8fb9ca799187c1" height="4096" width="3072" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/03ae6ism3cof1.jpg?width=1536&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=809e1156ea653cd13882742766f30700260fdc54" height="2048" width="1536" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/8i7gubjn3cof1.jpg?width=1152&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=ad9026478bc6dacc6d2c8ee9e743e0e31bf30f5e" height="2048" width="1152" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/vvd5fwun3cof1.jpg?width=3072&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=46c5ea4e630b86344a48e6995c1f329f86253572" height="4096" width="3072" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/fuwmsiyo3cof1.jpg?width=4096&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1a4714f6cbc98d82ed1e963044df6f3e168e4ac9" height="2304" width="4096" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/3k52t6gp3cof1.jpg?width=4096&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d5ae06596eca0c1003310e479bc3427ade1c3edb" height="2731" width="4096" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 18:21:51 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://english.cas.cn/newsroom/research_news/life/202506/t20250620_1045926.shtml</link><title>Scientists Use Engineered Cells to Reverse Aging in Primates (english.cas.cn)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd5kk4/scientists_use_engineered_cells_to_reverse_aging/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd5kk4/scientists_use_engineered_cells_to_reverse_aging/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd5kk4/scientists_use_engineered_cells_to_reverse_aging/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='http://english.cas.cn/images/share_logo.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>As we age, our bodies gradually lose their ability to repair and regenerate. Stem cells diminish, making it increasingly difficult for tissues to heal and maintain balance. This reduction in stem cells is a hallmark of aging and a key driver of age-related diseases. Scientists have long debated whether this decline is the root cause of aging or a side effect. Efforts to use stem cell transplants to reverse aging have faced many challenges, such as ensuring the cells survive and integrate into the body without causing serious side effects, like tumors.</p><p>In a recent study published in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.05.021"><em>Cell</em></a>, researchers from the Chinese Academy of Sciences and Capital Medical University introduced a new type of human stem cell called senescence-resistant mesenchymal progenitor cells (SRCs)&nbsp;by reprogramming&nbsp;the genetic pathways associated with longevity. These cells, which resist aging and stress without developing tumors, were tested on elderly crab-eating macaques, which share physiological similarities with humans in their 60s and 70s.</p><p>The research team conducted a 44-week experiment on&nbsp;these&nbsp;macaques. The macaques received biweekly intravenous injections of SRCs, with a dosage of 2&times;10<sup>6</sup>cells per kilogram of body weight. The researchers found&nbsp;no adverse effects among the macaques. Detailed assessments confirmed that the transplanted cells did not cause tissue damage or tumors.</p><p>The researchers discovered that SRCs&nbsp;triggered a multi-system rejuvenation, reversing key markers of aging across 10 major physiological systems and 61 different tissue types. The treated macaques exhibited improved cognitive function, and tissue analyses indicated a reduction in age-related degenerative conditions such as brain atrophy, osteoporosis, fibrosis, and lipid buildup.</p><p>At the cellular level, SRCs decreased the number of senescent cells, reduced inflammation, and increased progenitor cell populations in neural and reproductive tissues. They even stimulated sperm production. At the molecular level, SRCs enhanced genomic stability, improved responses to oxidative stress, and restored protein balance. More than 50% of the examined tissues showed a reversal of aging-related gene expression profiles to a younger state. Single-cell analyses revealed significant reversals in gene expression among peripheral blood cells (33%), the hippocampus (42%), and ovarian tissue (45%). Machine learning-based aging clocks estimated that the biological age of immature neurons was reversed by six-seven&nbsp;years, and that of oocytes by five&nbsp;years.</p><p>Furthermore, the researchers found that tiny particles called exosomes, released by the SRCs, were the key agents of rejuvenation. These exosomes suppressed chronic inflammation while preserving genomic and epigenomic integrity. When isolated SRC exosomes were administered to aged mice, they significantly reduced organ degeneration. In vitro studies demonstrated that these exosomes could rejuvenate various human cell types, including neurons, ovarian, and liver cells. This discovery suggests that exosome signaling could be a fundamental pathway for reversing aging.</p><p>These findings highlight SRC therapy as a promising intervention for multi-system aging. It&nbsp;demonstrates protective efficacy across interconnected systems like the nervous, reproductive, and immune systems, presenting a holistic approach that surpasses single-target therapies.</p><p><span>SRC Reverses Lipid Buildup in Aged Monkeys' Skeletal Muscle: Control Group (Left); SRC-Treated Group (Right). (Image by LIU Guanghui's lab)</span></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 10:43:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1nd4hb7</link><title>Imagen 4 vs Seedream 4 (Same prompt) (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd4hb7/imagen_4_vs_seedream_4_same_prompt/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd4hb7/imagen_4_vs_seedream_4_same_prompt/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd4hb7/imagen_4_vs_seedream_4_same_prompt/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><strong>Prompt:  A gaming room setup computer desk, keyboard, mouse, in student bedroom Toronto apartment large window show night Toronto downtown night, midnight , photographed by Canon EOS R6, 135mm, 1/1250s, f/2.8, ISO, highly detailed</strong></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/pj47ymdni9of1.png?width=1280&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=068ddcfb9bbf8339e66d168437229a795f2090b2" height="896" width="1280" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/6fkaaseni9of1.jpg?width=2304&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d96533fabc1428927c7555374e6db487b956c5eb" height="1728" width="2304" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:41:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1nd44y6</link><title>Seedance-4-edit ended my profession (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd44y6/seedance4edit_ended_my_profession/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd44y6/seedance4edit_ended_my_profession/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nd44y6/seedance4edit_ended_my_profession/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Guys, it’s a wrap. A few weeks after the next major update, I guess the 3D real estate artists at our company are going to get their termination letters. Looks like we’re all in for a wild ride.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/qxf8ak5pf9of1.jpg?width=1920&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=4a02494e471252f11e1777211432d2ee2ab4c0ff" height="1022" width="1920" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/dxxobx2pf9of1.jpg?width=1920&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=a7ee36b3b6232ca83e5b2a7d6e8b5edb629f0e11" height="1024" width="1920" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/uu8knz2pf9of1.jpg?width=1920&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d921207e1ceff80ac29244fa7e57f0e6d0a57ce0" height="1024" width="1920" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:23:40 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/hkj4ymlt67of1.jpeg</link><title>Microsoft will use Anthropic models to power some features of Office 365 Apps (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nctxr1/microsoft_will_use_anthropic_models_to_power_some/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nctxr1/microsoft_will_use_anthropic_models_to_power_some/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nctxr1/microsoft_will_use_anthropic_models_to_power_some/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.theinformation.com/articles/microsoft-buy-ai-anthropic-shift-openai">https://www.theinformation.com/articles/microsoft-buy-ai-anthropic-shift-openai</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/hkj4ymlt67of1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 01:50:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1ncn3qy</link><title>Seedream 4 is mind-blowingly good (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ncn3qy/seedream_4_is_mindblowingly_good/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ncn3qy/seedream_4_is_mindblowingly_good/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1ncn3qy/seedream_4_is_mindblowingly_good/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/m00cdsanx5of1.jpg?width=4032&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=6becba1356eac8c56160a6d30db55f0ac6979f0d" height="3024" width="4032" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/5fn0n4cqx5of1.jpg?width=4032&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=a7e37785378ff4afd77343ff89dd00234cee8a3a" height="3024" width="4032" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/vyupm3cqx5of1.jpg?width=3840&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1288a1a95d50725e84d060d61af4a3399ae6f5c3" height="2160" width="3840" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/50g0t0cqx5of1.jpg?width=1536&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=b101059524bf5f9c851975f06d489ad2d05f6309" height="2048" width="1536" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/xgzd37ktx5of1.jpg?width=1536&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c2b8bb303df8ce15d31e56c2dca53100fe3c29d2" height="2048" width="1536" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/9tb6ayhwx5of1.jpg?width=4032&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=a490b529e8c6d0e8cf82c67847fd477e99a01483" height="3024" width="4032" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/zyndwf01y5of1.jpg?width=4032&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=9eb3f5069f73eccbf57a5882d68e97ecb5e29c1b" height="3024" width="4032" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 21:39:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/b9xt5l81d0of1.jpeg</link><title>I feel like I am the only one that thinks this is insane (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nc0au8/i_feel_like_i_am_the_only_one_that_thinks_this_is/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nc0au8/i_feel_like_i_am_the_only_one_that_thinks_this_is/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nc0au8/i_feel_like_i_am_the_only_one_that_thinks_this_is/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I am not the most industry financial guru or whatever and I may be missing something but there are massive companies that make tens of billions every year since 20 years and valued at 20 billion while cognition is valued at 10 billion already for what exactly??</p><p>I am sure they are nice people and great team and all but 10 billion for fucking what lmao</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/b9xt5l81d0of1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 02:52:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbysbg/this_sub_is_getting_overrun_by_luddites/</link><title>This sub is getting overrun by Luddites</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbysbg/this_sub_is_getting_overrun_by_luddites/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbysbg/this_sub_is_getting_overrun_by_luddites/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbysbg/this_sub_is_getting_overrun_by_luddites/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’m not saying healthy skepticism is bad, but man… <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity">r/singularity</a> is getting flooded with “AI is gonna kill us” doomsayers or “AI is just a bubble” takes. Every time someone posts something cool about new tech, the comments are filled with “VC scam!” or post about how “We should just go back.”</p><p>It’s wild seeing those posts get 100+ upvotes. This is supposed to be a place to talk about the future, but it’s starting to feel more like <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology">r/Futurology</a>. Like… can we not turn every thread into a doom spiral or nostalgia fest? Some balance would be nice.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 01:54:09 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/5a9hu9antznf1</link><title>Introducing Alterego: the world’s first near-telepathic wearable that enables silent communication at the speed of thought (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbxgri/introducing_alterego_the_worlds_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbxgri/introducing_alterego_the_worlds_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbxgri/introducing_alterego_the_worlds_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://x.com/alterego_io/status/1965113585299849535?s=46">https://x.com/alterego_io/status/1965113585299849535?s=46</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/5a9hu9antznf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2CMjE3NGQzMjVmMzJmYjljZWQyZDYyN2RiNzZiOGRjODBlYzc1MTkzN2NmMjZiMjcwYmU0OTQzZmY1OGMyY2M4NA%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1920' height='1080'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 01:04:05 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/m0vc1kw51xnf1</link><title>The much awaited european humanoid robot Neura 4NE1 spotted at IFA'25 Berlin, sorting socks and underwear (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbjszd/the_much_awaited_european_humanoid_robot_neura/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbjszd/the_much_awaited_european_humanoid_robot_neura/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbjszd/the_much_awaited_european_humanoid_robot_neura/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://youtube.com/shorts/0N7_shp4QOM?si=joUsTGEWy9zVi54O">https://youtube.com/shorts/0N7_shp4QOM?si=joUsTGEWy9zVi54O</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/m0vc1kw51xnf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2CNDdkZWYxOTlhNTRkYTA1MTk3ZDA0MzkwYjc2OGNiNDYyNDVmNzIyOGNmZDY3YjlhMjY5MWVmZjM3ZmNjM2QzMA%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='360' height='640'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:40:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/50fm7mb3cvnf1.jpeg</link><title>OpenAI helping to make an AI generated feature length animated movie that will be released in 2026 (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbebg0/openai_helping_to_make_an_ai_generated_feature/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbebg0/openai_helping_to_make_an_ai_generated_feature/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nbebg0/openai_helping_to_make_an_ai_generated_feature/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/50fm7mb3cvnf1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 09:58:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1naz6d2/anyone_else_concerned_about_what_happens_when/</link><title>Anyone else concerned about what happens when humans have infinite novelty at their fingertips? [NSFW]</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1naz6d2/anyone_else_concerned_about_what_happens_when/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1naz6d2/anyone_else_concerned_about_what_happens_when/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1naz6d2/anyone_else_concerned_about_what_happens_when/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s almost been 2 weeks since nanobanana came out  and I&#39;m embarrassed to admit that of all the usecases I could be using it for, the primary one seems to be generating intimate images of myself with celebs. My productivity has absolutely plummeted. It’s fun and wild in the short term, but I can’t stop wondering what happens when this level of novelty becomes the new baseline. Our brains are wired to chase newness and stimulation, and now it feels like tech is handing us an endless supply on demand, as if social media wasn&#39;t enough. What do you think happens to the nature of sex, relationships and marriage in the future if a mere image editor has so much power? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 22:55:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/j3rlq10iaqnf1.png</link><title>Gemini 2.5 Pro is still first in LMArena Text, despite being rather old (6 months) (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1naqu4d/gemini_25_pro_is_still_first_in_lmarena_text/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1naqu4d/gemini_25_pro_is_still_first_in_lmarena_text/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1naqu4d/gemini_25_pro_is_still_first_in_lmarena_text/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/j3rlq10iaqnf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:01:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1najy26</link><title>"Seahorse Paranoia" is real. (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1najy26/seahorse_paranoia_is_real/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1najy26/seahorse_paranoia_is_real/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1najy26/seahorse_paranoia_is_real/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ChatGPT/comments/1n9vts3/does_a_seahorse_emoji_exist/">Context: There seems to be a meltdown with ChatGPT and seahorse emojis.</a></p><p>Turns out, I think it is Al cross-platform:</p><p>For your entertainment, I present you Qwen3-Max-Preview seahorse meltdown.</p><p>(Small world - I mean training dataset - huh?)</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/vofnfnzz6onf1.jpg?width=1440&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=32deffb9eb3b40302764f4d4c3ee0030ab81e727" height="2217" width="1440" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/dq1ina507onf1.jpg?width=1440&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c42061f1b4b6da23ed8412e015562f0d9f483eab" height="2224" width="1440" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/rc4s4ha07onf1.jpg?width=1440&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1cad438e18ffc0bb9081cf7f4aa6a5e0301d83b9" height="2223" width="1440" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/gh4y06c07onf1.jpg?width=1440&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=0ff70cd25fbc53af993e4a315ed4e197a24a5969" height="2204" width="1440" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/xgo1q6h07onf1.jpg?width=1440&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=df8f7c920b1129852121668476e0690b7f3ca3c3" height="2210" width="1440" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 09:57:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/e5wcd94lonnf1.jpeg</link><title>New Research from Meta Superintelligence Labs. Big deal? (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nai17r/new_research_from_meta_superintelligence_labs_big/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nai17r/new_research_from_meta_superintelligence_labs_big/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nai17r/new_research_from_meta_superintelligence_labs_big/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/e5wcd94lonnf1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 08:14:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/a4zfd81pnmnf1.png</link><title>ClockBench: A visual AI benchmark focused on reading analog clocks (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nadunq/clockbench_a_visual_ai_benchmark_focused_on/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nadunq/clockbench_a_visual_ai_benchmark_focused_on/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1nadunq/clockbench_a_visual_ai_benchmark_focused_on/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/a4zfd81pnmnf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 04:48:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/ysktb4ydtlnf1</link><title>Dario Amodei believes in 1-3 years AI models could go beyond the frontier of human knowledge and things could go crazy! (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1na9wd1/dario_amodei_believes_in_13_years_ai_models_could/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1na9wd1/dario_amodei_believes_in_13_years_ai_models_could/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1na9wd1/dario_amodei_believes_in_13_years_ai_models_could/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/ysktb4ydtlnf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2COGJkNzYwMGNjZTQ4OTAwNjdlMDVmNzNlM2Y0ZGZjMjUyMzA1MmI3ZTIyNGNlMTFiYTE0OGQ3Y2UxN2M4ZTZhYw%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1440' height='1080'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 01:57:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9q73l/big_tech_elite_lavish_praise_on_trump_at_white/</link><title>Big Tech elite lavish praise on Trump at White House dinner</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9q73l/big_tech_elite_lavish_praise_on_trump_at_white/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9q73l/big_tech_elite_lavish_praise_on_trump_at_white/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9q73l/big_tech_elite_lavish_praise_on_trump_at_white/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/tech-ceos-donald-trump-white-house/">https://www.wired.com/story/tech-ceos-donald-trump-white-house/</a></p><p><a href="https://people.com/trump-soaks-up-tech-ceo-praise-white-house-dinner-11804202">https://people.com/trump-soaks-up-tech-ceo-praise-white-house-dinner-11804202</a></p><p><a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/meet-33-silicon-valley-power-144226245.html">https://finance.yahoo.com/news/meet-33-silicon-valley-power-144226245.html</a></p><p><a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/09/05/trump-tech-dinner-ceo-zuckerberg-musk">https://www.axios.com/2025/09/05/trump-tech-dinner-ceo-zuckerberg-musk</a></p><p>Embarrassing to see people like Tim Cook, Bill Gates, Mark Zuckerberg, Sam Altman, Satya Nadella, Sundar Pichai sucking up to Trump.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 09:48:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theinformation.com/articles/openai-says-business-will-burn-115-billion-2029</link><title>OpenAI says it will burn $115 billion through 2029, $80 billion higher than it projected earlier this year (theinformation.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9ov1p/openai_says_it_will_burn_115_billion_through_2029/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9ov1p/openai_says_it_will_burn_115_billion_through_2029/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9ov1p/openai_says_it_will_burn_115_billion_through_2029/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://tii.imgix.net/production/articles/15712/14defb41-50c2-4486-99da-7a936b12035a.jpeg?fm=jpg&auto=compress&w=1200&frame=0' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 08:37:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/7a2tfbx63gnf1.jpeg</link><title>Two New Stealth Models (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9mkb2/two_new_stealth_models/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9mkb2/two_new_stealth_models/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9mkb2/two_new_stealth_models/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/7a2tfbx63gnf1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 06:41:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://openai.com/index/why-language-models-hallucinate/</link><title>New research from OpenAI: "Why language models hallucinate" (openai.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fued/new_research_from_openai_why_language_models/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fued/new_research_from_openai_why_language_models/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fued/new_research_from_openai_why_language_models/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.ctfassets.net/kftzwdyauwt9/5q3iK91iYCslMpYW0fmPNc/50776ce6fc897eacb94d2c05533dba96/oai_GA_Stories_16.9.png?w=1600&h=900&fit=fill' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>At OpenAI, we&rsquo;re working hard to make AI systems more useful and reliable. Even as language models become more capable, one challenge remains stubbornly hard to fully solve: hallucinations. By this we mean instances where a model confidently generates an answer that isn&rsquo;t true. Our <a href="https://cdn.openai.com/pdf/d04913be-3f6f-4d2b-b283-ff432ef4aaa5/why-language-models-hallucinate.pdf">new research paper&#8288;<span>(opens in a new window)</span></a> argues that language models hallucinate because standard training and evaluation procedures reward guessing over acknowledging uncertainty.</p><p>ChatGPT also hallucinates. GPT&#8209;5 has significantly fewer hallucinations <a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5/#:~:text=Building%20a%20more%20robust%2C%20reliable%2C%20and%20helpful%20model">especially when reasoning&#8288;</a>, but they still occur. Hallucinations remain a fundamental challenge for all large language models, but we are working hard to further reduce them.</p><div><h2>What are hallucinations?</h2></div><p>Hallucinations are plausible but false statements generated by language models. They can show up in surprising ways, even for seemingly straightforward questions. For example, when we asked a widely used chatbot for the title of the PhD dissertation by Adam Tauman Kalai (an author of this paper), it confidently produced three different answers&mdash;none of them correct. When we asked for his birthday, it gave three different dates, likewise all wrong.&nbsp;</p><div><h2>Teaching to the test</h2></div><p>Hallucinations persist partly because current evaluation methods set the wrong incentives. While evaluations themselves do not directly cause hallucinations, most evaluations measure model performance in a way that encourages guessing rather than honesty about uncertainty.</p><p>Think about it like a multiple-choice test. If you do not know the answer but take a wild guess, you might get lucky and be right. Leaving it blank guarantees a zero. In the same way, when models are graded only on accuracy, the percentage of questions they get exactly right, they are encouraged to guess rather than say &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p><p>As another example, suppose a language model is asked for someone&rsquo;s birthday but doesn&rsquo;t know. If it guesses &ldquo;September 10,&rdquo; it has a 1-in-365 chance of being right. Saying &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know&rdquo; guarantees zero points. Over thousands of test questions, the guessing model ends up looking better on scoreboards than a careful model that admits uncertainty.</p><p>For questions where there is a single &ldquo;right answer,&rdquo; one can consider three categories of responses: accurate responses, errors, and abstentions where the model does not hazard a guess. Abstaining is part of <b>humility</b>, one of <a href="https://openai.com/careers/#:~:text=to%20elevate%20humanity.-,Act%20with%20humility.,-Humility%20reminds%20us">OpenAI&rsquo;s core values&#8288;</a>. Most scoreboards prioritize and rank models based on accuracy, but errors are worse than abstentions. Our <a href="https://model-spec.openai.com/2025-02-12.html#express_uncertainty">Model Spec&#8288;<span>(opens in a new window)</span></a> states that it is better to indicate uncertainty or ask for clarification than provide confident information that may be incorrect.&nbsp;</p><p>In terms of accuracy, the older OpenAI o4-mini model performs slightly better. However, its error rate (i.e., rate of hallucination) is significantly higher. Strategically guessing when uncertain improves accuracy but increases errors and hallucinations.&nbsp;</p><p>When averaging results across dozens of evaluations, most benchmarks pluck out the accuracy metric, but this entails a false dichotomy between right and wrong. On simplistic evals like SimpleQA, some models achieve near 100% accuracy and thereby eliminate hallucinations. However, on more challenging evaluations and in real use, accuracy is capped below 100% because there are some questions whose answer cannot be determined for a variety of reasons such as unavailable information, limited thinking abilities of small models, or ambiguities that need to be clarified.</p><p>Nonetheless, accuracy-only scoreboards dominate leaderboards and model cards, motivating developers to build models that guess rather than hold back. That is one reason why, even as models get more advanced, they can still hallucinate, confidently giving wrong answers instead of acknowledging uncertainty.</p><p>There is a straightforward fix. Penalize confident errors more than you penalize uncertainty, and give partial credit for appropriate expressions of uncertainty. This idea is not new. Some standardized tests have long used versions of negative marking for wrong answers or partial credit for leaving questions blank to discourage blind guessing. Several research groups have also explored evaluations that account for uncertainty and calibration.</p><p>Our point is different. It is not enough to add a few new uncertainty-aware tests on the side. The widely used, accuracy-based evals need to be updated so that their scoring discourages guessing. If the main scoreboards keep rewarding lucky guesses, models will keep learning to guess. Fixing scoreboards can broaden adoption of hallucination-reduction techniques, both newly developed and those from prior research.</p><div><h2>How hallucinations originate from next-word prediction</h2></div><p>We&rsquo;ve talked about why hallucinations are so hard to get rid of, but where do these highly-specific factual inaccuracies come from in the first place? After all, large pretrained models rarely exhibit other kinds of errors such as spelling mistakes and mismatched parentheses. The difference has to do with what kinds of patterns there are in the data.</p><p>Language models first learn through <i>pretraining</i>, a process of predicting the next word in huge amounts of text. Unlike traditional machine learning problems, there are no &ldquo;true/false&rdquo; labels attached to each statement. The model sees only positive examples of fluent language and must approximate the overall distribution.&nbsp;</p><p>It&rsquo;s doubly hard to distinguish valid statements from invalid ones when you don&rsquo;t have any examples labeled as invalid. But even with labels, some errors are inevitable. To see why, consider a simpler analogy. In image recognition, if millions of cat and dog photos are labeled as &ldquo;cat&rdquo; or &ldquo;dog,&rdquo; algorithms can learn to classify them reliably. But imagine instead labeling each pet photo by the pet&rsquo;s birthday. Since birthdays are essentially random, this task would always produce errors, no matter how advanced the algorithm.</p><p>The same principle applies in pretraining. Spelling and parentheses follow consistent patterns, so errors there disappear with scale. But arbitrary low-frequency facts, like a pet&rsquo;s birthday, cannot be predicted from patterns alone and hence lead to hallucinations. Our analysis explains which kinds of hallucinations should arise from next-word prediction. Ideally, further stages after pretraining should remove them, but this is not fully successful for reasons described in the previous section.&nbsp;</p><div><h2>Conclusions</h2></div><p>We hope that the statistical lens in our paper clarifies the nature of hallucinations and pushes back on common misconceptions:</p><div><ul><li><b>Claim:</b> Hallucinations will be eliminated by improving accuracy because a 100% accurate model never hallucinates.<b><br>Finding: </b>Accuracy will never reach 100% because, regardless of model size, search and reasoning capabilities,<b> </b>some real-world questions are inherently unanswerable.&nbsp;</li><li><b>Claim: </b>Hallucinations are inevitable.<b><br>Finding:</b> They are not, because language models can abstain when uncertain.</li><li><b>Claim:</b> Avoiding hallucinations requires a degree of intelligence which is exclusively achievable with larger models.<b><br>Finding:</b> It can be <i>easier</i> for a small model to know its limits. For example, when asked to answer a M&#257;ori question, a small model which knows no M&#257;ori can simply say &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know&rdquo; whereas a model that knows some M&#257;ori has to determine its confidence. As discussed in the paper, being &ldquo;calibrated&rdquo; requires much less computation than being accurate.</li><li><b>Claim: </b>Hallucinations are a mysterious glitch in modern language models.<b><br>Finding: </b>We understand the statistical mechanisms through which hallucinations arise and are rewarded in evaluations.</li><li><b>Claim: </b>To measure hallucinations, we just need a good hallucination eval.<b><br>Finding: </b>Hallucination evals have been published. However, a good hallucination eval has little effect against hundreds of traditional accuracy-based evals that penalize humility and reward guessing. Instead, all of the primary eval metrics need to be reworked to reward expressions of uncertainty.</li></ul></div><p>Our latest models have lower hallucination rates, and we continue to work hard to further decrease the rates of confident errors output by our language models.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 01:48:25 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/wjok4efslenf1.jpeg</link><title>Anthropic: Paying $1.5 billion in AI copyright lawsuit settlement (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fp0n/anthropic_paying_15_billion_in_ai_copyright/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fp0n/anthropic_paying_15_billion_in_ai_copyright/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fp0n/anthropic_paying_15_billion_in_ai_copyright/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://apnews.com/article/anthropic-copyright-authors-settlement-training-f294266bc79a16ec90d2ddccdf435164">https://apnews.com/article/anthropic-copyright-authors-settlement-training-f294266bc79a16ec90d2ddccdf435164</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/wjok4efslenf1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 01:42:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ft.com/content/31feb335-4945-475e-baaa-3b880d9cf8ce</link><title>Computer scientist Geoffrey Hinton: ‘AI will make a few people much richer and most people poorer’ (ft.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9ddw7/computer_scientist_geoffrey_hinton_ai_will_make_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9ddw7/computer_scientist_geoffrey_hinton_ai_will_make_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9ddw7/computer_scientist_geoffrey_hinton_ai_will_make_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>No paywall <a href="https://archive.ph/ifSwh#selection-1889.0-1889.18">https://archive.ph/ifSwh#selection-1889.0-1889.18</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-after-selftext'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><div><p><span></span><span>Subscribe to unlock this article</span></p></div><div><h2><span><span>Try unlimited access</span></span></h2><h2><span><span>Only </span><span>Rs100</span><span> for 4 weeks</span></span></h2><p><span><span>Then </span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month. Complete digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Cancel anytime during your trial.</span></span></p></div></div><div><h2>Explore more offers.</h2><div><div><div><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_ftedit.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg" alt></p><h3>FT Edit</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4490</span><span> per year</span></span></p><p><span><span>Access to eight surprising articles a day, hand-picked by FT editors. For seamless reading, access content via the FT Edit page on FT.com and receive the FT Edit newsletter.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Standard Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs2850</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Essential digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Premium Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Complete digital access to quality FT journalism with expert analysis from industry leaders. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div></div></div><div><h2>Explore our full range of subscriptions.</h2><div><div><div><h3>For individuals</h3></div><p>Discover all the plans currently available in your country</p></div><div><div><h3> For multiple readers</h3></div><p>Digital access for organisations. Includes exclusive features and content.</p></div></div></div><div><div><h2>Why the FT?</h2><p>See why over a million readers pay to read the Financial Times.</p></div><p><a href="https://subs.ft.com/whytheft?ft-content-uuid=31feb335-4945-475e-baaa-3b880d9cf8ce">Find out why</a></p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_standard.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg"></p><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_premium.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:11:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/qs45dl814enf1.png</link><title>Andrej on 5-Pro (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9d6tn/andrej_on_5pro/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9d6tn/andrej_on_5pro/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9d6tn/andrej_on_5pro/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/qs45dl814enf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:03:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/szr3ifhugcnf1</link><title>Another day, another AI driven robomoto (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n94oci/another_day_another_ai_driven_robomoto/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n94oci/another_day_another_ai_driven_robomoto/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n94oci/another_day_another_ai_driven_robomoto/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>RAI institute<a href="https://x.com/rai_inst/status/1912869580210397217">https://x.com/rai_inst/status/1912869580210397217</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/szr3ifhugcnf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2COWQ2ZDcxZWFiMzBiYjFhY2M5Mzg5MzgxYWJmMGE3NTI1MGQ0Zjk0Mjg0ODJhZGM4YWRhZDUyYjQwOTQzNzQwZA%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1280' height='720'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:32:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/ejgfhwrvw8nf1.jpeg</link><title>OpenAI set to start mass production of its own AI chips with Broadcom (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8rp3a/openai_set_to_start_mass_production_of_its_own_ai/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8rp3a/openai_set_to_start_mass_production_of_its_own_ai/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8rp3a/openai_set_to_start_mass_production_of_its_own_ai/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/openai-set-start-mass-production-its-own-ai-chips-with-broadcom-ft-reports-2025-09-05/">https://www.reuters.com/business/openai-set-start-mass-production-its-own-ai-chips-with-broadcom-ft-reports-2025-09-05/</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/ejgfhwrvw8nf1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 06:33:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/ca9mw3fns7nf1</link><title>Will figure.ai take over home chores? (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8miwb/will_figureai_take_over_home_chores/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8miwb/will_figureai_take_over_home_chores/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8miwb/will_figureai_take_over_home_chores/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/ca9mw3fns7nf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2CNWVlZDFkNDM3NDA1NjhjNzQzYWE0N2UzZjMyNGQzYjJjNzc1YWVlOWQyZDEyMzRiMTQ3MDNlMTUzOWU4YzViNQ%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1280' height='720'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 02:48:33 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1n8eh6b</link><title>EmbeddingGemma, Google's new SOTA on-device AI at 308M Parameters (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8eh6b/embeddinggemma_googles_new_sota_ondevice_ai_at/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8eh6b/embeddinggemma_googles_new_sota_ondevice_ai_at/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n8eh6b/embeddinggemma_googles_new_sota_ondevice_ai_at/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/mixcpdbm96nf1.png?width=1171&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1d758068b966c2e4787051bc4d2ed370c03cd3fe" height="1010" width="1171" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/525fuj1u96nf1.png?width=4001&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=508b07a997d9f82250d59f31de667344dbdeddb7" height="2251" width="4001" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/nnrpdguu96nf1.png?width=4001&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=b30afb8129c79912a723d37db70e8306ef415058" height="2251" width="4001" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 21:41:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/mgu9fy21w2nf1</link><title>Casual conversation with the security robot dog (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n811zq/casual_conversation_with_the_security_robot_dog/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n811zq/casual_conversation_with_the_security_robot_dog/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n811zq/casual_conversation_with_the_security_robot_dog/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/mgu9fy21w2nf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2CMTUyNDFhYTg0OGY1ZWM0NzBlOTNkZjIyODVlYmU3MDAwN2M1YWRjYmZkM2JmZmIwNjIwYzIyYjk2NzliMmE1Mg%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='720' height='1280'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:18:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/s6555dgpn7hf1</link><title>Google Deepmind's new Genie 3 (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1miaoat/google_deepminds_new_genie_3/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1miaoat/google_deepminds_new_genie_3/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1miaoat/google_deepminds_new_genie_3/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://x.com/OfficialLoganK/status/1952732206176112915">https://x.com/OfficialLoganK/status/1952732206176112915</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/s6555dgpn7hf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760162821%2CYzM2NmZmNjhhZmFlYzg2ZDQ2Nzc1MjUzZmVhMDA3OTAyNTk1ZGE4YTJjZTI1ZWI1OTU3YjZiNzRhYjVmMTQxYQ%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1920' height='1080'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 19:56:30 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
