<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=science&amp;averagePostsPerDay=9&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/science</title><description>Hot posts in /r/science (roughly 9 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 21:10:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_mouw-styles-communityIcon_xtjipkhhefi41-144x400.png</url><title>/r/science</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.mdanderson.org/newsroom/sugary-drinks-may-increase-risk-of-metastasis-in-advanced-colorectal-cancer.h00-159779601.html</link><title>Sugary drinks may increase risk of metastasis in advanced colorectal cancer. Preclinical study provides first direct evidence linking colorectal cancer metastasis to glucose-fructose blend found in sugar-sweetened beverages. Cutting back on sugary drinks may slow progression of colorectal cancer. (mdanderson.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I assume this is related to the marathon runner study in potential causality.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/nf8nl5e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the press release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article: </p><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s42255-025-01368-w">https://www.nature.com/articles/s42255-025-01368-w</a></p><p>From the linked article: </p><p><strong>Sugary drinks may increase risk of metastasis in advanced colorectal cancer</strong></p><p><strong>Preclinical study provides first direct evidence linking colorectal cancer metastasis to the glucose-fructose blend found in sugar-sweetened beverages</strong></p><p>Metastasis is the leading cause of death among patients with colorectal cancer</p><p>The combination of glucose and fructose, found in most sodas and fruit juices, activates the SORD enzyme, fueling cancer cell migration and metastasis</p><p><strong>Study suggests cutting back on sugary drinks could help slow cancer progression in patients with colorectal cancer</strong> and points to possible new treatment targets</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/nf8f0nm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’m not trying to be a pain, but if sugar is one of the main energy sources, doesn’t sugar simply feed all cells? Including cancer cells?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/nf8nyr2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So the study the other week about statistically significant increased colorectal cancer rates among ultramarathoners — something tells me this might be related? All those energy/fueling/high carb gels and drinks are high in glucose and fructose for quick absorption. </p><p>High carb is all the rage, curious what we see in 5 to 10 years from now among ultramarathoners and trail runners. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/nf8trpf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Well, I&#39;m not sure where she heard it, but my dear departed grandmother, who beat cancer 3 times, and did not die of it, always said for decades &quot;cancer loves sugar&quot;.Nice see her proven right.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/nf8hggg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m pleased to see studies like this examining the dangers of soft drinks.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/nf8jl7c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I used to be addicted to drinking Coca-Cola. I became diabetic and had no idea. My rectal cancer metastasized, spread to my lung before I knew I had an either problem. I am now battling stage 4 cancer.</p><p>In retrospect, the addictive nature of Coca-Cola, that it was pushed on me everywhere I went as a kid, with marketing and availability heavier than any substance or brand, I don’t understand... I wish I could sue the absolute living hell out of them.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlwf0t/sugary_drinks_may_increase_risk_of_metastasis_in/nf9jcmr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 17:34:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://news.berkeley.edu/2025/09/18/genetic-study-of-nomadic-herders-in-kenya-shows-what-it-takes-to-adapt-to-desert-living/</link><title>The Turkana people consume an animal-based diet in one of the hottest, driest places on Earth. Scientists uncovered the genetic variation behind this desert adaptation. One specific genetic variation has allowed their kidneys to concentrate urine so that they eliminate less water. (news.berkeley.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlus3x/the_turkana_people_consume_an_animalbased_diet_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlus3x/the_turkana_people_consume_an_animalbased_diet_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlus3x/the_turkana_people_consume_an_animalbased_diet_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the press release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article:</p><p><a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2467">https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adv2467</a></p><p>From the linked article:</p><p>Genetic study of nomadic herders in Kenya shows what it takes to adapt to desert living</p><p><strong>The Turkana people consume an animal-based diet in one of the hottest, driest places on Earth. Scientists uncovered the genetic variation behind this desert adaptation</strong>, and how it leads to problems as the Turkana transition to city life.</p><p>The nomadic Turkana people of Northwest Kenya are superbly adapted to living in one of the hottest and driest places on Earth, with so little greenery that they base their diet on animal products, primarily milk, meat and blood from herds of goats and camels.</p><p>A new analysis of Turkana genomes led by UC Berkeley and Vanderbilt University, conducted in collaboration with Kenyan researchers and the Turkana community, shows how the activity of key genes has changed over millennia to allow them to thrive in extreme desert conditions. On the flip side, that exquisite adaptation to a nomadic, pastoral lifestyle sets them up for chronic health problems when, as increasingly happens, they move to cities in search of wage-paying jobs and adopt an urbanized, sedentary lifestyle.</p><p><strong>One specific genetic variation has allowed their kidneys to concentrate urine so that they eliminate less water</strong>. That gene may also play a role in protecting the kidneys from the waste generated by purine-rich foods such as red meat.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlus3x/the_turkana_people_consume_an_animalbased_diet_in/nf83ja5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Very interesting. I usually associated meat heavy diets with colder climates (artic circle, mongolia, etc) buy I guess its more accurate to say its a result of harsh climates in general</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlus3x/the_turkana_people_consume_an_animalbased_diet_in/nf8eqod/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The Turkana people of Kenya have as nomadic herders in one of the hottest, driest places on Earth for thousands of years.</p><p>Theire diet is mostly animal-based milk, meat, and blood from goats and camels and their bodies have genetically adapted to handle extreme heat, dehydration and a high-protein diet</p><p>Specific gene like STC1 that help their kidneys retain water and process the high amounts of protein in their diet.</p><p>This is why most Turkana stay healthy even though they drink very little water and eat a lot of meat</p><p>These same adaptations can become a problem when Turkana people move to cities and adopt a sedentary lifestyle.</p><p>Their genes, perfectly suited for desert life, may increase the risk of diseases like diabetes, kidney problems, and high blood pressure a concept called evolutionary mismatch.</p><p>Humans can genetically adapt to extreme environments over generations, but also how those adaptations don’t always fit modern lifestyles</p><p>A great example is our teeth almost everyone needs braces today. The reason is that our teeth aren’t made for soft, ultra-processed food they’re built to chew hard, natural foods. That’s why many tribal people in Africa still have strong, healthy teeth</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlus3x/the_turkana_people_consume_an_animalbased_diet_in/nf8irb2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 16:04:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/1098703</link><title>Poverty may be linked to lower fertility. Researchers have found that about half of couples on low incomes had fertility problems compared to about a third of couples on high incomes. Lifestyle factors, such as BMI, smoking, and drinking, did not fully explain this difference (eurekalert.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>How about financial stress as a confounding factor?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/nf7yvn7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This seems counterintuitive given the family sizes for lower income ranges are larger?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/nf80b4u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Living a stressful life releases a lot of cortisol into your blood stream. In stressful conditions women often miss their periods. Hence worse fertility. </p><p>This is somewhat a physiologic function. If you’re under stressful conditions you wouldn’t be able to properly care for a child or eat well enough to support the pregnancy.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/nf82vcx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The findings of this cohort study suggest that poverty and social disadvantage, characterized by low educational level and household income among both women and men, were associated with lower fecundability (defined as the per-month probability of conceiving) and increased risks of subfertility (defined as a time to pregnancy or the duration of actively pursuing pregnancy of more than 12 months or use of assisted reproductive technology) but not with miscarriage risk. Further studies are needed to identify the underlying and explanatory mechanisms associated with fertility outcomes and the potential for novel public health strategies for couples desiring pregnancy.</p><p><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2839089?utm_source=For_The_Media&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;utm_term=091925">https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2839089?utm_source=For_The_Media&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;utm_term=091925</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/nf7wlxi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We keep prioritizing as causal, lifestyle factors whereas the evidence in the literature is tipping towards the bulk of the effects and risks are due to environmental and healthcare access equity issues. I mean the baby boom happened when nearly 50% of adults smoked, compared to today&#39;s 10%, but most of our municipal drinking water was clean. Low income couples live in areas with high exposure risks for PFAS, OC pesticides, dioxin, PCBs, and heavy metals. They&#39;re more likely to have to source lower-quality products from Walmar, Amazon, &amp; Temu - all of which have issues with &quot;dirty&quot; suppliers, and the last one actively solicits products from such.</p><p>But we&#39;d have to fix some SERIOUS ish at societal soci-economic levels - and that against government policies directed *firmly* in the worsening direction - rather than blame individuals. And the people who might benefit from the former are decidedly NOT the people reaping huge benefits from status quo.</p><p>(long report at the link but there is an executive summary: <a href="https://www.endocrine.org/-/media/endocrine/files/advocacy/edc-report2024finalcompressed.pdf?lctg=217279927">https://www.endocrine.org/-/media/endocrine/files/advocacy/edc-report2024finalcompressed.pdf?lctg=217279927</a> )</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/nf8rujg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I mean the obvious reason is because the people with more money had better healthcare.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/nf888tp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Poor people must smash all the time given demographic numbers. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltnr4/poverty_may_be_linked_to_lower_fertility/nf8uhuk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:56:04 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2025/09/early-breakfast-could-help-you-live-longer/</link><title>Research has found in older adults later breakfast time was consistently associated with having physical and mental health conditions such as depression. As adults age, they tend to eat breakfast and dinner at later times, while also narrowing the overall time window in which they eat each day. (news.harvard.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The title says later breakfast time but then the article says changing breakfast time.</p><p>So actually it&#39;s when you used to be an earlier breakfast eater and then you slip later and later that&#39;s the problem? If you&#39;ve always taken a late breakfast that&#39;s ok?</p><p>The difference is important as a lot of people (myself included) get digestive upset/IBS style symptoms if we eat within the first few hours of waking.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/nf7vxux/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>When I’m feeling low it can take me hours to bring myself to rustle up breakfast. Even if it’s just toast, I’m eating it at 11 rather than 8, and that’s only because I was starting to feel low blood sugar. At those times I’d rather not need to eat at all.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/nf8b5p8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>but isnt intermittent fasting linked to better mental and physical health?</p><p>maybe the depressed peoples bodies are trying to push themselves  into intermittent fasting as a way of self medicating the depression</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/nf7ugm9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I only eat once a day at like 9 or 10pm becuase I lose track of time. I guess that makes me maximum old.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/nf7x44q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Researchers studied changes to meal timing in older adults and discovered people experience gradual shifts as they age. They also found characteristics that may contribute to mealtime shifts and revealed specific traits linked to an earlier death.</p><p>Results from the Mass General Brigham study are published in Communications Medicine</p><p>“Our research suggests that changes in when older adults eat, especially the timing of breakfast, could serve as an easy-to-monitor marker of their overall health status,” said lead author Hassan Dashti, a nutrition scientist and circadian biologist at Harvard-affiliated Massachusetts General Hospital and assistant professor of anesthesia at Harvard Medical School.</p><p>“Patients and clinicians can possibly use shifts in mealtime routines as an early warning sign to look into underlying physical and mental health issues. Also, encouraging older adults in having consistent meal schedules could become part of broader strategies to promoting healthy aging and longevity,” Dashti said.</p><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43856-025-01035-x">https://www.nature.com/articles/s43856-025-01035-x</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/nf7u3tk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I thought intermittent fasting was good?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/nf858sn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Well in the US it’s more typical of older adults to eat earlier and earlier. This is why you see senior meal discounts at like 5pm.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nltaf6/research_has_found_in_older_adults_later/nf86y94/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:32:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.helsinki.fi/en/news/food-and-nutrition/consuming-more-legumes-and-less-red-and-processed-meat-may-have-surprisingly-positive-impact-mens-health</link><title>Consuming more legumes and less red and processed meat may have a surprisingly positive impact on men's health. Replacing red and processed meat with pea- and faba bean-based foods resulted in reduced total and 'bad' LDL cholesterol levels in men, along with weight loss. (helsinki.fi)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>What is surprising about that?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5n0gl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The benefits of eating more beans and peas instead of red meat is you are getting a ton of more fiber which helps your colon out and prevents colon cancer. Keeps your regular. Also fiber pulls out bad cholesterol LDL from your blood into your poop, and you poop out the bad cholesterol. Also fiber in beans are very filling. I challenge anyone to try to over eat beans. It is almost impossible because it is fills you up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5uljr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I swapped out beef for bean burritos and love it just the same. My LDL cholesterol is down to 62mg/dL, which is probably also from other dietary swaps toward whole plants / more fiber / less saturated fat.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5lwzr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The legume lobby at it again.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5unp2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the press release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article: </p><p><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00394-025-03783-x">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00394-025-03783-x</a></p><p>From the linked article: </p><p>Consuming more legumes and less red and processed meat may have a surprisingly positive impact on men’s health</p><p>A University of Helsinki study found that partially replacing red and processed meat with pea- and faba bean–based foods resulted in reduced total and ‘bad’ LDL cholesterol levels in men, along with weight loss.</p><p>On average, men consume significantly more red and processed meat than is recommended, and more than women do. The high nutritional value of legumes makes them well suited to replacing meat. However, they do not naturally contain vitamin B12, which is found in animal-derived foods. The BeanMan study investigated how partially replacing red and processed meat with legumes thriving in Finnish conditions affected men’s health and levels of critical micronutrients in the blood.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5gskk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We know broadly what&#39;s good for us (except science deniers). We just don&#39;t want to do it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf63at4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I thought the ideal male body was supposed to be raised purely on a diet of raw beef and eggs?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf6dl1j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 03:59:20 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/keto-diet-health-risk-glucose-high-fat</link><title>Mice fed on the keto diet had trouble processing sugar, showed signs of liver and cardiovascular disease | Long-term adherence to the low-carb, high-fat diet caused buildups of fat in the bloodstream (sciencenews.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m pretty open to the evidence that a ketogenic diet has health benefits for a number of use cases. But I&#39;d never go for it myself because I know I have a genetic predisposition for high cholesterol (that makes dietary cholesterol affect my levels), non-alcoholic fatty liver disease, cardiovascular risk, and kidney insufficiency. I don&#39;t need evidence that it&#39;s bad for other people before I know it&#39;s bad for me personally.</p><p>There is a study showing that a ketogenic diet <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC5609489/">extended longevity and healthspan in male mice</a>. Scientific inquiry generates plenty of conflicting evidence. I hope we can look at this as a sign that, especially when it comes to medical science, your mileage is still highly individualised, and overall risk to health and longevity is a composite of the accumulated risks of many interconnected systems. I think it&#39;s worth the investment to learn about your own biological composition to anchor your decisionmaking instead of looking for an &quot;objective&quot; direction.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf5429j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve always said keto is a great weight loss “tool” but never thought of it as a long term method of sustaining weight loss.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf54xbz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>is it even a high fat diet?  It CAN be, but it doesn&#39;t have to be...like...what?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf632gb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&gt; Adult C57Bl/6J male and female mice were placed on one of four long-term diet regimens<br/><a href="https://www.jax.org/strain/000664">C57BL/6J is the most widely used inbred strain[...]They are also susceptible to diet-induced obesity, type 2 diabetes, and atherosclerosis.</a></p><p>It&#39;s good to know that feeding mice that have genetic predispositions to conditions, which naturally mostly eat seeds, grains and some insects, with extremely species inappropriate diets, leads to them having metabolic problems.</p><p>So their conclusion of:</p><p>&gt; In summary, while a KD can prevent and treat obesity, it causes hyperlipidemia, hepatic steatosis, and glucose intolerance.</p><p>Should come with a big, red, bold</p><h1>IN MICE.</h1></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf546k6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah. I am newly diabetic and switching to super low carb is the only thing that is keeping my blood sugar below 160 on metformin. On keto, your main energy source is fats, so them being in the bloodstream makes sense, but not sure if it&#39;s supposed to turn to sugar through the liver first or something.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf5fc1q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A 90% fat diet is not a modern keto diet. Generally 70% 25% 5% (fat, protein, carbs) is the most common. Also, different strains of mice have been known to respond dramatically different to keto diets. Also, they&#39;re mice.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf55ojd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How incredibly predictable. It’s like we had years of research that pointed to this already.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf51714/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 02:31:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://news.uga.edu/role-of-parents-in-social-anxiety/</link><title>Both mothers and fathers significantly shape their children's social anxiety: warmth, affection and acceptance from either parent reduce anxiety, while rejection, coldness, and controlling behaviors heighten it (news.uga.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Yes, the neglect and abuse did cause me all kinds of issues.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf5crqc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>More warmth and affection from both mothers and fathers were linked to fewer social anxiety symptoms. However, rejection and coldness were tied to higher levels of social anxiety.</p><p> “We’re finding these effects across cultures and age groups,” Howard said. “Giving more acceptance can be a way for parents to meaningfully help and support their children.”</p><p><strong>A controlling mom may have a stronger impact than a strict dad</strong></p><p>While it’s common for parents to set limits, tactics like guilt-tripping, holding their children to unrealistic expectations and overprotecting them can be damaging, the researchers said.</p><p>The study found children with overly controlling parents were more likely to exhibit social anxiety symptoms. And controlling mothers appeared to have a larger effect than overbearing fathers</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40894-025-00268-0">Perceived Mother and Father Parenting and Adolescent Social Anxiety Symptoms: A Meta-Analysis | Adolescent Research Review</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf4buzt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I guess the guilt-tripping and unrealistic expectations from my dad worked.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf5ugzw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thanks dad, ya fuckin mook.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf6klol/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Our primary caregivers model emotional capacity and (co)regulation skills. If kids are treated in a way that certain emotions aren&#39;t safe things to feel, labelled as a &#39;tantrums&#39;, leaving them to cry it out, punishing with physical punishments, the list goes on... This undermines their safety not just with the caregiver but also their own relationship to emotions. The healthy role of emotions is to inform us about our experience and environment as well as process our experiences in life.<br/>If they learn inner conflicts toward their own emotional states, this is when anxiety and other issues (including unhealthy coping mechanisms) start to enter the picture. It creates a predisposition to trauma and by extension vulnerability to abuse due to the lack of ability to process and integrate experiences due to these conflicts and inner aversions, lack of emotional safety and regulation skills.<br/>Would-be parents: Don&#39;t neglect your kids&#39; emotions. Take time to understand how it works and its importance. The world is harsh out there and they need a foundation of implicit <em>and</em> explicit safety (physical, emotional, social) which they can bring with themselves into the world.<br/>Emotional neglect is one of the most common and yet most covert and detrimental forms of abuse, and many parents themselves were raised that way and have no differentiating experience to understand what they&#39;re actually doing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf6bhfi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Learn what love is and love your children.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf5ahp4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Just call me Exhibit A.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf6tv5v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:25:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/disease/pancreatic-cancer-redox-protein-discovery/</link><title>By knocking out a protein duo's "bodyguard" role in mice, researchers have exposed a hidden weakness in pancreatic cancer | It's a discovery that could lead to smarter, more effective treatments for one of the deadliest cancers. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nl0awh/by_knocking_out_a_protein_duos_bodyguard_role_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nl0awh/by_knocking_out_a_protein_duos_bodyguard_role_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nl0awh/by_knocking_out_a_protein_duos_bodyguard_role_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) is the most common type of pancreatic cancer. With an overall survival rate of around 13%, it’s also one of the deadliest cancers. One reason for this is that the cancer is intrinsically resistant to nearly all forms of treatment, including chemotherapy, radiotherapy, and immunotherapy.</p><p>Now, though, a new <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2213231725003611?via%3Dihub">study</a> led by researchers from Indiana University’s (IU) School of Medicine has identified a way to weaken PDAC’s built-in defenses, offering a more effective treatment strategy for it and, potentially, other aggressive cancers.</p><p>“This research shows us a brand new vulnerability in pancreatic cancer,” said Melissa Fishel, PhD, study co-author and tumor cell biologist at the IU School of Medicine. “That opens the door to developing combination therapies that could work better than anything currently available, not just for pancreatic cancer but potentially for other aggressive cancers too.”</p><p>The researchers focused on two proteins they already knew were implicated in PDAC: redox effector factor-1 (Ref-1) and peroxiredoxin-1 (PRDX1). Both are abnormally abundant in pancreatic tumors compared with normal tissue and they work hand-in-hand to create resistance to treatment in pancreatic cancer cells. By studying Ref-1 and PRDX1 together, the researchers wanted to see if they could exploit this partnership, turning it into a therapeutic weakness.</p><p>Think of Ref-1 like a switchboard operator for cancer genes. Many cancer-driving transcription factors, which are proteins that bind to specific DNA sequences to control gene activity, need to be in the right chemical (redox) state to work. Ref-1 keeps them switched on, so they can turn up the activity of genes that help cancer cells grow, resist stress, and avoid dying. PRDX1 is, essentially, Ref-1’s bodyguard. Its main job is to clean up harmful molecules called reactive oxygen species (ROS), which build up in cells. By controlling the cell’s redox balance, PRDX1 makes sure Ref-1 can keep doing its job of activating cancer-driving genes. This “protection service” makes cancer cells tougher, because Ref-1 and its partners can keep the tumor alive even under stress.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nl0awh/by_knocking_out_a_protein_duos_bodyguard_role_in/nf1rx8p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:21:51 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/cancer/vitamin-b3-skin-cancer-risk/</link><title>Daily vitamin B3 dose cuts skin cancer risk by up to 54%: A common, over-the-counter form of vitamin B3 has emerged as an inexpensive ally in protecting us from skin cancer, lowering the risk by an average of 14% and increasing to a massive 54% for anyone who has previously had a positive diagnosis. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>My dad has Gorlin syndrome. Approximately 10years ago he commenced treatment with larger doses of B3. Instead of having 20-30 BCCs removed every ~6 months, the number has reduced to 8-12 removed every  12months.</p><p>When growing up it always confused me why he wore his hat in buildings with skylights etc. - he has always been extremely careful.</p><p>B3 has been a game changer for him.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf1qva2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The study used 500 mg of nicotinamide twice daily, for those curious.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf3239b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sounds like Australia should maybe introduce it into their food supply like iodine</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf27b4z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the news release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article: </p><p><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2838591">https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2838591</a></p><p>From the linked article: </p><p><strong>Daily vitamin B3 dose cuts skin cancer risk by up to 54%</strong></p><p><strong>A common, over-the-counter form of vitamin B3 has emerged as an inexpensive ally in protecting us from skin cancer, lowering the risk by an average of 14% and increasing to a massive 54% for anyone who has previously had a positive diagnosis</strong>. This latest study of more than 33,000 patients supports earlier evidence that emerged in a 2015 Australian trial.</p><p>Researchers from Vanderbilt University Medical Center conducted a large real-world analysis of US veterans, which looked at the health records of 33,822 individuals, comparing those prescribed niacinamide (typically 500 mg twice daily for more than 30 days) with matched patients who didn’t take it.</p><p>Overall, niacinamide – also known as nicotinamide, a vitamin B3 form found in food and supplements that supports cellular energy, DNA repair and healthy skin – was associated with a 14% lower risk of developing skin cancer. When people began nicotinamide after having earlier received a positive skin cancer diagnosis, the reduction in risk was 54%. What&#39;s more, the effect was seen in both basal cell carcinoma and cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, with the largest drop in squamous cell cancers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf1p5i8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Niacinimide is a popular skin care ingredient.  I wonder if topical use provides any cancer protection?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf2xt03/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Time to add a B vitamin complex back into my supplements.</p><p>Fluorescent pee here we come!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf2ur1w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What foods possess it? Not seeing any comments for it</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf3dv9w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:58:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41558-025-02399-7</link><title>New research shows human-caused climate change has already led to millions of deaths, illnesses, and economic losses worldwide. Heat, air pollution, infectious disease,  extreme weather are among the major drivers. (doi.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkufri/new_research_shows_humancaused_climate_change_has/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkufri/new_research_shows_humancaused_climate_change_has/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkufri/new_research_shows_humancaused_climate_change_has/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>the research shows when my balls get hot they sweat</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkufri/new_research_shows_humancaused_climate_change_has/nf6jzov/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This research shows (or claims to show) that climate change has had these effects. It does not as such show that this climate change was anthropogenic, relying on earlier work by others to make that assumption.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkufri/new_research_shows_humancaused_climate_change_has/nf1gdwp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:20:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://now.tufts.edu/2025/09/18/one-three-young-adults-skip-dentist-and-thats-problem</link><title>1 in 3 young adults skip the dentist, putting young adults at greater risk for future health problems. Dental care in the United States is still excluded from medical health insurance coverage and usually not integrated with public health initiatives that promote preventative care. (now.tufts.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn’t help that in the U.S., dental insurance is basically a coupon. If you have anything major, you’ll hit your limit and be paying out of pocket for most of the procedure.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez0i39/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s insane really. That somehow the government was convinced that eyes and mouth just don’t count as part of your body and you need a separate plan. And all we’re doing it finding out how the more we neglect the more harm we do to other parts of our body.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez11cr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I hate to break it to the researchers, but ALL ages are skipping dental visits or self limiting care. The cost of dental work to a fixed income senor means you &quot;might&quot; get one problem fixed per year and as your older, you have lots more problems than one per year and they only get worse.</p><p>I get $400 a quarter from my Advantage Medicare+ insurance. To cover <em>any</em> dental needs. I have two painful, abscessed, fractured teeth and I&#39;m struggling to figure out what necessity I can give up this next year to afford to have them pulled. Not fixed, not implanted, not even bridged. Just yank them out and give up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez63wd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Skip is a strong word for &quot;cannot afford&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez54nm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I JUST had a dentist appointment two weeks ago... after 20+ years.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez7rjb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We quite literally put $450 in our HSA every month, with the anticipation that we’ll be paying $2000/year out of pocket for dental stuff. Last 4 years: biteguard ($900); crown ($1500); gum grafting surgery ($2700); another biteguard ($800)</p><p>(Yes I’ve tried to find a cheaper option for my biteguards… every other option sucks and ends up needing to be replaced so quickly, I’d rather pay for a legit biteguard. I have very expensive post-orthodontic teeth, so it’s not worth cheaping out on this)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez6qsb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is also happening in the UK as, despite the NHS, nobody can actually get a dentist appointment without going private.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nezm9dr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:55:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://nyulangone.org/news/oral-microbes-linked-increased-risk-pancreatic-cancer</link><title>The new study sheds light on the potential relationship between bacteria and fungi in the mouth and risk of pancreatic cancer: maintaining good oral hygiene is critical (nyulangone.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkh9xn/the_new_study_sheds_light_on_the_potential/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkh9xn/the_new_study_sheds_light_on_the_potential/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkh9xn/the_new_study_sheds_light_on_the_potential/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It’s a real shame that in the United States, dental care is separated from healthcare, like it’s a completely different thing, even though all of your body works in unison. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkh9xn/the_new_study_sheds_light_on_the_potential/neyn9qu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>In the current study, the investigators analyzed bacterial and fungal DNA from the spit samples. Then, they identified 445 patients who were diagnosed with pancreatic cancer and compared the DNA of their microbes with that of another 445 randomly selected study subjects who had remained cancer-free. The team made sure to account for factors known to play a role in developing the condition, such as age, race, and how often subjects smoked cigarettes.</p><p>The findings identified 24 species of bacteria and fungi that individually either raised or lowered pancreatic cancer risk. Another three kinds of bacteria tied to the cancer were already known to contribute to periodontal disease, a serious gum infection that can eat away at the jawbone and the soft tissues surrounding teeth.</p><p>Altogether, the entire group of microbes boosted participants’ chances of developing the cancer by more than threefold.</p><p>In addition, by assessing the makeup of each participant’s oral microbiome, the scientists for the first time developed a tool that could estimate their cancer risk.</p><p>It is clearer than ever that brushing and flossing your teeth may not only help prevent periodontal disease but may also protect against cancer,” said study co-senior author Richard Hayes, DDS, MPH, PhD, a professor in the Department of Population Health</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamaoncology/fullarticle/2839132?guestAccessKey=c9b60472-cdd3-4fe3-b05b-d4f24722e2ab&amp;utm_source=for_the_media&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=ftm_links&amp;utm_content=tfl&amp;utm_term=091825">Oral Bacterial and Fungal Microbiome and Subsequent Risk for Pancreatic Cancer | Gastroenterology | JAMA Oncology | JAMA Network</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkh9xn/the_new_study_sheds_light_on_the_potential/nextfr9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Could one also not make the argument that someone that is sick with pancreatic cancer may not be doing as good of a job at taking care of their teeth as someone who does not have cancer?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkh9xn/the_new_study_sheds_light_on_the_potential/nf06oko/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:37:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.mdpi.com/2076-3425/15/9/998</link><title>A new study has found that dual n-back training improved verbal working memory in people with ADHD - a measure closely linked to IQ test performance. (mdpi.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Alright, I think I&#39;ve got it. They tested to see if working memory (in people with ADHD) improves with practice and found that it does. They had one practice setup that gets harder as you do better and found that it led to a larger improvement than the one where the difficulty doesn&#39;t scale.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/neyd4l3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Okay. I&#39;ve had a long-term interest in this. Back in 2017, Hopkins released a paper to the same effect. <a href="https://hub.jhu.edu/2017/10/17/brain-training-exercise/">https://hub.jhu.edu/2017/10/17/brain-training-exercise/</a>  </p><p>Here&#39;s the rub:  short transfer happens but they are way less sure about long transfer--iow--improvement in short-term memory on everyday tasks, for example.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/neyuv23/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Can someone summarize this for me, as I&#39;m adhd and won&#39;t get past the first paragraph.  Ok fine, I&#39;ll throw it in chatgpt</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/ney3sam/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here’s ELI5 from ChatGPT for my fellow adhd folks:</p><p>A month of playing a tough memory game (dual N-back) helped young adults with ADHD get better at remembering numbers and words, but didn’t do much for remembering visual stuff like shapes or locations.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/nf05p7x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Probably why I enjoy puzzle games like Portal so much.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/nf2q2bz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I thought IQ tests were discredited a long time ago?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkfsmw/a_new_study_has_found_that_dual_nback_training/nf0oynb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:41:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/dogs-with-large-vocabularies-can-understand-category-words-not-just-names/</link><title>Researchers found that some dogs can learn terms for functional categories, such as 'pull' and 'throw' toys. For the study published in Current Biology, owners of 10 talented dogs-mostly border collies-taught them words for two categories: tug toys, called pulls, and fetch toys, called throws. (scientificamerican.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>LAMO: &quot;mostly border collies&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/newv612/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I lived with 7 border collies on a sheep farm outside of St Davids, Wales for two months in 2024. I can attest they are almost too smart for their own good. They almost instantly figured out I was a soft touch. :-)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/nexoaa1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Huh, neat. I kinda stumbled across this myself with my Australian Cattle Dog. Anything that is used for fetch such as a soft toy or ball she&#39;ll bring to you if you say &quot;Get your ball.&quot; She will distinctly go after a rope if you ask for a rope instead though. </p><p>I assumed she was learning the toys by name and just thought anything was a ball, but this would match with what style of toy they are and how you play with it like this study.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/nexxmge/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I have border collies. Mine absolutely understand the difference and play with different toys accordingly. They also know the command “tug” and “fetch” </p><p>However mine are frisbee obsessed and would never tug a frisbee with you even on command.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/nexxaxb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We are taking care of our daughter and son in law’s Aussie/Border Collie while they manage young children and a house renovation. The dog is so smart it’s almost unbelievable.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/ney03y1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Well my retriever is very pretty.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/neyg00p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Our two dogs are from the same litter. They are almost two yrs old and half border collie/ half Siberian husky. They seem to be learning a lot of phrases with verbs. When it’s associated with treats they are always quicker to pick things up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcfgs/researchers_found_that_some_dogs_can_learn_terms/ney4iuq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:36:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/women-tend-to-feel-more-fearful-in-nature-especially-when-social-threats-are-present/</link><title>Women tend to feel more fearful in nature, especially when social threats are present | Study found women consistently expressed more fear, perceived higher risk, and were less inclined to explore wooded environments when potential dangers were present. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>As a woman who loves being in nature, I don’t feel secure if there’re no people around and I would be an easy target for a potential attacker.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nex701x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They buried the important bit in the article.</p><p>&#39;Across the board, women again reported higher levels of fear and lower willingness to explore the environments. This was especially true when the danger was social in nature. In fact, the presence of a social threat produced the strongest gender differences. Women’s fear scores spiked significantly in these conditions, while men’s responses remained largely unaffected. This pattern was not seen when the danger was physical or animal-related.&quot;</p><p>So it appears its all social threat  though the wording of the article is not that clear and im not going to examine the paper. The women were not more fearful or deterred by other threats. Which is interesting.</p><p>Though I wouldn&#39;t overly trust the results given the methodology.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nexjxqx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That&#39;s because of the implications...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/newwkdd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: Women are more likely than men to feel unsafe in nature, particularly in areas with dense vegetation or when social threats are implied, according to a new study <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0272494425002051?via%3Dihub">published</a> in the Journal of Environmental Psychology. Across three experiments involving hundreds of adults in the United Kingdom, women consistently expressed more fear, perceived higher risk, and were less inclined to explore wooded environments when potential dangers were present.</p><p>The study was partially inspired by a viral social media trend that captured public attention in 2024. The “Man or bear” debate asked users whether they would rather encounter a man or a bear while alone in the woods. Many women chose the bear, suggesting that they perceived a greater threat from an unknown man than from a wild animal. This phenomenon sparked a broader discussion about women’s experiences of safety in natural environments and highlighted how social fears can shape engagement with nature.</p><p>Although earlier studies have shown that environmental features like vegetation density can influence feelings of safety, relatively few had examined how those effects may vary by gender, especially when different types of threats — such as social, animal, or physical dangers — are involved. The researchers sought to fill this gap using experimental methods that allowed them to systematically vary environmental cues and measure psychological responses.</p><p>“I became interested in women’s experiences in forests and greenspaces because I had a few experiences in nature myself when I didn’t feel entirely safe, and as a consequence the visit was not as enjoyable as I hoped,” explained study author Anna Bornioli, a Marie Skłodowska-Curie Postdoctoral Fellow at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health and an associate researcher at the Environmental Psychology Research Group at the University of Surrey, where this study was conducted.</p><p>“When chatting with my friends about this, I realised that many female friends empathized, having had similarly bad experiences. On the other hand, many male friends had no idea of what we were talking about. So I started to wonder if gender has anything to do with how we experience nature, and reflected on how gender stereotypes, the way we are brought up, and safety concerns can affect nature experiences. This specific study focuses on safety perceptions.”</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/newqb4z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I love that no one reads in <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science">r/science</a>. The study is clearly suggesting women are more afraid of being attacked by &quot;social threats&quot;, in other words, people.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nexqa9k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Women also live longer</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nex7dvk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I feel like this is probably true in any setting? Women have more to be fearful of than men, generally… even walking a city street, I think women are just going to have more anxiety about people looking at them, following, etc.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nexp0zo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:32:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/wildfire-smoke-global-deaths-2050</link><title>Wildfire smoke will kill nearly 1.4m each year by end of century if emissions not curbed - study (theguardian.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Sadly Death of people doesnt matter. what is the financial costs to this? that is the only thing that will make anyone change their minds.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/newsjxq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>People don&#39;t care because they can&#39;t envisage it ever affecting them. There&#39;s also the element of the tragedy of the commons with all this. The people who do care fall into two camps. The first cares but doesn&#39;t want or can&#39;t afford to pay due to their own financial circumstances (this is not a criticism, just an observation) and the second do care, will pay but are sadly so much on the minority that it makes minimal difference.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/nex4oe5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Death is one way an ecosystem balances itself.  Whether it&#39;s food, resources, or carbon emissions.  If the system can&#39;t sustain something, that thing gets rebalanced.  4M people a year will mean fewer emissions.  Deaths will continue until balance is achieved.</p><p>Or, we can reduce emissions ourselves.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/newtsag/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here is some of the biggest news on the subject:  PBS, August 2025:  <em>Why firefighters are facing toxic smoke with little to no protection</em></p><blockquote><p>tens of thousands of wildfire fighters go out for weeks and months at a time in toxic smoke with no protection, no masks...many of them are getting very sick...</p><p>for these guys who are out fighting wildfires...they&#39;re told not to wear masks, even if they want to go and buy their own...the Forest Service, which employs most of the wildfire firefighters, says that that&#39;s because they worry about heat stress. They worry that, if these guys had masks on, they might get heatstroke.</p></blockquote><p>Article continues with the following, but this claim is debatable:</p><blockquote><p>in other countries, wildland firefighters now do wear masks, and there have not been upticks in heatstroke at all. </p></blockquote><p>Wildlands firefighters often work all day. Try to do any difficult physical labor hour after hour with a mask. America&#39;s summers are getting ferociously hot.   Firemen putting out fires in buildings typically work for shorter periods; arguably they can undergo that rigor.  Obviously anyone working near smoke <em>should</em> wear a mask, but this topic for all-day woodland firefighters is a challenging one.  And this:</p><blockquote><p>people who spent years at the agency...say that if the Forest Service were to allow firefighters to wear masks, it would mean admitting that smoke is dangerous. And that could cause a huge rethinking of the whole way the agency works right now.</p></blockquote></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/neyyc3v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>By some measures, that is somewhat optimistic.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/nex0dr9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Welcome to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science">r/science</a>! This is a heavily moderated subreddit in order to keep the discussion on science. However, we recognize that many people want to discuss how they feel the research relates to their own personal lives, so to give people a space to do that, <strong>personal anecdotes are allowed as responses to this comment</strong>. Any anecdotal comments elsewhere in the discussion will be removed and our <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/wiki/rules#wiki_comment_rules">normal comment rules</a> apply to all other comments.</p><hr/><p><strong>Do you have an academic degree?</strong> We can verify your credentials in order to assign user flair indicating your area of expertise. <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science/wiki/flair/">Click here to apply</a>.</p><hr/><p>User: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/Splenda">u/Splenda</a><br/>Permalink: <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/wildfire-smoke-global-deaths-2050">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/wildfire-smoke-global-deaths-2050</a></p><hr/><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/science">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/newljqy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If people would stop with the baby gender reveal parties…..</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkbpwk/wildfire_smoke_will_kill_nearly_14m_each_year_by/nexi67u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:10:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496879-vitamin-d-supplements-may-lower-your-level-of-one-type-of-vitamin-d/</link><title>Vitamin D supplements may lower your level of one type of vitamin D (newscientist.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;They found taking vitamin D2 supplements can lead to a drop in the body’s concentration of vitamin D3. Why this happens, or if vitamin D3 supplements reduce vitamin D2 levels, isn’t entirely clear.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/new609t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The headline is misleading, the study actually shows that D2 suplements lower your levels of D3, but there isn&#39;t evidence that supplementing with D3 affects your D2 levels. It doesn&#39;t recommend stopping supplementing with either, just suggests that D3 is probably more effective.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/new6y7k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While you should always double-check, I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve ever come across a supplement which wasn&#39;t D3.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/newadju/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>mods, why has this clickbaity title been allowed here?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/nexis7i/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tldr, just take D3</p><p>Bonus point, add K2</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/newaum4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This may be relevant to some parents of newborns and young infants, as formula is fortified with vitamin D, and infants exclusively on breast milk are recommended to have Vitamin D supplements. I just checked the vitamin D drops that I have, and it is cholecalciferol, which is D3. The formula I have on hand also specifies D3, but the drops and formula are both Enfamil. It wouldn&#39;t be a bad idea to double check any baby products to see if they specify D2 or ergocalciferol.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/nexpx4d/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>D3 K2 tablets here. I have MDS ( it&#39;s called a &quot; Cinderella condition &quot; because it&#39;s a bit off the radar, and the only famous people to pop their clogs from it are my hero the scientist Carl Sagan, and Larry Hagman the actor ) The D3 K2 supplements are veggie / vegan and cheap as chips.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/nex8npl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:54:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/cancer/medicine-colorectal-cancer/</link><title>Common daily pill slashes colorectal cancer's return by 55% | A study involving more than 1,000 cancer patients has found that a low dose of aspirin halves the risk of colorectal tumors returning after surgery. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Great news. But a cancer patient needs to know if they have this gene variant to decide if this treatment should be pursued.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/nev82uf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: A <a href="https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2504650">study</a> involving more than 1,000 cancer patients has found that a low dose of aspirin halves the risk of colorectal tumors returning after surgery. This readily available and inexpensive treatment could change health outcomes for a significant number of cancer survivors who have problematic gene variants.</p><p>Researchers from Karolinska Institutet and Karolinska University Hospital screened 3,508 patients with stage I, II, or III rectal cancer or stage II or III colon cancer, finding that 1,103 of these people had a specific variant in the PI3K pathway – the genetic marker of interest. The team then conducted a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial on this gene-altered cohort, with 626 patients receiving 160-mg aspirin daily for three years and the remainder taking a placebo.</p><p>This study, known as the ALASCCA trial, was a massive effort involving 33 hospitals in Sweden, Norway, Denmark and Finland. The team prioritized people with the PIK3CA gene mutation, as well as people with other moderate or high impact variants in PIK3R1 and PTEN. The researchers selected for these genetic alterations because some previous research has shown that aspirin intervention has had a positive impact on suppressing tumor growth.</p><p>&quot;Aspirin is being tested here in a completely new context as a precision medicine treatment,&quot; said first author Anna Martling, a professor at the Department of Molecular Medicine and Surgery, Karolinska Institutet. &quot;This is a clear example of how we can use genetic information to personalize treatment and at the same time save both resources and suffering.&quot;</p><p>What they found was that for people with the genetic mutation in PIK3, aspirin lowered the risk of recurrence by 55% compared with placebo treatment. The researchers believe that the benefit likely comes from aspirin acting in several ways – by reducing inflammation and inhibiting platelet function and tumor growth. Overall, aspirin makes the environment more challenging for cancer to get a foothold in, particularly for people with the genetic makeup predisposed to dysregulated cell function, where cancer cell growth and division is more likely.</p><p>&quot;Although we do not yet fully understand all the molecular links, the findings strongly support the biological rationale and suggest that the treatment may be particularly effective in genetically defined subgroups of patients,&quot; said Martling. &quot;Aspirin is a drug that is readily available globally and extremely inexpensive compared to many modern cancer drugs, which is very positive.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/nev5ko7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Great news but aspirin can also cause erosion of the small intestine so I’d like to see a long term chronic use study before anyone tries to adopt aspirin as a preventative therapy for cancer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/newb7ks/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As someone who&#39;s had a colorectal cancer... well, I&#39;m also allergic to aspirin, so that&#39;s a non-solution for me. I wonder how many other people are allergic to aspirin?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/newiwjd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Didn&#39;t RFK just say something bad about asprin?  Cancer has taken too many of my friends and family, and my family has history of cancerous gene variants.  </p><p>Colorectal is just terrible.  I hope this study  shows promise.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/new42u5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>why does the title say common dailypill and not just aspirin?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4z0o/common_daily_pill_slashes_colorectal_cancers/nez9nlf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:19:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/au/blog/the-asymmetric-brain/202509/is-this-the-end-of-the-growth-mindset-theory</link><title>Growth mindset interventions are often used to improve academic performance of students. But a new study found that growth mindset interventions do not improve academic achievements of students. Just by telling somebody that their intelligence can grow if they work hard, it does not actually grow. (psychologytoday.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This may suggest that you can&#39;t give them growth mindset training alone. If you&#39;re giving them that training but not also giving them the training how to study well, I could see this failing--you&#39;re telling them that they can do better without telling them how.</p><p>Moreover, what if you give them the training and they just don&#39;t care anyway?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev4on6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Telling someone about growth mindsets doesn&#39;t give them a growth mindset. And that&#39;s all these &#39;interventions&#39; ever are.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev64y8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you tell people to get over their depression, you&#39;ll probably get the same results.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev669x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But that isn’t what it was for? They were never primarily academic, and certainly not about quick results</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nevjqf7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Isn&#39;t growth mindset just about taking risks and being ok with failure and mistakes?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev42dp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What an awful headline. First is start talking about students academic performance then ends with intelligence. I am not certain the two are always synonymous nor do I believe intelligence can truly be measured in any useful capacity.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nevkb8y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Not to be facetious, but did anyone think this actually worked? Were there real studies that led people down this path?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev3ohh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://umaine.edu/news/blog/2025/09/15/culture-is-driving-a-major-shift-in-human-evolution-new-theory-proposes/</link><title>Culture is driving a major shift in human evolution, new theory proposes. Today, improvements in health, longevity and survival reliably come from group-level cultural systems like scientific medicine and hospitals, sanitation infrastructure and education systems rather than individual intelligence (umaine.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I was under the impression this was already the commonly accepted theory for post-stone-age human development</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/nev2ea8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Humans may be evolving into group-dependent superorganisms, where societal health matters more than individual traits. That makes our collective leadership even more powerful than ever before. The systems we build, the values we promote, and the leaders we empower become evolutionary levers. Political leadership isn’t just about policy and more about steering the collective intelligence that defines our survival.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/nev8k1m/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Researchers at the University of Maine are theorizing that human beings may be in the midst of a major evolutionary shift — driven not by genes, but by culture.</p><p>In a paper published in the Oxford journal BioScience, Timothy M. Waring, an associate professor of economics and sustainability, and Zachary T. Wood, a researcher in ecology and environmental sciences, argue that culture is overtaking genetics as the main force shaping human evolution. </p><p>“Human evolution seems to be changing gears,” said Waring. “When we learn useful skills, institutions or technologies from each other, we are inheriting adaptive cultural practices. On reviewing the evidence, we find that culture solves problems much more rapidly than genetic evolution. This suggests our species is in the middle of a great evolutionary transition.”</p><p>Cultural practices — from farming methods to legal codes — spread and adapt far faster than genes can, allowing human groups to adapt to new environments and solve novel problems in ways biology alone could never match. According to the research team, this long-term evolutionary transition extends deep into the past, it is accelerating, and may define our species for millenia to come. </p><p>Culture now preempts genetic adaptation</p><p>“Cultural evolution eats genetic evolution for breakfast,” said Wood, “it’s not even close.”</p><p>Waring and Wood describe how in the modern environment cultural systems adapt so rapidly they routinely “preempt” genetic adaptation. For example, eyeglasses and surgery correct vision problems that genes once left to natural selection. Medical technologies like cesarean sections or fertility treatments allow people to survive and reproduce in circumstances that once would have been fatal or sterile. These cultural solutions, researchers argue, reduce the role of genetic adaptation and increase our reliance on cultural systems such as hospitals, schools and governments.</p><p>“Ask yourself this: what matters more for your personal life outcomes, the genes you are born with, or the country where you live?” Waring said. “Today, your well-being is determined less and less by your personal biology and more and more by the cultural systems that surround you — your community, your nation, your technologies. And the importance of culture tends to grow over the long term because culture accumulates adaptive solutions more rapidly.”</p><p>Over time, this dynamic could mean that human survival and reproduction depend less on individual genetic traits and more on the health of societies and their cultural infrastructure.</p><p>But, this transition comes with a twist. Because culture is fundamentally a shared phenomenon, culture tends to generate group-based solutions.</p><p><a href="https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/advance-article-abstract/doi/10.1093/biosci/biaf094/8230384?redirectedFrom=fulltext">https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/advance-article-abstract/doi/10.1093/biosci/biaf094/8230384?redirectedFrom=fulltext</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/nev1g99/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Ape together strong.</p><p>Our collective intelligence and technology has been our key to success for thousands of years.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/nf06e1w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Culture can also drive those things in the other direction.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/nevaeu1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I feel like evolution currently “favors” whatever genes are in situations where education about and access to birth control are lacking. Moreover more patriarchal cultures that keep women thinking their role in society is to be a mother. </p><p>This may not be because of certain genes. But the genes that are commonly in this situation will replicate faster than others.</p><p>I feel like there’s sources to back this up but I  don’t feel like doing more work so this is purely an opinion and may be completely wrong.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/nev9ufg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Eusocial society’s similar to most modern cultures still are affected by genes, it’s just minimal but in the long run it still plays a roll. It’s why biodiversity is considered to include culture, I don’t feel like this is a new idea, it’s just a paper that’s clearly stating it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4e73/culture_is_driving_a_major_shift_in_human/nf70l2g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:45:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/17/climate/national-academies-climate-trump.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mk8.H9nY.DT8PLhUIEux5</link><title>Top Scientists Find Growing Evidence That Greenhouse Gases Are, in Fact, a Danger (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.zinnedproject.org/news/tdih/coal-burning-co2-emissions-and-global-temperatures/">https://www.zinnedproject.org/news/tdih/coal-burning-co2-emissions-and-global-temperatures/</a></p><p>Evidence growing for 113 years and counting.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netmlom/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hasn&#39;t this been known for a while?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/net4jkv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Posting this salient paragraph cause zero people commenting  clicked on the link </p><p>&gt;The report, published by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, is significant because it could complicate the Trump administration’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/07/29/climate/epa-endangerment-finding-repeal-proposal.html">efforts to revoke a landmark scientific determination</a>, known as the endangerment finding, that underpins the federal government’s legal authority to control the pollution that is driving climate change.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/nettart/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Shocker!! What’s amazing is how oil &amp; gas companies have suckered the world to cling to their ugly , toxic, inefficient, outdated fuel that ruins our planet and future!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netv2ec/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>yeah but the new nasa admin is announcing that the suns activity is increasing. that will be used to stop all green initiatives because &quot;it&#39;s not human caused&quot; climate change anymore. lots of conspiracy theories about the sun causing the issues just got validated</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netje4y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I feel like 99% if posts here are just &quot;study finds that water makes stuff wet.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netanrl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is the crux of why Trump and his administration is so anti-science, it&#39;s difficult to find any of his policies supported by the science. Trump is the mumbo-jumbo President.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/neu3sob/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:33:02 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.upi.com/Health_News/2025/09/17/circumcision-rates-decline-United-States-mistrust-doctors/5851758118319/</link><title>Study notes decrease in popularity of circumcision in United States (upi.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This article is misleading in how they represent the WHO. The WHO and UNAIDS only recommend male circumcision in their HIV prevention package which was geared towards areas with a high risk of HIV (namely Eastern and Southern Africa). This is <em>not</em> a universal recommendation.</p><p>I could not find any major medical bodies that recommend routine circumcisions in the West, and several bodies such as the AAP and Canadian Paediatric Society explicitly say that they do not recommend it. Some European bodies explicitly advise against routine circumcision for males unless medically necessary.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesskrx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>&quot;Based on our findings, we believe that multiple factors may contribute to the decline in the number of neonates circumcised,&quot; co-senior researcher Dr. Aaron Tobian, a professor of pathology at Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine in Baltimore, said in a news release.</p><p>The sort of distrust that&#39;s led to vaccine skepticism and hesitancy is likely one of those factors, researchers said.</p><p>&quot;Despite overwhelming evidence that neonatal male circumcisions provide health benefits, increasing public skepticism in the United States toward medical recommendations may be driving more parents to choose not to have their sons get circumcised,&quot; Tobian said.</p></blockquote><p>I really dislike this framing. I feel our decision to not circumcise was based on medical advice and recommendations from reputable, credible international and national organizations. Just not exclusively and entirely based on what a couple specific US based orgs and agencies may have recommended.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesqrak/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Disregarding the usual Reddit tilting about circumcision, it simply isn&#39;t medically necessary for most men, the history of circumcision in the US generally stems from religious purity culture, and decisions for elective surgeries should be left to the individual for when they&#39;re adults.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nessr46/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You know what else prevents HIV? Condoms. And not only are they several times more effective, they also don&#39;t involve violating an infant&#39;s bodily autonomy and disfiguring their genitals.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesuqx1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I am glad it&#39;s decreasing. I won&#39;t circumcise my son if I ever have one. Millions upon millions of European men are doing just fine, rarely if ever have issues being uncircumcised, and are somehow managing the <em>really simple</em> task of keeping themselves clean.  </p><p>There is no good reason to <em>proactively</em> do it. If a need arises, do it then. But issues are so rare it doesn&#39;t justify routinely doing it to everyone.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesvphl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yea I am not an antivax, distrust in healthcare kind of guy. I personally just think chopping of a piece of a baby&#39;s bits as soon they are born is simply weird, and wish someone had given me a say in the matter. Simply teaching your child to wash properly eliminates any and all issues related to infections. Shocking I know.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesvs3q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It should have been made illegal 100 years ago.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/netdbmt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 05:05:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.unsw.edu.au/newsroom/news/2025/09/ai-reveals-gender-bias-in-family-courts?&amp;</link><title>The language chosen by judges in family courts reinforces gender biases, with mothers seen mainly as caregivers and fathers judged on their ability to provide financially. Fathers were also praised for even a limited involvement in childcare, whereas mothers' efforts were expected (unsw.edu.au)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Another example – again, consistent with previous work – was when judges looked at whether a father has capacity to care for his child, he often received the benefit of his new partner’s capacity. Where the court was satisfied the father could provide care for his children ‘with the assistance of his present wife&#39;.”</p><p>This would really piss me off as a mother.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/neu6g0j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This title kind of buries the lede here. Language that the judges use always matters, and fathers are often rewarded for limited involvement while mothers’ efforts are expected, but those are both fairly surface level observations that society has regardless. The precise language you use always matters, especially in court. Mothers are always expected to give everything while fathers are generally praised for giving anything at all. Genuine sociological norms in the American 21st century that I’d expect a high schooler to know. </p><p>What I find interesting is that there’s apparent gender differences with 2/3 of all judges being men, but this article doesn’t go into how that imbalance really affects court orders. The article says female judges prioritize the kids while male judges prioritize “court procedures and processes”? But it doesn’t go into what that means or how it affects the children. </p><p>I think it’s <em>really</em> interesting that the article points out that these were known, voiced, and discussed issues already. But it’s interesting that the conversation was only given weight once ai confirmed its (known) existence. </p><p>They discuss how male &amp; female lecturers were evaluated differently. Men were authoritative, women were approachable. That’s interesting.</p><p>They didn’t even factor in minorities! They had ai run this study on gender but supposedly weren’t able to have ai run racial studies. Odd. Interesting, even. I don’t know yall. Basically, ai confirmed known biases that we knew exist. It only ran gender biases. It only confirmed known &amp; proven stereotypes that exist in family court. It’s just another straw in the hay bale of proof that discrimination exists in our society. <strong>It’s not new. It’s been known for decades.</strong></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nespk9t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yea. This sucks. I was the stay at home dad, took care and nurtured my kids. Effing judge still gave them to my ex.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesfe6b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Do judges anywhere get anti-bias trainings? </p><p>And I mean real training, tested, evaluated, and then repeated after some years?</p><p>Or, because judges ARE justice, there is no such mechanism?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nevhtpp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hi <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science">r/science</a> - sharing this study led by our researcher Associate Professor Mehera San Roque.</p><p>The team analysed more than 2500 custody and parenting judgments across 4330 documents, handed down in Australian family courts between 2001 and 2021. They looked at the way male and female judges spoke to, and about, male and female parties in relation to their capacity to care for their children and found that judgments reflected gender stereotypes.</p><p>Here&#39;s a link to the full study if you&#39;d like to check it out: <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0331841#sec012">https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0331841#sec012</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesam5w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Glad to have hard evidence on what has always seemed like reality.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesbbsw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&#39;“We used AI to uncover the biases we knew existed in the legal system but remained ‘hidden’,” says the study’s lead author Associate Professor Mehera San Roque&#39;</p><p>That&#39;s not how we do science.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesh681/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 03:46:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.fox13now.com/news/health/utah-researchers-find-decreased-risk-of-skin-cancer-in-those-with-tattoos</link><title>Utah researchers find decreased risk of skin cancer in those with tattoos (fox13now.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>And as the article mentions it is quite likely because those with multiple tattoos are more likely to apply sunscreen.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/nervuog/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There’s also evidence to suggest the ink is toxic, so ya know, pros and cons. </p><p><a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35592919/">https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35592919/</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/nes9a84/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I wonder if there is a behavioral link. Speaking anecdotally, I started using more sunscreen after I got my tattoos because constant sun can break them down faster. If there&#39;s a significant number of like minded tattooed people, that could explain it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/nes89oh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Glad I got that flaming hotdog with a naked lady riding it on my chest after all.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/nes1i4u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But with a higher risk of developing lymphoma. Statistic wise, not a good trade up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/nes18w3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I am covered in tattoos. I’ve always used sunscreen but it wasn’t until I was covered in tattoos that I did so religiously. </p><p>That being said, I can also see the argument that those most likely to get tattoos in the first place are also less likely to be vigilant about sunscreen.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/neshuz1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Never used so much lotion OR sunscreen until I got started my bodysuit to be honest.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njozex/utah_researchers_find_decreased_risk_of_skin/nesucmh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:23:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://news.northeastern.edu/2025/09/17/covid-precautions-polical-parties-study/</link><title>At the height of the pandemic, Americans of all political stripes were on guard against COVID, new research finds (news.northeastern.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Summary of a paywalled study.  What&#39;s the point of discussing this if we can&#39;t read the original study?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/ner0nui/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s been 5.5 years and people forget what was happening in the world that caused all political stripes to take COVID seriously when it made its way to the United States. Like the China lockdown and the morgues overflowing in Italy.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/nescsrq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There seems to be a distinction between two types of people. </p><p>As people became complacent and learned more about the virus they took fewer precautions. </p><p>Normal people are used to moving targets. But fools, well… they felt foolish, they felt like they over reacted. Rather than simply making peace with that fact they look for someone to offload that shame on to. </p><p>“FAuCI LieD to Us!1!!”</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/nerb00j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Were&quot; until a certain president decided he couldn&#39;t resist politicizing the situation and it was all downhill from there.  His first administration does still deserve a lot of the credit for Operation Warp Speed, but other than that, dear lord...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/neskr5e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Were&quot; is the key word. And then....</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/ner8np3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Isn&#39;t there a study that showed the damage by the virus before and after the vaccine, showing the difference between political affiliation?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/nesedx6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Not cops.  They would purposely congregate on corners in Chicago without masks.  I still respect them less for being so f’n weird about it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njl8tt/at_the_height_of_the_pandemic_americans_of_all/neu661h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chimpanzees-alcohol-cocktails-fruit-research/</link><title>Wild chimpanzees consume the equivalent of 2 cocktails a day in the form of boozy fruit, research finds (cbsnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I knew of a place in Portland (OR) that had cherry trees in the back yard. Starlings would party like crazy on the cherries fermenting on the ground. Drunk, flopping birds on the ground, birds in the trees keeping watch and making loud bird laughing noises. Crazy scene would go on for days. Outrageous amounts of noise.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/ner3qt0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Am ape<br/>I too like being buzzed, chillen among the trees</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/neqysmw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Wow how responsible of them, so no heavy boozy fruit consumption. I wonder if they would get any of the long term diseases associated with alcohol.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/nere85u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And humans think they are so different…</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/neqxdz0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sure ok but what about the more responsible chimps?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/ner5ols/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While in this case (Ugandan fig) it doesn&#39;t match the alcohol level of a more *impaired* primate, as far as tolerance &amp; abv level (fruit @ .3% by weight / kombucha-level ), other cases of primates included what appeared to be abv% seeking behaviour in other groups of wild chimps &amp; other primates.</p><p><strong><em>Caribbean monkeys</em></strong>, for example, with a penchant for pilfering tourist cocktails. Repeatedly in large amounts, resulting in a dramatic effect/impairment, apparently seeking intoxication.</p><p><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/277985406_Tools_to_tipple_Ethanol_ingestion_by_wild_chimpanzees_using_leaf-sponges/link/62a32160a3fe3e3df86c5ffd/download"><strong><em>The Palm Wine-drinking Chimpanzees of Bossou</em></strong></a></p><p>A community of wild chimpanzees in Guinea that have been observed for ~20 years consuming fermented raffia palm sap, a potent alcoholic beverage with up to 6.9% ABV. <strong><em>Using tools</em></strong> (leaf-sponges) they fashion by chewing leaves—to intentionally access the sap from containers left by villagers &amp; resulting in observed effective behaviour. This deliberate tool use indicates that their consumption of the alcoholic beverage isn&#39;t accidental.</p><p>On a humorous note:</p><blockquote><p>Wild chimpanzees consume the equivalent of 2 cocktails a day</p></blockquote><p><strong><em>Wild chimpanzees</em></strong>?... Wait until they learn:</p><p><strong><em>Really Wild Chimps</em></strong> are hammered by noon, hungover &amp; then breaking their fast by binging!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/net60t0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hey, after a long day of swinging through trees and avoiding hungry cheetahs who wouldn&#39;t enjoy a nice cocktail to wind down.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/nero2kf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:41:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09534-6</link><title>Repeated head trauma causes neuron loss and inflammation in young athletes (nature.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s almost like maybe the game of American Football should be drastically overhauled for the health of our young people and older athletes alike. </p><p>No? We like the game as is? Okay.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/neqwhzq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I remember Junior Seau never had a severe concussion during his pro career. But with all the repeated head blows, his brain was basically mush when they scanned his brained after his autopsy.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/nergan6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Puleez.  Next your going to try and tell me smoking causes cancer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/neqssne/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Meanwhile, in full contact martial arts, the goal remains to inflict traumatic brain damage on one&#39;s opponent....</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/ner45pa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Wrestlers have had these issues for a long time. There was that one guy who killed his family, Chris Benoit.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/nexv1gl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Nah you’re lying, that can’t be</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/nequo2b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I don&#39;t understand. Isn&#39;t this already established and a known fact for decades? What&#39;s the news in this article? </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njk5ts/repeated_head_trauma_causes_neuron_loss_and/ner0kje/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:20:52 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
