<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=science&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/science</title><description>Hot posts in /r/science (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:38:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_mouw-styles-communityIcon_xtjipkhhefi41-144x400.png</url><title>/r/science</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.sciencealert.com/our-sun-is-becoming-more-active-and-nasa-doesnt-know-why</link><title>NASA scientists say our Sun's activity is on an escalating trajectory, outside the boundaries of the 11-year solar cycle. A new analysis suggests that the activity of the Sun has been gradually rising since 2008, for reasons we don't yet understand. (sciencealert.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1niyo1j/nasa_scientists_say_our_suns_activity_is_on_an/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><img width="642" height="260" src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-642x260.jpg" alt="Our Sun Is Becoming More Active And NASA Doesn't Know Why" srcset="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-642x260.jpg 642w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-768x311.jpg 768w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity-600x243.jpg 600w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/sun-activity.jpg 1024w"> <span> <span>A snapshot of solar activity captured by NASA's Solar Dynamics Observatory in 2013.</span> <span><a href="https://science.nasa.gov/image-detail/amf-gsfc_20171208_archive_e001435/">(NASA/Goddard/SDO)</a></span> </span> </p><div><p>At the end of the last solar cycle in 2019, the official predictions were that the next cycle would be <a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/news/solar-cycle-25-forecast-update">just as mild as its predecessor</a>.</p><p>Those predictions were wrong. The current Solar Cycle 25 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Solar_Cycle_25_prediction_and_progression.png">turned out far stronger</a> than NASA and NOAA expected. Now, scientists say that the Sun's activity is on an escalating trajectory, outside the boundaries of the 11-year solar cycle. In fact, a new analysis of the data suggests that the activity of the Sun has been gradually rising since 2008.</p><p>"All signs were pointing to the Sun going into a prolonged phase of low activity," <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasa-analysis-shows-suns-activity-ramping-up/">says plasma physicist Jamie Jasinski</a> of NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL). "So it was a surprise to see that trend reversed. The Sun is slowly waking up."</p><p><b>Related: </b><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/something-is-up-with-the-sun-and-it-could-mean-our-models-are-wrong"><b>The Sun Is Being Weird. It Could Be Because We're Looking at It All Wrong.</b></a></p><p>The Sun seems like a constant, reassuring presence day to day, but it's actually fairly tempestuous and changeable. One particular change it undergoes is what we call the solar cycle. Every 11 years or so, the Sun undergoes an increase in activity to <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/its-official-nasa-declares-the-solar-maximum-is-happening-now">solar maximum</a> before subsiding again down to solar minimum.</p><p>This activity manifests as a significant increase in sunspots, solar flares, and coronal mass ejections at solar maximum, at which point the Sun's poles reverse their polarity. It's all very normal; if the number didn't give it away, we're currently in the 25th solar cycle on record, which means scientists have been watching this happen for centuries now, using sunspots as a proxy to record solar activity.</p><p>However, even with this wealth of solar cycle data, predicting how the Sun is going to behave is an inexact art. There's a lot more going on inside the Sun than we are privy to, driving changes that scientists are still trying to explain.</p><p>For example, for <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/we-might-finally-be-able-to-find-out-why-the-sun-was-naked-for-70-years">a 70-year period from 1645 to 1715</a>, almost no sunspots appeared at all, a period known as the Maunder Minimum. A similar lull occurred between 1790 and 1830, known as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dalton_Minimum">Dalton Minimum</a>.</p><figure><img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/solar-cycle-graph.jpg" alt width="642" height="266" srcset="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/solar-cycle-graph.jpg 642w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/solar-cycle-graph-600x249.jpg 600w"><figcaption>A graph showing sunspot activity since 1750. (<a href="https://www.swpc.noaa.gov/products/solar-cycle-progression">NOAA SWPC</a>)</figcaption></figure><p>"We don't really know why the Sun went through a 40-year minimum starting in 1790," <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/science-research/heliophysics/nasa-analysis-shows-suns-activity-ramping-up/">Jasinski says</a>. "The longer-term trends are a lot less predictable and are something we don't completely understand yet."</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_solar_cycles">Solar cycles</a> 22 and 23, commencing in 1986 and 1996, respectively, were pretty average in terms of sunspot activity. In spite of this, the solar wind pressure steadily decreased over both cycles, leading scientists to believe that we might be headed towards something similar to the Maunder or Dalton events.</p><p>In 2008, Solar Cycle 24 commenced, becoming one of the weakest solar cycles on record in terms of sunspot and flare activity. Solar Cycle 25, scientists thought, was going to be more of the same, but its activity level turned out to be higher, more consistent with an average solar cycle.</p><p>Jasinski and his colleague, space physicist Marco Velli of JPL, have now analyzed <a href="https://omniweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/">long-term solar data</a> and found something surprising. In 2008, at the start of Solar Cycle 24, the solar wind began growing stronger and has continued to increase steadily since then.</p><div></div><p>That strength is measured in speed, density, temperature, thermal pressure, mass, momentum, energy, and magnetic field magnitude, all of which showed an increase.</p><p>Now, the Sun is an extraordinarily complex engine, and one thing that's crystal clear is that it's really difficult to predict what it's going to do next. Jasinski and Velli believe their findings indicate that we could see an uptick in rowdy space weather, with powerful winds, <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/geomagnetic-storms">solar storms</a>, flares, and coronal mass ejections.</p><p>Their results are also consistent with another aspect of the Sun's behavior: the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hale%27s_law">Hale cycle</a>. This is represented by pairs of solar cycles, with each Hale cycle lasting 22 years, ending when the magnetic poles swap back to their original polarities. A growing body of evidence suggests that the Hale cycle is the primary cycle, and each solar cycle is only half of the full cycle.</p><p>At the moment, the solar wind pressure is still lower than it was at the turn of the 20th century. The only way we will know what it does from this point is to continue observing to see whether it continues to increase or remains stable.</p><p>The findings also have much broader implications, adding to the mounting evidence that sunspot numbers present, at best, an incomplete picture. We need to study a much wider catalog of solar behavior if we wish to understand the dynamics of our wild, beautiful star.</p><p>The research has been published in <a href="https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/adf3a6"><i>The Astrophysical Journal Letters</i></a>.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/SungFXUsoqw/0.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/TWjtYSRlOUI/0.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 06:00:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0895435625002768</link><title>A new study on SSRI antidepressants finds no support for the theorized subgroup of patients who get substantially more benefit from SSRIs than from placebo. (sciencedirect.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nijr86/a_new_study_on_ssri_antidepressants_finds_no/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nijr86/a_new_study_on_ssri_antidepressants_finds_no/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nijr86/a_new_study_on_ssri_antidepressants_finds_no/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S0895435625X00081-cov150h.gif' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-content"><span><span>Skip to main content</span></span></a><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-title"><span><span>Skip to article</span></span></a></p><header></header><div><article><div><p><span>Under a Creative Commons </span><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><span><span>license</span></span></a></p><p>Open access</p></div><div><h2>Abstract</h2><div><h3>Objectives</h3><p>To replicate Stone et al's (2022) finding that the distribution of response in clinical antidepressant trials is trimodal with large, medium-effect, and small subgroups.</p></div><div><h3>Methods</h3><p>To apply finite mixture modeling to pre-post Hamilton Depression Rating Scale (HDRS) differences (<em>n</em> = 2184) of STAR&lowast;D study's level 1, a single-arm, open-label study. For a successful replication, the best fitting model had to be trimodal, with comparable components as in Stone et al. Secondary/sensitivity analyses repeated the analysis for different baseline levels of depression severity, imputed values, and patient-reported depression symptoms.</p></div><div><h3>Results</h3><p>The best fitting models were either bimodal or trimodal but the trimodal solution did not meet criteria for replication. The bimodal model had 1 component with HDRS mean change of M = &minus;13.0, SD = 6.7 and included 65.3% of patients, and another component with M = &minus;1.8, SD = 5.1, 34.7%, respectively. For the trimodal model, the component with the largest change (M = &minus;14.3, SD = 6.4) applied to 52% of patients, which differed substantially from the large effect component in Stone et al (M = &minus;18.8, SD = 5.1), which applied to 7.2%. Secondary/sensitivity analyses arrived at similar conclusions, and for patient-reported depression symptoms the best fitting models were unimodal or bimodal.</p></div><div><h3>Conclusion</h3><p>This analysis failed to identify the trimodal distribution of response reported in Stone et al. In addition to being difficult to operationalize for regulatory purposes, results from mixture modeling are not sufficiently reliable to replace the more robust approach of comparing mean differences in depression rating scale scores between treatment arms.</p></div></div><ul><li><li></ul><div><h2>Keywords</h2><p><span>Antidepressants</span></p><p><span>Biases</span></p><p><span>Heterogeneity</span></p><p><span>Average</span></p><p><span>Treatment effect</span></p><p><span>Efficacy</span></p></div><section><h2>Data availability</h2><p>The authors do not have permission to share data.</p></section><section><header><h2>Cited by (0)</h2></header></section><p><span>&copy; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc.</span></p></article></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:25:10 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/new-paper-unpacks-how-trump-uses-strategic-victimhood-to-justify-retaliation/</link><title>Trump’s frequent claims of victimhood were more than rhetorical flair. A new study shows that this type of strategic victimhood is used to justify retaliation and puts to work anti-democratic, coercive, and illiberal governance and policies once an authoritarian populist is granted executive power (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ni6w6s/trumps_frequent_claims_of_victimhood_were_more/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ni6w6s/trumps_frequent_claims_of_victimhood_were_more/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ni6w6s/trumps_frequent_claims_of_victimhood_were_more/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/donald-trump.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new paper published in <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/journalmedia6030134">Journalism and Media</a></em> suggests Donald Trump&rsquo;s frequent claims of victimhood were more than rhetorical flair. The analysis indicates these narratives functioned as strategic tools to justify retributive policies, including sweeping global trade tariffs. The findings offer insight into how emotional appeals can legitimize authoritarian governance.</p><p>The author of the new paper, Marianna Patrona of the Hellenic Army Academy, sought to better understand how authoritarian populist leaders like Donald Trump use victimhood as a strategic communication tool&mdash;particularly how this rhetoric evolves once such figures gain power. While prior research had explored the emotional and symbolic power of victimhood in political discourse, Patrona saw a need to examine how these claims functioned within broader patterns of political communication and policy legitimation.</p><p>To explore this evolving use of victimhood rhetoric, Patrona employed Critical Discourse Analysis, a qualitative method that examines how language shapes and is shaped by social power dynamics. Her dataset included a range of Trump&rsquo;s public communications from 2020 through early 2025, encompassing campaign rallies, media appearances, social media posts, and official speeches during both his first and second terms in office.</p><p>Patrona&rsquo;s approach focused on identifying patterns in Trump&rsquo;s language, especially in how he constructed binaries of &ldquo;victims&rdquo; and &ldquo;victimizers.&rdquo; She paid close attention to the strategic use of emotionally charged terms, repeated metaphors, and speech acts such as promises and threats. Her analysis also examined how victimhood narratives intersected with broader populist themes, including nationalism, anti-elitism, and xenophobia.</p><p>A key feature of Patrona&rsquo;s analysis was her identification of a new communicative pattern that emerged after Trump&rsquo;s 2024 election victory. This pattern, which she terms &ldquo;inflicted pain plus retribution,&rdquo; was used to frame the United States as a long-suffering victim of international exploitation. Trump then used these narratives to announce retaliatory economic measures, such as imposing global trade tariffs.</p><p>Patrona&rsquo;s findings indicate that Trump&rsquo;s rhetorical style hinges on presenting both himself and the American public as victims of unfair treatment. During his first term, this often took the form of labeling investigations against him as &ldquo;witch hunts&rdquo; or &ldquo;election interference.&rdquo; These expressions created a moral narrative in which Trump positioned himself as a martyr persecuted by a corrupt system, while simultaneously reinforcing his outsider identity.</p><p>In the run-up to and following the 2024 election, Patrona observed a significant shift. Victimhood was no longer just about Trump&rsquo;s personal grievances or domestic elites. It became nationalized and externalized. Foreign countries, especially those involved in trade with the United States, were framed as exploitative aggressors. Nations like Canada, Mexico, and members of the European Union were described using vivid, emotionally charged language&mdash;such as having &ldquo;raped&rdquo; or &ldquo;plundered&rdquo; American industry.</p><p>These accusations were then used to justify economic retaliation. In a highly publicized speech at the World Economic Forum in Davos and other venues, Trump framed trade imbalances as injuries inflicted on the United States. He followed these claims with promises to take action, often using declarative language that signaled immediate and irreversible consequences, such as &ldquo;we&rsquo;re going to do something about it&rdquo; or &ldquo;they&rsquo;re going to pay.&rdquo;</p><p>Patrona argues that these statements function as commissive speech acts&mdash;language that commits the speaker to a future course of action. In this case, they served to justify executive decisions like the imposition of variable tariffs on nearly all trading partners, actions that disrupted longstanding norms around global trade.</p><p>Trump&rsquo;s speeches also frequently featured a narrative structure with clear emotional cues. He recounted personal threats, such as <a href="https://www.psypost.org/researchers-rushed-to-study-the-aftermath-of-the-trump-shooting-heres-what-they-found/">the assassination attempt</a> at a 2024 campaign rally, as part of a larger story about national suffering and moral courage. This blending of personal and national victimhood allowed Trump to present himself as both a survivor and a savior&mdash;someone who not only endured injustice but would also avenge it on behalf of the country.</p><p>Patrona&rsquo;s paper is qualitative in nature and based on a selective corpus of Trump&rsquo;s public communications. This means the findings are interpretive rather than statistical and should not be taken as representative of all populist leaders or all contexts. The focus on Trump also limits generalizability, although the detailed case study provides a useful framework for analyzing similar rhetorical patterns in other leaders.</p><p>Another limitation is the paper&rsquo;s reliance on publicly available content, which may exclude behind-the-scenes communications or strategy documents that could shed more light on the intentionality behind the rhetoric. Still, the public nature of the material makes it particularly relevant for understanding the relationship between political communication and audience engagement.</p><p>Future research could expand on Patrona&rsquo;s findings by examining how audiences respond to these narratives. Do they accept the framing of foreign nations as aggressors? Are they persuaded by victimhood claims that precede retributive policies? Additionally, comparative studies could investigate whether similar rhetorical strategies are used by other populist leaders in different geopolitical contexts, especially those who have risen to power on platforms of economic nationalism or cultural grievance.</p><p>Patrona concludes &ldquo;that authoritarian victimhood rhetoric is far from innocuous. It is much more than simple packaging, form devoid of content; rather, it both anticipates and puts to work anti-democratic, coercive, and illiberal governance and policies, once authoritarian populists are granted executive power post-electorally.&rdquo;</p><p>The paper, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/journalmedia6030134">From Victim to Avenger: Trump&rsquo;s Performance of Strategic Victimhood and the Waging of Global Trade War</a>,&rdquo; was published August 30, 2025.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 09:04:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newsweek.com/daylight-saving-time-americans-health-clock-change-2128349</link><title>Most Americans would be healthier without daylight saving. Study compared permanent standard, permanent daylight saving and biannual shifting, and found we currently have "worst choice". Permanent standard time is better than permanent daylight time, with both better than current biannual shift. (newsweek.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ni0rp0/most_americans_would_be_healthier_without/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ni0rp0/most_americans_would_be_healthier_without/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ni0rp0/most_americans_would_be_healthier_without/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newsweek.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/2720591-changing-clock.jpg?w=1200crop=1' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><article><p>Setting the clock forward to daylight saving time in spring and back to standard time in fall could be doing most Americans more harm than good.</p><p>While the loss of an hour of sleep in March has been linked to more heart attacks and fatal accidents in the days that follow, a Stanford Medicine study has discovered there are longer-term health hazards from the biannual changes&mdash;and better alternatives.</p><p>The team compared how three different time policies&mdash;permanent standard time, permanent daylight saving time and biannual shifting&mdash;could affect people's circadian rhythms and their health throughout the U.S.</p><p>Circadian rhythm is the body's innate, roughly 24-hour clock, which regulates many physiological processes. The researchers discovered that&mdash;from a circadian perspective&mdash;we currently have the "worst choice".</p><p>"While we have know for several years that the biannual shift, especially in the spring, is bad for your health, there is very little data indicating how permanently switching to standard or daylight time would impact health," study author circadian physiologist Jamie Zeitzer told <em>Newsweek</em>.</p><p>"Our data demonstrate that from a circadian health perspective, changing to permanent standard time would be better than permanent daylight time, with both being better than the current biannual shift."</p><p>The team simulated typical indoor and outdoor light exposure for individuals in every county in the contiguous, continental U.S. states for one year to predict changes in disease prevalence using data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (<a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/cdc">CDC</a>).</p><p>By modeling light exposure, circadian impacts and health characteristics county by county, they estimate that permanent standard time would prevent some 300,000 cases of stroke per year and result in 2.6 million fewer people having obesity.</p><p>Meanwhile, permanent daylight saving time would achieve about two-thirds of the same effect. Under this time policy, the nationwide prevalence of obesity would decrease by 1.7 million people and stroke by 220,000 cases, according to the team.</p><p>Obesity (which affects more than two in five adult Americans) and stroke (a case of which occurs around once every 40 seconds) are both conditions thought to be influenced by circadian health.</p><p>"We found that staying in standard time or staying in daylight saving time is definitely better than switching twice a year," said Zeitzer in a statement.</p><p>While some agree about wanting to end seasonal time shifts, there is still disagreement over which time policy to adopt.</p><p>Supporters of permanent daylight saving time argue more evening light could save energy, deter crime and give people more leisure after work, while objectors include parents worried about their children going to school in the dark.</p><p>Since 2018, a bill proposing permanent daylight saving time has been introduced in <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/congress">Congress</a> nearly every year, though it has never passed.</p><p>Proponents of permanent standard time, meanwhile, argue that more morning light is optimal for health, which has been endorsed by organizations like the American Academy of Sleep Medicine, the National Sleep Foundation and the American Medical Association.</p><p>"The problem is that it's a theory without any data. And finally, we have data," said Zeitzer.</p><div></div><p>"When you get light in the morning, it speeds up the circadian cycle. When you get light in the evening, it slows things down. You generally need more morning light and less evening light to keep well synchronized to a 24-hour day," Zeitzer explained.</p><p>"The more light exposure you get at the wrong times, the weaker the circadian clock. All of these things that are downstream&mdash;for example, your immune system, your energy&mdash;don't match up quite as well."</p><p>The researchers used a mathematical model to translate light exposure under each time policy, based on local sunrise and sunset times, to circadian burden&mdash;how much a person's innate clock has to shift to keep up with the 24-hour day.</p><p>They found that over a year, most people would experience the least circadian burden under permanent standard time, which prioritizes morning light. The benefits vary slightly depending on a person's location within a time zone and their chronotype&mdash;meaning whether they prefer early mornings, late nights or something in between.</p><p>People who are early birds make up about 15 percent of the population and tend to have circadian cycles shorter than 24 hours, would experience the least circadian burden under permanent daylight saving time as more evening light would extend their circadian cycles closer to 24 hours.</p><p>To link circadian burden to specific health outcomes, the researchers analyzed the prevalence of arthritis, cancer, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, coronary heart disease, depression, diabetes, obesity and stroke.</p><p>Their models suggest permanent standard time would lower the nationwide prevalence of obesity by 0.78 percent and the prevalence of stroke by 0.09 percent.</p><p>Permanent daylight time would lower the nationwide prevalence of obesity by 0.51 percent and stroke by 0.04 percent. While seemingly small percentage changes, these could amount to a vast change in the number of cases of the common conditions as described.</p><p>The models predicted no significant difference in conditions not directly linked to circadian rhythms, like arthritis.</p><p>While the study might be the "most evidence-based analysis" of the long-term health implications of different time policies, it won't be the last word on the matter, Zeitzer acknowledged.</p><p>The researchers didn't account for many factors that could influence real-life light exposure, including weather, geography and human behavior.</p><p>They also assumed consistent and relatively circadian-friendly light habits in their calculations, including a 10 p.m. to 7 a.m. sleep schedule, sunlight exposure before and after work and on weekends and indoor light exposure from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. and after sunset.</p><p>"People's light habits are probably much worse than what we assume in the models," Zeitzer said. "Even in California, where the weather is great, people spend less than 5 percent of their day outside."</p><p>Additional research could help uncover how individual differences relate to health outcomes and the implications for time policy, according to the researchers.</p><p>Zeitzer hopes the study will encourage similar evidence-based analyses from other fields, such as economics and sociology, including continuing to compare research from other considerations of time.</p><p>Commenting on whether he sees a world where we will move away from daylight saving time, Zeitzer told us: "Absolutely&mdash;it's a modern invention that is not universally loved!"</p><p><strong>Do you have a tip on a health story that <em>Newsweek</em> should be covering? Do you have a question about daylight saving time? Let us know via health@newsweek.com.</strong></p><h3>Reference</h3><p>Weed, L., &amp; Zeitzer, J. M. (2025). Circadian-informed modeling predicts regional variation in obesity and stroke outcomes under different permanent US time policies. <em>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 122</em>. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2508293122">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2508293122</a></p></article><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newsweek.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/2720591-changing-clock.jpg?w=1600&amp;quality=75&amp;webp=1"></p><p><img src="https://assets.newsweek.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/2720599-person-ywaning-sun.jpg?w=1600&amp;quality=75&amp;webp=1"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 04:20:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/cannabis-compounds-have-distinct-effects-on-brain-connectivity-and-blood-flow-study-finds/</link><title>Cannabis compounds THC and cannabidiol (CBD) have opposing effects on brain function—and combining the two produces more muted changes than THC alone, finds new neuroimaging study in rats to compare how these cannabis-derived compounds alter patterns of communication and blood flow in the brain. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nhiag4/cannabis_compounds_thc_and_cannabidiol_cbd_have/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nhiag4/cannabis_compounds_thc_and_cannabidiol_cbd_have/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 9 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nhiag4/cannabis_compounds_thc_and_cannabidiol_cbd_have/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/cannabis-thc-cbd.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study in rats provides evidence that tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) and cannabidiol (CBD) have opposing effects on brain function&mdash;and that combining the two produces more muted changes than THC alone. Published in the <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/02698811251360745">Journal of Psychopharmacology</a></em>, the research used advanced neuroimaging to compare how these cannabis-derived compounds alter patterns of communication and blood flow in the brain.</p><p>Cannabis contains a wide range of bioactive compounds, but two of its most studied constituents are THC and CBD. THC is primarily responsible for the euphoric high associated with cannabis use and exerts its effects through the cannabinoid type 1 receptor, found throughout the brain. It is also approved for medical use in treating symptoms such as nausea in chemotherapy patients, spasticity in multiple sclerosis, and chronic pain.</p><p>In contrast, CBD does not produce a high and has a very different pharmacological profile. It interacts with multiple systems in the body but does not strongly bind to cannabinoid receptors. Instead, it has shown promise as a treatment for conditions like epilepsy, anxiety, and psychosis. A pharmaceutical-grade form of CBD, known as Epidiolex, is already approved for certain seizure disorders. Research also suggests CBD may reduce neuroinflammation and protect brain cells in neurodegenerative diseases.</p><p>There is growing interest in how THC and CBD interact when used together. Products like nabiximols, which contain THC and CBD in roughly equal amounts, are already used to treat multiple sclerosis symptoms. These combination treatments are thought to allow for higher THC doses while limiting unwanted side effects, but the mechanisms behind these interactions remain unclear. The new study sought to shed light on this by examining how THC, CBD, and their combination affect brain connectivity and blood flow using non-invasive imaging.</p><p>&ldquo;We were interested in directly comparing the effects of the two best-known cannabis constituents: cannabidiol (CBD) and tetrahydrocannabinol (THC),&rdquo; said study author Diana Cash, an associate professor at King&rsquo;s College London and director of <a href="https://brain-imaging.org/">The Brain Centre</a>.</p><p>&ldquo;CBD, which is non-psychoactive, is often promoted as a treatment for a wide range of issues&mdash;from inflammation to stress and insomnia&mdash;although the scientific evidence does not always support these claims. THC, on the other hand, is often stigmatized because it is the psychoactive component of cannabis, the one responsible for the &lsquo;high,&rsquo; yet it also has recognized therapeutic benefits.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;We wanted to investigate how these compounds act alone and in combination, as in &lsquo;nabiximols,&rsquo; a licensed medication used to treat pain and spasticity in multiple sclerosis. We used rats as an experimental model but applied clinically relevant brain imaging techniques to measure neural connectivity and blood flow. These kinds of controlled studies are difficult to perform in humans due to ethical and practical challenges, such as prior recreational drug use, but of course, animal research also comes with limitations when translating findings to people.&rdquo;</p><p>The researchers used 48 adult male Sprague Dawley rats divided into four groups. Each group received a single dose of either THC, CBD, a THC:CBD combination, or a placebo. The THC dose was 10 milligrams per kilogram, the CBD dose was 150 milligrams per kilogram, and the combination contained both THC and CBD in a ratio similar to that used in nabiximols. About two hours after administration, the rats were scanned using magnetic resonance imaging to assess two key brain functions: resting-state functional connectivity and cerebral blood flow.</p><p>Functional connectivity refers to the level of synchrony in activity across different brain regions. It is measured by analyzing patterns in blood oxygenation over time and provides insight into how different parts of the brain communicate. Cerebral blood flow, on the other hand, is a measure of how much blood is reaching different brain areas, serving as a proxy for neural activity and metabolic demand.</p><p>The imaging data were analyzed using a combination of graph theory and statistical modeling. This allowed the researchers to examine both overall brain-wide changes and effects within specific neural networks. They also analyzed tissue samples to measure the concentrations of THC, CBD, and their metabolites in the brain and plasma.</p><p>The most pronounced effects were seen in the THC group. Rats given THC showed widespread increases in functional connectivity across the brain, especially between cortical regions and between the cortex and the hippocampus and striatum. Graph theory analysis revealed that THC increased both the strength and clustering of connections, suggesting more tightly knit communication within and between brain networks. Cerebral blood flow was also significantly elevated in many regions, including the thalamus, striatum, and cingulate cortex.</p><p>The rats given CBD, in contrast, showed a general reduction in functional connectivity. This reduction was not localized to a specific area but was more diffuse across the brain. Unlike THC, CBD did not produce any significant changes in cerebral blood flow. These results suggest that CBD may have a dampening or calming effect on neural synchrony, which aligns with its potential use in treating anxiety and seizure disorders.</p><p>&ldquo;We were somewhat surprised that CBD reduced brain connectivity,&rdquo; Cash told PsyPost. &ldquo;However, this is not necessarily a negative outcome&mdash;it&rsquo;s possible that THC-induced hyperconnectivity reflects an overstimulated state, whereas CBD may allow the brain to &ldquo;reset&rdquo; or relax. This interpretation is speculative, especially since our work was conducted in rats rather than humans, but it is an intriguing possibility.&rdquo;</p><p>When THC and CBD were given together, the effects were intermediate. Functional connectivity and cerebral blood flow were both elevated compared to the placebo group, but not to the same degree as with THC alone. Seed-based analyses showed that the combined treatment produced some of the same patterns as THC, such as increased connectivity between the striatum and sensorimotor cortex, but the effects were less robust.</p><p>Importantly, the researchers observed that CBD seemed to moderate some of THC&rsquo;s impact on brain activity. This was evident in both the graph theory metrics and the regional analyses. Increases in connectivity and blood flow were smaller in the combination group than in the THC-only group, even though THC levels in the brain were actually higher in the combination condition. This finding supports the idea that CBD can alter THC&rsquo;s effects, not just by reducing its absorption or metabolism but by actively influencing brain function.</p><p>The researchers also used a multivariate statistical approach to identify distinct neural signatures associated with each treatment. This analysis revealed that THC, CBD, and the combination treatment each produced unique patterns across connectivity and blood flow measures. These signatures were consistent enough to differentiate the drug groups and could be useful in future efforts to classify how other cannabis-based compounds affect the brain.</p><p>&ldquo;We found that THC strongly increased both brain connectivity and blood flow, while CBD had no effect on blood flow but significantly reduced connectivity,&rdquo; Cash explained. &ldquo;The combination produced an effect somewhat similar to THC, but much weaker&mdash;suggesting that CBD can dampen or modulate the effects of THC. This could help explain why traditional cannabis, which contains both compounds, is often reported to produce milder effects compared to newer strains bred for very high THC content.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Our results are broadly consistent with several previous studies in both animals and humans, though the literature is quite mixed. One striking aspect we noticed is just how heterogeneous the findings in this field are&mdash;likely reflecting differences in methods, models, and populations studied.&rdquo;</p><p>While the findings offer insight into how cannabis compounds affect brain function, there are limitations to consider. The study was conducted in healthy, anesthetized male rats, which means the results may not fully translate to human users or to individuals with medical conditions. The use of anesthesia, although necessary for high-quality imaging, may interact with cannabinoid signaling and affect brain activity in ways that do not occur in awake brains.</p><p>Additionally, the study only examined the short-term effects of a single dose. Longer-term studies are needed to understand how repeated use of THC, CBD, or their combination might reshape brain networks over time. There is also a need to study female animals and include disease models to better assess the therapeutic potential of these compounds.</p><p>Future research may build on these findings by incorporating additional brain imaging techniques, testing different doses and delivery methods, or examining how other cannabinoids and non-cannabinoid components of cannabis influence brain activity. The researchers note that they are working toward creating a comprehensive database of brain imaging profiles for different drugs. Such a resource could aid in drug development by linking specific brain signatures to therapeutic or side effect profiles.</p><p>&ldquo;The biggest limitation is that our experiments were conducted in animals, and the rats were lightly sedated during imaging to minimize stress,&rdquo; Cash said. &ldquo;These factors limit direct generalization to humans. Still, one of our main goals was to establish a framework for comparing the brain effects of different compounds, including synthetic cannabinoids and other psychoactive drugs. In that sense, the study provides a valuable blueprint for future work.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;We are currently extending this work by profiling a range of drugs that affect the brain. Ultimately, we aim to build a database of brain signatures using advanced imaging techniques, combined with AI and machine learning, to support drug discovery and the development of new therapeutics.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;We would like to emphasize the importance of using comparable brain imaging approaches in both animal and human studies, to make results more directly translatable,&rdquo; Cash added. &ldquo;Standardization of imaging analysis methods across research groups would also help the field move forward more effectively.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/02698811251360745">Acute cannabidiol (CBD), tetrahydrocannabinol (THC) and their mixture (THC:CBD) exert differential effects on brain activity and blood flow in rats: A translational neuroimaging study</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Eilidh MacNicol, Michelle Kokkinou, Maria Elisa Serrano Navacerrada, Donna-Michelle Smith, Jennifer Li, Camilla Simmons, Eugene Kim, Michel Mesquita, Loreto Rojo Gonzalez, Tierney Andrews, Sally Loomis, Royston A Gray, Volker Knappertz, Benjamin J Whalley, Andrew C McCreary, Steven CR Williams, David Virley, and Diana Cash.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://sp-ao.shortpixel.ai/client/to_webp,q_glossy,ret_img,w_250,h_85/https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/follow-on-google-news-1.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 16:05:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanmic/article/PIIS2666-5247(25)00050-3/fulltext</link><title>Researchers have found the longest known case of COVID-19 in a person living with HIV. Lasting 776 days, multiple viral populations were present displaying hallmarks of Omicron months before its global emergence. These often heavily mutated genomes are thought to be the source of variants of concern (thelancet.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nh1im5/researchers_have_found_the_longest_known_case_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nh1im5/researchers_have_found_the_longest_known_case_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nh1im5/researchers_have_found_the_longest_known_case_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 01:41:18 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/love-doesnt-thrive-on-ledgers-keeping-score-in-relationships-foreshadows-decline-study-finds/</link><title>“Love doesn’t thrive on ledgers”: Keeping score in relationships foreshadows decline, study finds. A long-term study of couples in Germany found that when partners expected something in return for favors or sacrifices, their satisfaction tended to decline over time. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ngncyy/love_doesnt_thrive_on_ledgers_keeping_score_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ngncyy/love_doesnt_thrive_on_ledgers_keeping_score_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ngncyy/love_doesnt_thrive_on_ledgers_keeping_score_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/relationship-conflict-upset-couple.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>People often say relationships should be fair. But new research suggests that keeping score may actually backfire. A long-term study of couples in Germany found that when partners expected something in return for favors or sacrifices, their satisfaction tended to decline over time. The study was published in the <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/01461672251330700">Personality and Social Psychology Bulletin</a></em>.</p><p>Relationship researchers have long distinguished between two broad mindsets: communal and exchange orientations. A communal approach involves caring for a partner&rsquo;s needs without expecting direct repayment. By contrast, an exchange orientation involves a sense of keeping score. A person might expect their partner to repay a favor, match effort, or show appreciation in proportion to what was given.</p><p>Past research has repeatedly found that exchange orientation tends to predict lower relationship satisfaction. But most of that work was based on cross-sectional data, which can only capture snapshots at one point in time. That makes it hard to determine whether expecting reciprocity leads to dissatisfaction or whether dissatisfaction makes people more likely to keep score.</p><p>Little was known about how exchange orientation changes over time. Is it a fixed personality trait, or does it shift with the ups and downs of a relationship? Another open question was whether similarity between partners in exchange orientation might help or hurt. Some researchers speculated that if both partners shared the same transactional mindset, they might better understand each other&rsquo;s expectations. Others suspected that any form of scorekeeping, whether mutual or not, could disrupt the emotional connection that supports long-term intimacy.</p><p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s been growing public concern that modern romance is becoming increasingly transactional&mdash;where people approach love less as emotional connection and more as a ledger of give-and-take. I thought exchange orientation, or the tendency to keep track of what one gives and receives, provided a timely and theoretically meaningful way to study this trend. It allowed us to ask whether adopting a transactional mindset actually shapes the course of romantic relationships,&rdquo; explained study author <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=ko&amp;user=r48auQUAAAAJ">Haeyoung Gideon Park</a>, a PhD candidate at the University of Toronto.</p><p>To investigate, the research team turned to a uniquely comprehensive dataset: a nationally representative panel of German couples followed for over a decade. This gave them the opportunity to track not only changes within individuals but also patterns across partners.</p><p>The researchers drew from the German Family Panel (pairfam), a long-running longitudinal study that follows individuals and their partners across different stages of life. For this project, they analyzed responses from 7,293 heterosexual couples who participated in up to seven survey waves over a 13-year period. The surveys were conducted every two years.</p><p>Participants responded to questions assessing their exchange orientation, such as whether they expected something in return when doing a favor or giving in to their partner. They also rated their overall satisfaction with their relationship using a standard scale. By collecting repeated responses from both members of each couple, the researchers could examine both individual and dyadic patterns.</p><p>To analyze the data, the researchers used a statistical approach called latent curve modeling with structured residuals. This method allowed them to separate long-term trends from shorter-term fluctuations and distinguish within-person effects (how someone changes over time) from between-person differences (how people compare to each other on average). They also used a technique called dyadic response surface analysis to explore whether partners&rsquo; similarity in exchange orientation had any impact on their shared satisfaction.</p><p>Across the full sample, the researchers observed that most individuals became less exchange-oriented as their relationships matured. In other words, over time, people were less likely to expect direct repayment or acknowledgment for sacrifices made in the relationship. This overall shift away from transactional thinking suggests that romantic partners may gradually adopt a more communal mindset as their bond deepens.</p><p>Importantly, the speed of this shift mattered. People who showed slower declines in exchange orientation were also more likely to experience steeper drops in relationship satisfaction over the years. This pattern held true even when controlling for initial satisfaction levels. It suggests that clinging to a transactional mindset may interfere with the natural development of emotional intimacy.</p><p>The researchers also examined more immediate changes within individuals. They found that when a person&rsquo;s exchange orientation increased from their usual level at a given time point, their relationship satisfaction tended to drop&mdash;both in that moment and two years later. These time-lagged effects support the idea that expecting something in return may gradually wear down relationship quality.</p><p>&ldquo;Our findings suggest that keeping score isn&rsquo;t just a reaction to relationship struggles&mdash;it can actually foreshadow them,&rdquo; Park told PsyPost. &ldquo;In other words, when people become more focused on payback, their satisfaction tends to decline in the years that follow. We also found that couples didn&rsquo;t necessarily benefit from both being transactional; what mattered most was whether either partner was focused on keeping things even. The less emphasis on payback, the better the relationship tended to be.&rdquo;</p><p>The researchers found little evidence that being dissatisfied led people to become more exchange-oriented later on. This points to a directional link in which transactional thinking tends to reduce satisfaction, not the reverse.</p><p>&ldquo;I expected that declines in satisfaction would predict increases in exchange orientation, but that wasn&rsquo;t the case,&rdquo; Park said. &ldquo;One limitation is that our data were collected every two years, which may have missed short-term or situational shifts.&rdquo;</p><p>Another key finding concerned partner similarity. While it might seem intuitive that sharing a similar mindset would promote harmony, the data did not support this assumption. Couples who were equally high or equally low in exchange orientation did not report greater satisfaction than couples who differed. Instead, relationship satisfaction was lower whenever either partner was more exchange-oriented, regardless of the other&rsquo;s views.</p><p>These results challenge the idea that &ldquo;matching&rdquo; mindsets protect relationships. Instead, they suggest that lower levels of exchange orientation in both partners&mdash;regardless of similarity&mdash;tend to support higher satisfaction.</p><p>&ldquo;I was surprised that partner similarity in exchange orientation didn&rsquo;t provide any benefits,&rdquo; Park said. &ldquo;As a follow-up, We&rsquo;re now examining the emotional processes that underlie the negative effects of exchange orientation, which may help explain why this mindset is harmful regardless of whether both partners share it.&rdquo;</p><p>It is important to note that the findings are correlational, which means they cannot establish definite causation. While the use of lagged analyses and longitudinal methods strengthens the argument for directional effects, it remains possible that unmeasured factors influenced both exchange orientation and relationship satisfaction.</p><p>Future research could explore whether the effects of exchange orientation differ across relationship stages. A transactional mindset might feel more acceptable in early dating relationships, but less so in long-term partnerships where emotional bonds are deeper. Another avenue is to examine how exchange orientation plays out across different domains.</p><p>&ldquo;Right now, we&rsquo;re investigating the emotional processes that contribute to the harmful effects of exchange orientation,&rdquo; Park explained. &ldquo;Looking further ahead, I&rsquo;d like to examine whether these dynamics differ across relationship stages (such as new vs. long-term relationships), across domains (such as chores, finances, or intimacy), and across cultures. It&rsquo;s also important to understand what leads people to adopt a transactional mindset in the first place, and whether it can be intentionally altered.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Our study highlights a simple but important message: love doesn&rsquo;t thrive on ledgers,&rdquo; the researcher added. &ldquo;Fairness matters, but constantly expecting something in return can quietly erode warmth and trust. Letting go of the mental tally may help relationships flourish.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/01461672251330700">&lsquo;Pay Me Back&rsquo;: Testing the Implications of Long-Term Changes and Partner Similarity in Exchange Orientation Within Intimate Relationships</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Haeyoung Gideon Park, Matthew D. Johnson, Amie M. Gordon, and Emily A. Impett.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://sp-ao.shortpixel.ai/client/to_webp,q_glossy,ret_img,w_250,h_85/https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/follow-on-google-news-1.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 15:31:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/medical/gut-brain-axis-postpartum-depression/</link><title>Researchers have uncovered a gut-diet link to postpartum depression, finding that eating a diet of soy, fermented foods, and seaweed may nurture beneficial gut bacteria and protect mothers’ mental health. The new study is  by Kyoto University on diet and postpartum depression in Japanese mothers. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ng9wai/researchers_have_uncovered_a_gutdiet_link_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ng9wai/researchers_have_uncovered_a_gutdiet_link_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ng9wai/researchers_have_uncovered_a_gutdiet_link_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/f625525/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F69%2Fd3%2Ffedac3934b7a80cf48aab7ea0fde%2Fdepositphotos-357330654-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Researchers have uncovered a gut-diet link to postpartum depression, finding that eating a diet of soy, fermented foods, and seaweed may nurture beneficial gut bacteria and protect mothers&rsquo; mental health.</p><p>With the link between the gut microbiome and <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/reduced-lactobacillus-microbiome-immune-response-mental-health/">mental health</a> now fairly well established, scientists have begun looking at how promoting a healthy microbiome can improve conditions such as depression in real-life scenarios.</p><p>A new study led by Kyoto University has investigated how gut bacteria and diet are linked to postpartum depression in Japanese mothers.</p><p>&ldquo;Our investigation was driven by the need to better understand how intestinal microbiota, physical condition, and dietary habits relate to maternal mood, even among mothers not clinically diagnosed with mental illness,&rdquo; said <a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0002-0316-3839">Michiko Matsunaga</a>, an associate professor in developmental psychology and neuroscience at Kyoto University, and the study&rsquo;s lead and co-corresponding author.</p><p>Globally, the <a href="https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-024-18502-0">prevalence</a> of postpartum depression (PPD), the onset of depressive episodes after childbirth, is estimated to be around 10% to 20%. Symptoms can include an unstable mood, loss of interest, feelings of guilt, sleep disturbances and disorders, and changes in appetite. PPD can develop at any time within the first year after the birth of a child and last for years. For Japanese women, particularly, <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC4472610/#:~:text=The%20most%20frequently%20reported%20reason,use%20of%20mental%20health%20services.">cultural factors</a> such as stigma, reluctance to seek outside help, and a preference for independence can deter women from seeking mental health treatment.</p><p>The researchers recruited 344 mothers of children up to age four, none of whom had diagnosed psychiatric or physical illnesses. The severity of participants&rsquo; depression was assessed using the <a href="https://www.nctsn.org/measures/beck-depression-inventory-second-edition">Beck Depression Inventory-II</a> (BDI-II), with scores of 20 or above considered high risk for depression. Mothers also reported on their sleep quality and duration, and completed a multidimensional physical scale that covered factors such as fatigue, hormone balance, and circulation. Stool samples were analyzed using RNA sequencing to measure microbiota diversity and the abundance of specific bacteria. </p><p>Participants also reported how often they ate 18 categories of foods. Factor analysis revealed two dietary patterns among participants: a vegetable and meat diet (VMD), which consisted of lots of vegetables, meat and fish; and a soy and fermented food diet (SFD), which was high in soy, fermented foods, seaweed, mushrooms, and fruits.</p><div><figure><div><figcaption>The types of foods that resulted in lower depression scores </figcaption><p>ChatGPT 5</p></div></figure> </div><p>About 14% of mothers scored in the high-depression range despite being considered &ldquo;healthy&rdquo;. Lower gut microbiota diversity was associated with higher depression scores. Specific butyrate-producing bacteria &ndash; beneficial gut bacteria that ferment dietary fibers to produce butyrate, a <a href="https://newatlas.com/heart-disease/dietary-fiber-gut-microbes-cardioprotection-scfas/">short-chain fatty acid</a> (SCFA) &ndash; were less abundant in mothers with more depressive symptoms. These bacteria are known to improve gut and immune health.</p><p>From a physical perspective, depressed mothers reported poorer sleep quality and worse overall physical condition. However, the researchers found that mothers who ate the SFD had lower depression scores, better physical condition, and healthier gut bacteria. The VMD pattern was linked to some physical health benefits, but not to lower depression. Mothers with depression were also found to eat less yogurt, dairy, and pickled vegetables than those with lower depression scores.</p><p>&ldquo;These findings deepen our appreciation for the richness of traditional Japanese dietary culture and its potential mental health benefits,&rdquo; said <a href="https://orcid.org/0000-0001-6080-106X">Masako Myowa, PhD</a>, the study&rsquo;s other corresponding author.</p><p>One of the study&rsquo;s biggest limitations is that its cross-sectional design can show associations but not cause-and-effect. Additionally, food intake was self-reported, with only 18 food categories; there were no details on whether the foods were processed or fresh, nor on the types of meat and fish eaten, for example. Factors like marital status, exercise, or family mental health history were not included. Results may reflect unique aspects of Japanese diets and may not fully apply elsewhere.</p><p>Despite these limitations, the study does raise an interesting consideration: diet as prevention. Eating more soy, fermented foods, seaweed, mushrooms, and vegetables may help reduce the risk of postnatal depression, partly by supporting gut bacteria that produce beneficial fatty acids. The study highlights the importance of the gut-brain axis in maternal mental health, suggesting non-drug interventions such as dietary changes or probiotics could support long-term well-being.</p><p>The researchers plan to conduct further studies to examine whether targeted dietary changes can improve both gut bacteria and mental health in postpartum women.</p><p>&ldquo;I find it fascinating that this integrated perspective may help us better understand emotional states and develop new, holistic approaches to mental health support,&rdquo; Matsunaga said.</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/pnasnexus/pgaf169"><i>PNAS Nexus</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.kyoto-u.ac.jp/en/research-news/2025-09-09">Kyoto University</a></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/e76a0dd/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1536x1024+0+0/resize/1440x960!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F55%2F0c%2F7ce276d74d78888882c093f73373%2Fsfd-foods.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 03:25:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0160449X251370759</link><title>Study finds unionization among hospital healthcare workers led to significantly higher raises, no overtime work pressure, access to insurance, experiencing less workplace harassment and higher mental well-being (journals.sagepub.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ng414p/study_finds_unionization_among_hospital/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ng414p/study_finds_unionization_among_hospital/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ng414p/study_finds_unionization_among_hospital/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 23:22:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/evolutionary-psychology-reveals-patterns-in-mass-murder-motivations-across-life-stages/</link><title>There is a bimodal age distribution among mass murderers - late adolescence or middle age. Younger offenders have a history of social rejection, with manifestos or social media posts desiring revenge or recognition, for dominance or notoriety. Older offenders are often preceded by acute life crises. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nftzko/there_is_a_bimodal_age_distribution_among_mass/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nftzko/there_is_a_bimodal_age_distribution_among_mass/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nftzko/there_is_a_bimodal_age_distribution_among_mass/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/holding-rifle.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new systematic review published in <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s40806-025-00443-5">Evolutionary Psychological Science</a></em> suggests that the life stage of a mass murderer plays a significant role in shaping their motivations, stressors, and target selection. While younger perpetrators are often driven by chronic social rejection and status deprivation, older offenders are more likely to be reacting to acute life disruptions. By applying evolutionary theory, the authors propose that these acts of violence may reflect exaggerated responses to perceived threats to social status and control.</p><p>Mass murder is a rare but profoundly traumatic phenomenon. Although psychological and criminological research has documented many of the immediate precursors to these acts, the underlying question of why certain individuals respond to stress in violent ways remains open. The researchers behind this study aimed to address that question by integrating evolutionary perspectives, particularly Life History Theory and models of male competition, into existing frameworks.</p><p>This theoretical approach suggests that behaviors related to status, aggression, and reproductive strategy have been shaped by ancestral pressures and continue to influence modern behavior. While the authors emphasize that evolutionary theory does not justify or excuse violence, it may help explain why certain recurring patterns emerge in different types of offenders.</p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been studying mass violence for the past five years, driven by its devastating impact not just on direct victims, but on entire communities and social systems,&rdquo; explained study author <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/keith-minihane-a11a9b172/">Keith Minihane</a>, a PhD researcher in applied psychology, at University College Cork.</p><p>&ldquo;Despite the attention mass murder receives, there&rsquo;s still limited understanding of how offenders differ by life stage, and almost no work that systematically examines these differences through an evolutionary lens. This project emerged from that gap. We wanted to know: why do these crimes cluster in late adolescence and middle age, and what might that tell us about the underlying psychological processes at work?&rdquo;</p><p>To identify recurring psychological stressors among mass murderers, the researchers conducted a systematic review of peer-reviewed empirical studies. They searched four major academic databases, along with a manual search, identifying a total of 634 papers. After screening for relevance and applying strict inclusion criteria, 20 studies were included in the final synthesis. These studies all directly examined the motivations, stressors, and behavioral patterns of individuals who had committed mass murder, familicide, or school shootings, excluding ideologically motivated or politically driven cases.</p><p>One of the most striking findings was a bimodal age distribution among mass murderers. Offenders tended to cluster in either late adolescence or middle age, with each group displaying distinct behavioral patterns, motivations, and stress responses.</p><p>Younger offenders, including school shooters and public mass murderers, were often characterized by a history of social rejection. This included experiences of bullying, exclusion, and romantic failure. In many cases, violence was preceded by a long buildup of grievance, during which the offender internalized a sense of humiliation or insignificance. These individuals often left behind manifestos, videos, or social media posts expressing a desire for revenge or recognition. Some appeared to view mass violence as a way to assert dominance or gain notoriety, particularly after being denied social status during a key developmental period.</p><p>In contrast, older offenders were more likely to commit acts of familicide, often killing their partners and children before taking their own lives. These acts were frequently preceded by acute life crises, such as financial collapse, divorce, or job loss. In many cases, the offenders framed their violence as a protective or &ldquo;compassionate&rdquo; act&mdash;attempting to &ldquo;rescue&rdquo; their families from a perceived future of hardship. While the reasoning may appear twisted, the researchers suggest that these actions may reflect a distortion of evolved caregiving mechanisms under extreme stress.</p><p>What was particularly surprising was the consistency of these findings, Minihane said. &ldquo;Younger offenders were often driven by chronic rejection, humiliation, or identity struggles, while older offenders were more likely facing acute crises like divorce, job loss, or financial collapse. These themes emerged repeatedly. Different life stages, different stressors, but both converged on violence as a perceived solution to social failure.&rdquo;</p><p>Across both age groups, revenge was a consistently reported motivation. Whether directed at peers, romantic partners, employers, or family members, many mass murderers appeared to view their actions as a form of retaliation. This was especially true among younger offenders, who often blamed classmates or society for their perceived failures. The researchers point to evolutionary models of status competition and risk-taking to explain why some young men may be especially prone to respond violently to rejection or humiliation.</p><p>While younger offenders often survived their attacks, older perpetrators were significantly more likely to die by suicide. Suicide rates were especially high among those who committed familicide. These older offenders appeared to view violence as a final response to what they saw as irreversible status loss or existential failure. Rather than seeking fame or recognition, they often acted in private and left behind notes expressing despair, guilt, or hopelessness.</p><p>The review also noted clear sex differences. Mass murder is overwhelmingly committed by men. Women who do commit mass killings often act in domestic settings and tend to target family members using less direct means, such as poisoning or arson. Female perpetrators were also more likely to report motives tied to perceived altruism rather than revenge or dominance. These differences suggest that gendered patterns in violence may reflect underlying psychological and social distinctions shaped by both evolutionary and cultural factors.</p><p>&ldquo;Mass murder is seldom a sudden or random act; it is well planned, sometimes for years,&rdquo; Minihane told PsyPost. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s rarely the result of a mental health crisis in the way people often assume. In fact, people with mental health difficulties are far more likely to be victims of violence than perpetrators. Stigmatizing them only distracts from the real social and psychological dynamics we need to address, these dynamics include social stress, rejection, and perceived status loss. These pressures tap into deep-rooted psychological systems evolved to monitor threats to social standing and identity. That&rsquo;s important, because it helps us move beyond reactive explanations and toward proactive ways of identifying and interrupting pathways to violence.&rdquo;</p><p>The review also highlights key limitations in the current research landscape. Definitions of mass murder vary across studies, with some setting the threshold at three victims and others at four. This inconsistency can affect who gets included in analyses and may obscure meaningful comparisons across subtypes.</p><p>The researchers also acknowledge that the focus on peer-reviewed, English-language studies introduces potential selection bias. While the review includes international cases, much of the available research is based in Western contexts. A broader global dataset would allow for more culturally nuanced comparisons. The authors call for the development of a standardized international mass murder database to enable such analysis.</p><p>The authors also emphasize that evolutionary theory is not a replacement for existing models of violence but a complementary tool to help understand consistent patterns.</p><p>&ldquo;Evolutionary psychology is only one lens,&rdquo; Minihane said. &ldquo;Other perspectives such as feminist theory (mass murder is overwhelmingly carried out by males), and sociological and criminological approaches, are vital. Our goal isn&rsquo;t to replace those theories, but to augment them with a broader framework that highlights how age and life-history pressures shape responses to stress. Methodological considerations include our strict inclusion criteria, and, although worldwide studies were included, the literature still mainly focuses on western based offenders.</p><p>&ldquo;This paper is part of a larger effort to build a comprehensive, interdisciplinary framework for exploring extreme violence. One path we&rsquo;re pursuing now focuses on &lsquo;legacy tokens,&rsquo; manifestos, suicide notes, or online posts that reveal how offenders want to be remembered. As we recently saw with the case of Robin Westman, the publication of legacy tokens remains a crucial dimension of mass violence today. Our initial research into this topic revealed significant differences between how those in late adolescence and their early 20s conceptualize their violence as compared with middle aged offenders. This research was <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s11896-025-09739-5">published earlier this year</a> in the <em>Journal of Criminal and Police Psychology</em> and offers an initial step in outlining how offenders narrativize their violence.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;The key point, and I really want to stress this, is that evolutionary psychology does not excuse violence, nor does it offer a singular, explanatory framework,&rdquo; Minihane added. &ldquo;Instead, it helps explain why certain patterns emerge when evolved minds encounter modern stressors. By better understanding the distinct trajectories of younger and older offenders, we can improve focused risk assessment, identify warning signs earlier, and ultimately work toward prevention.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s40806-025-00443-5">The Bimodal Age Distribution of Mass Murder: a Systematic Review Using Evolutionary and Life History Perspectives</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Keith Minihane, Maria Dempsey, and Robert King.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 15:50:56 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/women-prone-to-self-objectification-tend-to-have-lower-empathy/</link><title>Women prone to self-objectification (view and evaluate themselves mainly in terms of how their bodies appear to others) tend to have lower empathy with diminished theory-of-mind abilities—the capacity to understand that other people have their own thoughts, perceptions, and goals. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nfhbf9/women_prone_to_selfobjectification_view_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nfhbf9/women_prone_to_selfobjectification_view_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nfhbf9/women_prone_to_selfobjectification_view_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/narcissistic-woman-looking-in-mirror.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A series of three studies found that women who are more prone to self-objectification tend to have reduced empathy, both affective and cognitive. These women were also more likely to experience self-dehumanization. In turn, self-dehumanization was associated with diminished theory-of-mind abilities&mdash;the capacity to understand that other people have their own thoughts, perceptions, and goals. The paper was published in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/03616843251340962"><em>Psychology of Women Quarterly</em></a>.</p><p>Self-objectification is a psychological process in which individuals, especially women, view and evaluate themselves mainly in terms of how their bodies appear to others, rather than their abilities or internal qualities. Women who adopt this perspective often monitor their physical appearance, a behavior known as &ldquo;self-surveillance.&rdquo;</p><p>This habit leads them to compare themselves with cultural beauty standards, which are often unrealistic or unattainable. As a result, self-objectification is linked to body shame, as people judge themselves harshly for failing to meet these ideals. It can also heighten anxiety about how one&rsquo;s body is perceived in social situations.</p><p>Over time, these pressures may contribute to disordered eating and depression. Sexual experiences can also be affected, as self-objectifying individuals often focus on how their body looks rather than on their sensations or satisfaction. Women high in self-objectification may feel pressure to conform to external evaluations, which can lower self-esteem and increase vulnerability to depression. The process is not only psychological but also social, reinforced by media, advertising, and interpersonal feedback.</p><p>Study author Gian Antonio Di Bernardo and his colleagues set out to examine whether self-objectification interferes with the ability to understand other people&rsquo;s emotions and mental states. They hypothesized that women prone to self-objectification would show lower empathy, weaker theory-of-mind abilities, and a greater tendency toward self-dehumanization&mdash;the process by which individuals come to see themselves as less than fully human, denying their own dignity, agency, or worth.</p><p>The researchers conducted three studies. The first examined whether self-objectification was linked to decreased empathy. Participants were 226 heterosexual Italian women with an average age of 28. They completed an online survey that measured self-objectification (using the 14-item Self-Objectification Beliefs and Behaviors Scale), self-dehumanization, and empathy (via the Interpersonal Reactivity Index).</p><p>The second study repeated this procedure with a new sample of 336 heterosexual Italian women, who were slightly older, with an average age of 34. The third study also surveyed Italian heterosexual women but added an assessment of theory-of-mind abilities (the Reading the Mind in the Eyes test).</p><p>Results from the first two studies indicated that women more prone to self-objectification tended to report lower levels of empathy, including both cognitive empathy (perspective taking) and affective empathy (empathic concern). They also showed higher levels of self-dehumanization. A statistical model suggested that self-objectification may lead to self-dehumanization, which in turn predicts lower empathy.</p><p>The third study confirmed these findings and also showed that women who scored higher in self-dehumanization tended to have somewhat weaker theory-of-mind abilities. Although theory-of-mind performance was not directly associated with self-objectification, the researchers suggested that both may be indirectly linked through self-dehumanization.</p><p>&ldquo;Taken together, our findings suggest that a dysfunctional body image may have detrimental effects not only internally (i.e., the denial of full humanity to oneself) but also externally (i.e., greater difficulty in understanding others&rsquo; emotional and mental states). These results underscore the urgent need to challenge self-objectification and promote a healthier, more authentic perception of self,&rdquo; the study authors concluded.</p><p>The study sheds light on the links between self-objectification and empathy. However, it should be noted that all three studies were conducted on Italian women, mostly young. Results on other cultural and demographic groups might not be identical.</p><p>The paper &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/03616843251340962">No Hard Feelings: The Role of Self-Objectification and Self-Dehumanization in Understanding Emotions and Mental States in Cisgender Heterosexual Women</a>&rdquo; was authored by Gian Antonio Di Bernardo, Chiara Pecini, Bianca Tallone, Giuseppe Raguso, and Luca Andrighetto.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 04:15:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/study-finds-video-gaming-during-covid-19-had-little-impact-on-mental-health/</link><title>People spent slightly more time playing video games during COVID-19 pandemic, but this was not meaningfully associated with changes in mental health. The findings indicate that concerns about gaming being a widespread risk to psychological well-being during lockdowns may have been overstated. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nf1fo2/people_spent_slightly_more_time_playing_video/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nf1fo2/people_spent_slightly_more_time_playing_video/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nf1fo2/people_spent_slightly_more_time_playing_video/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/playing-video-games.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new meta-analysis published in <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-025-05581-6">Humanities and Social Sciences Communications</a></em> suggests that while people spent slightly more time playing video games during the COVID-19 pandemic, this increase was not meaningfully associated with changes in mental health. The findings are based on data from over tens of thousands of participants and indicate that concerns about gaming being a widespread risk to psychological well-being during lockdowns may have been overstated. At the same time, the results do not support the idea that more gaming led to mental health benefits either.</p><p>The COVID-19 pandemic led to sweeping lifestyle changes, including restrictions on in-person social interactions. Video gaming was often promoted as a safe form of entertainment that could help people stay connected and cope with stress. But some experts expressed concern that the rise in gaming might fuel problematic use and mental health problems.</p><p>Reports emerged of individuals playing for excessively long hours, raising questions about whether increased screen time was contributing to anxiety, depression, or other forms of psychological distress. Prior research offered mixed findings, with some studies suggesting that gaming could provide stress relief and emotional support, while others raised flags about overuse and potential harm.</p><p>&ldquo;Before the COVID-19 pandemic, video gaming was often criticized. Most stakeholders highlighted potential harms, such as gaming addiction, aggression, and social isolation. As a researcher focused on the positive aspects of digital media, I was struck by how the discourse shifted during the pandemic,&rdquo; said study author <a href="http://lukaszkaczmarek.com">&#321;ukasz Kaczmarek</a>, a professor at Adam Mickiewicz University, where he heads the Social Psychology Center, the founder of the Psychophysiology Laboratory: Gaming &amp; Streaming.</p><p>&ldquo;Within weeks, video gaming was widely recommended as an at- home activity with possible benefits. The World Health Organization (WHO) promoted active video game use for exercise (#HealthyAtHome). The WHO&rsquo;s #PlayApartTogether initiative disseminated &lsquo;stay-at-home&rsquo; messages through popular games. Early findings published during the pandemic also suggested that gaming might support well-being. At the same time, other experts, including the WHO, expressed concern that increased playtime could do more harm than good. There were worrying reports of individuals escalating from 2 to 14 hours of daily play, thereby increasing the risk of gaming disorder.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Consequently, we saw a need for a broad synthesis of the findings documented in the scientific literature, so that we can evaluate the role of gaming during the COVID-19 pandemic. We focused on gaming time because it is a behavioral metric frequently addressed by parents, industry, and policymakers. Moreover, it is the most commonly reported measure across studies, enabling a more comprehensive and robust meta-analysis.&rdquo;</p><p>The researchers reviewed studies published between March 2020 and December 2021 that reported on both gaming time and mental health indicators. They searched multiple academic databases and contacted dozens of researchers for unpublished data, ultimately including 17 studies that compared gaming time before and during the pandemic and 22 studies that analyzed the relationship between gaming time and mental health. In total, their analysis covered data from 37,778 participants.</p><p>The team focused on both positive mental health indicators&mdash;such as happiness, relaxation, and positive affect&mdash;and negative indicators, including stress, anxiety, depression, and loneliness. They also conducted moderator analyses to determine whether factors like geographic region or type of mental health measure influenced the results.</p><p>The results indicated a modest but statistically significant increase in gaming time during the COVID-19 pandemic (with an average effect size of d = 0.26). This suggests that people played more, but not dramatically more. The prediction intervals were wide, meaning some studies found notable increases while others did not.</p><p>&ldquo;Average increases in gaming time were small,&rdquo; Kaczmarek told PsyPost. &ldquo;The scientific literature indicates a more modest change than some industry reports suggest. This could result from gaming platforms&rsquo; limited ability to distinguish accurately whether a game account is being used by the primary user or by their children. Thus, the narratives around video gaming time during the pandemic might have been overstated.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;My intuition was that increases in gaming time would be substantial. However, this was not the case. One possibility is that there was greater competition for access to electronic devices when all family members were at home, some of whom were teleworking. Another is that individuals and families found more attractive ways of spending time together that competed successfully with gaming, such as cooking or gardening. There may be many alternative explanations.&rdquo;</p><p>When the researchers examined the link between gaming time and mental health, they found no significant association. The overall correlation was r = &minus;0.03, which is close to zero. In other words, people who played more games during the pandemic were not significantly more likely to experience better or worse mental health than those who played less.</p><p>Even when broken down into positive and negative mental health indicators, the differences remained negligible. The researchers also tested for several potential moderators, including participant age, region, type of mental health measure, and data collection timing. None of these significantly altered the core finding: gaming time had no meaningful association with well-being or distress.</p><p>&ldquo;There is no clear evidence that time spent gaming, by itself, either helped or harmed mental health during the pandemic,&rdquo; Kaczmarek explained. &ldquo;On average, gaming time was not associated with negative indicators (e.g., depression, anxiety) or positive indicators (e.g., positive affect, happiness). At both high and low levels of mental health, some individuals played a lot and others played very little. This suggests that gaming time alone is unlikely to be the primary factor associated with mental health. Other parameters may matter more. For example, several studies point not to time but timing &ndash; when people play, so that sleep patterns remain intact.&rdquo;</p><p>There were a few exceptions. For instance, people in Asia showed a slightly stronger negative association between gaming time and well-being, and gaming time was more weakly linked to measures of psychological distress than to measures of positive well-being. But even these effects were small and likely of limited practical significance.</p><p>The authors suggest that much of the concern around gaming during the pandemic may have been based on anecdotes or extreme cases rather than representative trends. Similarly, the belief that gaming broadly improved well-being may stem from subjective impressions rather than consistent data.</p><p>&ldquo;There were so many striking reports showing evidence of the positive impact of games on mental health during the pandemic that I was surprised to see no association in the aggregated data,&rdquo; Kaczmarek said. &ldquo;Perhaps mass media selectively showed positive evidence more often.&rdquo;</p><p>There are limitations to note. Most of the included studies relied on self-reported gaming time and mental health, which can be influenced by memory biases and social desirability. The analysis also focused on average changes, which may obscure meaningful shifts in specific subgroups. For example, people who were already struggling with mental health issues before the pandemic may have been more affected by changes in gaming behavior than others.</p><p>In addition, the researchers could not account for people who began gaming for the first time during the pandemic. Games like Animal Crossing: New Horizons and Among Us surged in popularity and attracted many new players. These individuals may have had different experiences than regular gamers, but the data did not separate them out.</p><p>Future research could explore not just how much people play, but why and how they play. Measuring motivation, context, and quality of gaming experiences may provide a fuller picture of gaming&rsquo;s role in mental health. The researchers also advocate for more longitudinal studies and for the inclusion of both positive and negative mental health measures in future work.</p><p>&ldquo;We hope this publication will be a call to action for many researchers studying video gaming and mental health,&rdquo; Kaczmarek said. &ldquo;We observed recurring gaps in research designs. There is a need for more comprehensive research programs on gaming and mental health during pandemics or lockdowns. For instance, gaming time and timing should be measured in relation to mental health.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Moreover, researchers concerned with negative mental health metrics could also control for positive metrics as part of a standardized approach, and vice versa. This is important because positive and negative metrics of mental health are not redundant. Both are informative and are influenced differently by life opportunities and challenges. Such programs should start as soon as possible and be maintained between crises so that baseline data are available when future events occur. Finally, as new empirical data become available, we hope to have even more material for further analyses that will revise the outcomes or increase confidence in them, and provide new insights.</p><p>&ldquo;I previously mentioned that many individuals overestimate the risks of video gaming,&rdquo; Kaczmarek added. &ldquo;Paradoxically, this increased alertness may be a desirable state even if the vast majority of the population, in fact, benefits from video gaming. Most likely, this motivates individuals to be more observant regarding the development of negative symptomatology and to adjust their gaming behavior so that it fosters their mental health. I hope our findings will encourage readers to be more observant of their gaming activity and mental health and to game more thoughtfully, rather than taking these issues lightly.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41599-025-05581-6">Video game play and well-being during the COVID-19 pandemic: a meta-analysis of global findings</a>,&rdquo; was authored by &#321;ukasz D. Kaczmarek, Patrycja Chwi&#322;kowska, Maciej Behnke, and Dariusz Dr&#261;&#380;kowski.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 17:37:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://today.ucsd.edu/story/frequent-cannabis-users-show-no-driving-impairment-after-two-day-break</link><title>In the largest such study to date, frequent cannabis users did not display impairments in driving performance after at least 48 hours of abstinence. The new findings have implications for public health as well as the enforcement of laws related to cannabis and driving. (today.ucsd.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nepmha/in_the_largest_such_study_to_date_frequent/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nepmha/in_the_largest_such_study_to_date_frequent/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nepmha/in_the_largest_such_study_to_date_frequent/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://today.ucsd.edu/teaser_uploads/_social/DriveSimulator_C0A9830-teaser-1200x628.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><video> <source src="https://today.ucsd.edu/video_uploads/DrivingSim-Banner-1920x1080-9s.mp4"> Your browser does not support the video tag. Please upgrade your browser. </source></video> </div><section><div><p>Scientists from the Center for Medicinal Cannabis Research (CMCR) at the University of California San Diego School of Medicine found that, in the largest such study to date, frequent cannabis users did not display impairments in driving performance after at least 48 hours of abstinence. The new findings have implications for public health as well as the enforcement of laws related to cannabis and driving.</p><p>Approximately three-quarters of Americans live in a state where cannabis is legally available, and about 15% of Americans currently use cannabis. As cannabis usage becomes more widespread, understanding its effects on daily activities like driving is crucial to maintaining public safety and appropriate legislation around cannabis use.</p><p>While acute cannabis intoxication can <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapsychiatry/fullarticle/2788264">impair driving</a>, it can be challenging to enforce cannabis and driving laws because, unlike alcohol, there is no biological test (e.g., blood concentrations) that directly relates to cannabis intoxication. Tetrahydrocannabinol (THC), the psychoactive compound in cannabis, can be detected in blood for several days to weeks after use, and in urine for weeks or even months.</p></div><div><div><p>One unanswered question around cannabis and driving is whether frequent cannabis users, who may or may not still have THC detectable in their blood, experience reduced driving abilities when not actively high. To answer this question, researchers analyzed data from two studies. The first, a randomized clinical trial, assessed driving performance in a sample of 191 cannabis users, all of whom had abstained for at least 48 hours. The second study compared a subset of the most frequent users from the first study with a smaller comparison group of people who don&rsquo;t use cannabis. A driving simulator was used to assess driving performance and potential impairment.</p><p>The researchers found no indications of reduced driving ability in cannabis users who had abstained for at least two days. First-author Kyle Mastropietro, a graduate student in the San Diego State University/UC San Diego Joint Doctoral Program in Clinical Psychology, commented, &ldquo;We did not find any relationship between driving performance, and cannabis use history or time of abstinence, nor blood THC concentrations. Of note, the most intensive users from the group, who mostly used cannabis daily and smoked an average of four joints per day, did no worse during this period of abstinence than a healthy, non-using comparison group.&rdquo;</p><p>Thomas Marcotte, Ph.D., professor of psychiatry at UC San Diego School of Medicine and the study&rsquo;s senior author, added, &ldquo;The findings add to the growing body of evidence that relying on blood THC concentrations in regular cannabis users as possible indicators of impairment is not justified, given that THC may be detectable many days (or longer) after use.&rdquo; Marcotte, who is also the co-director of the CMCR, added that &ldquo;the findings reinforce the challenges in relating findings from cognitive testing in very frequent users who are abstinent to how they might function during real-world, overlearned behaviors like driving.&rdquo;</p></div><div><figure> <img alt="Instructor view driver in a simulator" width="705" height="470" src="https://today.ucsd.edu/news_uploads/C0A9867-800px-Marcotte.png"> <figcaption><p>Using an onsite driving simulator at the Center for Medicinal Cannabis research, researchers at UC San Diego School of Medicine have found that frequent cannabis users show no driving deficits after at least two days of abstinence. Photo credit: Kyle Dykes/UC San Diego Health Sciences</p></figcaption> </figure> </div></div><div><p>The authors note that this study was done in a controlled lab environment, did not address all possible driving scenarios, and the nonuser comparison group was small. That said, the findings do provide new insights into the potential risks and consequences of chronic cannabis use.</p><p>The <a href="https://rdcu.be/eEDgt">study</a> was published in Psychopharmacology on September 6, 2025. It was funded, in part, by the State of California award to the CMCR via Assembly Bill 266 (Bonta/Cooley/Jones-Sawyer/Lackey: Agreement #907). The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</p></div></section><div><h2> You May Also Like </h2> </div><div><div><h2>Stay in the Know</h2><p>Keep up with all the latest from UC San Diego. Subscribe to the newsletter today. </p></div><div><form><div><p><label> Email </label> </p><div><p>Please provide a valid email address.</p></div></div></form> </div></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 06:21:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/magic-mushroom-edibles-found-to-contain-no-psilocybin/</link><title>Researchers tested 12 “magic mushroom” edible products sold in Portland, Ore., and found no trace of psilocybin, the hallucinogenic compound that gives magic mushrooms their name. The research was published on Thursday in JAMA Network Open. (scientificamerican.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1neciw0/researchers_tested_12_magic_mushroom_edible/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1neciw0/researchers_tested_12_magic_mushroom_edible/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1neciw0/researchers_tested_12_magic_mushroom_edible/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><p>September 11, 2025</p><p>4 min read</p></div><h2></h2><p>Magic Mushroom Edibles Found to Contain Undisclosed Ingredients&mdash;And No Psilocybin</p><p>Researchers tested 12 &ldquo;magic mushroom&rdquo; edibles. None contained psilocybin, but most contained undisclosed ingredients, including synthetic drugs whose safety hasn&rsquo;t been tested in humans</p><p>By <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/author/allison-parshall/">Allison Parshall</a> <span>edited by <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/author/dean-visser/">Dean Visser</a></span></p><figure><img src="https://static.scientificamerican.com/dam/m/2cb152d05ed4d363/original/magic_mushroom_psilocybe_cubensis.jpg?m=1757691950.833&amp;w=600" alt="Low angle image of magic mushrooms (Psilocybe cubensis) lit with magenta lighting" srcset="https://static.scientificamerican.com/dam/m/2cb152d05ed4d363/original/magic_mushroom_psilocybe_cubensis.jpg?m=1757691950.833&amp;w=600 600w, https://static.scientificamerican.com/dam/m/2cb152d05ed4d363/original/magic_mushroom_psilocybe_cubensis.jpg?m=1757691950.833&amp;w=900 900w, https://static.scientificamerican.com/dam/m/2cb152d05ed4d363/original/magic_mushroom_psilocybe_cubensis.jpg?m=1757691950.833&amp;w=1000 1000w, https://static.scientificamerican.com/dam/m/2cb152d05ed4d363/original/magic_mushroom_psilocybe_cubensis.jpg?m=1757691950.833&amp;w=1200 1200w, https://static.scientificamerican.com/dam/m/2cb152d05ed4d363/original/magic_mushroom_psilocybe_cubensis.jpg?m=1757691950.833&amp;w=1350 1350w"><figcaption><p>Magic mushrooms (<i>Psilocybe cubensis</i>).</p><p>Yarphoto/Getty Images</p></figcaption></figure></div><div><p>Researchers tested 12 &ldquo;<a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/restrictions-on-psilocybin-magic-mushrooms-are-easing-as-research-ramps-up/">magic mushroom</a>&rdquo; edible products sold in Portland, Ore., and found no trace of psilocybin, the hallucinogenic compound that gives magic mushrooms their name. Instead seven of the products contained <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2025.31345">at least one undisclosed active ingredient</a>. Such ingredients included <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/video/how-thc-the-psychoactive-compound-in-weed-gets-you-high/">cannabis extrac</a>t and <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/ai-program-finds-thousands-of-possible-psychedelics-will-they-lead-to-new-drugs/">synthetic psychedelics </a>whose effects and safety have not been formally documented or studied.</p><p>&ldquo;We found no evidence of mushroom compounds of any kind, coming from any species,&rdquo; says the new study&rsquo;s co-author Richard van Breemen, a pharmaceutical sciences professor at Oregon State University. The research was published on Thursday in <i>JAMA Network Open.</i></p><p>Psilocybin and other psychedelic drugs have received a lot of attention in recent years as potential treatments for mental health conditions such as depression and post-traumatic stress disorder. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s a lot of hype around these substances, so people are increasingly trying them outside current legal pathways,&rdquo; says Lori Bruce, a bioethicist at Yale University, who researches psychedelics.</p><hr><h2>On supporting science journalism</h2><p>If you're enjoying this article, consider supporting our award-winning journalism by <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/getsciam/">subscribing</a>. By purchasing a subscription you are helping to ensure the future of impactful stories about the discoveries and ideas shaping our world today.</p><hr><p>In June 2024 the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention announced that the agency was <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/environmental-health-studies/outbreak-investigation-diamond-shruumz-products/index.html">investigating reports of severe illness</a> after people consumed certain purported psilocybin edibles. By last October, 73 hospitalizations and three deaths&mdash;all possibly associated with such products&mdash;had been reported across 34 states. &ldquo;The mislabeling highlighted in this [study] causes harms,&rdquo; Bruce says. &ldquo;And as usage rates increase across the U.S., harms from retail products are also likely to increase.&rdquo;</p><h2><b>Are Any Commercial Psilocybin Products Legal?</b></h2><p>Psilocybin comes from several mushroom species, including some in the genus<i> Psilocybe</i>. When consumed, the body breaks down the compound into psilocin, an alkaloid that can cause startling visual hallucinations and psychological effects, often including intense introspection. The U.S. federal government classifies both psilocybin and psilocin as Schedule I drugs, meaning they&rsquo;re deemed to have a high potential for abuse and no currently accepted medical use.</p><p>But a handful of states have recently legalized the manufacture, sale, possession and use of psilocybin under certain conditions. Both medical and recreational use are legal in Colorado, and New Mexico passed a law this year that legalizes certain medical uses. In Oregon the regulations are stricter: the drug must be taken in the company of a licensed facilitator at a specific &ldquo;psilocybin service center.&rdquo; These centers receive psilocybin from licensed growers, whose products are tested by a licensed laboratory.</p><p>Oregon does not allow the sale or use of psilocybin products outside of these centers; it is otherwise a criminal offense to buy, sell or possess the drug in the state. But the legal channels are prohibitively expensive to many: the average trip costs <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/15265161.2024.2433420">somewhere between $750 and $1,200</a>.</p><p>This dynamic may be leading more people to try purported psilocybin products that are untested and prohibited but nonetheless sold at some retail stores, says legal researcher Mason Marks, a law professor at Florida State University who focused on psychedelics. &ldquo;A lot of people are very curious about these substances. And if you&rsquo;re in a state, like Oregon, that does not decriminalize them, people might go to these shops and buy these products that are either blatantly illegal or kind of in this gray area.&rdquo;</p><h2><b>Undisclosed and Untested Ingredients</b></h2><p>For the new study, the researchers purchased 12 edible products (11 gummies and a chocolate) that were advertised as containing &ldquo;magic mushrooms&rdquo; and were sold at gas stations and convenience stores in Portland. These products are &ldquo;being marketed widely in local convenience stores and on the Internet,&rdquo; van Breemen says.</p><p>The edibles were first tested at a state-licensed facility that normally certifies the quality of the drug for Oregon&rsquo;s psilocybin service centers. None of the products contained any psilocybin at all. To determine what they actually <i>did</i> contain, van Breemen and his colleagues turned to more advanced mass spectrometry techniques.</p><p>Seven products contained undisclosed active ingredients such as caffeine, kava extract (a legal herbal supplement with antianxiety and hallucinogenic effects) and cannabis extract (including the plant&rsquo;s main psychoactive ingredient, tetrahydrocannabinol, or THC). Four of the gummies contained no active ingredients at all.</p><p>Two of the gummies did contain psilocin, which also occurs naturally in some mushrooms in small quantities&mdash;and which is easier to synthesize in a laboratory than psilocybin. If the psilocin in the edibles came from natural sources, the researchers would expect to also detect other, related compounds from mushrooms. Such compounds turned out to be absent, leading van Breemen and his colleagues to conclude that the psilocin was likely synthetic.</p><p>Of greatest concern to the researchers, though, was the identification of synthetic psychedelic, or &ldquo;syndelic,&rdquo; compounds in two of the gummies. These drugs, mipracetin and 4-hydroxy-diethyltryptamine, have a chemical structure that is similar to that of psilocybin and psilocin and are psychoactive. Their effects on the body have not been studied in humans. "We don&rsquo;t know what harm they might cause,&rdquo; van Breemen says.</p><p>Van Breemen was surprised by the extent of the mislabeling. &ldquo;Over the years, we&rsquo;ve tested many botanical dietary supplements,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;Rarely do you find 12 products, none of which contain what they're supposed to contain. So the sample number is small, but the number of mislabeled or adulterated products was significant.&rdquo;</p><p>This is an &ldquo;important and timely study,&rdquo; Bruce says. &ldquo;Psychedelics show initial promise for intractable mental health disorders, but science is still teasing out who will benefit and who will be harmed from their psychedelics experience.&rdquo; The Trump administration has <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/rfk-jr-suggests-administration-support-for-psychedelic-therapy-for-depression-trauma">indicated an interest in deregulating psychedelics</a> for therapeutic purposes. In this context, Bruce adds, &ldquo;the concerns I raise may become more widespread.&rdquo;</p></div><section><h2>It&rsquo;s Time to Stand Up for Science</h2><p>If you enjoyed this article, I&rsquo;d like to ask for your support. <span>Scientific American</span> has served as an advocate for science and industry for 180 years, and right now may be the most critical moment in that two-century history.</p><p>I&rsquo;ve been a <span>Scientific American</span> subscriber since I was 12 years old, and it helped shape the way I look at the world. <span>SciAm </span>always educates and delights me, and inspires a sense of awe for our vast, beautiful universe. I hope it does that for you, too.</p><p>If you <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/getsciam/">subscribe to <span>Scientific American</span></a>, you help ensure that our coverage is centered on meaningful research and discovery; that we have the resources to report on the decisions that threaten labs across the U.S.; and that we support both budding and working scientists at a time when the value of science itself too often goes unrecognized.</p><p>In return, you get essential news, <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/podcasts/">captivating podcasts</a>, brilliant infographics, <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/newsletters/">can't-miss newsletters</a>, must-watch videos, <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/games/">challenging games</a>, and the science world's best writing and reporting. You can even <a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/getsciam/gift/">gift someone a subscription</a>.</p><p>There has never been a more important time for us to stand up and show why science matters. I hope you&rsquo;ll support us in that mission.</p></section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 21:25:53 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/parental-values-demonstration-can-help-defiant-teens-665942/</link><title>The way teenagers receive their parents’ warnings depends less on the message and more on whether their parents genuinely living their own values. When parents model their values consistently in daily life, their warnings are more likely to be perceived by teenagers as guidance instead of control. (rochester.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ne70q5/the_way_teenagers_receive_their_parents_warnings/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ne70q5/the_way_teenagers_receive_their_parents_warnings/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ne70q5/the_way_teenagers_receive_their_parents_warnings/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.rochester.edu/newscenter/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/fea-parental-values-demonstration-GettyImages-1361216224-1200x630.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>New research shows that teens heed warnings more when parents model their values and show understanding.</h2><p>Adolescence is a period when some teenagers begin experimenting with risky or rule-breaking behaviors such as skipping school, drinking, lying, or staying out past their curfew. When parents find out, their natural response is often to warn their child: Continue with the behavior and you&rsquo;ll incur stricter rules, less freedom, and the loss of privileges.</p><p>On the surface, this response seems a reasonable attempt to deter further misbehaving. But how do teens actually experience these warnings&mdash;and why do some comply while others become even more defiant?</p><p>A team of US and Israeli researchers&mdash;among them <a href="http://www.rochester.edu">University of Rochester</a> psychologist <a href="https://www.sas.rochester.edu/psy/people/faculty/smetana_judith/index.html">Judith Smetana</a>&mdash;set out to find answers. The resulting <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10964-025-02196-7">study</a>, published in the <em>Journal of Youth and Adolescence</em>, concludes that the way teenagers receive their parents&rsquo; warnings depends less on the message itself and more on whether they see their parents as genuinely living up their own purported values.</p><p>If parents model their values consistently in everyday life and appear satisfied and vital while acting on their values, their warnings are more likely to be perceived by their teenagers as caring guidance. If not, teens often experience the warnings as an attempt to control them, which can spark defiance. But the researchers also discovered that while authentic parental values reduced defiance, they did not, by themselves, lead teens to stop their risky behaviors. The warnings proved most effective when parents took the time to understand their teens&rsquo; perspectives.</p><p>&ldquo;Parents really have to &lsquo;walk the walk&rsquo; and act on their values if they want their teens to behave responsibly,&rdquo;&nbsp;says Smetana, an expert on adolescent-parent relationships.</p><h3>The science behind motivation</h3><p>The study, Smetana points out, builds directly on&nbsp;a famous Rochester construct&mdash;the highly influential, evidence-based framework for motivation, called <a href="https://www.urmc.rochester.edu/community-health/patient-care/self-determination-theory">self-determination theory (SDT)</a>, which was formulated in the 1970s and 1980s by Rochester psychologists <a href="https://www.sas.rochester.edu/psy/people/faculty/deci_edward/index.html">Edward Deci</a> and <a href="https://www.sas.rochester.edu/psy/people/faculty/ryan_richard/index.html">Richard Ryan</a>.</p><p>According to SDT, people have three basic, intrinsic psychological needs:</p><ul> <li><strong>Autonomy</strong>&mdash;the need to feel free from control so one can realize one&rsquo;s authentic preferences</li> <li><strong>Competence</strong>&mdash;the need to feel capable</li> <li><strong>Relatedness</strong>&mdash;the need to feel connected and respected by others</li> </ul><p>When parenting actively supports these needs, adolescents feel motivated and understood. But when parents&rsquo; behaviors hinder these needs&mdash;what Deci and Ryan call &ldquo;need thwarting&rdquo; (where a person&rsquo;s basic psychological needs for autonomy, competence, and relatedness are actively undermined)&mdash;teens may feel pressured, powerless, or disconnected, which can trigger resistance and rebellion.</p><p>&ldquo;The idea of &lsquo;need thwarting&rsquo; leading to defiance is drawn directly from self-determination theory, as is the very important notion of autonomy-supportive parenting, which is widely used in studies of parenting,&rdquo; says Smetana.</p><h3>Modeling values while parenting</h3><p>Smetana and her team focused specifically on one parental factor called &ldquo;inherent value demonstration&rdquo; that can influence how warnings are received. For example, a parent who stresses the importance of kindness, volunteers regularly, and treats others respectfully&mdash;and appears satisfied and energetic while doing so&mdash;would be seen as high in value demonstration. In contrast, parents whose actions don&rsquo;t match their words would be perceived as low in value demonstration.</p><p>The team surveyed 105 Israeli adolescents, average age 15, who had engaged in at least one problem behavior in the previous month. Each teen reported the most serious behavior their parents had discovered and then rated how their parents reacted&mdash;whether through warnings or by trying to understand their child&rsquo;s perspective. The teens also shared how these reactions made them feel: Did they experience the reactions as supportive or as controlling? Did they feel motivated to stop, or did they feel defiant? Finally, they rated how much their parents generally demonstrated their values in daily life.</p><p>The findings were clear: When parents were perceived as low&nbsp;in value demonstration, their teens were much more likely to experience their warnings as&nbsp;&ldquo;need thwarting.&rdquo; But when parents were perceived&nbsp;as high&nbsp;in value demonstration, their warnings were more likely to be seen as protective and the teens experienced the warnings as &ldquo;need supporting.&rdquo; Teenagers in these families were less defiant and felt more supported, even if the warnings included unpleasant consequences, such as the loss of privileges.</p><h3>Stopping teens&rsquo; risky behaviors</h3><p>The researchers discovered that while authentic parental values reduced defiance, they did not, by themselves, lead teens to stop their risky behaviors.</p><p>&ldquo;We were surprised to learn that even children who perceived their parents as demonstrating their values in their everyday behavior experienced their parents&rsquo; warnings as frustrating and insensitive to their basic psychological needs,&rdquo; says lead coauthor Avi Assor at Israel-based Ben-Gurion University of the Negev. &ldquo;We thought that because parents&rsquo; warnings referred to potentially harmful problem behaviors, children who appreciate their parents as good models of virtuous behavior may not experience these warnings as insensitive to their needs.&rdquo;</p><p>Instead, the team found that the only parenting reaction linked to actually stopping the problem behavior was&nbsp;&ldquo;perspective taking&rdquo;&mdash;when parents tried to understand their child&rsquo;s feelings and reasons. This empathic approach seemed to prompt reflection, making it more likely that teens reconsidered and stopped their risky actions.</p><p>In short: Putting yourself in your teenager&rsquo;s shoes may be your best bet in trying to keep your child safe.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 17:36:02 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/chronic-pain/perfectionists-chronic-pain/</link><title>Chronic pain worsened by harsh self-criticism, study finds. People living with chronic pain tend to be more perfectionistic, less self-compassionate and – depending on the measure – less confident in their ability to cope. These psychological traits may intensify suffering. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ne3vde/chronic_pain_worsened_by_harsh_selfcriticism/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ne3vde/chronic_pain_worsened_by_harsh_selfcriticism/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ne3vde/chronic_pain_worsened_by_harsh_selfcriticism/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/af67926/2147483647/strip/true/crop/6733x3535+0+754/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Ffd%2F62%2F17b9998c47c99a223572a506bba5%2Fdepositphotos-731272008-xl.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study has found that people living with chronic pain tend to be more perfectionistic, less self-compassionate and &ndash; depending on the measure &ndash; less confident in their ability to cope. These psychological traits may intensify suffering, but they also point to new avenues for relief.</p><p>An international research team led by Australia's Murdoch University, recruited hundreds of Canadian adults, half with chronic conditions such as <a href="https://newatlas.com/tag/back-pain/">back pain</a>, <a href="https://newatlas.com/tag/arthritis/">arthritis</a> or <a href="https://newatlas.com/tag/migraines/">migraines</a>, and half without. Participants completed detailed online questionnaires regarding personality and coping styles. The team focused on three traits: perfectionism, self-compassion and general self-efficacy. Perfectionism was then split into two categories &ndash; self-oriented&nbsp;&ndash; the internal drive to meet very high standards&nbsp;&ndash; and socially prescribed, or the belief that others expect it. Self-compassion was gauged by how kindly people treat themselves in difficult moments. Self-efficacy measured the extent to which participants believed they can achieve goals and handle challenges.</p><p>&ldquo;We undertook this study because although the association between stress and pain is recognized, little is known about links between chronic pain and stress arising from perfectionist expectations,&rdquo; said Dr Graeme Ditchburn from Murdoch University's School of Psychology. </p><p>The two-part study involved 531 participants aged 18 to 65 years with chronic pain that had endured for longer than three months and 515 individuals with no chronic pain. In the first study, 237 participants with chronic pain and 237 without pain completed an online survey. The researchers found that those with pain had significant higher levels of socially prescribed perfectionism and lower levels of self-compassion than those without pain. In the second study, 294 individuals with chronic pain, and 278 without, completed the online survey. Those with chronic pain reported significantly higher levels of perfectionism and lower levels of self-compassion and self-efficacy than the pain-free group. </p><p>What's more, both kinds of perfectionism &ndash; self-oriented and socially prescribed &ndash; were higher in those with low self-compassion scores. Statistical analyses found that self-oriented perfectionism and self-compassion was positively associated with self-efficacy, while socially prescribed perfectionism was negatively associated with self-efficacy.</p><p>&ldquo;Chronic pain sufferers may experience frustration with difficulties performing day-to-day activities and push themselves toward unrealistic or unachievable goals,&rdquo; Ditchburn said. &ldquo;Furthermore, they may also feel that others have expectations that are difficult to meet.</p><p>&ldquo;Self-compassion may reflect fear of judgment or self-criticism, perceiving the pain condition and the burden caused by this condition as their own fault," he added. "These also have negative implications for perceptions of self-efficacy or self-belief in one&rsquo;s capacity. In turn, these have both direct and indirect associations with stress, which has negative consequences for physical and mental health."</p><p>Ultimately, across both studies, there were clear differences between those with chronic pain and those without &ndash;&nbsp;especially when it came to perfectionism. People with chronic pain reported higher levels of socially prescribed perfectionism, the sense of being judged and pressured by others. And in one of the two studies, they also scored higher on self-oriented perfectionism, suggesting they have an inner voice that demands constant flawlessness and performance. The researchers suggest this perfectionistic mindset may exacerbate pain by fueling stress, frustration and a relentless drive to &ldquo;push through&rdquo; rather than pacing activity in a sustainable way.</p><p>In both studies, those with chronic pain scored significantly lower in regards to self-compassion than their pain-free peers. Instead of treating themselves with understanding, chronic-pain sufferers were more likely to be harsh self-critics. The researchers described self-compassion as a protective buffer &ndash; so, without it, pain may feel like more of a load, stripping away emotional resources that build resilience.</p><p>While the study captures a snapshot in time rather than a direct causal link, and is based on self-reported data, it does highlight the role psychology plays in living with chronic pain. The way people evaluate themselves &ndash; and imagine others evaluating them &ndash; shapes how they endure long-term pain conditions. </p><p>This is important because these traits &ndash; perfectionism and self-compassion &ndash; can be changed. The researchers suggest that therapy and targeted coaching, including interventions such as cognitive-behavioral therapy, could help people quiet their inner critics. Earlier studies have shown that <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/chronic-pain-brain-chemistry-emotion-regulation/">chronic pain</a> alters brain chemistry and affects emotional regulation.</p><p>&ldquo;Our findings suggest that interventions aimed at increasing self-compassion and addressing perfectionistic tendencies may be beneficial for individuals experiencing chronic pain," Ditchburn. </p><p>The team suggest their work opens the door to more nuanced assessment of the relationship between psychology and physical impairment, which could help people with specific conditions better manage their <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/mindfulness-meditation-placebo-effect-pain/">pain and their mental health</a>.</p><p>"As the types and number of pain conditions may impact the individual physically and psychologically to different degrees, future research should explore whether the type of condition and degree of impairment, as perceived by the individual and others, are associated with perfectionism, self-compassion and self-efficacy," the researchers noted in the study. "Further studies examining the extent to which age is associated with perfectionism, self-compassion, and self-efficacy for those with and without chronic pain may also be beneficial, particularly if coupled with analysis of any association it may have with inter-relationships between the scales. </p><p>"Furthermore, given pain is not experienced in a vacuum but rather involves caregivers, family members and others, research is needed to explore the potential impact of these systems on the expectations, perfectionism, self-compassion, and self-efficacy of those experiencing chronic pain conditions," they added.</p><p>As therapeutic intervention is limited, other recent studies looking into non-drug treatments that build <a href="https://newatlas.com/chronic-pain/drug-free-pain-relief-game/">mental resilience</a> as well as <a href="https://newatlas.com/chronic-pain/chronic-pain-diet-adiposity/">changes to diet</a> have shown promise in chronic pain management and improved quality of life.</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/epdf/10.1080/08870446.2025.2552227?needAccess=true"><i>Psychology and Health</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.murdoch.edu.au/news/articles/new-research-uncovers-link-between-perfectionism-and-pain">Murdoch University</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 14:33:31 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
