<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=science&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/science</title><description>Hot posts in /r/science (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 22:55:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_mouw-styles-communityIcon_xtjipkhhefi41-144x400.png</url><title>/r/science</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/news/study-highlights-cultural-differences-in-parenting-and-reveals-that-how-babies-are-soothed-matters-more-than-how-fast-/</link><title>The way babies are soothed may be more important than how quickly mothers respond. UK mothers responded more quickly, but Ugandan infants recovered faster. UK mothers used more verbal reassurance and less tactile contact. Ugandan mothers used more tactile strategies, particularly breastfeeding. (durham.ac.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.durham.ac.uk/media/durham-university/central-news-and-events-images/news/Infant-comforting-web-pic.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>The way in which babies are soothed could be more important than how quickly mothers respond, according to new research revealing cultural differences in how babies are comforted.&#8239;&#8239; </p><div><p><span>Researchers including Professor Zanna Clay of our Psychology Department observed mother&ndash;infant interactions in urban UK and rural Ugandan communities.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>They focused on how mothers soothed their babies following naturally occurring episodes of distress.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Challenging assumptions&nbsp;</h4><p><span>They found that although the UK mothers responded to their babies' distress more quickly, Ugandan infants actually recovered faster.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This challenges long-standing assumptions rooted in Western models of parenting by showing that maternal promptness is not the only factor influencing how infants manage their emotions.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Instead, the type of soothing behaviour used, which is shaped by cultural context, may play a key role in helping babies regulate distress.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>While both UK and Ugandan mothers soothed their babies at three months with tactile contact, like breastfeeding, UK mothers tended to use more verbal reassurance and less tactile contact as babies grew older.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>By comparison, Ugandan mothers were more likely to rely on tactile strategies, particularly breastfeeding, even with older infants.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Everyday interactions&nbsp;</h4><p><span>The researchers analysed 147 naturally occurring episodes of infant distress involving 82 infants aged three and six months.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Unlike controlled lab settings or surveys, the observations reflected genuine, everyday spontaneous parent&ndash;infant interactions.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>In both countries, infants recovered more quickly when mothers responded faster.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>But notably, Ugandan mothers - who tended to respond more slowly - soothed their infants more effectively using tactile strategies, like breastfeeding, leading to quicker recovery.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This effect appears to stem from cultural differences in caregiving style and suggests that soothing methods may be more influential than speed of response alone.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The researchers hope these insights will inform more culturally inclusive approaches to parenting support and early intervention.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The research has been published in the journal Developmental Psychology and was funded by the European Research Council.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Find out more&nbsp;</h4> <ul> <li><span>Read the full paper in the journal </span><a href="https://doi.org/10.1037/dev0002038"><span>Developmental Psychology</span></a><span>.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> <li><span>Learn more about the work of </span><a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/staff/zanna-e-clay/"><span>Professor Zanna Clay</span></a><span>.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> <li><span>Our Department of Psychology is ranked 84th in the QS World University Rankings by Subject 2025. Visit our </span><a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/"><span>Psychology webpages</span></a><span> for more information on our undergraduate and postgraduate programmes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> </ul> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 16:27:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.additudemag.com/chronic-boredom-working-memory-attention-control/</link><title>A new study has found that people with ADHD traits experience boredom more often and more intensely than peers, linked to poor attention control and working memory (additudemag.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i0.wp.com/www.additudemag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/understand-conditions-adhd-research-and-news.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><em>September 1, 2025</em></p><p>Poor working memory and attention control may help explain why people with ADHD experience boredom more often and more acutely than do their non-ADHD peers. &ldquo;Part of the reason individuals with ADHD often experience boredom is due to difficulty controlling their attention and using their working memory effectively, leading to interpretations of that situation as boring,&rdquo; explains a study published last month in the <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/10870547251356723"><em>Journal of Attention Disorders</em></a>.<sup><a href="https://www.additudemag.com#footnote1">1</a></sup></p><p>In the small study, young adults completed self-reported measures of ADHD symptoms (using the Barkley Adult ADHD Rating Scale and the Wender Utah Rating Scale) and <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-so-bored-how-to-cure-boredom-adhd/">propensity for boredom</a> (on the Short Boredom Proneness Scale). They also submitted performance-based cognitive measures of <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/working-memory-deficit-weak-short-term-memory-symptoms-test-adults/">working memory</a> and attentional control. Based on their ADHD symptom self-reports, 31 participants were placed in the ADHD traits group and 57 in the control group.</p><p>Participants in the ADHD group experienced significantly higher levels of proneness to <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-bored-life-is-boring-impulsive-decisions/">boredom</a> compared to the control group (<em>d</em>&thinsp;=&thinsp;2.09), confirming previous research findings. Researchers also discovered that proneness to boredom and inclusion in the ADHD trait group were associated with significantly worse performance on working memory and attention control tests. &ldquo;Both attention control and <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/improve-working-memory/">working memory</a> factors partially mediated the relation between <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/slideshows/i-am-bored-agitation-restlessness/">ADHD and boredom</a>, accounting for 5.8% and 6.4% of the variance in ADHD-related boredom, respectively,&rdquo; researchers explained.</p><p>The findings of the study, the first to connect ADHD traits and boredom to performance-based <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/what-is-executive-function-disorder/">executive function</a> measures, support the Cognitive Theory of Boredom, which suggests that the experience of boredom is a result of the inability to direct attention on the task at hand.</p><p>One of the researchers who originated this theory, John Eastwood, Ph.D., co-author of <a href="https://www.hup.harvard.edu/books/9780674984677"><em>Out of My Skull: The Psychology of Boredom</em></a>, discussed the close association between boredom and ADHD in the recent <em>ADDitude</em> article, <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-so-bored-how-to-cure-boredom-adhd/"><em>Why ADHD Brains Go Over-Bored</em></a>,</p><p>&ldquo;Boredom points to our need to have agency, to be the captain of our own ship,&rdquo; Eastwood says, adding that the struggle to be self-directed is common among <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/what-is-adhd-symptoms-causes-treatments/">people with ADHD</a>, who are often corrected and directed by parents and teachers from a young age.</p><p>&ldquo;When a feeling like boredom is uncomfortable, we are sometimes unable to hear its deeper message because we just try to make the feeling go away,&rdquo; explains Eastwood. &ldquo;But boredom often has a message for us. I would encourage people to take boredom seriously, try not to be afraid or intolerant of it. There may be an opportunity to see how you can live in a way that gives fuller expression to who you are.&rdquo;</p><p>Eastwood also offered pragmatic interventions for those who experience chronic boredom, recommending adaptive, intentional responses to replace automatic, <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/stressors-adhd-brain/">stress responses</a>.</p><ul> <li>Instead of using avoidance-based coping strategies, such as a long break in the bathroom during a lecture, <strong>try engagement-based strategies,</strong> such as gamifying the experience &ndash; for instance, noting whenever the professor uses a three-syllable word.</li> <li>Strategies that help people <strong>tolerate intense emotions with a minimal stress response</strong>, such as active forms of <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/mindfulness-meditation-for-adhd/">mindfulness</a>, such as yoga or mindful walking, may also be effective with boredom</li> </ul> <h3>View Article Sources</h3><p><a></a><small><sup>1</sup>Orban, S. A., Blessing, J. S., Sandone, M. K., Conness, B., &amp; Santer, J. (2025). Why Are Individuals With ADHD More Prone to Boredom? Examining Attention Control and Working Memory as Mediators of Boredom in Young Adults With ADHD Traits. <em>Journal of Attention Disorders</em>, <em>0</em>(0). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/10870547251356723">https://doi.org/10.1177/10870547251356723</a></small></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 22:31:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/army-basic-training-appears-to-reshape-how-the-brain-processes-reward/</link><title>Army basic training appears to reshape how the brain processes reward. The stress experienced during basic combat training may dampen the brain’s ability to respond to rewarding outcomes. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/us-army-soldiers.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpsc.2025.05.007">Biological Psychiatry: Cognitive Neuroscience and Neuroimaging</a></em> suggests that stress experienced during basic combat training may dampen the brain&rsquo;s ability to respond to rewarding outcomes. Researchers found that Army National Guard recruits showed a measurable decline in neural signals linked to reward processing after completing a physically and emotionally demanding 10-week training program. The findings suggest that real-world stressors can influence how the brain processes both positive and negative feedback, with potential implications for resilience and mental health.</p><p>The ability to respond to rewards is considered an important aspect of healthy emotional functioning. Previous research has shown that greater neural responsiveness to rewards is associated with positive outcomes such as well-being, motivation, and resilience to stress. On the other hand, reduced responsiveness has been linked to symptoms of anhedonia, which refers to the loss of interest or pleasure in typically enjoyable activities. Anhedonia is a symptom seen across many psychiatric disorders, including depression.</p><p>Laboratory studies have demonstrated that acute or chronic stress can reduce the brain&rsquo;s responsiveness to rewards, possibly by disrupting dopamine signaling. However, much of this prior research has either relied on artificial stress manipulations in lab settings or retrospective self-reports of stress that may be biased.</p><p>Few studies have assessed how real-world, naturally occurring stressors affect neural reward processing over time. The authors of the current study sought to fill this gap by using a longitudinal design to examine how stress during a real-world challenge &mdash; basic combat training &mdash; might influence brain function.</p><p>The researchers drew on data from the ARMOR study, a large, ongoing project that investigates resilience and stress responses in military service members. From the broader sample, a subset of 123 Army National Guard recruits participated in a neuroimaging substudy. These participants were assessed before and after completing a 10-week basic combat training program. The training is designed to prepare civilians for military service and is widely recognized as a stressful experience due to its intense physical, psychological, and social demands.</p><p>Participants completed a computerized gambling task while their brain activity was recorded using electroencephalography, a method that tracks electrical signals from the scalp. The task involved choosing between two options to either win or lose points, with the outcome determined at random. This setup allowed the researchers to measure how the brain responded to positive (gain) or negative (loss) feedback. A particular brain signal, known as the reward positivity (or RewP), was used as a marker of reward processing. The RewP typically occurs between 175 and 325 milliseconds after feedback is received.</p><p>In addition to recording brain activity, the researchers also assessed each participant&rsquo;s experience of stress during training using the Basic Training Stressors Scale. This self-report measure captures both the frequency and perceived impact of various stressors related to performance, interpersonal dynamics, and living conditions. The stress survey was completed about two weeks after the end of basic training, prior to the follow-up brain scan.</p><p>The researchers also examined brain activity in specific frequency bands&mdash;delta and theta oscillations&mdash;associated with reward and loss processing, respectively. These time-frequency analyses provide an additional window into the dynamics of neural responses and may tap into different mechanisms than the traditional event-related potentials like the RewP.</p><p>The main finding was that neural responses to both rewards and losses were significantly reduced after the recruits completed basic training. This decrease was observed in the RewP time window and was not explained by the length of time between study visits. Interestingly, the difference between reward and loss responses did not change significantly, indicating that the decline occurred across both types of feedback rather than being specific to one.</p><p>The researchers then looked at whether self-reported stress during basic training was related to these changes in brain activity. They found that higher levels of perceived stress were associated with a smaller neural response to rewards, although this relationship weakened when additional variables were included in the model. This suggests that the subjective impact of stress, more than just the number of stressors, might influence how the brain adapts to stressful situations.</p><p>While the time-domain measures of brain activity showed a clear decline, analyses of delta and theta oscillations did not show consistent changes following training. This distinction may reflect differences in the neural processes captured by each approach. Time-domain signals like the RewP are typically phase-locked to feedback and reflect a more synchronized response, while time-frequency measures capture a broader and more variable range of neural activity. The researchers suggest that stress might reduce the consistency of brain responses rather than their amplitude, which could explain the discrepancy.</p><p>Participants who had stronger delta-band power before training were more likely to report lower levels of stress afterward. This finding hints at the possibility that some individuals may have a form of neural resilience, where their brains are better equipped to maintain reward sensitivity in the face of stress. These individuals may perceive stressful experiences as less overwhelming or disruptive, possibly buffering them from negative psychological outcomes.</p><p>While the study provides new evidence linking real-world stress to reduced reward responsiveness, the authors acknowledge some limitations. Most notably, there was no control group of recruits who completed the same assessments but did not undergo basic training. Without such a comparison, it is not possible to definitively conclude that the observed changes were caused by the stress of training rather than other factors, such as natural brain development or repeated exposure to the task.</p><p>Additionally, while participants reported on their stress shortly after completing training, the follow-up brain assessments occurred several months later. This introduces uncertainty about the timing of changes in reward processing relative to stress exposure. The study also cannot determine whether the observed neural changes have any lasting behavioral or psychological effects. Participants were generally high-functioning and did not show elevated levels of depression or anxiety, so the long-term impact of reduced reward responsiveness remains unclear.</p><p>The study raises important questions about whether these changes are temporary or long-lasting, and whether they might predict vulnerability to future mental health problems. It also suggests that individuals who enter stressful situations with higher reward sensitivity may be more resilient, but further research is needed to explore this possibility.</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S2451902225001661">Neural Response to Reward and Loss Following Basic Combat Training</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Clara Freeman, Eric Rawls, Collin D. Teich, Scott R. Sponheim, Melissa A. Polusny, and Craig Marquardt.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:33:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/sedentary-parents-children-mirror/</link><title>The activity level of parents affects the activity level of their kids: When parents sit too much, their kids tend to follow suit. But if parents keep active, children don’t mirror the same sedentary habits. It highlights the power of parents as role models for healthier lifestyles. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/5f4932d/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F90%2Fa8%2F19527eb24ba3b345a3aa55b27d1d%2Fdepositphotos-547980888-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>When parents sit too much, their kids tend to follow suit. But if parents keep active, children don&rsquo;t mirror the same sedentary habits, a new study has shown. It highlights the power of parents as role models for healthier lifestyles.</p><p>The <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7700832/">health risks</a> associated with an <a href="https://newatlas.com/30-minutes-sedentary-mortality/51323/">inactive</a> or sedentary lifestyle are pretty well known: <a href="https://newatlas.com/disease/obesity/high-speed-internet-access-obesity/">obesity</a>, heart disease, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, and type 2 diabetes. But what if parents are inactive? Are their children likely to follow suit?</p><p>A new study led by researchers from S&atilde;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Brazil, has investigated how parents&rsquo; activity levels affect the activity levels of their kids.</p><p>&ldquo;The results indicate that parents&rsquo; level of physical activity can directly influence their children&rsquo;s habits,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s corresponding author, <a href="https://portaldocentes.unesp.br/portaldocentes/docentes/105083">Diego Christ&oacute;faro, PhD</a>, an assistant professor at UNESP. &ldquo;In other words, when parents maintain a more active routine, their children are less likely to remain seated for long periods.&rdquo;</p><p>The researchers recruited 182 young people (aged six to 17) and their parents (161 mothers, 136 fathers). Participants&rsquo; sedentary behavior and physical activity were objectively measured with accelerometers worn on the hip for seven days. Parents were categorized as &ldquo;physically active&rdquo; if they did 150 minutes or more of moderate-to-vigorous activity per week, or as &ldquo;insufficiently active&rdquo; if they didn't.</p><p>Statistical analysis was used to look at whether sedentary behavior in parents was associated with sedentary behavior in children, adjusting for age, sex, socioeconomic status, and the child&rsquo;s own activity levels. The researchers found high sedentary levels in all groups. Children, mothers, and fathers all averaged around eight to nine hours of sedentary time per day. There was a strong association between mother and child sedentary time, although no significant association when mothers were active. A modest but significant association was seen between father and child sedentary time. As with mothers, there was no association when fathers were active.</p><p>The study&rsquo;s findings suggest that the sedentary habits of children mirror their parents only when the parents are inactive. When parents are active, their kids&rsquo; sedentary behavior doesn&rsquo;t track as closely.</p><p>&ldquo;Sedentary habits are the result of multiple factors, such as lack of access, time, and places where physical activity can be practiced,&rdquo; Christofaro said. &ldquo;However, our study shows that parents&rsquo; habits can affect their children&rsquo;s health. Therefore, we believe that these results can support public policies and campaigns aimed at promoting a more active lifestyle in the family environment.&rdquo;</p><p>Because the study was cross-sectional, it only looked at one point in time, so it can&rsquo;t prove cause and effect. Additionally, families volunteered to take part, which may not represent the general population. The study was conducted in Brazil; results may differ in other cultural or social settings. And the lack of randomization in the study reduces the ability to generalize the findings widely.</p><p>Regardless of these limitations, the study suggests that kids are more likely to adopt sedentary habits if their parents are inactive. Which, in turn, suggests that active parents protect kids from sedentary behavior. So, when parents meet physical activity guidelines, this can break the &ldquo;like parent, like child&rdquo; cycle. Encouraging parents to be more physically active could be an effective strategy to reduce sedentary behavior in children and adolescents.</p><p>The study was funded, in part, by the S&atilde;o Paulo Research Foundation (FAPESP) and published in the journal <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666337625000691"><i>Sports Medicine and Health Science</i></a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Source: <a href="https://agencia.fapesp.br/study-confirms-that-inactive-parents-contribute-to-sedentary-behavior-in-their-children/55757">Ag&ecirc;ncia FAPESP</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:15:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2495132-a-single-dose-of-lsd-seems-to-reduce-anxiety/</link><title>A single dose of LSD seems to reduce anxiety (newscientist.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n8ek01/a_single_dose_of_lsd_seems_to_reduce_anxiety/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n8ek01/a_single_dose_of_lsd_seems_to_reduce_anxiety/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n8ek01/a_single_dose_of_lsd_seems_to_reduce_anxiety/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.newscientist.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/04150347/SEI_264621700.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section> <figure><figcaption><div><p>Can psychedelics help treat generalised anxiety disorder?</p><p>Science Photo Library/Alamy</p></div></figcaption></figure><p>A single dose of the psychedelic drug LSD seems to reduce anxiety without lasting side effects.</p><p>&ldquo;Ours is the first modern trial to look specifically at LSD, or any psychedelic, for generalised anxiety disorder,&rdquo; says <a href="https://mindmed.co/team/dan-karlin-md-ma/">Dan Karlin</a> at biotech company MindMed in New York.</p><p>The condition is characterised by excessive worry about a broad range of things, such as work and relationships. First-line treatment includes mood-enhancing drugs, like selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) and other antidepressants, and talking therapies.</p><p>But <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7653736/">about half of people don&rsquo;t respond</a> to such treatments. &ldquo;For a lot of people, SSRIs are not very effective, they have intolerable side effects [such as feeling emotionally numb] because people have to take them on a daily basis, and they only work while you&rsquo;re taking them,&rdquo; says Karlin.</p><p>Previous studies have suggested that LSD may be an alternative. The <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2430072-psychedelic-toxins-from-toads-could-treat-depression-and-anxiety/">psychedelic</a> is often used recreationally for its <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2416478-microdosing-lsd-increases-the-complexity-of-your-brain-signals/">mind-altering</a>, hallucinogenic effects. Karlin says it is thought to act by increasing levels of the mood-boosting chemical serotonin in the brain, which some people say induces a profound emotional experience in them. He adds that it may also <a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2494391-just-one-dose-of-psilocybin-seems-to-be-enough-to-rewire-the-brain/">enhance the brain&rsquo;s ability to rewire itself</a> and form new thought patterns.</p><p>But until now, no trial comparing people taking LSD with others taking placebo pills has explored whether the substance can benefit those with generalised anxiety disorder.</p><p>To fill this gap, Karlin and his colleagues recruited 198 adults with the condition. The participants slowly tapered off any anxiety medications they had been using, but those who were receiving psychotherapy continued with their sessions.</p><p>In a survey commonly used in clinics, the participants then rated the severity of each of 14 symptoms, such as feeling worried, tense or struggling to focus, on a scale of 0 to 4. Out of a maximum total score of 56, the participants scored 30, on average, above the threshold of 24 for severe anxiety.</p><p>Next, the team randomly split the participants into five groups that either took LSD &ndash; at various doses of 25, 50, 100 or 200 micrograms &ndash; or placebo pills, without being told which they were given. A day later, those who had received 100 and 200 microgram doses, but not the other groups, already reported an improvement in symptoms, says Karlin.</p><p>A month later, those who had received the 100 and 200 microgram doses experienced an average 21 and 19 point reduction in anxiety, respectively, with the improvement sustained until the end of the study, three months after the dosing day. About 46 per cent of these participants went into remission, which is a score of 7 or below.</p><p>Meanwhile, those taking the placebo and the two lower doses saw between a 14 and 17 point reduction in anxiety over the same period, with about 20 per cent going into remission. This suggests the lower doses provided no additional relief beyond the placebo.</p><p>The benefit seen by the two highest dose groups is a substantial improvement above the placebo, says <a href="https://profiles.ucl.ac.uk/5848-sunjeev-kamboj">Sunjeev Kamboj</a> at University College London. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s a clinically meaningful improvement in terms of impairment and distress,&rdquo; he says.</p><p>The improvement in the placebo group, a phenomenon commonly seen in anxiety trials, probably resulted from a mixture of factors, such as people feeling attended to and cared for as part of the trial, says Kamboj.</p><p>The team found that most participants could accurately guess whether they had taken LSD or the placebo. This is common with psychedelics because they have hallucinogenic side effects for many people. In all the groups, some participants&nbsp;also experienced nausea and headaches in the 12 hours after treatment.</p><p>Those on lower doses of LSD and on the placebo experienced changes in visual perception like hallucinations at far lower rates than those on the higher doses of the psychedelic. This makes it hard to tell whether the LSD-related benefits were due to a person&rsquo;s expectations based on the effects they felt or the direct effects of the drug on the brain, says Kamboj.</p><p>Despite this caveat, the study provides some of the best evidence to date that LSD could be a useful treatment for anxiety, he says. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s a very promising finding that you can get a very rapid effect in symptom reduction, that would be extremely meaningful to patients.&rdquo;</p><p>The results are promising enough that the US Food and Drug Administration has designated MindMed&rsquo;s LSD formulation as a Breakthrough Therapy, which expedites the process for drug development. Karlin says the team is carrying out larger trials that will track benefits beyond three months, with results expected in the next couple of years.</p><section><p>Topics:</p></section> </section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 21:44:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/toilet-smartphone-use-hemorrhoids/</link><title>Smartphone scrolling on toilet linked to higher hemorrhoid risk, raising risk of hemorrhoids by nearly 50%, from extra minutes spent sitting. 66% reported using phone on toilet. 37% stayed on toilet for more than 5 minutes. Most common reasons were to read news (54%) and use social media (44%). (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n85czq/smartphone_scrolling_on_toilet_linked_to_higher/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n85czq/smartphone_scrolling_on_toilet_linked_to_higher/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n85czq/smartphone_scrolling_on_toilet_linked_to_higher/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/216c52a/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F59%2F1f%2Feef8321f42eeb77f92479c407aec%2Fdepositphotos-332243026-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Scrolling on your smartphone while on the toilet may be doing more than passing the time. A new study has found it could raise your risk of hemorrhoids by nearly 50%, thanks to the extra minutes spent sitting.</p><p>Sitting on a cold surface. Eating spicy foods. Poor hygiene. Those are some of the old wives&rsquo; tales about hemorrhoids that are pure myth. However, sometimes such beliefs turn out to be backed by science.</p><p>New research led by Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center (BIDMC) in Boston has found that smartphone use while <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/automated-toilet-flushing-device-bacteria/">on the toilet</a> increases the risk of hemorrhoids.</p><p>&ldquo;Using a smartphone while on the toilet was linked to a 46% increased chance of having hemorrhoids,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s corresponding author, <a href="https://findadoc.bidmc.org/details/5679/">Trisha Pasricha, MD, MPH</a>, from BIDMC&rsquo;s Division of Gastroenterology. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re still uncovering the many ways smartphones and our modern way of life impact our health. It&rsquo;s possible that how and where we use them &ndash; such as while in the bathroom &ndash; can have unintended consequences.&rdquo;</p><p>It's probably worthwhile starting with an explanation of what hemorrhoids are. If you&rsquo;re familiar, you can skip the next couple of paragraphs.</p><p>&ldquo;We all have hemorrhoid cushions &ndash; vascular cushions made of blood vessels, connective tissue, and smooth muscle &ndash; right at the end of our GI [gastrointestinal] tract,&rdquo; Pasricha explained. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s a normal part of our body. It&rsquo;s only when they get engorged that we notice them and that&rsquo;s when they become symptomatic and they&rsquo;re called hemorrhoids.</p><p>"When they become engorged, they often bleed and become uncomfortable. The external ones are the ones that can cause itching. It can feel like there&rsquo;s a bump, it can feel like there&rsquo;s something there and they&rsquo;re difficult to clean. And then that kind of like causes this vicious cycle of like more discomfort, more irritation. The more angry they get, the more likely they are to bleed. It can really just spiral.&rdquo;</p><div><figure><div><figcaption>The most popular phone-related activities were scrolling through the news and social media</figcaption></div></figure> </div><p>For the study, the researchers recruited 125 adults aged 45 and older who were scheduled to undergo routine colonoscopies. Participants filled out surveys about demographics, physical activity, fiber intake, and bathroom habits (including smartphone use). The <a href="https://theromefoundation.org/rome-iv/rome-iv-criteria/">Rome IV</a> questionnaire was used to assess bowel function and straining. Doctors performing the colonoscopies visually confirmed whether participants had hemorrhoids.</p><p>Smartphone users were compared to non-users. Statistical methods were used to adjust for confounding factors like age, sex, body mass index (BMI), fiber intake, exercise and straining. Of all the participants, 66% reported using their phone on the toilet. Phone users spent more time sitting than non-users: 37% of users stayed on the toilet for more than five minutes per visit, compared to just 7% of non-users. The most common things people did on the toilet were read the news (54%) and use social media (44%). Smartphone users were younger and exercised less on average than non-users.</p><p>Colonoscopy confirmed that 43% of all participants had hemorrhoids. After adjusting for other risk factors, smartphone use on the toilet was linked to a 46% higher risk of hemorrhoids. Straining did <i>not</i> independently predict hemorrhoids in the phone user group, suggesting that time spent sitting is more relevant.</p><p>&ldquo;This study bolsters advice to people in general to leave the smartphones outside the bathroom and try to spend no more than a few minutes to have a bowel movement,&rdquo; said Pasricha. &ldquo;If it&rsquo;s taking longer, ask yourself why. Was it because [having] a bowel movement was really so difficult, or was it because my focus was elsewhere?</p><p>"It&rsquo;s incredibly easy to lose track of time when we&rsquo;re scrolling on our smartphones &ndash; popular apps are designed entirely for that purpose. But it&rsquo;s possible that constantly sitting longer on the toilet than you intended because you&rsquo;re distracted by your smartphone could increase your risk of hemorrhoids. We need to study this further, but it&rsquo;s a safe suggestion to leave the smartphone outside the bathroom when you need to have a bowel movement.&rdquo;</p><p>The study has drawn comment from other GI experts, such as <a href="https://profiles.auckland.ac.nz/j-dowrick">Jarrah Dowrick, PhD</a>, a research fellow with the Gastrointestinal Research Group at the Auckland Bioengineering Institute, University of Auckland.</p><p>&ldquo;From what I can see, this paper is a thinly veiled study of the relationship between time spent on the toilet and hemorrhoids, but using the catchier hook of &lsquo;phone use&rsquo; to attract wider attention,&rdquo; said Dowrick. &ldquo;While the reality of modern screen addiction does make the smartphone narrative more compelling, the real story here is that spending longer on a seated toilet appears to be linked with hemorrhoid presentation.</p><p>&ldquo;This is still an important finding. There is a surprising lack of evidence for commonly believed hemorrhoid risk factors like low fiber intake, straining, constipation, age, sex differences, pregnancy, and time on the toilet. Studies like this one are vital to empower clinicians to make evidence-based recommendations to patients. Phone or no, this study suggests limiting each visit to the toilet to five minutes where possible.&rdquo;</p><p>There are some key limitations to the study. Its cross-sectional design means it can show associations but not prove cause and effect. Additionally, because participants&rsquo; behavior was self-reported, time spent on the toilet and straining could be affected by recall bias. And, the participants were over 45 undergoing colonoscopies, so results may not reflect younger populations or the general public. Finally, the study didn&rsquo;t measure how many years people had been using phones on the toilet.</p><p>Nonetheless, the study has real-world implications. Its findings suggest that it&rsquo;s not so much straining but prolonged sitting without pelvic support that raises hemorrhoid risk. So, medical professionals might want to recommend limiting toilet sessions &ndash;especially with phone &ndash; to five minutes or less.</p><p>Larger, long-term future studies could track whether years of toilet-phone use worsen hemorrhoid rates, and behavioral interventions such as timers might help reduce sitting time.</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0329983&amp;utm_source=pr&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=plos006"><i>PLOS One</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.bidmc.org/about-bidmc/news/2025/09/how-smartphones-may-increase-hemorrhoid-risk">BIDMC in Boston</a>, <a href="https://www.scimex.org/newsfeed/scrolling-on-the-toilet-linked-to-haemorrhoids">Scimex</a></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/ea0aa0c/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1333+0+0/resize/1440x960!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fb7%2F06%2F0573537247c887347faadbde0a8f%2Fviralyft-nq7y-rauzdy-unsplash.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 14:50:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/common-artificial-sweeteners-linked-to-cognitive-decline-in-large-study/</link><title>People who consumed higher amounts of artificial sweeteners (aspartame, saccharin, erythritol, xylitol, sorbitol) showed steeper drops in verbal fluency, memory, and cognitive function over 8 years. This link was stronger in people with diabetes but also observed with people without it. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7r2xd/people_who_consumed_higher_amounts_of_artificial/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7r2xd/people_who_consumed_higher_amounts_of_artificial/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7r2xd/people_who_consumed_higher_amounts_of_artificial/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/sweetener.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in the journal <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000214023">Neurology</a></em> provides evidence that regular consumption of certain artificial and low-calorie sweeteners may be linked to a faster decline in memory and other cognitive abilities over time. Using data from more than 12,000 middle-aged and older adults in Brazil, researchers found that individuals who consumed higher amounts of these sweeteners tended to show steeper drops in verbal fluency, memory, and overall cognitive function over an eight-year period. The association appeared stronger in people with diabetes but was also observed among participants without the condition.</p><p>With global dementia cases projected to triple by 2050, researchers are increasingly focused on identifying lifestyle factors that might influence cognitive aging. While sugary diets have been linked to poorer brain health, many individuals have shifted toward low- and no-calorie sweeteners as perceived healthier alternatives. These sweeteners&mdash;commonly found in diet beverages, yogurts, protein bars, and tabletop products&mdash;include aspartame, saccharin, acesulfame potassium, and sugar alcohols like erythritol and xylitol.</p><p>Despite their widespread use, concerns have grown around their potential health effects. Prior studies have linked artificial sweeteners to higher risks of diabetes, cardiovascular problems, and depression, even when consumed within official safety limits. Some research has also suggested a potential connection between these sweeteners and dementia or poor memory, but evidence from large-scale, long-term studies has been lacking. The current study was designed to address this gap.</p><p>The research drew on data from the Brazilian Longitudinal Study of Adult Health (ELSA-Brasil), a multicenter cohort that began in 2008 and enrolled over 15,000 public employees aged 35 and older from six cities across Brazil. After excluding individuals with incomplete dietary data or extreme reported calorie intake, the final sample included 12,772 adults, with an average age of 52 at baseline. Participants were followed over three waves of assessment: 2008&ndash;2010, 2012&ndash;2014, and 2017&ndash;2019&mdash;a span of approximately eight years.</p><p>At the start of the study, participants completed a detailed food frequency questionnaire that asked about their diet over the past year. This allowed researchers to estimate the intake of seven specific low- and no-calorie sweeteners: aspartame, saccharin, acesulfame potassium, erythritol, xylitol, sorbitol, and tagatose.</p><p>Based on total daily intake, participants were divided into three consumption groups. The lowest group averaged 20 milligrams per day, while the highest group averaged 191 milligrams per day&mdash;an amount equivalent to the aspartame content of one can of diet soda. Among all sweeteners, sorbitol was consumed in the highest quantity, with an average intake of 64 milligrams per day.</p><p>Cognitive performance was assessed at the start, middle, and end of the follow-up period. The battery of tests included measures of verbal fluency, working memory, word recall, and processing speed, enabling researchers to track changes in memory, language, and general thinking skills. These scores were standardized to allow comparison across waves and participants.</p><p>After statistically adjusting for a wide range of factors&mdash;including age, sex, income, physical activity, blood pressure, cardiovascular disease, body mass index, and diet quality&mdash;the researchers found that individuals in the highest tertile of sweetener consumption showed a 62% faster decline in global cognitive scores than those in the lowest group. This translated to an estimated 1.6 additional years of cognitive aging over the eight-year period. Participants in the middle group experienced a 35% faster decline, equivalent to about 1.3 extra years of aging.</p><p>The association between sweetener intake and cognitive decline was strongest in adults under the age of 60. In this group, higher consumption was linked to steeper losses in verbal fluency and overall cognition. Among those aged 60 and older, the study did not find a significant association between sweetener intake and cognitive performance. The researchers also found that the relationship between sweetener use and cognitive decline was stronger in individuals with diabetes compared to those without.</p><p>When each sweetener was analyzed separately, consumption of aspartame, saccharin, acesulfame potassium, erythritol, xylitol, and sorbitol was associated with faster decline in global cognition, especially in memory and verbal fluency. In contrast, tagatose&mdash;a naturally occurring sugar found in some dairy products and fruits&mdash;was not associated with cognitive decline.</p><p>Notably, the trend held even when looking at the frequency of consumption, rather than the exact quantity. Participants who consumed any type of low- or no-calorie sweetener on a daily basis showed a significantly faster decline in memory, language, and overall cognitive function compared to those who consumed sweeteners only occasionally or not at all.</p><p>&ldquo;Low- and no-calorie sweeteners are often seen as a healthy alternative to sugar, however our findings suggest certain sweeteners may have negative effects on brain health over time,&rdquo; explained Claudia Kimie Suemoto of the University of S&atilde;o Paulo, the senior author of the study.</p><p>Although the study was large and followed participants over several years, the researchers caution against drawing firm conclusions about cause and effect. The study relied on self-reported dietary data collected only at the beginning of the study, which may not capture long-term changes in diet. People with certain health conditions, such as diabetes or obesity, may also be more likely to consume artificial sweeteners in place of sugar, raising the possibility that underlying health issues, rather than the sweeteners themselves, contributed to cognitive decline.</p><p>In addition, while the researchers adjusted for a wide range of demographic, clinical, and lifestyle factors, unmeasured variables could still play a role. The study also lacked brain imaging or biological markers that could offer clues about how these sweeteners might affect brain structure or function.</p><p>Despite these caveats, the new findings add to a growing body of research raising concerns about the long-term safety of common sugar substitutes. Recent laboratory studies have suggested that erythritol, a sugar alcohol frequently used in low-carbohydrate and ketogenic products, <a href="https://www.psypost.org/popular-sugar-substitute-erythritol-may-impair-brain-blood-vessel-health-study-finds/">may impair the function of blood vessels in the brain</a>. In one in vitro study, erythritol increased oxidative stress and reduced nitric oxide production in human endothelial cells, potentially disrupting blood flow and increasing the risk of stroke.</p><p>Epidemiological studies have also linked elevated levels of erythritol in the blood to higher risks of heart attacks and strokes, while clinical trials have reported increased platelet reactivity following erythritol intake&mdash;another possible contributor to clot formation.</p><p>Sucralose, another widely used sweetener, <a href="https://www.psypost.org/a-common-calorie-free-sweetener-alters-brain-activity-and-appetite-control-new-research-suggests/">has been implicated in altered brain activity</a> related to hunger and reward. A recent brain imaging study found that sucralose increased activity in the hypothalamus, a region involved in appetite regulation, and heightened connectivity with brain areas involved in motivation and sensory processing. These effects varied depending on sex and body weight, with women and individuals with obesity showing stronger responses. Such findings suggest that sucralose may disrupt the brain&rsquo;s normal signaling related to satiety, potentially contributing to overeating or altered eating behavior over time.</p><p>While these studies do not focus directly on cognition, they raise broader concerns about how artificial sweeteners may influence brain health through vascular, metabolic, and neural pathways&mdash;concerns that align with the new findings from Brazil.</p><p>In <a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000214129">an accompanying editorial</a> published in <em>Neurology</em>, Rush University physician scientist Thomas M. Holland wrote that these findings pose &ldquo;a fundamental question&rdquo; to the medical community. &ldquo;In our efforts to prevent stroke and preserve cognition through dietary modification, are we inadvertently recommending substances that may accelerate the very cognitive decline we seek to prevent?&rdquo;</p><p>The new study, according to Holland, has &ldquo;provided neurologists, and the broader medical community, caring for cognitively at-risk populations, with critical evidence that dietary counseling must extend beyond traditional cardiovascular risk reduction to address the potential cognitive effects of food additives, particularly artificial sweeteners. Supporting long-term brain health requires a proactive, integrated approach, optimizing diet, movement, sleep, stress, cognitive stimulation, and social connection to build cognitive resilience over time.&rdquo;</p><p>Given the widespread consumption of artificial sweeteners, especially among people seeking to manage weight or blood sugar, researchers emphasize the need for more longitudinal and experimental studies to clarify their potential effects on the brain. Future research should include repeated dietary assessments over time, neuroimaging to detect changes in brain structure, and biomarkers of inflammation and neurotoxicity.</p><p>There is also a need to examine whether certain populations&mdash;such as people with diabetes, metabolic syndrome, or low insulin sensitivity&mdash;are more vulnerable to the potential harms of artificial sweeteners. In addition, researchers should compare the cognitive effects of natural sweeteners like tagatose, stevia, or monk fruit to those of synthetic ones.</p><p>&ldquo;While we found links to cognitive decline for middle-aged people both with and without diabetes, people with diabetes are more likely to use artificial sweeteners as sugar substitutes,&rdquo; said Suemoto. &ldquo;More research is needed to confirm our findings and to investigate if other refined sugar alternatives, such as applesauce, honey, maple syrup or coconut sugar, may be effective alternatives.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000214023">Association Between Consumption of Low- and No-Calorie Artificial Sweeteners and Cognitive Decline: An 8-Year Prospective Study</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Natalia Gomes Gon&ccedil;alves, Euridice Martinez-Steele, Paulo A. Lotufo, Isabela Bensenor, Alessandra C. Goulart, Sandhi Maria Barreto, Luana Giatti, Carolina Perim de Faria, Maria del Carmen Bisi Molina, Paulo Caramelli, Dirce Maria Marchioni, and Claudia Kimie Suemoto.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 02:39:22 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.eurekalert.org/news-releases/1096727</link><title>American small business owners are more likely to identify with and vote for right-wing parties. People who inherited a business are more right-leaning. People without college degrees but who earn higher-than-median incomes are more likely to identify with the Republican Party and vote for Trump. (eurekalert.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7aw71/american_small_business_owners_are_more_likely_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7aw71/american_small_business_owners_are_more_likely_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n7aw71/american_small_business_owners_are_more_likely_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.eurekalert.org/images/EurekAlert-bluebg_Twitter_601X601.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Small business owners are more likely to identify with and vote for right-wing parties, a new study in the<em> <a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/british-journal-of-political-science/article/politics-of-small-business-owners/492835B42B70C24F6613B352E4C3B83E?utm_date=20250718&amp;utm_id=1752827467&amp;utm_campaign=JPS#article">British Journal of Political Science</a>,</em> published by Cambridge University Press reveals. The research suggests it is the experience of being a small business owner that leads people to adopt conservative views on government regulation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>The study, which analysed the political leanings of small business owners in the United States, also found that current business owners, but not past owners of businesses, vote more to the right than people who never owned a business; that people who inherited a business, more than those who started a new business, are more right-leaning; and that even within a narrow professional subset such as physicians with their own practices, business ownership aligns with a disproportionate right lean.&nbsp;</p><p>Neil Malhotra, Professor of Political Economy in the Graduate School of Business at Stanford University, said the findings indicate that the <strong>appeal of right-wing parties derives from experiences associated with running a business, rather than from background characteristics that lead people to open or run a business</strong>.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;The heightened need to deal with the regulatory state especially can lead small business owners to lean further to the right,&rdquo; said Malhotra.&nbsp;</p><p>The study used a wide range of data sources: an original, first-of-its-kind bespoke survey of small business owners based on a unique administrative sampling frame of the recipients of the US Paycheck Protection Program; a comparable survey of a general sample of the US adult population; a cross-national survey data; and data on the partisan registration and donations of a targeted set of occupations.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>The gig economy could benefit right-wing parties&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p><p>Malhotra highlighted how the gig economy is familiarising more people with the pressures experienced by small business owners.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;As the labour market veers toward gig platforms and gig jobs, more people will become, in many ways, a new form of small business owners: they will have no boss and enjoy more flexibility in their work schedules, while also experiencing the burden of heightened responsibility for key aspects of work as compared to waged staff,&rdquo; said Malhotra.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;At the same time, gig workers face economic precarity and instability. As a growing number of people have daily experiences akin to those of a business owner, it will be interesting to see if parties and candidates on the right are likely to benefit, or if this is an opportunity for the left to build the social safety net.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p><strong>The politics of wealthy small business owners&nbsp;</strong></p><p>The study found that small business owners are significantly overrepresented among individuals without college degrees but who earn higher-than-median incomes &ndash; also known as &lsquo;High Income Low Education&rsquo;, or HILEs. Indeed, one of the main ways a person can make a high income without a college degree is by running a successful small business.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>HILEs comprise approximately 20.2 percent of Americans that are not small business owners. This figure, however, is substantially higher among small business owners: 33.1 percent of employer small business owners and 26.6 percent of non-employer small business owners fall into this category&nbsp;</p><p>The study found that 59.2 percent of HILEs identify with the Republican Party, and 50.3 per cent would vote for Trump. Among other respondents, these figures are 47.6 percent and 36.2 percent respectively.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Political differences by sector&nbsp;</strong></p><p>The study also found that many of the small business owner occupation types that are Democratic-leaning are creative functions done mainly by sole proprietors &ndash; for example, therapy, massage, and graphic design. On the other hand, Republican-leaning small business owners are more involved in complex industries such as construction, healthcare, and manufacturing, which have more of an interface with regulations involving labour laws, health and safety, and compliance.&nbsp;</p><hr> <hr><div><div><h4>Journal</h4><p>British Journal of Political Science</p></div><div><h4>Method of Research</h4><p>Survey</p></div><div><h4>Subject of Research</h4><p>People</p></div><div><h4>Article Title</h4><p>The Politics of Small Business Owners</p></div><div><h4>Article Publication Date</h4><p>18-Jul-2025</p></div></div></div><p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> AAAS and EurekAlert! are not responsible for the accuracy of news releases posted to EurekAlert! by contributing institutions or for the use of any information through the EurekAlert system.</p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:44:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S3050474025000205?via%3Dihub#sec5</link><title>Research on children with autism using a prepared vitamin D3-loaded nanoemulsion has led to a reduction in the severity of autism and a rise in the social IQ, especially fine motor performance and language abilities of the children with ASD, without adverse effects (sciencedirect.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n79mdx/research_on_children_with_autism_using_a_prepared/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n79mdx/research_on_children_with_autism_using_a_prepared/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n79mdx/research_on_children_with_autism_using_a_prepared/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S3050474025X00033-cov150h.gif' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-content"><span><span>Skip to main content</span></span></a><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-title"><span><span>Skip to article</span></span></a></p><header></header><div><article><div><p><span>Under a Creative Commons </span><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/"><span><span>license</span></span></a></p><p>Open access</p></div><div><h2>Abstract</h2><div><h3>Objective</h3><p>Children with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) had lower vitamin D3 levels than neurotypical (NT) children, as well as deficits in language, social, and fine motor abilities. Nanotechnology has appeared as a suitable answer to absorption and bioavailability problems related to vitamin D3. This study aims to investigate the influence of vitamin D3-loaded nanoemulsion supplementation on adaptive behavior and language performance in children with ASD compared to the influence of the marketed product of vitamin D3.</p></div><div><h3>Methods</h3><p>Supplementation of ASD children with an oral vitamin D3-loaded nanoemulsion was performed in group I while the marketed product of the oral vitamin D3 was used in group II for 6 months. Evaluation of their abilities and measuring the plasma levels of 2 types of vitamin D3 were performed using ultra-performance liquid chromatography before and after supplementation.</p></div><div><h3>Results</h3><p>Supplementation in group I (<em>n</em> &#8203;= &#8203;40) has led to an elevation of levels of 25 (OH) and 1, 25 (OH)<sub>2</sub> forms of vitamin D3 (<em>P</em> &#8203;&lt; &#8203;0.000,1), to behavioral improvement in the form of a reduction in ASD severity, and to a rise in the social IQ and total language age of ASD children (<em>P</em> &#8203;= &#8203;0.000,2, 0.04, 0.000,9, respectively). On the other hand, group II (<em>n</em> &#8203;= &#8203;40) did not show adaptive behavioral improvements.</p></div><div><h3>Conclusions</h3><p>The vitamin D3-loaded nanoemulsion provided better vitamin D3 bioavailability and a true influence on severity, adaptive behavior, fine motor abilities, and language performance, reflecting the desired benefits of the rise of vitamin D3 levels in the blood.</p></div></div><ul><li><li></ul><div><h2>Keywords</h2><p><span>Autism spectrum disorder (ASD)</span></p><p><span>Vitamin D3</span></p><p><span>Nanoemulsion</span></p><p><span>Core manifestation</span></p><p><span>Language performance</span></p><p><span>Ultra-performance liquid chromatography (UPLC)</span></p></div><section><header><h2>Cited by (0)</h2></header></section><p><span>&copy; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. on behalf of Ruijin Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine.</span></p></article></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 14:23:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://academic.oup.com/pnasnexus/article/4/9/pgaf253/8245251</link><title>Donald Trump's criminal prosecution in 2024 had strikingly limited effects on public opinion. It did caused sharp backlash against the prosecutor among Trump supporters. When citizens hold strong prior beliefs about an accused leader, prosecutions have strikingly limited effects on public opinion. (academic.oup.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n6vxqh/donald_trumps_criminal_prosecution_in_2024_had/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n6vxqh/donald_trumps_criminal_prosecution_in_2024_had/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n6vxqh/donald_trumps_criminal_prosecution_in_2024_had/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 02:48:27 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/older-obese-individuals-have-a-lower-risk-of-dementia-but-there-is-a-big-caveat/</link><title>Overweight people had a 14% lower risk of developing dementia compared to those with normal weight, while obese participants had a 19% lower risk. However, those who lost weight from midlife to late life had an increased risk of dementia. This is the so-called obesity paradox. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n6kgeb/overweight_people_had_a_14_lower_risk_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n6kgeb/overweight_people_had_a_14_lower_risk_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n6kgeb/overweight_people_had_a_14_lower_risk_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/obese-overweight-man-fat-measurement.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A longitudinal study of more than 5,000 older adults revealed that individuals classified as overweight had a 14% lower risk of developing dementia compared to those with normal weight, while obese participants had a 19% lower risk. However, further analysis indicated that individuals who lost weight from midlife to late life had an <em>increased</em> risk of dementia. Those whose weight remained stable had the lowest risk. The paper was published in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000213534"><em>Neurology</em></a>.</p><p>Late-life dementia refers to dementia that develops in older adulthood, typically after the age of 65. It is most often caused by Alzheimer&rsquo;s disease, but vascular dementia, Lewy body dementia, and mixed forms are also common in later life. Risk increases sharply with age, with prevalence doubling approximately every five years after age 65.</p><p>Symptoms typically begin with mild memory loss and confusion and gradually progress to impaired judgment, disorientation, language difficulties, and loss of independence. Age-related changes in blood vessels, the accumulation of abnormal proteins in the brain, and other chronic conditions contribute to its onset. Midlife risk factors such as hypertension, diabetes, and obesity are important predictors of late-life dementia. Lifestyle factors such as physical activity, cognitive engagement, and social connectedness may delay or reduce risk.</p><p>Study author Ethan J. Cannon and his colleagues noted that obesity in midlife is a known risk factor for dementia. However, studies indicate that obesity in late life is associated with a lower risk. The researchers sought to better investigate this paradox and identify the factors that might explain it. They particularly focused on changes in body weight between midlife and late life. The authors hypothesized that individuals who lost weight during this period would be at increased risk of dementia, even more so than normal-weight individuals who maintained a stable weight.</p><p>They analyzed data from the Atherosclerosis Risk in Communities (ARIC) study, a longitudinal project conducted at four U.S. sites: suburban Minneapolis, MN; Jackson, MS; Forsyth County, NC; and Washington County, MD. From 1987 to 1989, the study enrolled a total of 15,792 participants. Multiple follow-up visits occurred through 2020. For the present analysis, 5,129 participants who remained dementia-free at Visit 5 (2011&ndash;2013) were included. At enrollment, participants were 45&ndash;64 years old. At Visit 5, the average age was approximately 75 years.</p><p>The researchers used data on participants&rsquo; body weight and BMI collected at two key timepoints&mdash;midlife (1996&ndash;1998) and late life (2011&ndash;2013)&mdash;and linked it to dementia diagnoses through a combination of in-person neuropsychological testing, structured telephone interviews, hospital discharge records, and death certificates.</p><p>They first examined whether BMI in late life alone predicted future dementia risk. Consistent with previous studies, individuals classified as overweight or obese in 2011&ndash;2013 were less likely to develop dementia in the years that followed. Specifically, those who were overweight had a 14% lower risk, and those who were obese had a 19% lower risk than normal-weight individuals.</p><p>However, when the researchers accounted for weight change from midlife to late life, the pattern shifted. Participants who maintained a normal weight over this 15-year period had the lowest risk of dementia. In contrast, individuals who lost at least 2 kg/m&sup2; in BMI during this period were at elevated risk&mdash;regardless of their BMI category in late life.</p><p>Compared to normal-weight individuals who remained weight stable, the hazard of developing dementia was, 2.22 times higher for those who lost weight but remained normal weight in late life, 1.78 times higher for those who lost weight and were overweight in late life, and 1.80 times higher for those who lost weight and were obese in late life.</p><p>Even individuals who gained weight and were classified as obese in late life had a slightly increased dementia risk&mdash;about 29% higher than the reference group. However, after adjusting for factors such as smoking, alcohol use, depressive symptoms, frailty, hypertension, and diabetes, this association was weakened.</p><p>For example, after full statistical adjustment overweight individuals who had lost weight from midlife to late life had a 53% higher risk of dementia, while normal-weight individuals who had lost weight had a 2.05-fold increased risk.</p><p>Meanwhile, overweight and obese individuals whose weight remained stable&mdash;or increased&mdash;did not differ significantly in dementia risk from the reference group of weight-stable, normal-weight individuals.</p><p>&ldquo;In this study of older adults (mean age 75 years), we found that overweight or obesity in late life was associated with a lower risk of dementia, but that when stratified by weight change history, this result was explained in part by a disproportionate number of low-BMI [body mass index] participants who had experienced weight loss,&rdquo; the study authors wrote. &ldquo;Regardless of late-life BMI category, weight loss from midlife to late life was associated with a higher risk of dementia, compared with being normal weight in late life and weight stable from midlife to late life.&rdquo;</p><p>The findings suggest that the so-called obesity paradox may be at least partly explained by unintentional weight loss associated with underlying health decline. The study could not determine whether weight loss was intentional or unintentional. Unintentional weight loss is common in older adults and is often a sign of deteriorating health. In such cases, both weight loss and cognitive deterioration can be the consequence of a decline in physical health.</p><p>Additionally, it is important to note that the design of the study does not allow any causal inferences to be derived from the results. That is, higher weight in late life should not be interpreted as protective <em>per se</em>, nor should normal weight be viewed as inherently risky. Rather, trajectories of weight change may serve as an important signal for dementia risk assessment.</p><p>The paper, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000213534">Association of Body Mass Index in Late Life, and Change from Midlife to Late Life, With Incident Dementia in the ARIC Study Participants</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Ethan J. Cannon, B. Gwen Windham, Michael Griswold, Priya Palta, David S. Knopman, Sanaz Sedaghat, and Pamela L. Lutsey.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 19:37:01 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
