<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:51:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://thewire.in/communalism/muslim-teens-suicide-spotlights-gujarats-controversial-disturbed-areas-act</link><title>Muslim Teen's Suicide Spotlights Gujarat's Controversial Disturbed Areas Act (thewire.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nicpd0/muslim_teens_suicide_spotlights_gujarats/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nicpd0/muslim_teens_suicide_spotlights_gujarats/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nicpd0/muslim_teens_suicide_spotlights_gujarats/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cms.thewire.in/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/WhatsApp-Image-2025-09-02-at-15.07.06-1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:55:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businesstoday.in/india/story/mugging-up-random-trivia-for-500-seats-founder-slams-upsc-iit-system-for-killing-talent-494110-2025-09-16</link><title>'Mugging up random trivia for 500 seats': Founder slams UPSC, IIT system for killing talent (businesstoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni90np/mugging_up_random_trivia_for_500_seats_founder/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni90np/mugging_up_random_trivia_for_500_seats_founder/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni90np/mugging_up_random_trivia_for_500_seats_founder/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><h2>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not just unfair. It&rsquo;s stupid. It&rsquo;s destructive,&rdquo; Suhag concludes. &ldquo;India kills its own talent before the world even gets to see it.&rdquo; </h2><div><p><img width="948" height="533" title="'Mugging up random trivia for 500 seats': Founder slams UPSC, IIT system for killing talent" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/businesstoday/images/story/202509/68c8c6893545c-his-post-strikes-a-chord-in-a-country-where-education-is-often-the-only-perceived-route-to-successb-160803429-16x9.jpg?size=948:533" alt="'Mugging up random trivia for 500 seats': Founder slams UPSC, IIT system for killing talent"><span>His post strikes a chord in a country where education is often the only perceived route to success&mdash;but the process itself, he warns, is turning ambition into disillusionment.</span></p></div><div><div><div><p>India is quietly bleeding talent&mdash;not through brain drain, but through its own brutal entrance test obsession, says startup founder Akhil Suhag in a LinkedIn post.</p><p>His critique? A system that filters future engineers through chemistry papers, shoves coders into textile degrees, and rewards memorization over mastery.</p></div><p>&ldquo;A 13-year-old obsessed with coding wants to be the best in the world,&rdquo; Suhag writes. &ldquo;What does the system do? It forces him to waste 4&ndash;5 years memorizing chemistry and physics just to get into IIT/NIT.&rdquo;</p><div><h4>Related Articles</h4></div><p>Even if they clear the entrance exams, Suhag says students are often assigned random branches&mdash;Textile, Mining, Metallurgy&mdash;not because of aptitude, but because their rank wasn't &ldquo;high enough.&rdquo; This, he argues, derails not only individual potential but the country&rsquo;s long-term innovation pipeline.</p><p>In his post, Suhag dismantles the deeply entrenched belief that elite college tags are the only markers of intelligence. &ldquo;We test how good a computer engineer one can be based on his chemistry skills,&rdquo; he writes, adding that fever, anxiety, or one bad day can derail an entire career trajectory.</p><p>He also points out the ripple effect on career pivots like MBA admissions: &ldquo;Your college determines your first job, your first job determines your MBA profile.&rdquo; In a system where where you studied overshadows what or how well you learned, Suhag says the odds are stacked against even the brightest minds.</p><p>His criticism extends to the UPSC exam, India&rsquo;s gateway to its most prestigious civil services. &ldquo;Hundreds of thousands of brilliant young people waste their prime years mugging up random trivia for 500 seats,&rdquo; he writes. &ldquo;Even the army does psychological testing&mdash;not UPSC.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not just unfair. It&rsquo;s stupid. It&rsquo;s destructive,&rdquo; Suhag concludes. &ldquo;India kills its own talent before the world even gets to see it.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p><span>Published on: Sep 16, 2025 7:38 AM IST</span> </p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:00:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://share.google/fkja23REA66xFGrC6</link><title>India brags about having 1.4 billion people but won't buy one bushel of U.S. corn: Lutnick - The Hindu (share.google)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni8ahd/india_brags_about_having_14_billion_people_but/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni8ahd/india_brags_about_having_14_billion_people_but/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni8ahd/india_brags_about_having_14_billion_people_but/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/26z95g/article70049800.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-09-11T160336Z_1151754268_RC2QPGA4SITS_RTRMADP_3_USA-STOCKS.JPG' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>U.S. Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick. File. | Photo Credit: Reuters </p></div><div><div><p>India brags about having 1.4 billion people but won&rsquo;t buy even a small amount of American corn, United States Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick has said, asserting that New Delhi must bring down its tariffs or face a &ldquo;tough time&rdquo; doing business with the U.S.</p><p>Mr. Lutnick made the comments during an interview on Saturday (September 13, 2025) when he was asked whether the U.S. is mismanaging &ldquo;very valuable relationships&rdquo; with &ldquo;important allies&rdquo; like India, Canada and Brazil with the tariffs imposed on these countries.</p><p><strong> Editorial |<a href="https://www.thehindu.com/opinion/editorial/doublespeak-on-the-trump-administrations-actions-and-india/article70042525.ece"> &#8203;Doublespeak: On the Trump administration&rsquo;s actions and India &nbsp;</a></strong></p><p>&ldquo;The relationship is one way, they sell to us and take advantage of us. They block us from their economy, and they sell to us while we are wide open for them to come in [and] take advantage,&rdquo; Mr. Lutnick said. &ldquo;The president says, &lsquo;fair and reciprocal trade&rsquo;,&rdquo; he added.</p><p>&ldquo;India brags that they have 1.4 billion people. Why won't 1.4 billion people buy one bushel of U.S. corn? Doesn't that rub you the wrong way that they sell everything to us and they won't buy our corn. They put tariffs on everything,&rdquo; Mr. Lutnick said.</p><h4>&lsquo;President's model&rsquo;</h4><p>He added that President Donald Trump has said &ldquo;&lsquo;bring down your tariffs, treat us the way we treat you&rsquo;&rdquo;. The Commerce Secretary further added &ldquo;we&rsquo;ve got to right years of wrong so we want a tariff going the other way until we fix this&rdquo;.</p><p>&ldquo;That's the President's model, and you either accept it or you're going to have a tough time doing business with the world's greatest consumer,&rdquo; Mr. Lutnick said.</p><p>The Trump administration has imposed 50% tariffs on India, including 25% for Delhi&rsquo;s purchases of Russian oil, among the highest imposed on any country in the world.</p><p>India has described the U.S. action as &ldquo;unfair, unjustified and unreasonable&rdquo;. Defending its purchase of Russian crude oil, India has been maintaining that its energy procurement is driven by national interest and market dynamics.</p></div><p>Published <span>- September 14, 2025 08:39 pm IST</span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:19:18 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/delhi-woman-driving-bmw-that-killed-senior-finance-ministry-official-taken-into-cutody/articleshow/123896440.cms</link><title>Delhi woman driving BMW that killed senior Finance ministry official taken into cutody (economictimes.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhm2bv/delhi_woman_driving_bmw_that_killed_senior/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhm2bv/delhi_woman_driving_bmw_that_killed_senior/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhm2bv/delhi_woman_driving_bmw_that_killed_senior/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-123896446,width-1200,height-630,imgsize-2310386,overlay-economictimes/articleshow.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A day after a senior <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/topic/finance-ministry-official">Finance Ministry official</a> was killed when a <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/bmw-india">BMW</a> hit his motorcycle in the Delhi Cantonment area, an ANI report on Monday said that the woman driving the car, Gagandeep Kaur (38), has been taken into custody.</p><p>Police earlier today registered a case of culpable homicide. </p><p>Deputy Secretary in the Department of Economic Affairs, Navjot Singh (52), a resident of Hari Nagar, was killed in the accident on Sunday afternoon, while his wife sustained serious injuries.</p><br><p>The couple was returning home after visiting the Bangla Sahib Gurdwara.</p><p>The BMW, which was being driven by a woman with her husband by her side, who were also injured in the incident. According to police, the couple, residents of Gurugram, are in the business of manufacturing leather saddles, seats, covers, belts and other products.</p><p>They have been admitted to a hospital and their statements are yet to be recorded, police said.</p><p>According to a Delhi Police official, the case has been registered under Bharatiya Nyaya Sanhita sections sections 281 (rash driving or riding on a public way), 125B (acts endangering life or personal safety of others), 105 (culpable homicide not amounting to murder) and 238 (causing disappearance of evidence of offence, or giving false information to screen offender).</p><p>Police said the BMW and the motorcycle have been seized. The accident spot was examined by the crime team and forensic experts.</p><p>Further investigation into the case is underway, police said.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:06:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/asia-cup/handshake-row-takes-ugly-turn-as-pakistan-threaten-to-withdraw-from-asia-cup-2025/articleshow/123900093.cms</link><title>Handshake row takes ugly turn as Pakistan threatens to withdraw from Asia Cup 2025 (timesofindia.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhjg5u/handshake_row_takes_ugly_turn_as_pakistan/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhjg5u/handshake_row_takes_ugly_turn_as_pakistan/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhjg5u/handshake_row_takes_ugly_turn_as_pakistan/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123900299,width-1070,height-580,imgsize-54072,resizemode-75,overlay-toi_sw,pt-32,y_pad-40/photo.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><section><div><p><span title="India vs Pakistan (AP Photo) ">India vs Pakistan (AP Photo) </span></p></div></section><p><span>TimesofIndia.com in Dubai:</span> Pakistan are highly likely to withdraw from the remaining matches of the Asia Cup if match referee <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/andy-pycroft">Andy Pycroft</a> is not removed from the tournament&rsquo;s panel, PCB Chairman Mohsin Naqvi has warned.TimesofIndia.com understands that the latest warning of withdrawal is the result of the controversy over the missing handshakes in the high-voltage Asia Cup clash between India and Pakistan on Sunday evening. <span></span>The situation has escalated into a full-blown row, with the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) formally lodging a complaint with the International Cricket Council (ICC). </p><div><p>Suryakumar Yadav statement on Pahalgam to handshake drama: How India HUMILIATED Pakistan</p></div><p><span></span>Naqvi confirmed on Monday that the board has demanded &ldquo;an immediate removal of the Match Referee from the Asia Cup&rdquo; over alleged violations of the ICC Code of Conduct and MCC Laws pertaining to the Spirit of Cricket.&ldquo;The PCB has lodged a complaint with the ICC regarding violations by the Match Referee of the ICC Code of Conduct and the MCC Laws pertaining to the Spirit of Cricket. The PCB has demanded an immediate removal of the Match Referee from the Asia Cup,&rdquo; Naqvi posted on X.<span></span>The flashpoint occurred at the Dubai International Cricket Stadium during the toss when Pakistan captain Salman Ali Agha and Indian skipper <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/suryakumar-yadav">Suryakumar Yadav</a> avoided the customary handshake. According to the PCB, Pycroft had specifically instructed Salman to refrain from shaking hands.</p><p>&ldquo;The match referee Andy Pycroft had asked captain Salman Ali Agha, at the time of the toss, not to shake hands with his Indian counterpart. The Pakistan team management has lodged a protest, calling the behaviour against the spirit of sports,&rdquo; the board said.<span></span>The situation worsened after India&rsquo;s emphatic seven-wicket win, when Suryakumar shook hands only with batting partner Shivam Dube and walked off without acknowledging the Pakistani players. </p><p>Pakistan coach Mike Hesson voiced his disappointment.&ldquo;Obviously, we were ready to shake hands at the end of the game. We were disappointed that our opposition didn't do that. We sort of went over there to shake hands and they were already going to the changing room. That was a disappointing way for the match to end. In a match where we were already disappointed with the way we played, we were at least willing to go and shake hands,&rdquo; Hesson said.<span></span></p><div><p>PCB Chairman Mohsin Naqvi's social media posts </p></div><p>In protest, captain Salman Ali Agha skipped the post-match presentation ceremony.<span></span>Suryakumar, however, stood firm, linking the gesture to India&rsquo;s solidarity with the victims of the <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/pahalgam-terror-attack">Pahalgam terror attack</a> and the armed forces.&ldquo;Perfect occasion, taking the time out, we stand by the victims and families of the Pahalgam terror attack. We express our solidarity. I want to dedicate the win to all our armed forces who showed a lot of bravery,&rdquo; he said.<span></span>&ldquo;I feel a few things in life are ahead of sportsmanship. I said at the presentation as well that we stand with all the victims of the Pahalgam terror attack. And we stand with their families too, expressing our solidarity. Also, as I said at the post-match presentation, we dedicate this win to our brave armed forces who took part in Operation Sindoor.&rdquo;The PCB&rsquo;s complaint now sits at the ICC headquarters chaired by Jay Shah, creating fresh diplomatic and sporting tensions between the two rivals. </p><p>The board&rsquo;s stance has been further hardened by the fact that Pycroft is also listed as the referee for Pakistan&rsquo;s next match against UAE on Wednesday.<span></span>&ldquo;There is nothing more important to me than the honour and prestige of my country,&rdquo; Naqvi posted later.Pakistan and India are likely to clash again in the Super Four stage if both sides progress. India have virtually sealed their spot with two wins, while Pakistan face a must-win encounter against UAE. Their potential rematch is scheduled for Sunday in Dubai.<span></span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123900299,imgsize-54072,width-400,resizemode-4/india-vs-pakistan-ap-photo.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/83033472.cms"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:09:33 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/india-prime-minister-narendra-modi-spared-china-xi-jinping-the-new-villain-in-donald-trumps-latest-tariff-post-2786985-2025-09-14</link><title>India spared, China the new villain in Trump's latest tariff post (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhh6ky/india_spared_china_the_new_villain_in_trumps/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhh6ky/india_spared_china_the_new_villain_in_trumps/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhh6ky/india_spared_china_the_new_villain_in_trumps/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>After months of berating India as Moscow's enabler, Donald Trump has found a bigger villain in Beijing. In shifting his fury eastward, he spares New Delhi &ndash; but only to keep it from slipping deeper into Russia's embrace.</h2></div><div><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/trump-lobbies-nato-to-sanction-russia-and-hit-china-with-50-100-tariffs-140625523-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=whC8KD_FNJGDYchiE__pADFlxDe1DGqB&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Trump lobbies Nato to sanction Russia and hit China with 50-100% tariffs." title="Trump lobbies Nato to sanction Russia and hit China with 50-100% tariffs." height="388"></p><p>Trump lobbies Nato to sanction Russia and hit China with 50-100% tariffs.</p></div><div><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 14, 2025 08:50 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>Donald Trump has found a new villain. After months of railing against India for buying Russian oil and hammering New Delhi with punitive tariffs, the US president is now training his guns on China. In his latest Truth Social post, Trump thundered that Nato nations must "stop buying oil from Russia" and unite to<strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/ready-to-do-major-sanctions-on-russia-when-all-nato-nations-agree-and-do-the-same-thing-says-trump-2786834-2025-09-13"> impose "major sanctions" on Moscow </a></strong>&ndash; while also calling for devastating 50 per cent to 100 per cent tariffs on Beijing.</p><p>In a fiery letter addressed to Nato members and "the world", Trump declared: "I am ready to do major sanctions on Russia when all Nato nations have agreed, and started, to do the same thing, and when all Nato Nations STOP BUYING OIL FROM RUSSIA. As you know, Nato's commitment to win has been far less than 100 per cent, and the purchase of Russian Oil, by some, has been shocking! It greatly weakens your negotiating position, and bargaining power, over Russia."</p><p>Trump urged the alliance to act collectively, insisting he was prepared to "go" once Nato members align on sanctions: "Anyway, I am ready to 'go' when you are. Just say when?" he wrote.</p><p>In his most direct remarks yet, Trump said he is "ready" to move on the sanctions, which could have a devastating impact on Russia's finances &ndash; but ultimately left the decision in the hands of Nato allies.</p><p>The sharpest edge of his demand, though, was reserved for Beijing. "I believe that this, plus Nato , as a group, placing 50 per cent to 100 per cent TARIFFS ON CHINA, to be fully withdrawn after the WAR with Russia and Ukraine is ended, will also be of great help in ENDING this deadly, but RIDICULOUS, WAR," he added.</p><p>Trump stressed that "China has a strong control, and even grip, over Russia, and these powerful Tariffs will break that grip".</p><h3>TRUMP SHIFTS HIS ATTENTION TO CHINA</h3><p><strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/donald-trump-softening-stance-india-ties-tariff-trade-deal-after-harsh-criticism-2781316-2025-09-03">The demand marks a stark reversal</a></strong>: until recently, Trump had spared China with a lighter 30 per cent tariff while punishing India with a bruising 50 per cent duty, often lumping the two in the same breath as Moscow's biggest enablers.</p><p>After US President Donald Trump pressed Nato nations to impose tariffs on Russian oil purchasers in a bid to pressure Moscow, China on Saturday said that it <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/china-hits-back-at-trump-100-per-cent-tariff-call-india-sanctions-russia-ukraine-war-2786934-2025-09-13">neither plots nor participates in wars</a></strong>, in a stern and clear message to Washington.</p><p>Beijing's dig at the US came just hours after Trump's post urging Nato members to halt Russian oil purchases and impose sanctions of up to 100 per cent on China, one of Moscow's biggest buyers.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/g7-finance-ministers-discuss-tariffs-possible-sanctions-to-increase-pressure-on-russia-glbs-2786586-2025-09-13">Additionally, the US has been urging G7 countries</a></strong> &ndash; including Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, and the United Kingdom, most of whom are also Nato members &ndash; to step up pressure on Russia by imposing tariffs on India and China, both major buyers of Russian oil.</p><p>This shift in target comes after weeks of acrimony in India-US ties. Washington had unleashed some of its harshest rhetoric in decades, with Trump aides branding India the "Kremlin's laundromat" and even <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/modis-war-white-house-adviser-navarro-links-india-to-ukraine-war-glbs-2777904-2025-08-28">dismissing the Russia-Ukraine conflict as "Modi's war".</a></strong></p><p>Trade advisor Peter Navarro went further, lacing his attacks with casteist undertones by accusing "Brahmins" of profiteering at the expense of ordinary Indians.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/weve-lost-india-russia-to-darkest-china-trump-shares-pic-of-modi-putin-xi-together-from-sco-summit-2782533-2025-09-05">Trump himself grumbled that the US had "lost" India to "the darkest China" </a></strong>after images from the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) summit showed Prime Minister Narendra Modi chatting amiably with Xi Jinping and Vladimir Putin.</p><p>The optics of the SCO summit clearly rattled Washington. PM Modi's visible camaraderie with Putin &ndash; walking hand-in-hand, holding candid conversations, even sharing a car ride in Tianjin &ndash; and his warm exchanges with Xi, symbolised a deepening comfort between the world's three biggest powers.</p><p>For a US administration banking on India as the democratic counterweight to China, the sight of New Delhi leaning on Moscow and Beijing through multilateral forums was nothing short of alarming.</p><p>India's firmness has only added to Washington's unease. Despite the barrage of US criticism, New Delhi has refused to yield on what it considers red lines &ndash; particularly opening its dairy and agricultural sectors, which could devastate millions of farmers.</p><p>Trump's imposition of a 25 per cent tariff on Indian goods and an additional 25 per cent penalty over Russian oil imports deepened the chill, and stalled trade talks languished in deadlock. Yet, the government held its ground, signalling that no amount of hectoring would shake India's stance.</p><p>Faced with that resolve &ndash; and the nightmare scenario of India, China, and Russia banding together, Washington has begun to soften its tone.</p><p>Last week, Trump abruptly changed tack, calling <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/will-speak-to-pm-modi-trump-says-india-us-to-continue-trade-talks-glbs-2784767-2025-09-10">PM Modi a "great Prime Minister" and a "dear friend"</a></strong>. PM Modi reciprocated swiftly, describing the US as a "close friend and natural partner", and expressing confidence that the trade negotiations would soon unlock the <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/india-us-natural-partners-pm-modi-says-he-too-is-looking-forward-to-speaking-with-president-trump-2784778-2025-09-10">"limitless potential" of the partnership.</a></strong></p><h3>REASON BEHIND WASHINGTON'S RECALIBRATION</h3><p>Trump's lieutenants, too, have recalibrated. Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent, who<strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/scott-bessent-backs-us-india-ties-hits-russian-oil-trade-glbs-2780400-2025-09-02"> once led the charge against India's Russian oil purchases</a></strong>, now plays the conciliator.</p><p>"Two great countries will get this solved," he said, emphasising the personal rapport between Trump and PM Modi. Even he brushed off SCO optics as manageable, though conceding that the relationship was "very complicated." By contrast, Navarro has continued his barrage &ndash; but his vitriol now looks increasingly isolated.</p><p>The reasons for this pivot are both external and domestic. At home, Trump has been hammered by Democrats, former officials, and even Republican rivals like Nikki Haley for imperilling two decades of painstakingly built ties with India. Alienating Indian-Americans &ndash; a demographic increasingly warming to Trump &ndash; also carries political risks. Abroad, the idea of India tilting closer to China and Russia is a strategic nightmare that the US can ill afford.</p><p>By shifting the spotlight to Beijing, Trump is signalling a recalibration: China, with its USD 7.2 billion purchase of Russian fossil fuels in July and its "grip" over Moscow, is the real prize. India, with its USD 3.6 billion in imports and an <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/india-us-trade-talks-agriculture-dairy-sector-donald-trump-explain-bilateral-trade-gm-crops-subsidy-explained-2749828-2025-07-03">uncompromising government unwilling to bend on trade red lines</a></strong>, has effectively forced Washington's hand.</p><p>The softer tone towards New Delhi and the tougher rhetoric against Beijing reveal a US strategy in transition &ndash; one that acknowledges India's leverage and the costs of pushing it further into the arms of Moscow and Beijing.</p><p>For now, Trump insists he is "ready" to devastate Russia's finances with sanctions &ndash; but only when Nato nations unite and stop buying Russian oil. More telling, though, is his demand that China face up to 100 per cent tariffs. In Trump's calculus, sparing India and targeting Beijing may be the only way to break what he calls China's "grip" over Russia &ndash; and to ensure that America does not lose India for good.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Nakul Ahuja</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 14, 2025</p></div></div><p>Tune In</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/Nakul-profile_image_one_to_one.jpeg?VersionId=38FoOGLj4yavzOeKV44CGYATC92xdZir&amp;size=50:50"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:58:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/missing-truck-driver-rescued-from-sacked-ias-officer-puja-khedkars-pune-home-9276453?pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll</link><title>Missing Truck Driver Rescued From Sacked IAS Officer Puja Khedkar's Pune Home (ndtv.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngx3gf/missing_truck_driver_rescued_from_sacked_ias/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngx3gf/missing_truck_driver_rescued_from_sacked_ias/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngx3gf/missing_truck_driver_rescued_from_sacked_ias/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 22:50:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sikh-woman-raped-by-2-men-in-uk-oldbury-told-go-back-to-your-country-9269438</link><title>"Go Back To Your Country": Sikh Woman Raped, Faced Racist Abuse In UK (ndtv.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nguaow/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_raped_faced/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nguaow/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_raped_faced/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nguaow/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_raped_faced/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 21:02:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/</link><title>Got cheated by Niva Bupa Insurance + Ombudsman + IRDAI</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’m sharing my experience with <strong>Niva Bupa Health Insurance</strong> and the regulators in India because it’s been a nightmare of <strong>fraud, collusion, and cover-up.</strong> Posting here to spread awareness and also get suggestions on what legal action I can take.</p><h1>Background</h1><ul><li>I took a Niva Bupa policy in 2021 and renewed it in 2022, and then for 3 years in Sept 2023.</li><li>The policy always included a <strong>free annual health checkup,</strong> which could be claimed on a reimbursement basis. I successfully claimed it in 2022 and 2023.</li></ul><p><strong>The Fraudulent Change</strong></p><ul><li>In the 2023 renewal, Niva Bupa <strong>secretly changed the terms</strong>: “This benefit is available ONLY on cashless, and no reimbursement is allowed.”</li><li>As per the earlier policy wording, they were <strong>legally required to give 3 months&#39; prior notice</strong> of such changes. They never did.</li><li>When I filed a reimbursement claim in Aug 2024, it was rejected using the new wording. I only came to know about the change after this rejection.</li></ul><h1>Failed Complaints</h1><ul><li>I complained twice on <strong>IRDAI’s Bima Bharosa site</strong>. Both were closed within days without addressing the actual issue.</li><li>I went to the <strong>Insurance Ombudsman (Delhi)</strong>. Despite me sending all documents (email + courier), they falsely closed my case, saying I didn’t submit documents.</li><li>I later got proof through RTI that they had indeed received them.</li></ul><h1>The “Fake” Hearing &amp; Award</h1><ul><li>In December 2024, they called me for a hearing, but with the <strong>wrong case number, the wrong insurer name, and the wrong policy number.</strong></li><li>At the hearing, I clearly said it was about breach of contract (changing terms without notice). The Niva Bupa rep asked for more time. Nothing was settled.</li><li>Later, I suddenly received an “Award” from the Ombudsman office stating:<ul><li>That I had <strong>accepted an offer</strong> from Niva Bupa (a lie).</li><li>The case was settled through conciliation.</li><li>That only ₹4,194 was awarded against my relief request of ₹1,00,000.</li><li>It mentions that “<em>At this stage, Insurers agreed to consider the claim and review the continuation of the Policy on the basis of terms and conditions of previous insurance policies for the renewed period. The Complainant accepted this offer. Thus complaint is resolved by way of Conciliation and Mediation under Rule 16 of the Insurance Ombudsman Rules, 2017</em>.”</li></ul></li><li>RTI replies later claimed I had “verbally accepted” in the online hearing 🤯. No proof, no recording.</li></ul><h1>More Stonewalling</h1><ul><li>I escalated through the <strong>PG Portal</strong> (DARPG). Instead of sending it to IRDAI/Ombudsman, they wrongly forwarded my complaints back to <strong>Niva Bupa</strong> 🤦🏻‍♂️. All were closed without action.</li><li>Appeals were also closed the same way.</li><li>Even after the Ombudsman’s own award saying the insurer should honour previous terms, <strong>Niva Bupa rejected my reimbursement claims again in Aug 2025.</strong></li></ul><h1>Where I Stand Now</h1><ul><li>Niva Bupa = Breached contract, lied, ignored Ombudsman order.</li><li>IRDAI = Closed complaints blindly.</li><li>Ombudsman = Issued a false award, colluded with insurer.</li><li>PG Portal = Mishandled and misrouted complaints.</li></ul><p>This is a <strong>systemic failure</strong>. Feels like the regulator, redressal system, and insurer are all hand-in-glove.</p><h1>What I’m Considering:</h1><ul><li>Filing a <strong>Consumer Court case</strong> for breach of contract, deficiency of service, and harassment.</li><li>Filing a <strong>Writ Petition in the High Court</strong> for regulatory failure and misconduct by IRDAI &amp; Ombudsman.</li><li>Exploring the possibility of a <strong>class action suit</strong> since this likely affects many other Niva Bupa customers.</li></ul><p>👉 Has anyone here fought something similar with an insurance company or the Ombudsman? What worked for you?</p><p>👉 Should I start with Consumer Court, or directly go for High Court since IRDAI + Ombudsman are involved?</p><p>Any advice, guidance, or even visibility would help 🙏</p><p>(All documents, RTI replies, emails, and even the hearing video are with me for proof.)</p><p>------</p><p>⚡ TL;DR: Niva Bupa secretly changed policy terms, IRDAI closed my complaints without looking, Ombudsman fabricated a false award, and PG Portal misrouted grievances. Complete collapse of the system. Thinking of going to the Consumer Court/High Court.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 17:22:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/sikh-woman-raped-by-two-men-in-uk-park-oldbury-told-go-back-to-your-country-racial-attack-hate-crime-sikh-community-abroad-2786721-2025-09-13</link><title>Go back to your country, Sikh woman told after being raped at UK park (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngjkdf/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_told_after/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngjkdf/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_told_after/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngjkdf/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_told_after/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>A Sikh woman was told to "go back to her own country" by two men who allegedly raped her at a park in Oldbury, UK.&nbsp;Police are treating the assault as a racially aggravated hate crime and launched a manhunt for the suspects.</h2></div><div><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/uk-police-1226477-16x9.jpg?VersionId=xlvn.P5zJRNBmqi5WuP8naBCqzuZumaG&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="UK police" title="Image used for representational purpose only" height="388"></p><p>Image used for representational purpose only</p></div><div><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 13, 2025 17:02 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>A Sikh woman in her 20s was allegedly raped by two men in broad daylight at a park in Oldbury, UK, and told to &ldquo;go back to your country&rdquo; during the assault.</p><p>The attack took place just before 8.30am on Tuesday in an area off Tame Road. Police said they were treating the assault as a racially aggravated hate crime and have launched a manhunt for the suspects.</p><p>Both attackers are described as white men. One is heavy-built with a shaven head and was wearing a dark sweatshirt and gloves; the other was seen in a grey top with a silver zip.</p><p>Officers have appealed for CCTV, dashcam or mobile footage from the area and have urged anyone with information to come forward.</p><p>&ldquo;This was a horrific attack. We are appealing to anyone who saw two men in the area or has CCTV or dashcam footage to contact us urgently,&rdquo; West Midlands Police said in a statement.</p><p>The assault has triggered anger and fear among the Sikh community, which has reported rising incidents of racism in recent months.</p><p>Labour MP Preet Kaur Gill condemned the attack, calling it &ldquo;an act of extreme violence and racism.&rdquo; She wrote in a post on X: &ldquo;She does belong here. Racism and misogyny have no place in Oldbury or anywhere in Britain,&rdquo; and pledged to work with police to ensure justice and improve safety for the Sikh community.</p><p>Police have stepped up patrols in the area, and the victim is receiving specialist support as investigations continue.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Priyanka Kumari</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 13, 2025</p></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/IndiaToday_8-profile_image_one_to_one_2.jpg?VersionId=YHWhNjkqMc4flF9vvzdfMRFJETGjKZY9&amp;size=50:50"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 11:40:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://scroll.in/article/1086343/why-young-indians-are-not-interested-in-the-prime-ministers-ambitious-internship-scheme</link><title>Why young Indians are not interested in the prime minister’s ambitious internship scheme (scroll.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nghqdb/why_young_indians_are_not_interested_in_the_prime/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nghqdb/why_young_indians_are_not_interested_in_the_prime/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 23 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nghqdb/why_young_indians_are_not_interested_in_the_prime/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://sc0.blr1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/book/209257-nqkuxjjpdp-1757324616.jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><div><p><strong>S</strong>ometime around September 2024, Santosh Kumar&rsquo;s parents heard on the radio about the newly launched Prime Minister&rsquo;s Internship Scheme. They told their son, an engineering graduate, about it.</p><p>Kumar&rsquo;s father is a farmer and his mother, a homemaker. They live in a small village in Maharashtra&rsquo;s Osmanabad district. They had worked hard to put their children, a son and a daughter, through engineering college. While their daughter managed to find a job, their son, who graduated with a BTech degree in computer science in 2023, did not hear back from any of the companies to which he had applied.</p><p>The couple thought the internship scheme might offer their son an opportunity to land a job. So, they urged him to apply.</p><p>When he applied in October, he found the process was &ldquo;very simple&rdquo;. He had to supply information about his education and his skills, and from a list of job profiles, choose five that he thought would suit him. &ldquo;However, they didn&rsquo;t provide any information about the companies that were offering the jobs, so I just picked at random,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>He received a positive response within a few days of applying, and was asked to appear for an interview. Within seven days of the interview, Kumar received an internship offer letter from one of the country&rsquo;s top tech companies.</p><p>The family was overjoyed. Kumar, however, was apprehensive. The monthly stipend for the programme was just Rs 5,000, apart from a one-time payment of Rs 6,000 he would receive on joining. Nevertheless, he took up the offer and was posted to an office in Pune, around 300 km from his home.</p><p>Now, nine months into his internship, Kumar fears that it could be a waste of both his time and his money. (He and other interns <em>Scroll</em> spoke to for this story are identified by pseudonyms to protect them from any backlash from the companies they work for.)</p><figure><a href="https://x.com/nsitharamanoffc/status/1817526724055228573/photo/1"> <img src="https://sc0.blr1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/inline/fccdppeoia-1757315091.jpeg" alt title="The prime minister's internship scheme was launched under the aegis of the corporate affairs ministry in 2024. The corporate affairs minister Nirmala Sitharaman has stated that the scheme did not aim to provide interns with jobs. Photo: @nsitharamanoffc/X"> </a><figcaption>The prime minister's internship scheme was launched under the aegis of the corporate affairs ministry in 2024. The corporate affairs minister Nirmala Sitharaman has stated that the scheme did not aim to provide interns with jobs. Photo: @nsitharamanoffc/X</figcaption></figure><p>Kumar stays in a paying-guest facility, whose monthly rent of Rs 6,000 is itself more than his stipend. He also has various other expenses. &ldquo;I can&rsquo;t do anything with Rs 5,000,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;I have to travel about 5 km to the office. I take the bus or an auto to work. So, I have to spend on transport.&rdquo;</p><p>Food is another major expense. &ldquo;The rent money doesn&rsquo;t include the food bill at the paying guest accommodation,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>He also has to pay for his meals at the office canteen &ndash; it &ldquo;costs about 60 to 70 rupees, which is a big expense for me&rdquo;, he explained. To save money, &ldquo;Sometimes I pack some extra breakfast for lunch,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Apart from these costs, &ldquo;I need to spend on my phone recharges and other miscellaneous expenses that arise now and then,&rdquo; Kumar said.</p><h3>Kumar&rsquo;s monthly expenses amount to around Rs 13,000 &ndash; in effect, he is paying Rs 8,000 out of his pocket to participate in the internship scheme. &ldquo;It is a real struggle,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;For somebody like me who comes from a poor background, this is a huge expense to incur.&rdquo;</h3><p>Kumar is only able to manage because his family sends him money. &ldquo;I know it is very difficult for them to provide me with so much money every month,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>His parents are supporting him in the hope that he will secure a job at the company at the end of his internship. &ldquo;They think that it is okay to make this investment now because I&rsquo;ll get a job,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>But the internship programme does not guarantee jobs. In fact, Nirmala Sitharaman, who is the finance minister and corporate affairs minister, stated earlier this year in the <a href="https://www.business-standard.com/india-news/pm-internship-scheme-youth-provide-exposure-jobs-nirmala-sitharaman-125020401192_1.html"><u>Rajya Sabha</u></a> that &ldquo;The intent of the program is not to provide jobs, but to offer exposure and create awareness about market opportunities, so that candidates can be trained accordingly.&rdquo;</p><p>The question of employment is what most frustrates and terrifies Kumar. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m scared that after 12 months, all this would have been a waste,&rdquo; Kumar said. &ldquo;An entire year of my life and so much money.&rdquo;</p><hr><p><strong><em>This story is part of </em></strong><a href="https://scroll.in/topic/56439/common-ground"><strong><em><u>Common Ground</u></em></strong></a><strong><em>, our in-depth and investigative reporting project. Sign up </em></strong><a href="https://scrollstack.us7.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f11eeab993ed2fbea0bfb512e&amp;id=e2fc1bf83f"><strong><em><u>here</u></em></strong></a><strong><em> to get the stories in your inbox soon after they are released.</em></strong></p><hr><p><strong>I</strong>ndia faces a stark problem of unemployment among its youth, particularly pronounced among educated youth. According to a 2024 <a href="https://www.ilo.org/sites/default/files/2024-08/India%20Employment%20-%20web_8%20April.pdf"><u>report</u></a>, in 2022, the unemployment rate among those who had completed their education up to at least the secondary level was 18.4%, while among graduates, the rate was a stark 29.1%. These rates were around six and nine times higher, respectively, than the rate among those who could not read or write.</p><p>The Prime Minister&rsquo;s Internship Scheme, which Sitharaman introduced in the July 2024 budget session of the parliament, represented a major effort by the government to tackle this crisis. The scheme was launched under the corporate affairs ministry with the goal of making youth &ldquo;more employable&rdquo; by industries in the country.</p><figure><img src="https://sc0.blr1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/inline/ftgdldspsc-1757316447.jpg" alt title="Job-seekers at a job fair organised by the Karnataka state government in Bengaluru in 2024. In 2022, the unemployment rate in India among those who had completed their education up to at least the secondary level was 18.4%, while among graduates, the rate was a stark 29.1%. Photo for representation: Idrees Mohammed/AFP"><figcaption>Job-seekers at a job fair organised by the Karnataka state government in Bengaluru in 2024. In 2022, the unemployment rate in India among those who had completed their education up to at least the secondary level was 18.4%, while among graduates, the rate was a stark 29.1%. Photo for representation: Idrees Mohammed/AFP</figcaption></figure><p>The scheme aimed to provide internships to one crore young people in &ldquo;the top 500 companies&rdquo; in India over the following five years. These companies encompass a wide range, from those in the automobile sector, to those in travel and hospitality, as well as in banking, finance, sales, marketing and other sectors.</p><p>The internships, which last 12 months, are open to those between the ages of 21 and 24 who have at least cleared their Class 10 exams. Candidates cannot be enrolled in a full-time academic programme or have a full-time job, and must not have an annual family income that exceeds Rs 8 lakh. Candidates who have degrees from certain institutions like National Law Universities and Indian Institutes of Technology, or have advanced degrees, are ineligible to apply.</p><p>Of the interns&rsquo; stipend of Rs 5,000, the government pays Rs 4,500, and companies pay Rs 500.</p><p>In the first phase of the scheme&rsquo;s pilot phase, which began in October 2024, 280 companies from around 745 districts advertised more than 1.27 lakh internships. In the second, which began in January 2025, around 327 companies<strong> </strong>advertised more than 1.18 lakh internships, which included some internships that had not been filled in the previous round.</p><p>The website and social media accounts of the corporate affairs ministry carries pictures and videos of the smiling faces of interns who have passed through the programme. In short videos, some speak of the benefits of the internship and how thankful they are to the government for providing them with the opportunity.</p><p>But data on the response to the scheme shows a less rosy picture. In the first round, though 1.81 lakh individuals applied for the 1.27 lakh internships advertised, only 60,000 received offers, indicating that the companies rejected many as unsuitable. Worse, of the 60,000 who had offers, only 8,700 joined their internships. The second round saw 2.14 lakh applicants, of which 72,000 received offers &ndash; but only a little under 23,000 accepted them.</p><figure><a href="https://pminternship.mca.gov.in/login/#gallery-block"> <img src="https://sc0.blr1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/inline/uxvgzljnxg-1757316927.jpg" alt title="Though the government's publicity material about the internship scheme shows happy interns engaged in productive work, data on the response to the scheme shows a less rosy picture. Photo: Ministry of Corporate Affairs website"> </a><figcaption>Though the government's publicity material about the internship scheme shows happy interns engaged in productive work, data on the response to the scheme shows a less rosy picture. Photo: Ministry of Corporate Affairs website</figcaption></figure><p>Activists and experts from the field of youth empowerment and employment say a combination of factors is responsible for the poor response to the scheme.</p><p>Chief among these is that the scheme is aimed at individuals in an age group in which they would be seeking jobs, but offers them only internships.</p><h3>&ldquo;If somebody is looking for a job, then they&rsquo;re looking for a job, right?&rdquo; said Byomkesh Mishra, co-founder of Medha, an organisation that works on youth employment. &ldquo;Internships may help them learn some of the skills and maybe improve their prospects of employment further, but it cannot itself be a proxy for a job.&rdquo;</h3><p>He argued that ideally, internships &ldquo;should be embedded in education&rdquo;. Such programmes &ldquo;have the best impact when they happen while the student or the candidate is still learning or still in the education system. The concept is called work-based learning,&rdquo; he noted.</p><p>But this was not the only problem with the scheme. Job-seekers who were interested in enrolling in the scheme found that most of the internships on offer were concentrated in certain parts of the country, making them difficult for many from other regions to access.</p><p>In the second phase, for instance, companies in Tamil Nadu and Maharashtra offered more than 15,000 internships each, while companies in Gujarat offered around 11,000 internships and those in Karnataka offered close to 10,000. The total of more than 50,000 internships in these states represented just under half of the total number on offer in that phase.</p><p>But apart from Maharashtra, all these states currently have less than 300 interns enrolled in the scheme. Instead, the five states where the most number of interns enrolled are Assam, with 1,408 interns, Uttar Pradesh, with 1,067, Bihar, with 634, Odisha, with 420, and Kerala, with 516.</p><p>Tanoj Meshram, a public policy researcher and professor at the SP Jain Institute of Management and Research, argued that these numbers suggested that &ldquo;since the stipends are so low, candidates who mostly have no other options might have taken up the internships.&rdquo; He added, &ldquo;It could be that candidates in Assam were most in need of jobs, and so they took up the offers.&rdquo;</p><p>Aamir Nurule, who works with an organisation that holds job fairs and aids students in recruitment, noted that the National Apprenticeship Promotion Scheme, which provides year-long apprenticeships to young people, pays them stipends ranging between Rs 6,000 and Rs 10,000. &ldquo;The reimbursement is higher than the PM Internship Scheme,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Why would students opt for the internship scheme then?&rdquo; </p><p><em>Scroll</em> emailed the corporate affairs ministry, seeking responses to criticisms about the scheme &ndash; this story will be updated if any responses are received.</p><hr><p><strong>L</strong>ike Kumar, Praveen Arun is also struggling to meet his expenses after enrolling in the internship programme, with a company in Chandigarh. Arun, who belongs to a family of farmers from a small town in Bihar, graduated from a college in Punjab this year with an engineering degree, and was disappointed with how placements were conducted in his college. Most of the companies that visited were hiring for sales positions, he noted, and not for engineering ones.</p><p>Staff at his college suggested that he apply to the prime minister&rsquo;s internship scheme. &ldquo;I had never heard about it until the staff mentioned it to me,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;I wasn&rsquo;t even asked to fill in the application, the college did it for me. They asked for some documents and asked me to choose three companies I would like to join.&rdquo;</p><p>When he was selected and appeared for the interview, Arun sought to understand from his interviewers what benefit he would gain by taking up this internship, and particularly if it would eventually lead to a job. &ldquo;They told me that the government had only directed them to provide internships so far,&rdquo; Arun said. &ldquo;And so until the government gave them any further instructions, they would not be able to assure me of a job.&rdquo;</p><p>Though he was disappointed, he recounted, &ldquo;An internship seemed like a better option than sitting at home.&rdquo;</p><p>Arun was offered an internship in Bengaluru, which he would have accepted had he been able to afford the expenses. &ldquo;Bengaluru is the IT hub. The exposure would have been very good for me,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;But it would have been too expensive for me to move there for a year.&rdquo;</p><p>Instead, he took up the offer in Chandigarh. &ldquo;But in Chandigarh, only one such software company exists,&rdquo; he said. Since he had completed his engineering degree in Punjab, he was familiar with the city and more confident of navigating its challenges.</p><figure><img src="https://sc0.blr1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/inline/kixriedtjl-1757317456.jpg" alt title="A coding event in 2012 in Bengaluru. Though interns in the field of software would have benefited from work experience in the city, some noted that the stipend was too low to allow them to shift from their home cities. Photo for representation: Manjunath Kiran/AFP"><figcaption>A coding event in 2012 in Bengaluru. Though interns in the field of software would have benefited from work experience in the city, some noted that the stipend was too low to allow them to shift from their home cities. Photo for representation: Manjunath Kiran/AFP</figcaption></figure><p>But even Chandigarh is proving expensive &ndash; Arun spends between Rs 15,000 and Rs 17,000 each month.</p><h3>&ldquo;Since Chandigarh doesn&rsquo;t have too many industries, there weren&rsquo;t any paying guest accommodations that exist in the city and most were already full. So I had to rent out a room,&rdquo; he said.</h3><p>Like Kumar, for the bulk of his expenses, Arun depends on his family. &ldquo;It is difficult for them to arrange the money for me every month,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Sayyed Etemaad, a 21-year-old pharmacy student, faced the same problem. Etemaad, a resident of Amravati, applied and was selected under the scheme, but realised that the centre nearest to him was Aurangabad, 300 km away. &ldquo;The travel, accommodation and food would cost me way more than the internship money,&rdquo; he told <em>Scroll</em>. &ldquo;I did not take up any offers.&rdquo; </p><p>His friend and fellow pharmacy student, Kamran Ahmad, also decided against applying. &ldquo;The starting package for a fresh graduate of pharmacy is Rs 4 lakh per annum,&rdquo; Ahmad said. &ldquo;But the internship paid almost nothing.&rdquo;</p><hr><p>The low stipend is not the only problem that interns struggle with. Kumar explained that he also feels that his time at the company is not well utilised.</p><p>He is required to be in his office by 10 am. Though his internship is supposed to be in the field of software development, he is usually not given any project to work on.</p><p>Instead, he sits at the desk allocated to him, sets his laptop on it and does &ldquo;self study&rdquo;, he said.</p><h3>&ldquo;On some days, my mentor will check in and find out how my skill development is going,&rdquo; he added. &ldquo;But he does not give me any work to do.&rdquo;</h3><p>Thus, on most days, he spends his hours in the office preparing for future job interviews. At 5 pm, he leaves and returns to his place of accommodation.</p><p>Some of his peers have had better luck, he noted. &ldquo;Some of my friends have different mentors, who give them software development work,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;So, whether or not you get work also depends on whose care you are under.&rdquo;</p><p>But those who take up internships through other avenues have a uniformly better experience, he explained. &ldquo;Those who come from big institutions like the IITs or other big colleges are given a lot of work to do all day,&rdquo; Kumar said.</p><p>Other interns also receive significantly more pay. Kumar noted that in his company, some interns who were still undergraduate students were paid stipends of between Rs 12,000 and Rs 15,000, up to three times more than interns in the government scheme. Meanwhile, interns from IITs are given a much higher stipend, he said.</p><p>&ldquo;It is very discriminatory in the way that they treat the interns who come in through the scheme, and other interns,&rdquo; he added.</p><p>In fact, in Arun&rsquo;s company, the programme for interns who enroll through the government scheme was structured in such a way as to separate them from other interns.</p><p>Most other interns, he noted, were sent to a main internship centre in South India. Those that entered through the government scheme, however, were allocated to centres in other cities, including Chandigarh, where only they worked. &ldquo;It is only the PMIS interns who are distributed in other branches of the company,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Because there are hundreds of us that have come in through the scheme, we were told that they would not have been able to accommodate all of us at the internship centre.&rdquo;</p><p>The interns <em>Scroll</em> spoke to were also largely disappointed with the training they have received so far at these centres. &ldquo;The company conducted training for us only for seven days,&rdquo; Kumar said.</p><p>He noted that the training was &ldquo;very basic, just an introduction to the subject&rdquo; &ndash; the kind that could be easily gained through online programmes. In contrast, new employees at the company undergo a more intensive three-month training, he explained.</p><figure><img src="https://sc0.blr1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/inline/vtrudbdzxm-1757317702.jpg" alt title="Interns noted that they were not given much work to do during their internships. They also said that they only received very basic training that did not add much to their experience. Photo for representation: Parivartan Sharma/Reuters"><figcaption>Interns noted that they were not given much work to do during their internships. They also said that they only received very basic training that did not add much to their experience. Photo for representation: Parivartan Sharma/Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Raj&rsquo;s experience was similar. &ldquo;Maybe people who come from other streams, these sessions will be helpful,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;But for somebody who is coming from a software background, these lessons are repetitive.&rdquo; He and Kumar both also argued that 12 months was too long a duration for an internship at what is a crucial period in a young person&rsquo;s life &ndash; in their view, six months would be sufficient to impart important skills to them.</p><p>Kumar rued the fact that the company gave them no information about the internship beforehand. &ldquo;It would be good to know what the curriculum is for the year,&rdquo; he said.</p><h3>Meshram echoed this view. &ldquo;When the internships were announced, the companies should have announced a series of roles for which people can apply &ndash; the roles should have very specific descriptions,&rdquo; he said.</h3><p>Rafique Shaikh, a recruitment agent, described the scheme as a &ldquo;great platform to connect youth with big corporations&rdquo;. But, he noted, applicants &ldquo;can only apply in three companies which limits their options. And the job description is very basic, making it vague for a candidate.&rdquo;</p><p>Meshram noted, &ldquo;Candidates need to know that with the training that they are getting, they have been kind of certified for a specific job, and after completion of the internship, if not in that company, they should be able to land a job somewhere else.&rdquo;</p><p>The only clear benefit that both Raj and Kumar said they had gained from their internship so far was an improvement in their communication skills. &ldquo;When I initially joined the office, I was awkward and hesitant to talk to others at the office,&rdquo; Kumar said. &ldquo;But my communication skills have improved since I joined.&rdquo;</p><p>But all three interns <em>Scroll </em>spoke to said that they were not particularly committed to completing their internships and would quit if they found a job or any better opportunities. &ldquo;Who wants to work as an intern with a pay of Rs 5,000? The minute I find a job, I will leave,&rdquo; Raj said.</p><p>Arun said that his programme requires him to be in his office between 9 am and 5 pm, leaving him little time to look for jobs. &ldquo;But if I do find a job, I will leave immediately,&rdquo; Arun said.</p><p>Kumar felt considerable anxiety at the fact that many of his peers who graduated with him had secured jobs with reasonable salaries. &ldquo;I feel I&rsquo;m stuck while they have moved on,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;An internship is of low priority, it is a proper full-time job that I would have liked to have.&rdquo;</p><p>But when Kumar attended one interview for a job, he was dismayed to learn that the company did not regard his internship experience as significant. &ldquo;They interviewed me and asked me if I had gained any work experience,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;When I told them that I was currently working at this company, they said that it would not count as experience.&rdquo;</p><p>This filled him with the fear that &ldquo;the entire year is going to be a complete waste for me&rdquo;.</p><p>In fact, he also fears he will lose at least another six months or so afterwards, applying for jobs. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s extremely stressful and frustrating to think about what will happen after I finish the internship, in case I&rsquo;m not offered a job at this company,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;I keep asking the manager at my company if it would be possible to get a job, but he does not give me any straight answers.&rdquo;</p><hr><p><strong>D</strong>espite the problems with the scheme, experts did not dismiss the idea of an internship scheme outright.</p><p>Priya Agrawal, the founder of the Maharashtra-based Antarang Foundation, noted that even if interns are not given very important tasks to do, young people in internships often benefited just from spending time in an office or a workplace that inspired them. &ldquo;Even if they are doing mundane jobs, the fact that they are present in these spaces itself is beneficial to them,&rdquo; she said.</p><p>Byomkesh Mishra of Medha concurred. &ldquo;For somebody from a poor and low-income background, just getting exposure to a prestigious workplace can sometimes also add to their confidence,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Meshram, however, disagreed with this view. &ldquo;After the person has done the internship, the question is what specific role did the candidate perform and what training have they received,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;They will eventually be interviewed about that, right?&rdquo;</p><h3>Agarwal argued that the scheme would be more effective if the government opened it up to people who were 18 and above. &ldquo;Lowering the age would help students get a chance to experience a workspace before they decide what jobs to pursue,&rdquo; she said.</h3><figure><img src="https://sc0.blr1.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/inline/nhpxynsyta-1757318616.jpg" alt title="Indian students at a "><figcaption>Indian students at a "hackathon" in 2018. Experts suggested that lowering the age limit for the internship scheme to 18 would allow students to gain valuable work experience in the course of their education. Photo for representation: Xavier Galiana/AFP</figcaption></figure><p>Meshram argued that since the stipend was low, and interns were not provided any accommodation, to ensure that their family life and economic circumstances were not disrupted, the government should ensure that they were posted in or close to their places of residence.</p><p>Mishra also noted that those enrolled in the scheme would benefit if the government monitored their progress. &ldquo;Is anyone keeping track of what happens after the internship?&rdquo; Mishra said. &ldquo;The government should know what happens to candidates who complete the internship.&rdquo;</p><p>While the government could not mandate that companies hire interns, Mishra said, even a simple mechanism that required them to report back to the government about the internships would be beneficial. &ldquo;It would be good if the companies let the government know the progress of the interns and how many would be absorbed into the company,&rdquo; Mishra said. &ldquo;It would be a good sort of nudge for them to absorb some of them and then it will naturally happen.&rdquo;</p></div><i> We welcome your comments at <a href="https://scroll.inmailto:?Subject=Why%20young%20Indians%20are%20not%20interested%20in%20the%20prime%20minister%E2%80%99s%20ambitious%20internship%20schemeto=letters@scroll.in">letters@scroll.in</a>. </i> <ul><li> <a href="https://scroll.in//scroll.in/tag/Work"> Work </a> </li><li> <a href="https://scroll.in//scroll.in/tag/Employment"> Employment </a> </li><li> <a href="https://scroll.in//scroll.in/tag/Ministry-of-Corporate-Affairs"> Ministry of Corporate Affairs </a> </li></ul> </section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 09:52:24 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
