<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 22:01:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.pcmag.com/news/zuckerberg-caught-in-revealing-hot-mic-moment-during-white-house-dinner</link><title>Meta’s Zuckerberg caught in revealing hot mic moment with Trump -- After offering to spend “at least $600 billion through ’28 in the US,” he whispered, “I'm sorry I wasn’t ready ... I wasn’t sure what number you wanted to go with” (pcmag.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9xfyc/metas_zuckerberg_caught_in_revealing_hot_mic/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9xfyc/metas_zuckerberg_caught_in_revealing_hot_mic/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9xfyc/metas_zuckerberg_caught_in_revealing_hot_mic/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 17:12:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?CMP=share_btn_url&amp;page=with%3Ablock-68bb62758f085f50533e8ac1#block-68bb62758f085f50533e8ac1</link><title>Trump, misled by video of 2020 protests shown on Fox, threatens to send troops to Portland (theguardian.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9lvx7/trump_misled_by_video_of_2020_protests_shown_on/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9lvx7/trump_misled_by_video_of_2020_protests_shown_on/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 196 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9lvx7/trump_misled_by_video_of_2020_protests_shown_on/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/cfca5917286444f66c62b2c529ab8bd6f2957631/375_0_3750_3000/master/3750.jpg?width=1200&height=630&quality=85&auto=format&fit=crop&precrop=40:21,offset-x50,offset-y0&overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&overlay-width=100p&overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctbGl2ZS5wbmc&enable=upscale&s=7f00a60955a50e6eca2fc7f805df878f' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><gu-island></gu-island><div><article><header><h2>Misled by video of 2020 protests shown on Fox, Trump threatens to invade Portland and 'wipe out' protesters</h2></header><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> told reporters on Friday that he might send national guard troops to Portland, Oregon, apparently because he was misled about the scale of small protests outside an immigration detention facility there by a TV report which incorrectly presented video recorded during a protest in 2020 as having taken place in the city this summer.</p><p>&ldquo;I will say this, I watched today, I didn&rsquo;t know that was continuing to go on, but Portland is unbelievable, what&rsquo;s going on,&rdquo; <a href="https://youtu.be/_dTSbtfXwDg?si=EO06p1VSobt8fDJu&amp;t=1">Trump said</a>. He then claimed, incorrectly, that he had seen video evidence of &ldquo;the destruction of the city&rdquo;.</p><p>In fact, a handful of protesters have demonstrated outside an Immigration and Customs Enforcement facility in a remote area of Portland along the south waterfront this year, but the scale of the protests, which attract dozens at most, is nothing like the 2020 protests that regularly drew thousands or tens of thousands of demonstrators to a central part of the city.</p><p>&ldquo;Are you going into Portland?&rdquo; a reporter asked Trump.</p><p>&ldquo;Well, I&rsquo;m going to look at it now because I didn&rsquo;t know that was still going on; this has been going on for years,&rdquo; the president replied. He then explained how he had been misled into the entirely false belief that the large-scale protests from 2020 had continued.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;ll be able to stop that very easily, but that was not on my list, Portland, but when I watched television last night, this has been going on,&rdquo; Trump said.</p><figure><div><figcaption><span>Donald Trump threatened to invade Portland, Oregon during an Oval Office event on Friday.</span></figcaption></div></figure><p>The president did not cite the specific news report that he was basing his impression on, but his favorite channel, Fox News, broadcast <a href="https://x.com/KatieDaviscourt/status/1963819280249807236">a report</a> on Thursday that mixed images of a recent protest in Portland, attended by dozens of protesters, with <a href="https://x.com/PDXzane/status/1284726088187310080">a viral video clip</a> from 2020 of one protester, Christopher David, being pepper-sprayed in the face by a federal agent that was wrongly described as having been shot in June of this year.</p><p>The report focused mainly on one protest outside the facility on Tuesday, attended by dozens of protesters who brought a guillotine as a prop before being doused with chemical agents by federal officers.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Dozens of protesters rallied against Donald Trump&rsquo;s immigration policies, outside an Ice detention facility in Portland on Tuesday.</span> Photograph: John Rudoff/Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>&ldquo;These are paid terrorists,&rdquo; the president said, once again spreading <a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/06/04/white-house-forced-retract-claim-viral-videos-prove-antifa-plotting-violence/">a baseless conspiracy theory</a> his administration amplified about anti-fascist protesters in 2020.</p><p>&ldquo;These are paid agitators, these are professional. I watched that last night, I&rsquo;m very good at this stuff. These are paid agitators, they get paid money by radical left groups,&rdquo; the president claimed. He then went on to suggest that well-printed signs displayed by some protesters proved his theory.</p><p>&ldquo;These are paid agitators and they&rsquo;re very dangerous for our country and when we go there, if we go to Portland, we&rsquo;re going to wipe &lsquo;em out. They&rsquo;re going to be gone. They won&rsquo;t even stand to fight. They will not stay there. They&rsquo;ve ruined that city.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s like living in hell,&rdquo; the president said, describing an imaginary version of Portland that bears no resemblance to the actual city, in which fences around the federal courthouse that was the scene of mass protests in 2020 have now been removed and the central police headquarters no longer has boarded up windows.</p></article></div><p><span><gu-island>This brings our surreal-time coverage of the second <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a> to a close for the day. We will be back soon, but in the meantime, here are the latest developments:</gu-island></span></p>","elementId":"a919c7e3-ee96-495d-8999-5890af70001e"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<ul>\n <li>\n<p>Hundreds of people were arrested in an immigration raid at a Hyundai battery factory in Georgia, most of them Korean nationals, despite the fact that a warrant said that just four people, with Spanish names, were targeted.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> signed an executive order authorizing the US Department of Defense to refer to itself as the &ldquo;Department of War&rdquo;, as part of an attempt to formalize his rebranding effort without the legally required act of Congress.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>Trump announced that the US will host the 2026 meeting of the G20 at his privately owned Doral golf course and spa in Miami.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>Asked about Florida&rsquo;s move to lift mandates on vaccinations for schoolchildren, Trump said that officials have to &ldquo;be careful&rdquo; in removing access to vaccines he described as &ldquo;amazing&rdquo; and &ldquo;incredible&rdquo;.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>After watching a misleading report on small protests in Portland, Oregon over immigration, the president said that he might send troops there. A Fox News report on the protests used video recorded during a protest in 2020 and wrongly said it had been recorded in the city this summer.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><a href='\"https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/trump-weighs-strikes-targeting-cartels-inside-venezuela\"'>CNN reported</a> that Trump &ldquo;is weighing options for carrying out military strikes targeting drug cartels operating inside Venezuela, including possible strikes within the country&rdquo;.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>The Pentagon made some immediate cosmetic changes to signage on Friday, after <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> signed an executive order to rebrand the Department of Defense as the Department of War.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>Two leading Republican lawmakers, the House speaker <strong>Mike Johnson</strong> and <strong>Nancy Mace</strong>, both claimed this week that Trump had acted as an FBI informant to take down <strong>Jeffrey Epstein</strong>. They offered no evidence, but if it existed it would be in the files Trump has fought to keep from the public.</p></li>\n</ul>","elementId":"05739a2a-8cc6-4724-a081-59d505a3a31b"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757123721000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"02.55&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757124285000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"03.04&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757124285000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"03.04&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"03.04","title":"Closing summary","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb917e8f085f50533e8b6e","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>As the Republican leadership in the House continues to block a bipartisan effort to force the full release of files from the federal investigation into Jeffrey Epstein, the late sex offender who was once Donald Trump&rsquo;s friend, several of them have started to make the same unsourced claim: that Trump aided the federal effort to prosecute Epstein.</p>","elementId":"49b740b5-1039-415d-87b2-ae5e71d88c54"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>On Tuesday, Nancy Mace, the South Carolina congresswoman who has supported the petition to force the release of the files, told a reporter for the Independent that she had no reason to believe that Trump has opposed hte releae of the files because they might be embarrassing to him.</p>","elementId":"7ebd022c-0e6e-4781-983c-1c5494e79f7f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Donald Trump is the one who banned Jeffrey Epstein from Mar-a-Lago&rdquo;, <a href='\"https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:e7gbntp2tzobn7cfi37viei3/post/3lxvcaihah22b?ref_src=embed&amp;ref_url=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.dailykos.com%252Fstories%252F2025%252F9%252F3%252F2341692%252F-WHOA-Nancy-Mace-Says-Trump-Was-an-FBI-Informant-So-Did-He-Flipped-on-Epstein-to-Save-Himself\"'>she said</a>. &ldquo;He was an FBI informant, and he talked to the feds to get this guy turned over. So Donald Trump is a hero in this.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"db4b7648-9e0f-4be8-a6b2-05f5180b96de"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Then on Thursday, the House speaker, Mike Johnson, made the same claim in <a href='\"https://x.com/mkraju/status/1963640592514081026\"'>an interview</a> with Manu Raju of CNN.</p>","elementId":"eab5a921-5b15-40b5-9fff-e96c905e1ab8"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>When the reporter said that Trump had called the effort to release the Epstein files &ldquo;a hoax&rdquo;, Johnson replied: &ldquo;He&rsquo;s not saying that what Epstein did is a hoax. It&rsquo;s a terrible, unspeakable evil. He believes that himself. When he first heard the rumor, he kicked him out of Mar-a-Lago. He was an FBI informant to try to take this stuff down.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"5a4d76f0-08ac-4819-99e4-33f704d311da"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>As the conspiracy theory expert Mike Rothschild noted: &ldquo;This has been a supposition among QAnon believers for years. Maybe they could release the files and prove it!&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"3d84a208-5ec6-4a31-8dc7-6cb95f31219b"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757122942000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"02.42&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757123712000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"02.55&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757123713000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"02.55&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"02.55","title":"Republican lawmakers push unsourced claim Trump was an 'FBI informant' against Epstein","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb8cc48f087e152e27f903","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The Pentagon made some immediate cosmetic changes to signage on Friday, after <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> signed an executive order to rebrand the Department of Defense as the Department of War.</p>","elementId":"5581a1b2-5428-4bbe-a949-e1c4cb47d5be"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A video clip <a href='\"https://x.com/SecWar/status/1964071478955032634\"'>posted</a> on social media by the defense secretary, Pete Hegseth, showed workers replacing the sign on his office door with one that read &ldquo;Secretary of War&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"7ecc5b9e-e4ba-416f-91e9-d3c31a9ad3e0"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Other images gathered by Pentagon reporters showed workers scraping letters that spelled out &ldquo;Department of Defense&rdquo; from the wall near Hegseth&rsquo;s office.<br><br>\n The URL of the Pentagon&rsquo;s official website was changed from from &ldquo;defense.gov &rdquo; to &ldquo;war.gov&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"34bc31eb-9a0b-409a-b08d-65af569e4b4a"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.VideoYoutubeBlockElement","source":"YouTube","originalUrl":"https://youtu.be/tohOU_zHE-E?si=CqF_t5ilynybnwxm","caption":"Pentagon workers changed signs on Friday.","elementId":"22faa41c-907f-473d-ae8d-5f7269e017fc","width":854,"embedUrl":"https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/tohOU_zHE-E?wmode=opaque&amp;feature=oembed","role":"inline","url":"https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tohOU_zHE-E","height":480,"sourceDomain":"youtube-nocookie.com","title":"Signs changed outside Pete Hegseth's office to say 'Secretary of War'","isThirdPartyTracking":false}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757121732000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"02.22&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757122807000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"02.40&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757122808000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"02.40&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"02.40","title":"Sign on Hegseth's office door now says 'Secretary of War'","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb8b028f085f50533e8b52","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Speaking at a dinner for Republican lawmakers on the newly paved-over lawn on the Rose Garden, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> boasted of what he called the success of his federal takeover of policing in the District of Columbia and promised to send troops to Chicago and New Orleans next.</p>","elementId":"750c5e69-37e1-4fdd-8cef-06a7870d6b15"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to make Chicago like this&rdquo;, <a href='\"https://x.com/Acyn/status/1964123337741000952\"'>Trump said</a>. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to come into New Orleans and we&rsquo;re gonna make that place so safe. It&rsquo;s got a little problem right now, a couple of headaches like murders. A lot of little murders going on, and we&rsquo;re not going to stand for it&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"b7352f61-b241-4dac-ae01-26ec5eb8be27"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757121282000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"02.14&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757121614000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"02.20&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757121615000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"02.20&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"02.20","title":"Trump promises to send federal troops to police Chicago and New Orleans","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb7d5d8f087e152e27f8bf","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Donald Trump refused to answer on Friday when a reporter asked him, amid reports of US ships and bombers massing in the Caribbean, if he would &ldquo;like to see regime change in Venezuela&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"69b0fec9-b129-4b97-897d-6d992a19c821"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re not talking about that&rdquo;, the president said, &ldquo;but we are talking about the fact that you had an election which was a very strange election, to put it mildly&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"c9caef6c-35fb-4bde-a14a-fd568e36d786"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>He went on to say that &ldquo;billions of dollars of drugs are pouring into our country from Venezuela&rdquo;, in line with his administration&rsquo;s claim that it is now at war with drug cartels operating in the country.</p>","elementId":"4ed85ad2-5800-4f1b-9734-25cb90c1f468"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The president&rsquo;s comments came after Fox News reported that the Pentagon is deploying 10 F-35 stealth fighter jets to Puerto Rico, joining eight US Navy destroyers. That prompted the Fox national security correspondent Jennifer Griffin to observe that there was no apparent reason that stealth fighter jets were needed for a counternarcotics mission.</p>","elementId":"042a235e-9e2e-41ba-a307-c1f5e9ef8fa1"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;The F35s being sent to Puerto Rico are usually used for large bombing missions like the targeting of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities- a 5th generation supersonic fighter jet known for its lethality&rdquo;, Griffin <a href='\"https://x.com/JenGriffinFNC/status/1964001832172179733\"'>wrote on X</a>. &ldquo;It looks to me like the US military is going to war.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"840b70b9-3a4d-41ce-99d5-f1b3aeaf2c58"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Later on Friday, <a href='\"https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/trump-weighs-strikes-targeting-cartels-inside-venezuela\"'>CNN reported</a> that Trump &ldquo;is weighing options for carrying out military strikes targeting drug cartels operating inside Venezuela, including possible strikes within the country&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"976ec03d-3365-4ab6-9b1f-0fda959942cf"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Such strikes would be an escalation from deadly attack on a boat from Venezuela in the Caribbean, which killed 11 people the administration suspected on smuggling drugs bound for the US.</p>","elementId":"764a7294-d2cc-4a81-945c-461acd34e5ec"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>During Trump&rsquo;s first term in office, according to his defense secretary, Mark Esper, the president asked him on at least two occasions if the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/us-military\"'>US military</a> could &ldquo;shoot missiles into Mexico to destroy the drug labs.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"0685ef20-a840-4f49-8c31-eb617ab03eb1"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Esper recounted the requests in his memoir, and wrote that when he objected, Trump suggested that &ldquo;no one would know it was us&rdquo; if the US fired &ldquo;some Patriot missiles&rdquo; and he would just deny that the US had carried out the strikes.</p>","elementId":"c4379338-2f57-44f9-92d1-98bab407475a"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>In 2019, when Trump reportedly considered forcing its president, Nicol&aacute;s Maduro, from office, a Democratic congresswoman opposed to what she called &ldquo;regime change wars&rdquo; objected very strongly. &ldquo;The United States needs to stay out of Venezuela&rdquo;, <a href='\"https://x.com/TulsiGabbard/status/1088531713649713153\"'>Tulsi Gabbard wrote</a> at the time. &ldquo;Let the Venezuelan people determine their future. We don&rsquo;t want other countries to choose our leaders--so we have to stop trying to choose theirs.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"2a017d1a-7323-4426-a643-aa1b20350834"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757117789000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"01.16&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757120370000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"01.59&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757120371000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"01.59&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"01.59","title":"Trump says he is 'not talking about' regime change in Venezuela, as he reportedly weighs air strikes","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb62758f085f50533e8ac1","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> told reporters on Friday that he might send national guard troops to Portland, Oregon, apparently because he was misled about the scale of small protests outside an immigration detention facility there by a TV report which incorrectly presented video recorded during a protest in 2020 as having taken place in the city this summer.</p>","elementId":"9fd43b34-05ac-432b-b15f-4312ef342a76"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;I will say this, I watched today, I didn&rsquo;t know that was continuing to go on, but Portland is unbelievable, what&rsquo;s going on,&rdquo; <a href='\"https://youtu.be/_dTSbtfXwDg?si=EO06p1VSobt8fDJu&amp;t=1\"'>Trump said</a>. He then claimed, incorrectly, that he had seen video evidence of &ldquo;the destruction of the city&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"d327309c-6ce7-4529-9123-e74b0c364f12"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>In fact, a handful of protesters have demonstrated outside an Immigration and Customs Enforcement facility in a remote area of Portland along the south waterfront this year, but the scale of the protests, which attract dozens at most, is nothing like the 2020 protests that regularly drew thousands or tens of thousands of demonstrators to a central part of the city.</p>","elementId":"2ee95a3c-3f50-41a3-9b3c-d9ab4e2a1619"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Are you going into Portland?&rdquo; a reporter asked Trump.</p>","elementId":"525313f5-63da-4028-9fbb-8e7885d50b66"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Well, I&rsquo;m going to look at it now because I didn&rsquo;t know that was still going on; this has been going on for years,&rdquo; the president replied. He then explained how he had been misled into the entirely false belief that the large-scale protests from 2020 had continued.</p>","elementId":"bda29e8d-06f9-4ebd-aba3-e7708822bb95"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;ll be able to stop that very easily, but that was not on my list, Portland, but when I watched television last night, this has been going on,&rdquo; Trump said.</p>","elementId":"cb997646-4460-49a2-ae31-cb6d4a46e40a"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.VideoYoutubeBlockElement","source":"YouTube","originalUrl":"https://youtu.be/_dTSbtfXwDg?si=EO06p1VSobt8fDJu&amp;t=1","caption":"Donald Trump threatened to invade Portland, Oregon during an Oval Office event on Friday.","elementId":"f31b271e-ccc0-4e37-9937-8065cdac9871","width":854,"embedUrl":"https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_dTSbtfXwDg?start=1&amp;wmode=opaque&amp;feature=oembed&amp;start=1","role":"inline","url":"https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_dTSbtfXwDg","height":480,"sourceDomain":"youtube-nocookie.com","title":"U.S. President Donald Trump mentions Portland in Sept. 5, 2025 interview","isThirdPartyTracking":false},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The president did not cite the specific news report that he was basing his impression on, but his favorite channel, Fox News, broadcast <a href='\"https://x.com/KatieDaviscourt/status/1963819280249807236\"'>a report</a> on Thursday that mixed images of a recent protest in Portland, attended by dozens of protesters, with <a href='\"https://x.com/PDXzane/status/1284726088187310080\"'>a viral video clip</a> from 2020 of one protester, Christopher David, being pepper-sprayed in the face by a federal agent that was wrongly described as having been shot in June of this year.</p>","elementId":"aacfb8cf-c293-4650-996e-b9d2a2b7706b"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The report focused mainly on one protest outside the facility on Tuesday, attended by dozens of protesters who brought a guillotine as a prop before being doused with chemical agents by federal officers.</p>","elementId":"209da955-366e-48d7-8707-4715e8f238da"},{"displayCredit":true,"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.ImageBlockElement","role":"inline","media":{"allImages":[{"index":0,"fields":{"height":"3667","width":"5500"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/5500.jpg"},{"index":1,"fields":{"isMaster":"true","height":"3667","width":"5500"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg"},{"index":2,"fields":{"height":"1333","width":"2000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/2000.jpg"},{"index":3,"fields":{"height":"667","width":"1000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/1000.jpg"},{"index":4,"fields":{"height":"333","width":"500"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/500.jpg"},{"index":5,"fields":{"height":"93","width":"140"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/140.jpg"}]},"elementId":"9b97d199-0a76-44f9-9a3f-71f103bfb9ef","imageSources":[{"weighting":"inline","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=3a96c5caf7926ae8e9b5b4c9990a0daa","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=38eaca37874656e4ecce7aa3ba99376a","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=08d37e739347c390b74df321e3a7eb21","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=37fc973a55ad15ff85bd3beaecab93fd","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=eb9c9805c945516a1df671dd7242bac8","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=45b553f1f0c1796fd9c792d4f86d5172","width":890}]},{"weighting":"thumbnail","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=96bd454965063c6427c847392fd78a22","width":140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=c40409708ab655184a0863ccfdf339ef","width":280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=02ecb65d5bf5ee91f49c486ca80593f8","width":120},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=9fa548211e28b806b57e8c2be2f21c29","width":240}]},{"weighting":"supporting","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=db4c1c87e373f2de87baf3b55dfb8e1e","width":380},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=75c81467d011cf4fe86d9ebf952b469a","width":760},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=391759e93fb510c2990df9f3c7d821cc","width":300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=f42419b6b58452014da61395d01985e0","width":600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=3a96c5caf7926ae8e9b5b4c9990a0daa","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=38eaca37874656e4ecce7aa3ba99376a","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=08d37e739347c390b74df321e3a7eb21","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=37fc973a55ad15ff85bd3beaecab93fd","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=eb9c9805c945516a1df671dd7242bac8","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=45b553f1f0c1796fd9c792d4f86d5172","width":890}]},{"weighting":"showcase","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=f06a9d7315ebd74ad8ec033f951df736","width":860},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=5a9f47fa3030ac67df263bfb07b134b2","width":1720},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=13448e795a4a88ad60c3ee4d0a15854f","width":780},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=699cb614b1a23a1058e366052573282f","width":1560},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=3a96c5caf7926ae8e9b5b4c9990a0daa","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=38eaca37874656e4ecce7aa3ba99376a","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=08d37e739347c390b74df321e3a7eb21","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=37fc973a55ad15ff85bd3beaecab93fd","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=eb9c9805c945516a1df671dd7242bac8","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=45b553f1f0c1796fd9c792d4f86d5172","width":890}]},{"weighting":"halfwidth","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=3a96c5caf7926ae8e9b5b4c9990a0daa","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=38eaca37874656e4ecce7aa3ba99376a","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=08d37e739347c390b74df321e3a7eb21","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=37fc973a55ad15ff85bd3beaecab93fd","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=eb9c9805c945516a1df671dd7242bac8","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=45b553f1f0c1796fd9c792d4f86d5172","width":890}]},{"weighting":"immersive","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=b475071feec815c0a62c9ff576f991f5","width":1900},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=59cf57dcbac9d7d0d1cf768a8409a0b3","width":3800},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=e3c00eef7627ad5d0d9311425600b5ea","width":1300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=7fc03ed029bcf992f329efd88113fcc9","width":2600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=d9054fb116752511b2600ce137b5dd95","width":1140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=8800129ea16b5a2e55b1381bd7c1aae1","width":2280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=b2948abde1787caf29d236db4002d399","width":980},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=93eacfb200b0e52363addaf3e6246460","width":1960},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=9b9b06b8f27d109a07e5db6998d24345","width":740},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=25ff171af6f1fe4959a6515800ae814d","width":1480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=67f865ea40ca59433eba778c5b7170e4","width":660},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=82440645369fadeff2569ab0a681bd0c","width":1320},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=98adce32227331c7e84b9560bec37c25","width":480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=97818334148dc697e233592f23f295f0","width":960}]}],"data":{"alt":"People at protest","caption":"Dozens of protesters rallied against Donald Trump&rsquo;s immigration policies, outside an Ice detention facility in Portland on Tuesday.","credit":"Photograph: John Rudoff/Reuters"}},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;These are paid terrorists,&rdquo; the president said, once again spreading <a href='\"https://theintercept.com/2020/06/04/white-house-forced-retract-claim-viral-videos-prove-antifa-plotting-violence/\"'>a baseless conspiracy theory</a> his administration amplified about anti-fascist protesters in 2020.</p>","elementId":"d6ef4b49-4b21-4b68-9373-7cddbfebcee5"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;These are paid agitators, these are professional. I watched that last night, I&rsquo;m very good at this stuff. These are paid agitators, they get paid money by radical left groups,&rdquo; the president claimed. He then went on to suggest that well-printed signs displayed by some protesters proved his theory.</p>","elementId":"41831af5-da5d-40bc-8154-22afbcb851c5"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;These are paid agitators and they&rsquo;re very dangerous for our country and when we go there, if we go to Portland, we&rsquo;re going to wipe &lsquo;em out. They&rsquo;re going to be gone. They won&rsquo;t even stand to fight. They will not stay there. They&rsquo;ve ruined that city.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"3f37da2a-9ebb-487d-b98b-1adb57f19f0b"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s like living in hell,&rdquo; the president said, describing an imaginary version of Portland that bears no resemblance to the actual city, in which fences around the federal courthouse that was the scene of mass protests in 2020 have now been removed and the central police headquarters no longer has boarded up windows.</p>","elementId":"9e6d2084-3c6c-4fb0-a0d3-4b5c134782e8"}],"attributes":{"pinned":true,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757110901000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"23.21&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757115573000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"00.39&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757114680000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"00.24&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"00.24","title":"Misled by video of 2020 protests shown on Fox, Trump threatens to invade Portland and 'wipe out' protesters","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb58d68f08638a14b785fb","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Asked about Florida&rsquo;s move to lift mandates on vaccinations for schoolchildren, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> said that officials have to &ldquo;be careful&rdquo; in removing access to vaccines he described as &ldquo;amazing&rdquo; and &ldquo;incredible&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"8d4da494-09e3-469d-8788-d40379ee7053"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;I think we have to be very careful&rdquo; Trump said in the Oval Office on Friday. &ldquo;Look, you have some vaccines that are so amazing. The polio vaccine, I happen to think, is amazing. A lot of people think that Covid is amazing. You know, there are many people that believe strongly in that. But you have some vaccines that are so incredible and I think that you have to be very careful when you say that some people don&rsquo;t have to be vaccinated&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"7af754b5-b8ac-4cd3-a75b-1ed69e0fbff9"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump said that the position adopted by Florida was &ldquo;a tough stance&rdquo;, given the risks to the community by unvaccinated children attending school.</p>","elementId":"38d00985-b386-4526-a357-90a04ca4cd6d"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Look, you have vaccines that work; they just pure and simple work, they&rsquo;re not controversial at all, and I think those vaccines should be used, otherwise some people are going to catch it and they endanger other people&rdquo;, the president said.</p>","elementId":"2fec134b-897b-4cb5-a011-d265f6704b9b"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;When you don&rsquo;t have controversy at all, I think people should take it&rdquo;, Trump added.</p>","elementId":"6dfe2787-69f1-45bd-9d6f-5dae1c5f29c8"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>His remarks come one day after his anti-vaccine health secretary, <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong>, told senators that he agrees with the views of an Israeli management professor he recently appointed to a key CDC vaccine advisory panel, <strong>Retsef Levi</strong>, who has said that mRNA vaccines against Covid-19 are deadly and should no longer be used.</p>","elementId":"99c0b5a3-92eb-403a-a279-724d8f663fab"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>At the same hearing, Bill Cassidy, a Republican senator who is also a medical doctor, suggested that Trump deserves a Nobel prize for Operation Warp Speed, which sped up the development of mRNA vaccines against Covid-19 in 2020.</p>","elementId":"17998bde-cb58-487e-9e44-b3ba10d2a91b"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757108438000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"22.40&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757109600000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"23.00&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757109419000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"22.56&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"22.56","title":"Trump says US must be 'very careful' in removing mandates for 'vaccines that are so amazing'","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb50fa8f085f50533e8a4a","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> just announced that the US will host the 2026 meeting of the G20 at his privately owned Doral golf course and spa in Miami.</p>","elementId":"6ecc9e5f-ec29-458f-9c64-deb2e1d504a0"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The president was joined by Miami&rsquo;s mayor, <strong>Francis Suarez</strong>, for the announcement in the Oval Office.</p>","elementId":"b681cc14-d070-45f8-8139-fffb34dd4a34"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump initially did not mention that his Doral resort was the location, but confirmed it in response to a question from a reporter. The president then quickly moved to downplay concerns that he was using his office for personal profit, claiming that &ldquo;we will not make any money on it&rdquo; and that the location was chosen because &ldquo;everybody wants it there&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"899f5afe-a7f1-4804-96e5-25a1499a0d6a"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The president was asked if he intends to invite Russia&rsquo;s president, Vladimir Putin, to attend as an observer. He initially said that he had not yet considered that possibility, but has previously claimed that excluding Russia, over its initial invasion of Ukraine in 2014, was a mistake.</p>","elementId":"f11fb4f8-f302-426f-88f7-ea74cfbbf4e6"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Minutes later, Trump was asked again and said that both Putin and China&rsquo;s leader, Xi Jinping, were welcome to attend as observers. &ldquo;I&rsquo;d love them to, if they want to&rdquo;, the president said. &ldquo;If they want to, we can certainly talk&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"6f5e7428-3f3d-4efa-9481-f9bbe9f283ab"},{"displayCredit":true,"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.ImageBlockElement","role":"inline","media":{"allImages":[{"index":0,"fields":{"height":"4000","width":"6000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/6000.jpg"},{"index":1,"fields":{"isMaster":"true","height":"4000","width":"6000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg"},{"index":2,"fields":{"height":"1333","width":"2000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/2000.jpg"},{"index":3,"fields":{"height":"667","width":"1000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/1000.jpg"},{"index":4,"fields":{"height":"333","width":"500"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/500.jpg"},{"index":5,"fields":{"height":"93","width":"140"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/140.jpg"}]},"elementId":"6d3d91b5-235a-4c1c-813b-9e63b9e58795","imageSources":[{"weighting":"inline","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8d9c6c9ba7b0a1dcd609cc9f9486e272","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=902b3b8538cfb4b20bff278909f75524","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=d4532b1b956dbd12cc7cd4db8903e5a6","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=bb889ca547810abab32adf6e47ec6290","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=ca7185e45fd589a90d1102db73cfa058","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=d8ad5d88b1db9d11dd531df760a12d2e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"thumbnail","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=65f956abb70fcf08fff685b05cf2112c","width":140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=84c9e6c579d3ca147e8295a1d68a6031","width":280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=e98af13e0b501bc8d0e3081bcc113014","width":120},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=ff9b43947f873a2460b6892976ccc5bc","width":240}]},{"weighting":"supporting","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=80298dc7f0d7cad6dc3d856995726cec","width":380},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=635458a68b607090b7a0c961380c21f8","width":760},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=34d7dafc817f18b5f5587cdcdfb48ea7","width":300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=e5397b885d478b178b42a35875dc2092","width":600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8d9c6c9ba7b0a1dcd609cc9f9486e272","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=902b3b8538cfb4b20bff278909f75524","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=d4532b1b956dbd12cc7cd4db8903e5a6","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=bb889ca547810abab32adf6e47ec6290","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=ca7185e45fd589a90d1102db73cfa058","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=d8ad5d88b1db9d11dd531df760a12d2e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"showcase","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=f0449b4a5f29f49cf257fc5195887938","width":860},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=105618adcec6beeff1ef0353a9f1b967","width":1720},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=19782dc1c41c66e5c58300499e9646fe","width":780},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=4124aa6d3f1b4c6d02594fdca6678a2e","width":1560},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8d9c6c9ba7b0a1dcd609cc9f9486e272","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=902b3b8538cfb4b20bff278909f75524","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=d4532b1b956dbd12cc7cd4db8903e5a6","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=bb889ca547810abab32adf6e47ec6290","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=ca7185e45fd589a90d1102db73cfa058","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=d8ad5d88b1db9d11dd531df760a12d2e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"halfwidth","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8d9c6c9ba7b0a1dcd609cc9f9486e272","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=902b3b8538cfb4b20bff278909f75524","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=d4532b1b956dbd12cc7cd4db8903e5a6","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=bb889ca547810abab32adf6e47ec6290","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=ca7185e45fd589a90d1102db73cfa058","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=d8ad5d88b1db9d11dd531df760a12d2e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"immersive","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=9672f43161d7c062ac4c1f649868b39f","width":1900},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=a6eb1c679c807a06f6a98876e4280948","width":3800},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=69817f47fb4b38a0dcf7feab704e1742","width":1300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=b05e53408c58be8ed06a734c8c33bc1b","width":2600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=747e13fb0b359e654a37c05156beb08b","width":1140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=17770e11ffae4cee50ce3de13d537ae3","width":2280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8fcc8ceb2056aa08c275bee840f1fc1e","width":980},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=eb5b1ef081f6859db4135772d0a1f5eb","width":1960},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=70524178df6167e4fd3a0a04117daa7c","width":740},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=84647b9c74d8a6b63ba1bf16522d8836","width":1480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8a776cb16078bbdd47575845a322a5f9","width":660},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=2bc56fcb8456965f669468974dd62258","width":1320},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=6e4c94424a163b53d26a753ab8c0674f","width":480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=cad0b12beaf100bf6f1b3a8d524f9d3b","width":960}]}],"data":{"alt":"Donald Trump announced on Friday that the US will host the G20 summit 2026 at his Doral resort in Miami. He was joined by Miami&rsquo;s mayor, Francis Suarez.","caption":"Trump announced that the US will host the G20 summit 2026 at his Doral resort in Miami. He was joined by Miami&rsquo;s mayor, Francis Suarez.","credit":"Photograph: Brian Snyder/Reuters"}}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757106426000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"22.07&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757108380000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"22.39&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757108049000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"22.34&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"22.34","title":"Trump announces US will host 2026 G20 meeting at his Doral resort in Miami","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb49ef8f087e152e27f78b","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Speaking to reporters in the Oval Office, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> just claimed that &ldquo;a lot of illegal aliens, some not the best of people&rdquo; were working at a factory in Georgia raided by immigration officers on Friday, resulting in nearly 500 arrests.</p>","elementId":"747a0ae0-6715-4ea4-8e84-0ce792113207"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>However, a warrant for the raid on the HL-GA battery factory, which is being built to make car batteries for South Korean electric vehicles, identified just four &ldquo;target persons&rdquo;. The warrant was obtained and <a href='\"https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26084943-hyundaisearchwarrant/\"'>posted online by Politico</a>.</p>","elementId":"0526f491-a28e-4e15-ad62-2c61007ef27c"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757104623000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"21.37&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757106654000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"22.10&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757106282000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"22.04&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"22.04","title":"Trump claims 'a lot of illegal aliens' worked at raided Georgia plant, but warrant targeted just four","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb44fb8f085f50533e89e5","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> signed an executive order on Friday authorizing the US Department of Defense to refer to itself as the &ldquo;Department of War&rdquo;, as part of an attempt to formalize his rebranding effort without the legally required act of Congress.</p>","elementId":"70ab9657-973d-4284-8891-1191d4637278"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>According to a draft White House factsheet seen by the Guardian on Thursday, the order designates &ldquo;Department of War&rdquo; as a &ldquo;secondary title&rdquo;, as a way to get around the need for congressional approval to formally rename a federal agency.</p>","elementId":"2145fc8c-d123-4b93-9c50-5cb04dd40a84"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The move, to have the executive branch use a name for the department Trump called &ldquo;much more appropriate&rdquo;, restores a name <a href='\"https://www.defense.gov/Multimedia/Experience/The-History-of-the-Department-of-Defense/#jul1947\"'>used until 1947</a>, when Congress merged the previously independent war department and navy department with the air force into a single organization, known as the National Military Establishment. In 1949, Congress <a href='\"https://www.defense.gov/Multimedia/Experience/The-History-of-the-Department-of-Defense/#1949\"'>changed the name</a> of the National Military Establishment to the Department of Defense, and made the army, navy and air force secretaries subordinate to a single, cabinet-level secretary of defense.</p>","elementId":"cad3abc0-53ba-462a-8233-d61805f49843"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Referring to the creation of the defense department in 1949, <a href='\"https://x.com/cspan/status/1964064319714300314\"'>the president said</a>: &ldquo;We decided to go woke and we changed the name to Department of Defense, so we&rsquo;re going Department of War&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"9aec6aaa-db3a-47f4-aebc-43f13b476b08"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump also introduced the defense secretary, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/pete-hegseth\"'>Pete Hegseth</a>, as &ldquo;our secretary of war&rdquo; and claimed that the name change &ldquo;really it has to do with winning&rdquo;, suggesting that the US military had somehow been hampered by the choice &ldquo;to be politically correct, or wokey&rdquo; and, as a result, failed to win &ldquo;wars that we would&rsquo;ve won easily&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"bc1f0f2d-5c9c-4f6f-b479-9f346fc40061"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The draft White House factsheet on Trump&rsquo;s rebranding initiative implicitly acknowledged that only Congress can formally change the department&rsquo;s name, saying that the order would authorize the defense secretary to propose legislation that would make the change permanent.</p>","elementId":"04a49dac-5b45-4822-93dc-0873aa5ce408"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757103355000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"21.15&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757106275000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"22.04&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757104355000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"21.32&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"21.32","title":"Trump signs executive order directing Department of Defense to call itself 'Department of War'","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb40da8f08638a14b7855e","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Eric Adams, the sitting mayor of New York, has <a href='\"https://x.com/bern_hogan/status/1964050160775795120\"'>just announced</a> a hastily scheduled event to begin 30 minutes from now in which he will &ldquo;make an important announcement regarding the future of his campaign&rdquo;. The event is scheduled for 4.30pm ET.</p>","elementId":"d8bc0e64-9742-4336-8d52-16bdce5f7092"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Adams, who is running as an independent and trails in the polls, has previously <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/03/eric-adams-trump-new-york-mayor\"'>denied reports</a> that he is in talks with the White House over taking a role in the Trump administration in exchange for ending his apparently doomed re-election campaign.</p>","elementId":"2163ab0d-c590-4db0-9a16-808e255583c3"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>At a dinner with tech industry leaders last night, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> denied that he is encouraging Adams to drop out of the race to help New York&rsquo;s former governor, Andrew Cuomo, defeat Zohran Mamdani, the 33-year-old democratic socialist who is the frontrunner to be elected mayor in November. Trump then immediately said that he would like Adams to drop out for that reason.</p>","elementId":"d5b1b015-b28b-4638-a869-7e20879927d1"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The New York Times <a href='\"https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/05/nyregion/eric-adams-saudi-arabia-ambassador.html\"'>reported</a> on Friday that Adams met in person with Trump&rsquo;s friend and diplomatic envoy Steve Witkoff to discuss the possibility of being nominated as US ambassador to Saudi Arabia.</p>","elementId":"72f57f96-daca-4ede-b683-e1c84d8c579f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Last year, federal prosecutors <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/26/eric-adams-bribes-turkey\"'>accused</a> members of the Turkish government of a years-long influence campaign to cultivate and secure favors from Adams.</p>","elementId":"a883d266-c5db-45f0-80b9-4b232f5077fc"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>In the federal indictment, the US attorney for New York&rsquo;s southern district alleged that government officials and business leaders with ties to Recep Tayyip Erdo&#287;an, the Turkish president, showered Adams with thousands in illegal foreign campaign donations and free or heavily discounted luxury hotel stays and flights around the world.</p>","elementId":"44949ae3-c18c-49cf-948d-2209c1d3dcb4"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Charges against Adams were dropped by the Trump justice department this year, over the strong objections of prosecutors who claimed that there was an explicit quid pro quo arrangement in which the mayor would cooperate with federal immigration enforcement in the city in return for corruption charges being dropped.</p>","elementId":"36c6af95-dcd3-4029-867c-31edc6d18000"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Should Adams become the US ambassador to Saudi Arabia, he would oversee diplomacy with the kingdom whose de-facto leader, crown prince Mohammed bin Salman, US intelligence believes approved the 2018 murder of the Washington Post journalist Jamal Khashoggi in Turkey.</p>","elementId":"e32b71c6-7734-441e-867f-f11d26a28ad1"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757102299000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"20.58&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757106321000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"22.05&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757102932000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"21.08&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"21.08","title":"New York's mayor, Eric Adams to make 'important announcement regarding the future of his campaign'","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb3b0f8f08638a14b7852e","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> plans to announce executive orders shortly in the Oval Office, with the theme we know most about so far being an instruction to <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/trump-defense-war-department\"'>rename</a> the Department of Defense the <strong>&ldquo;Department of War&rdquo;</strong>.</p>","elementId":"8a7cbda7-bbfd-4a10-a187-0e16bfaf854f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Until then, here&rsquo;s a quick recap of some of the day&rsquo;s key developments:</p>","elementId":"9708c7ae-ebec-4efe-9fe7-4239b46db049"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<ul>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Trump</strong> criticized the <strong>European Union</strong>&rsquo;s <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/sep/05/google-fined-european-union\"'>decision to fine</a> <strong>Google</strong> $3.46bn over antitrust concerns and threatened a wider trade probe against the EU in response to the move.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>Health secretary <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong> plans to announce that use of Kenvue&rsquo;s popular over-the-counter pain medication <strong>Tylenol</strong> in pregnant women is potentially linked to autism, without including evidence for the claims, <a href='\"https://www.wsj.com/health/healthcare/rfk-jr-hhs-to-link-autism-to-tylenol-use-in-pregnancy-and-folate-deficiencies-e3acbb4c?mod=hp_lead_pos2\"'>the Wall Street Journal reported</a>, citing people familiar with the matter.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong><a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/state-of-georgia\"'>Georgia</a></strong> is about to become the eighth state to send national guard troops to <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/washington-dc\"'>Washington DC</a> to support <strong>Trump</strong>&rsquo;s federal law enforcement big foot operation there, as the US capital <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/national-guard-washington-dc-lawsuit-trump-administration\"'>sues the administration</a> over its actions.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Most of the 475 people</strong> arrested in a massive Immigration and Customs Enforcement (Ice) raid at a Hyundai factory construction site in southern Georgia <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb18108f085f50533e8841#block-68bb18108f085f50533e8841\"'>are Korean</a> nationals.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>The federal Ice raid</strong> is being <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb17068f08638a14b783ae#block-68bb17068f08638a14b783ae\"'>described</a> as the biggest single Department of Homeland Security (DHS, the parent agency of Ice) enforcement operation at one side in the department&rsquo;s history. The DHS was created after <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/september11\"'>9/11</a>.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Treasury secretary Scott Bessent</strong> <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb12238f08638a14b7836c#block-68bb12238f08638a14b7836c\"'>called for</a> renewed scrutiny of the Federal Reserve, including its power to set interest rates, as the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a> continues its efforts to exert control over the US central bank.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Vladimir Putin</strong> <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb032e8f087e152e27f403#block-68bb032e8f087e152e27f403\"'>has said</a> any western troops placed in Ukraine would be &ldquo;legitimate targets&rdquo; for Russian strikes, upping the stakes for Kyiv as Donald Trump&rsquo;s efforts to forge a peace deal show little sign that are any closer to success.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Trump</strong> <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bab3fe8f08305da53f837f#block-68bab3fe8f08305da53f837f\"'>is sending</a> 10 F-35 stealth fighter jets to <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/puerto-rico\"'>Puerto Rico</a> to bolster US military operations against drug cartels in the Caribbean region. The action to send jets to be based in the US territory follows a <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/02/trump-venezuela-boat-lethal-strike\"'>deadly US missile strike</a> on Tuesday on a boat that the administration insisted was carrying 11 Venezuelan drug traffickers.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>And the big economics news of the day was that <strong>the US added just 22,000 jobs in August</strong>, continuing the slowdown amid Trump&rsquo;s tariff policy.</p></li>\n</ul>","elementId":"111e07b7-ace4-489d-9984-6ef953c913e4"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":false,"summary":true},"blockCreatedOn":1757100815000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"20.33&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757101107000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"20.38&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757101108000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"20.38&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"20.38","title":"The day so far","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb36fa8f087e152e27f6da","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> has criticized the <strong>European Union</strong>&rsquo;s decision to fine <strong>Google</strong> $3.46bn over antitrust concerns and threatened a wider trade probe against the EU in response to the move.</p>","elementId":"61942bba-0d7b-430a-b272-3d50bd9fd2ed"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;We cannot let this happen to brilliant and unprecedented American Ingenuity and, if it does, I will be forced to start a Section 301 proceeding to nullify the unfair penalties being charged to these Taxpaying American Companies,&rdquo; the president wrote on his Truth Social platform.</p>","elementId":"21fbad41-4303-4e0e-af06-f3aeb5b597db"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Google&rsquo;s fine for <strong>breaching the EU&rsquo;s competition rules by favoring its own digital advertising services</strong> marks the fourth such antitrust penalty for the company as well as a retreat from previous threats to break up the tech giant.</p>","elementId":"ba663038-15c8-407b-acf1-719e73deae5c"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The <strong>European Commission</strong>, the 27-nation bloc&rsquo;s executive branch and top antitrust enforcer, also <strong>ordered the US company to end its &ldquo;self-preferencing practices&rdquo;</strong> and take steps to <strong>stop &ldquo;conflicts of interest&rdquo; along the advertising technology supply chain</strong>.</p>","elementId":"a567569e-250e-4f93-ac5e-0321b5c6a777"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The commission&rsquo;s investigation found that <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/technology/google\"'>Google</a> had <strong>&ldquo;abused&rdquo; its dominant positions</strong> in the ad-technology ecosystem.</p>","elementId":"808acc9f-ae38-4cdf-ae4c-eee12f07880f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Google said the decision was &ldquo;wrong&rdquo; and that it would appeal.</p>","elementId":"e8f24f7f-59e0-4662-b609-4862fbd7a754"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"EU fines Google nearly &euro;3bn for &lsquo;abusing&rsquo; dominant position in ad tech","elementId":"a65f21ad-a2ea-4375-a322-639e9fb3238a","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/sep/05/google-fined-european-union"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757099770000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"20.16&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757101536000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"20.45&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757099805000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"20.16&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"20.16","title":"Trump threatens trade investigation over EU antitrust fine against Google","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb2da28f085f50533e88fe","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Health secretary <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong> plans to announce that use of Kenvue&rsquo;s popular over-the-counter pain medication <strong>Tylenol</strong> in pregnant women is potentially linked to autism, without including evidence for the claims, <a href='\"https://www.wsj.com/health/healthcare/rfk-jr-hhs-to-link-autism-to-tylenol-use-in-pregnancy-and-folate-deficiencies-e3acbb4c?mod=hp_lead_pos2\"'>the Wall Street Journal reported</a>, citing people familiar with the matter.</p>","elementId":"c9b387e1-e1da-440e-ac6d-dc6d3c9ea002"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Kennedy, in a report, will also suggest a medicine derived from folate called folinic acid can be used to treat symptoms of autism in some people, the WSJ reported.</p>","elementId":"f32df350-d623-46c4-ba0d-abbab32a87a9"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Tylenol, whose active ingredient is <strong>acetaminophen</strong>, is a widely used pain reliever, including by pregnant women.</p>","elementId":"5aab092f-3e17-4c19-8504-536fc9259a35"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The report, expected this month from the US Department of Health and Human Services, is likely to highlight low levels of folate, an important vitamin, and Tylenol taken during pregnancy, as well as other potential causes of autism, the report said.</p>","elementId":"3248adc2-01d4-4033-81ec-46bbc816cf29"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The health department and Kenvue did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p>","elementId":"f504710b-2170-4ed4-a410-f2fef9adb56b"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>It is not the first time Kenvue or J&amp;J have faced questions about the link between Tylenol and the condition. In 2023, a judge rejected claims the drug causes autism if mothers take it during pregnancy.</p>","elementId":"53e341a7-d7d4-4e3a-9232-3586aa708766"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The <strong>American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists</strong> says Tylenol is <a href='\"https://www.acog.org/womens-health/faqs/headaches-and-pregnancy\"'>safe to use in pregnancy</a>, though it recommends pregnant women consult their doctors before using it, as with all medicines.</p>","elementId":"49b085d7-ffd8-4840-bfb1-85c2682f43bc"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Children&rsquo;s Health Defense</strong>, the anti-vaccine group formerly headed by Kennedy, has posted several times in recent weeks on social media site X about the potential link between Tylenol and autism.</p>","elementId":"c977813c-b44c-4ee0-83e4-868afb7b099c"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757097378000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"19.36&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757099512000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"20.11&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757097718000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"19.41&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"19.41","title":"Kennedy and HHS to link Tylenol use in pregnancy to autism &ndash; report","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb280e8f08638a14b7846e","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong><a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/state-of-georgia\"'>Georgia</a></strong> is about to become the eighth state to send national guard troops to <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/washington-dc\"'>Washington DC</a> to support <strong>Donald Trump</strong>&rsquo;s federal law enforcement big foot operation there, as the US capital <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/national-guard-washington-dc-lawsuit-trump-administration\"'>sues the administration</a> over its actions.</p>","elementId":"c385d349-02f5-4f49-ab0c-3488c32c48a6"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Georgia governor <strong>Brian Kemp</strong> announced he would be sending 316 members of the state national guard to Washington later this month, in the latest indication that Trump&rsquo;s law enforcement action there will drag on, the Associated Press reports.</p>","elementId":"8dc34e4a-b0b7-4825-8839-311447455055"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Kemp, a Republican, said he will mobilize the roughly 300 troops in mid-September to take part in Trump&rsquo;s DC operation to relieve soldiers from elsewhere who deployed earlier.</p>","elementId":"e2e2ffb0-cd16-4040-9b97-0b041d06b6a1"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.BlockquoteBlockElement","html":"<blockquote>\n<p>Georgia is proud to stand with the Trump administration in its mission to ensure the security and beauty of our nation&rsquo;s capital,&rdquo; Kemp said in a statement.</p>\n</blockquote>","elementId":"f1aa25d1-ecc4-4c47-b57f-2ba4cbcffc4d"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump initially called up 800 members of the District of Columbia national guard to assist federal law enforcement in his unilateral action to impose federal resources on DC with the stated goal of cracking down on crime, homelessness and illegal immigration. Since then, seven other Republican-led states have sent troops &ndash; Louisiana, Mississippi, Ohio, South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee and West Virginia.</p>","elementId":"e90bbdcf-dfc6-47e7-939d-e0ed0c2375d5"},{"displayCredit":true,"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.ImageBlockElement","role":"inline","media":{"allImages":[{"index":0,"fields":{"height":"4000","width":"6000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/6000.jpg"},{"index":1,"fields":{"isMaster":"true","height":"4000","width":"6000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg"},{"index":2,"fields":{"height":"1333","width":"2000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/2000.jpg"},{"index":3,"fields":{"height":"667","width":"1000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/1000.jpg"},{"index":4,"fields":{"height":"333","width":"500"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/500.jpg"},{"index":5,"fields":{"height":"93","width":"140"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/140.jpg"}]},"elementId":"7990f910-bdc4-43dd-b424-8b3b4c1cd305","imageSources":[{"weighting":"inline","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=c39e29b21792196fdbe9af7a8736be7b","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=3aceff0d20cf1e058d97fbd4e5822c45","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=df46345f44f550fa90da3cd182fec9a0","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1c9478c81c01eae5899da53a786b0b5e","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=70c394b96c8495264a5d5f598ca05b12","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=f65b1cc90503262c5ba5df5fe5dde814","width":890}]},{"weighting":"thumbnail","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=f51b6446057c6ba7f051ec0787dd063a","width":140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=c227eef12c3916e2e7b5ef281fff5af6","width":280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=f11b4c29608d95ecec4259de25d8992b","width":120},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=e907e7c98e9b4a96d36965fbf3cb610f","width":240}]},{"weighting":"supporting","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=36a605a2ed7d5a27b14f8c053625325d","width":380},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=c008464c76bfc834080f2b66b6cb215e","width":760},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=2992c3e3291f310987c34b4625058ffa","width":300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=8e1f4b646b85fdb6969306d0d55aa5ee","width":600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=c39e29b21792196fdbe9af7a8736be7b","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=3aceff0d20cf1e058d97fbd4e5822c45","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=df46345f44f550fa90da3cd182fec9a0","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1c9478c81c01eae5899da53a786b0b5e","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=70c394b96c8495264a5d5f598ca05b12","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=f65b1cc90503262c5ba5df5fe5dde814","width":890}]},{"weighting":"showcase","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=c519ffe7aefd5e19d7effdcc9664f089","width":860},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=af5125579cb0d149dcf2259a963ab6b8","width":1720},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=5f3777a5334f8dfa020f5da45ee0f4a7","width":780},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=63278ae6ca32b15ca0f02255438d0eab","width":1560},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=c39e29b21792196fdbe9af7a8736be7b","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=3aceff0d20cf1e058d97fbd4e5822c45","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=df46345f44f550fa90da3cd182fec9a0","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1c9478c81c01eae5899da53a786b0b5e","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=70c394b96c8495264a5d5f598ca05b12","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=f65b1cc90503262c5ba5df5fe5dde814","width":890}]},{"weighting":"halfwidth","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=c39e29b21792196fdbe9af7a8736be7b","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=3aceff0d20cf1e058d97fbd4e5822c45","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=df46345f44f550fa90da3cd182fec9a0","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1c9478c81c01eae5899da53a786b0b5e","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=70c394b96c8495264a5d5f598ca05b12","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=f65b1cc90503262c5ba5df5fe5dde814","width":890}]},{"weighting":"immersive","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=44edc3f44229212456fab2a43b1214b6","width":1900},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=a93d3cd78e7ffe2ff9eebf1611422bf9","width":3800},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=84aaf5c2ee391bd9645663a223d0e7dd","width":1300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=09262c24055867de079d30ab787d53bb","width":2600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=5630f26c2524d0e5542e06c5b672faaa","width":1140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=5f3cc77d37da573eee06ecfb92606394","width":2280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=a4d0094394e4d7c68d9411557f4bb66b","width":980},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=e44d76a2ac1999686ec43a8d93e93a86","width":1960},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=168b62fdaeb8729a194ceb4c9dbad652","width":740},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=bec0be5a3ded83a21d20125984034979","width":1480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=ba043778eff5a6ffa95dc96a28f6bbd3","width":660},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=7b68ba7837891e6433f6aa94b2950b43","width":1320},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=5b11d2a5863db27dd5384da002cd9264","width":480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=7073b851fb80e69588c07fb88c52a9e1","width":960}]}],"data":{"alt":"Train at station","caption":"National guard military police at L&rsquo;Enfant Plaza station in Washington.","credit":"Photograph: Kent Nishimura/Getty Images"}}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757095950000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"19.12&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757099609000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"20.13&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757096547000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"19.22&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"19.22","title":"Georgia to send national guard troops to Washington","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb1aae8f085f50533e886c","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Hello, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/us-politics\"'>US politics</a> live blog readers, it&rsquo;s another busy Friday and there is much more to come, so stay with the Guardian for all the relevant news as it happens. Here&rsquo;s where things stand:</p>","elementId":"ff81af2a-7f13-4d0a-9d96-754f4b430474"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<ul>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Most of the 475 people</strong> arrested in a massive Immigration and Customs Enforcement (Ice) raid at a Hyundai factory construction site in southern Georgia <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb18108f085f50533e8841#block-68bb18108f085f50533e8841\"'>are Korean</a> nationals.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>The federal Ice raid</strong> is being <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb17068f08638a14b783ae#block-68bb17068f08638a14b783ae\"'>described</a> as the biggest single Department of Homeland Security (DHS, the parent agency of Ice) enforcement operation at one side in the department&rsquo;s history. The DHS was created after <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/september11\"'>9/11</a>.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Treasury secretary Scott Bessent</strong> <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb12238f08638a14b7836c#block-68bb12238f08638a14b7836c\"'>called for</a> renewed scrutiny of the Federal Reserve, including its power to set interest rates, as the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a> continues its efforts to exert control over the US central bank.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Vladimir Putin</strong> <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb032e8f087e152e27f403#block-68bb032e8f087e152e27f403\"'>has said</a> any western troops placed in Ukraine would be &ldquo;legitimate targets&rdquo; for Russian strikes, upping the stakes for Kyiv as Donald Trump&rsquo;s efforts to forge a peace deal show little sign that are any closer to success.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bab3fe8f08305da53f837f#block-68bab3fe8f08305da53f837f\"'>is sending</a> 10 F-35 stealth fighter jets to <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/puerto-rico\"'>Puerto Rico</a> to bolster US military operations against drug cartels in the Caribbean region. The action to send jets to be based in the US territory follows a <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/02/trump-venezuela-boat-lethal-strike\"'>deadly US missile strike</a> on Tuesday on a boat that the administration insisted was carrying 11 Venezuelan drug traffickers.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>US jobs report</strong>. Our sister live blog run by the business team in London has closed now, so here&rsquo;s <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/sep/05/us-jobs-report-august-tariffs\"'>our story</a> on the big economics news of the day, that the US added just 22,000 jobs in August, continuing the slowdown amid Trump tariffs.</p></li>\n</ul>","elementId":"7d1a85c2-29d0-47f9-8365-d2de8d0339a3"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757092526000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"18.15&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757096468000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"19.21&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757093352000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"18.29&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"18.29","title":"Summary","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb18108f085f50533e8841","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The arrested workers were being held at Ice&rsquo;s Folkston detention facility in Georgia, Schrank said. <strong>Most of the 475 people are Korean nationals</strong>, he said.</p>","elementId":"d5c0c9e9-4b2e-48f1-906a-92bb96e1600d"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Local Korean media said roughly 300 people detained were South Korean nationals.</p>","elementId":"3309effb-34d2-4be0-aeac-d3f99d3c60c4"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;<strong>It is our understanding that none of those detained is directly employed by Hyundai Motor Co.</strong> We prioritize the safety and well-being of everyone working at the site and comply with all laws and regulations wherever we operate,&rdquo; a Hyundai spokesperson said in a statement provided to Reuters.</p>","elementId":"f240a7d3-82f8-44d9-b050-b682932e9555"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757091856000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"18.04&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757096510000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"19.21&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757091901000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"18.05&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"18.05","title":"Most of 475 people arrested at Hyundai facility are Korean nationals","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb17068f08638a14b783ae","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>With some 475 workers arrested, according to US immigration officials, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/05/immigration-ice-raid-hyundai-georgia\"'>the Ice raid</a> at the Georgia<strong> Hyundai facility</strong> is the largest single-site enforcement operation in the Department of Homeland Security&rsquo;s history, Reuters notes.</p>","elementId":"26c1de6d-daf1-4879-baf2-2ebfdbf868cf"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757091590000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"17.59&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757092143000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"18.09&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757091655000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"18.00&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"18.00","title":"Hyundai facility raid is largest single-site operation in DHS history","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb12238f08638a14b7836c","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Treasury secretary Scott Bessent earlier called for renewed scrutiny of the Federal Reserve, <strong>including its power to set interest rates</strong>, as the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a> continues its efforts to exert control over the US central bank, whose insulation from short-term political pressures is widely seen as key to its effectiveness.</p>","elementId":"794af253-fbb0-4611-be0b-e725482b464f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;There must also be an honest, independent, nonpartisan review of the entire institution, including monetary policy, regulation, communications, staffing and research,&rdquo; Bessent wrote in the Wall Street Journal.</p>","elementId":"96365dc0-ca1a-4c6a-803f-5b3f863612dc"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>He called for the Fed to leave bank supervision to other governmental authorities and to &ldquo;scale back the distortions it causes in the economy&rdquo;, including by bond purchases made outside of true crisis conditions.</p>","elementId":"c7f4d934-3de4-41a5-a0ad-f92a5616244a"},{"displayCredit":true,"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.ImageBlockElement","role":"inline","media":{"allImages":[{"index":0,"fields":{"height":"2937","width":"4406"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/4406.jpg"},{"index":1,"fields":{"isMaster":"true","height":"2937","width":"4406"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg"},{"index":2,"fields":{"height":"1333","width":"2000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/2000.jpg"},{"index":3,"fields":{"height":"667","width":"1000"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/1000.jpg"},{"index":4,"fields":{"height":"333","width":"500"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/500.jpg"},{"index":5,"fields":{"height":"93","width":"140"},"mediaType":"Image","mimeType":"image/jpeg","url":"https://media.guim.co.uk/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/140.jpg"}]},"elementId":"e9ba3e40-e258-4d4e-bc1b-bc4c9d67d31a","imageSources":[{"weighting":"inline","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1d9dcefa3662e44ad17d660c362327db","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=5b0ddcf5e026602940ed2e1ff2197f0e","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=6413ea0fccfb4906299d15bfd2e4178d","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=0810f46d23927d92807cdd60efad3a58","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=0da5fa0ac624ab7df03178c89ccd0360","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1823f3b6b62655bb4424b98f6cc6851e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"thumbnail","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=28b1ee3b4ee7f9312acc25a853d1053c","width":140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=b3096fdb073c3ce261ab76c069010da9","width":280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1370507b7932eb3982f16e4ab81e9702","width":120},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=120&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=a18d9546bb1788f8be482fd24891d577","width":240}]},{"weighting":"supporting","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=42fc707c16fd4a220b30791c77cd79b3","width":380},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=380&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=a4959ff71184ff58ad2997f54c2891cf","width":760},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=00eedc7c58b02a77a1d663bd4835fbcc","width":300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=09df0e9541bd363cea5080ad29c733f6","width":600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1d9dcefa3662e44ad17d660c362327db","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=5b0ddcf5e026602940ed2e1ff2197f0e","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=6413ea0fccfb4906299d15bfd2e4178d","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=0810f46d23927d92807cdd60efad3a58","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=0da5fa0ac624ab7df03178c89ccd0360","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1823f3b6b62655bb4424b98f6cc6851e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"showcase","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=7e73250a93325f77fba93cc7a957cadb","width":860},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=860&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=e9a006bd210e44c784323eced737e1d1","width":1720},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=a70402d621b5de84f0f997006d1ab58e","width":780},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=780&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=f042b64076a63f11c519498c351b5f94","width":1560},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1d9dcefa3662e44ad17d660c362327db","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=5b0ddcf5e026602940ed2e1ff2197f0e","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=6413ea0fccfb4906299d15bfd2e4178d","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=0810f46d23927d92807cdd60efad3a58","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=0da5fa0ac624ab7df03178c89ccd0360","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1823f3b6b62655bb4424b98f6cc6851e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"halfwidth","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1d9dcefa3662e44ad17d660c362327db","width":620},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=620&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=5b0ddcf5e026602940ed2e1ff2197f0e","width":1240},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=6413ea0fccfb4906299d15bfd2e4178d","width":605},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=605&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=0810f46d23927d92807cdd60efad3a58","width":1210},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=0da5fa0ac624ab7df03178c89ccd0360","width":445},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=445&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=1823f3b6b62655bb4424b98f6cc6851e","width":890}]},{"weighting":"immersive","srcSet":[{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1554c3e6961a0043405b0b9b9a00618d","width":1900},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=1900&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=4773dcaf841f58440614438f68c46ae8","width":3800},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=20c272430e7bf2dc708480611e37271c","width":1300},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=1300&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=04a908a096754d527923670dd29b599d","width":2600},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=79b6e5f2f2331e5a64954711a85a001e","width":1140},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=1140&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=ce3ade869733e51083f52e8276774b0a","width":2280},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1e88853eeeb37d0f76e21731065d9e47","width":980},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=980&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=c32c67b25e0a3268ae93dba6cb27b8de","width":1960},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=c224e4a72ebee3b8874f7fdf73c600f7","width":740},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=740&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=3750653c9e27a4c9664a5697cc2cbaed","width":1480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8a6310259e791b49ac7c8cbbb4d9d5dc","width":660},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=660&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=f7fe3d27b7da571f83984039fcde4c91","width":1320},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=44adc56f29728704dd6989f4ba3bc1cf","width":480},{"src":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4a86d67c66ae4e293bd84a15239d1da8d5ac3ec/0_0_4406_2937/master/4406.jpg?width=480&amp;quality=45&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=466c816a98d0ee63f77b58f11fa8e212","width":960}]}],"data":{"alt":"Man with other men","caption":"Scott Bessent, at the back, in Washington on Monday.","credit":"Photograph: Jacquelyn Martin/AP"}}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757090339000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"17.38&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757096554000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"19.22&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757090403000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"17.40&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"17.40","title":"Treasury secretary Bessent calls for 'entire' review of Fed","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb0cf18f08638a14b78325","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A US homeland security department spokesperson had earlier said that US immigration authorities <strong>executed a judicial search warrant</strong> <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/05/immigration-ice-raid-hyundai-georgia\"'>at the Hyundai facility in Georgia</a> on Thursday <strong>over unlawful employment practices and other alleged federal crimes</strong>.</p>","elementId":"431bd6f7-0a5f-4e03-9e03-58be7c765772"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The spokesperson said in a statement provided to Reuters that <strong>Ice&rsquo;s investigative arm executed the warrant as part of a</strong><strong>criminal investigation</strong>.</p>","elementId":"05fb71a4-ea75-455f-8ae6-c430165b46e0"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;This operation underscores our commitment to protecting jobs for Georgians, ensuring a level playing field for businesses that comply with the law, safeguarding the integrity of our economy, and protecting workers from exploitation,&rdquo; the spokesperson said.</p>","elementId":"5163d18e-0fd8-4346-8e1d-4ee9390f676a"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757089009000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"17.16&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757096570000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"19.22&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757089118000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"17.18&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"17.18","title":"Ice executed search warrant at Hyundai facility over employment practices, DHS says","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb0c828f087e152e27f50e","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Following on from my last post, the White House said today that the Trump administration will enforce laws that require foreign workers have proper authorization to be in the United States, after immigration authorities <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/05/immigration-ice-raid-hyundai-georgia\"'>raided a Hyundai facility in Georgia</a>.</p>","elementId":"a922c101-7d91-43a5-8dd2-9de8ccb78db1"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Any foreign workers brought in for specific projects must enter the United States legally and with proper work authorizations,&rdquo; said White House spokeswoman Abigail Jackson, quoted by Reuters.</p>","elementId":"fd39e16c-a0a5-463a-bd92-417bc998f221"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;President Trump will continue delivering on his promise to make the United States the best place in the world to do business, while also enforcing federal immigration laws.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"8e7f0696-3798-4088-bc56-2c88193bc500"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757088898000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"17.14&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757088979000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"17.16&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757088979000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"17.16&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"17.16","title":"Trump administration will enforce foreign worker laws, White House says after Hyundai raid","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb054a8f087e152e27f417","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Hundreds of workers at a factory being built in <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/state-of-georgia\"'>Georgia</a> to make car batteries for <strong>Hyundai</strong> and <strong>Kia</strong> electric vehicles were detained in a massive raid by <strong>Immigration and Customs Enforcement (<a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ice-us-immigration-and-customs-enforcement\"'>Ice</a>)</strong> on Thursday that stopped construction.</p>","elementId":"c36202bf-60b7-4927-8b1c-142a712b3e68"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The facility is part of what would be the biggest industrial investment in the state&rsquo;s history and had been hailed as a huge boost for the economy by Georgia&rsquo;s Republican governor, <strong>Brian Kemp</strong>.</p>","elementId":"dddda922-2f2b-46ab-a3c0-2f16ad94b0f6"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>At least 450 people were arrested</strong>, according to the Atlanta office of the US justice department agency, the <strong>Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives</strong>.</p>","elementId":"5de9a43b-167b-45aa-bdd8-2bc139d98337"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>However the Korea Economic Daily later reported around <strong>560 workers at the Hyundai facility and LG Energy Solution (LGES), had been detained</strong>, citing unidentified industry sources. Some 300 are <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/world/south-korea\"'>South Korean</a> nationals, according to local media reports. Hyundai Motor is a South Korean automotive company but has many international plants.</p>","elementId":"71773f55-3c86-45bb-81a6-4900092fb055"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The raid on Thursday has dealt a setback to the company&rsquo;s substantial project in Georgia and was a dramatic iteration of the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a>&rsquo;s harsh crackdown on immigrants in the US.</p>","elementId":"a8d68cfa-a266-4492-8b01-f2aa5c352ab4"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>It also showed the disruptive impact that <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a>&rsquo;s mass deportation agenda is having on businesses, even as the White House tries to spur more inflows from foreign investors.</p>","elementId":"32490579-2416-4287-9b34-15bec5e1ee88"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A government official representing <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/world/south-korea\"'>South Korea</a>, the home of Hyundai Motor, said those arrested were being held at an Ice detention facility.</p>","elementId":"7c9c1a22-6064-4c03-92f0-6b38ac642361"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>South Korea&rsquo;s foreign ministry said that &ldquo;many of our nationals&rdquo; have been detained and expressed concern about the impact of the raid.</p>","elementId":"d1eb7329-19f1-4adc-a554-80e95590a456"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;<strong>The economic activities of our companies investing in the United States and the interests of our citizens must not be unduly violated during the course of US law enforcement</strong>,&rdquo; ministry spokesperson <strong>Lee Jae-woong</strong> said in a statement on Friday.</p>","elementId":"570b69b0-7e36-4e58-b028-3f810c308412"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"Hundreds of workers detained in major Ice raid at US Hyundai factory","elementId":"d5a2c665-ed72-4d1e-98e1-449ba08f2923","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/05/immigration-ice-raid-hyundai-georgia"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757087050000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"16.44&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757087174000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"16.46&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757087174000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"16.46&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"16.46","title":"Hundreds of workers detained in major Ice raid at US Hyundai factory","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bb032e8f087e152e27f403","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Vladimir Putin</strong> has said any western troops placed in <strong>Ukraine</strong> would be &ldquo;legitimate targets&rdquo; for <strong>Russian</strong> strikes, upping the stakes for Kyiv as <strong>Donald Trump</strong>&rsquo;s efforts to forge a peace deal show little sign that are any closer to success</p>","elementId":"5b15988a-c722-41a4-8d7d-24a985e03e72"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Kyiv&rsquo;s allies scramble to come up with a convincing offer of post-war support to Ukraine.</p>","elementId":"bde9143c-bbe9-4d7b-9f11-bf5eb989abf3"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>With little sign that , Putin on Friday said any guarantees that involved boots on the ground would violate Moscow&rsquo;s long-standing objections to Nato troops in Ukraine.</p>","elementId":"01c3db95-6686-4a95-9977-40f62d50d591"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The Russian leader knows that western countries are unwilling to go to war over <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/world/ukraine\"'>Ukraine</a>, and his threats on Friday look designed to further spook European capitals on the escalatory dangers of committing troops.</p>","elementId":"c2009764-fb7f-4bf9-b868-2ac69ca57c88"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump has vacillated over what support the US might provide for such a mission. At a meeting with <strong>Volodymyr Zelenskyy</strong> and European leaders the day before he met Putin in Alaska, he appeared to promise some kind of US involvement but many are still blurry on the details.</p>","elementId":"fec5dea6-c842-4fd7-803a-3b86879c2021"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"Western troops in Ukraine would be &lsquo;legitimate targets&rsquo;, Putin says","elementId":"c5f5608e-aadb-4b9e-a6a6-6b23adefc888","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/05/western-troops-ukraine-legitimate-targets-vladimir-putin-says"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757086510000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"16.35&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757086983000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"16.43&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757086983000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"16.43&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"16.43","title":"Western troops in Ukraine would be &lsquo;legitimate targets&rsquo;, Putin says","contributors":[{"name":"Shaun Walker","imageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2019/08/19/Shaun_Walker.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=f5c078a7eed08b80eb5bcf05d0345c6b","largeImageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2019/08/19/Shaun_Walker.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=1548bf6394a64fcab46ae09c6745a507"}],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bafbf88f087e152e27f36a","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump&rsquo;s justice department is considering proposals to limit the rights of transgender people to own guns, <a href='\"https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/04/politics/transgender-firearms-justice-department-second-amendment\"'>CNN reports</a>, citing two officials familiar with the internal discussions.</p>","elementId":"4a418c0a-632c-4ee4-8e12-9e6f8bdc0ec8"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>According to CNN, the &ldquo;preliminary&rdquo; discussions stem from the recent <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/aug/27/minneapolis-active-shooter-school\"'>deadly school shooting in Minneapolis</a> that killed two children and injured 21 people, which police say was carried out by a transgender woman.</p>","elementId":"3433d3f7-000f-410b-8c1c-1ca67cd6e7df"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Republicans have long resisted gun control policies aimed at limiting possession among those suffering from mental health issues, but CNN reports that the DOJ discussions centre on <strong>a proposal to &ldquo;declare that people who are transgender are mentally ill</strong> and can lose their second amendment rights to possess firearms&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"7c37bce6-9a55-4583-99d3-f5c47b6b79da"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A reminder that it is well-known that <a href='\"https://www.theviolenceproject.org/mass-shooter-database/\"'>the</a> <a href='\"https://rockinst.org/gun-violence/mass-shooting-factsheet/\"'>vast</a> <a href='\"https://nij.ojp.gov/topics/articles/public-mass-shootings-database-amasses-details-half-century-us-mass-shootings#mass-shooting-demographics\"'>majority</a> of mass shooters in the US are cisgender men, and LGBTQ+ individuals as perpetrators are very rare. They are more often the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2022/nov/22/the-us-right-is-stoking-anti-lgbt-hate-this-shooting-was-no-surprise\"'>targets of violence</a>.</p>","elementId":"1d7aa4f2-e98b-4784-a829-77033c6bc3db"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>It goes without saying that if the DOJ&rsquo;s proposal goes ahead it would be highly controversial and certain to draw a swift legal challenge.</p>","elementId":"b5a07312-7be8-4037-a7ad-923b6442ad40"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757084664000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"16.04&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757086130000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"16.28&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757085080000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"16.11&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"16.11","title":"DOJ looking at ways to ban transgender Americans from owning guns - report","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68baf4d58f08da2028ad9282","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> is expected to issue an executive order as early as Friday to establish a designation for state sponsors of wrongful detention, in a move that would allow the US to punish countries that illegally detain Americans or take them hostage, <a href='\"https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-wrongful-detention-state-sponsors-order/\"'>CBS News reports this morning</a>.</p>","elementId":"3c68461b-5970-4e5c-a920-cab1ea78ebf7"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>According to the president&rsquo;s schedule, Trump is due to sign executive orders later today at 2pm ET including, as we&rsquo;ve been reporting, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/trump-defense-war-department\"'>rebranding</a> the Department of Defense as the &ldquo;department of war&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"33cda78d-c1f5-4e20-859f-d3fdedae5de0"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757082837000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"15.33&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757083334000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"15.42&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757083334000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"15.42&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"15.42","title":"Trump to issue executive order to allow punishments for countries wrongfully detaining Americans - report","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68baec878f08da2028ad9215","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump said this week he will be sending troops into <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/chicago\"'>Chicago</a>, calling the Democrat-led city a &ldquo;hellhole&rdquo;. It would be the second US city to receive national guard troops after Trump declared a national crime emergency and deployed about 800 troops to Washington DC in August.</p>","elementId":"997a38a6-68d6-488a-9649-b858f879d0fa"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re going in,&rdquo; Trump said about Chicago. &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t say when, [but] we&rsquo;re going in.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"a547c4cc-8c27-4062-a0a4-bbbb78b09f91"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>An advance team of at least 30 agents is currently undergoing crowd control and flash grenade training at Naval Station Great Lakes north of Chicago, and 230 agents, most of whom work for Customs and Border Protection, are being sent to <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/aug/30/chicago-mayor-executive-order-trump-immigration-raids\"'>Chicago</a> from <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/aug/05/us-citizens-jailed-ice-los-angeles\"'>Los Angeles</a>, sources told the <a href='\"https://chicago.suntimes.com/the-watchdogs/2025/09/03/chicago-illinois-crime-immigration-ice-national-guard-donald-trump-jb-pritzker\"'>Chicago Sun-Times</a>.</p>","elementId":"94c4171d-011b-4c1e-b763-0e9f495602e7"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Chicago leaders have pushed back on Trump&rsquo;s views of the city. Chicago residents say the city&rsquo;s immigrant communities are on edge. Illinois governor JB Pritzker has expressed concern that Ice agents will target Mexican Independence Day events this month, and a large festival planned for the day this weekend was postponed.</p>","elementId":"3286dfac-3aa6-4e7d-b0d5-2eee5ea058e3"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>But there is a long history of organized resistance that will stand up to the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a>. &ldquo;If you think of the civic action you&rsquo;ve seen over history, whether that&rsquo;s the Pullman strikes a century ago, or Haymarket, or the early union movement, or what we did in the civil rights movement, or the organizing for the Women&rsquo;s March, Chicagoans are organized. So we aren&rsquo;t helpless,&rdquo; said Edwin Eisendrath, a former member of the Chicago city council.</p>","elementId":"e686fba1-e633-47e0-9eca-580b919a906d"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757080711000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"14.58&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757081443000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"15.10&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757080737000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"14.58&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"14.58","title":"Chicago braces for Trump&rsquo;s federal law enforcement deployment","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bac4668f08305da53f84a9","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>This week&rsquo;s dramatic court ruling that Donald Trump&rsquo;s sweeping trade tariffs, which he has used to upend global trade, were in fact illegal is the latest in a series of losses for the president&rsquo;s radical agenda that are ultimately heading for a final showdown in the US supreme court.</strong></p>","elementId":"44e03c85-8c97-4447-be20-8e9943e6bdc0"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump has already asked the supreme court to overturn the lower court ruling in the tariffs case. Almost certain to follow are Trump&rsquo;s invocation of the Alien Enemies Act to deport Venezuelans, his hostile conflict with Harvard University and his deployment of the national guard and marines to Los Angeles. All have been deemed unlawful in lower courts.</p>","elementId":"67fcb968-474e-4f5f-8d46-aff687d7361e"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s simple: the president and his administration continue to do illegal things at an astonishing pace, and so the courts are finding that these things are illegal,&rdquo; said Donald Sherman, executive director and chief counsel at Citizens for Responsibility and Ethics in Washington.</p>","elementId":"dc48d820-f434-4e79-86f9-c835076b5423"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;The president is committed to pursuing his agenda regardless of whether it&rsquo;s legal or not, and is seeing what he can get away with.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"8a5be1db-5a85-4510-a429-523a830ef776"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The ultimate arbiter of that will be the supreme court, which is stacked 6-3 in favor of conservatives, many of whom Trump has appointed. The court has already dramatically limited the ability of lower courts to issue nationwide injunctions to pause <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a> policies across the country.</p>","elementId":"bc46b082-86aa-4897-a94c-ffbad6045f95"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"Trump&rsquo;s legal woes mount as supreme court to rule on trade tariffs","elementId":"aa90137b-0d73-4b45-a0ef-ad4d51639906","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-legal-woes-mount-supreme-court-rule-trade-tariffs"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757070438000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"12.07&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757072893000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"12.48&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757072893000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"12.48&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"12.48","title":"Trump&rsquo;s legal woes mount as supreme court to rule on trade tariffs","contributors":[{"name":"Lucy Campbell"}],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bab57e8f08305da53f8396","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Tensions between Michelle Wu, the mayor of Boston, and the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration\"'>Trump administration</a> have been escalating in recent months over the administration&rsquo;s aggressive immigration policies, with reports now signaling the possibility of a federal immigration enforcement surge in the city.</strong></p>","elementId":"d352e7aa-1e08-47af-93e4-f3e11d197bf2"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The friction came to a head last week when the Trump administration reportedly began preparing an &ldquo;immigration enforcement blitz&rdquo; for Boston in the coming weeks, according to <a href='\"https://www.politico.com/news/2025/08/29/trump-admin-plans-immigration-enforcement-surge-in-boston-00536276\"'>Politico</a>.</p>","elementId":"ba6fe903-a5d6-4e8b-804d-dd9e5f8821c7"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The report, which cited unnamed current and former administration officials, <a href='\"https://www.nbcboston.com/news/local/boston-follows-the-law-mayor-wu-responds-to-report-of-planned-ice-surge/3799776/\"'>prompted a swift rebuke</a> from Wu, who has in recent months become a vocal defender of sanctuary laws and immigrant protections.</p>","elementId":"160b1224-b9af-45a1-a83e-2de7574fdb81"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Unlike the Trump administration, Boston follows the law &ndash; city, state and federal,&rdquo; Wu said in a <a href='\"https://www.facebook.com/MayorWu/posts/unlike-the-trump-administration-boston-follows-the-lawlocal-state-and-federalthe/791123140088049/\"'>statement</a>. &ldquo;We are the safest major city in the country because all of our community members know that they are part of how we keep the entire community safe. Stop attacking cities to hide your administration&rsquo;s failures.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"a0e28087-253e-43f6-8b04-963adc299bfc"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>This standoff has been steadily building since March when Wu <a href='\"https://www.wgbh.org/politics/live-updates/boston-mayor-wu-testifies-before-congress-on-immigration-policies\"'>testified</a> before Congress alongside <a href='\"https://oversight.house.gov/release/boston-chicago-denver-nyc-sanctuary-mayors-to-be-held-publicly-accountable-on-march-5/\"'>three other Democratic mayors</a> to defend their cities&rsquo; immigration policies &ndash; specifically so-called sanctuary city laws that <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/apr/30/donald-trump-sanctuary-cities\"'>limit state and local law enforcement cooperation</a> with federal Immigration and Customs Enforcement (Ice).</p>","elementId":"40cfe27c-b963-4a37-a4de-0dac583f05a6"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Supporters of the laws, including local leaders and <a href='\"https://www.congress.gov/118/meeting/house/116200/witnesses/HHRG-118-JU01-Wstate-BatistaR-20230713.pdf\"'>police chiefs</a> in jurisdictions that have them, argue that these measures can help build trust between immigrant communities and law enforcement. Some studies have <a href='\"https://www.congress.gov/118/meeting/house/116200/documents/HHRG-118-JU01-20230713-SD003.pdf\"'>found</a> that crime rates tend to be lower in sanctuary counties compared with those without such protections.</p>","elementId":"7282a28a-fde8-4f2d-b6a6-794e07d943bc"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Critics of these policies <a href='\"https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/22/us/sanctuary-cities-trump-immigration.html\"'>claim</a> that sanctuary laws undermine federal law enforcement&rsquo;s ability to arrest and deport individuals with criminal records.</p>","elementId":"eaff3f8a-3b23-45d8-9052-d5509d15758f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>So-called &ldquo;sanctuary cities&rdquo; have become <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/apr/30/donald-trump-sanctuary-cities\"'>a central target</a> of this Trump administration, as it pushes for mass deportations as part of its crackdown on immigration. In June, Pam Bondi, the US attorney general, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/aug/14/pam-bondi-sanctuary-cities-letter-immigration\"'>sent letters </a>to 32 US mayors, including Wu, demanding they end their sanctuary policies or face cuts to federal funding and possible legal consequences.</p>","elementId":"0dd33367-4174-4e86-ac65-5192081bae1d"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"Boston readies for Ice&rsquo;s offensive amid Trump&rsquo;s onslaught on sanctuary cities","elementId":"9c6955ce-9185-4b57-a8d6-2ce159fbb034","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/05/boston-ice-trump-michelle-wu"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757067537000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"11.18&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757071785000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"12.29&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757071786000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"12.29&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"12.29","title":"Boston readies for Ice&rsquo;s offensive amid Trump&rsquo;s onslaught on sanctuary cities","contributors":[{"name":"Anna Betts","imageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2025/03/25/Anna_Betts.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=0c7ea7feb513855421062d73042ae34a","largeImageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2025/03/25/Anna_Betts.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=deeaa994f0d665c2085cdab3c992af10"}],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bab52e8f08305da53f8391","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>The US justice department has initiated a criminal investigation into mortgage fraud claims against <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/business/federal-reserve\"'>Federal Reserve</a> governor Lisa Cook as a lawsuit she filed against <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> over her firing makes its way through court.</strong></p>","elementId":"caa591dd-22f4-4894-a806-7c3953528d34"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Lawyers with the justice department have issued subpoenas for the investigation, according to the <a href='\"https://www.wsj.com/politics/policy/lisa-cook-justice-department-probe-e7e801a6?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAhFa2dCwKLHPmFPwUqgdoTVPDQnbLyhYNPnHGkhnJMf34xu0Rw78KVxJJ2M7Kw%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68b9e019&amp;gaa_sig=QzNRPSjoWJ0R3ECdjSBjfE5NKmuky8foazFn-4pd3ZMCkV5U0goT4aazbVirk0CqssYe5lVr9lrgs92giwpSOw%3D%3D\"'>Wall Street Journal</a>, who first reported the investigation, which has since been confirmed by multiple news publications.</p>","elementId":"ebf61731-e9ef-40b2-8632-6dfb3b54e463"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Last month, Trump <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/aug/25/trump-fires-federal-reserve-governor-lisa-cook\"'>moved to fire</a> Cook over unconfirmed claims that she listed two properties as her primary residence. Bill Pulte, the director of the Federal Housing and Finance Agency and a close ally of Trump, alleged Cook had lied on bank documents and records to obtain a better mortgage rate.</p>","elementId":"3206f6fc-ec1b-4bdc-ac54-da020442eb4f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Cook, a voting member of the Fed board that sets interest rates, said she has &ldquo;no intention of being bullied to step down&rdquo; and that she would &ldquo;take any questions about my financial history seriously&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"5206438f-ab69-4126-9c11-bd3e2c50adf3"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>In response to Trump&rsquo;s bid to dismiss her, Cook filed a <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/aug/28/fed-governor-lisa-cook-sues-trump\"'>lawsuit</a> against the president arguing that her removal was unconstitutional and threatened the independence of the Fed. Cook&rsquo;s lawyers say the firing was &ldquo;unprecedented and illegal&rdquo; and that federal law requires showing &ldquo;cause&rdquo; for a Fed governor&rsquo;s removal.</p>","elementId":"00ce28af-a895-42a0-92fb-47084f6e504e"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;An unsubstantiated allegation about private mortgage applications submitted by Governor Cook prior to her Senate confirmation is not [cause],&rdquo; her lawyers said in court documents.</p>","elementId":"b6fdecb2-841a-4cae-ac55-b203defcf2c7"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"US justice department opens criminal inquiry into Fed governor Lisa Cook","elementId":"987272d1-8342-437a-887f-09cc9d565e32","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/sep/04/lisa-cook-federal-reserve-mortgage-investigation"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757067537000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"11.18&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757071288000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"12.21&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757071288000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"12.21&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"12.21","title":"US justice department opens criminal inquiry into Fed governor Lisa Cook","contributors":[{"name":"Lauren Aratani","imageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2022/12/12/Lauren_Aratani.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=a35f56b97ca95c1948defd63ba5fd078","largeImageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2022/12/12/Lauren_Aratani_Next_Gen.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=2617eedb648a6025d72a9d70a2a46a36"}],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bab3fe8f08305da53f837f","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>The US has ordered the deployment of 10 F-35 fighter jets to a Puerto Rico airfield to conduct operations against drug cartels, two sources briefed on the matter said, in a move likely to further inflame tensions in the region.</strong></p>","elementId":"8e6b08ac-88ab-44f9-a380-9b2f1574e590"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The advanced fighter jets will be added to an already bristling US military presence in the southern Caribbean as president <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> carries out a campaign pledge to crack down on groups he blames for funneling drugs into the United States, Reuters reported.</p>","elementId":"91080a28-8940-49e7-be7d-0c77e8152d10"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Friday&rsquo;s development comes three days after US forces attacked a boat that Trump said was carrying &ldquo;massive amounts of drugs&rdquo; from Venezuela, killing 11 people. The strike appeared to set the stage for a sustained military campaign in Latin America.</p>","elementId":"e7cdae3e-cdc5-4875-ad1b-3ef3d5c1a4bb"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The sources, speaking on condition of anonymity, said the 10 fighter jets are being sent to conduct operations against designated narco-terrorist organizations operating in the southern Caribbean. The planes should arrive in the area by late next week, they said.</p>","elementId":"5833b8e9-b582-4e57-9920-0d582a7129d6"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The US has deployed warships in the southern Caribbean in recent weeks, with the aim of carrying out Trump&rsquo;s crackdown.</p>","elementId":"aa28dc00-5e7b-4221-a251-aba9f765a51e"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757067537000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"11.18&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757069543000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"11.52&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757069543000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"11.52&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"11.52","title":"US deploying 10 fighter jets to Puerto Rico for drug cartel fight, sources say","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68bab3218f083127d2c22e22","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Donald Trump&rsquo;s deployment of the national guard in Los Angeles in response to protests in the city over immigration raids cost taxpayers nearly $120m, the California governor&rsquo;s office said on Thursday.</strong></p>","elementId":"82392386-07b8-4021-9e14-446c0107cd5e"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The US president sent 2,000 national guard troops into the city in June amid clashes between federal immigration agents and protesters. This week a <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/02/trumps-national-guard-troops-los-angeles-illegal\"'>judge ruled</a> that dispatching the military to accompany authorities on immigration enforcement operations violated federal law.</p>","elementId":"758b5bc6-a031-44e8-a627-50dc996cada9"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>More than 4,200 national guard soldiers and 700 marines were deployed in the region. Although relatively few assisted with raids, the costs mounted &ndash; $71m for food and necessities, $37m in pay and $3.5m in travel, among other expenses, Gavin Newsom&rsquo;s office said in a <a href='\"https://www.gov.ca.gov/2025/09/04/trumps-illegal-national-guard-deployment-in-los-angeles-cost-taxpayers-120-million/\"'>statement</a>.</p>","elementId":"97274317-ba79-4e99-99a5-37d754de0bf6"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>About 300 troops remain in the city. Newsom described the move as &ldquo;waste, fraud and abuse&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"66a074be-483a-4d3b-b43e-7608189a7b93"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Let us not forget what this political theater is costing us all &ndash; millions of taxpayer dollars down the drain, an atrophy to the readiness of guardsmembers across the nation and unnecessary hardships to the families supporting those troops,&rdquo; the governor said.</p>","elementId":"c896b779-fb6c-4b75-8ca7-c07d497e7e22"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"Trump&rsquo;s LA national guard deployment cost taxpayers $120m, Newsom says","elementId":"a2e7e9fa-b898-4a19-b6e9-f603fe321477","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/trump-national-guard-deployment-los-angeles"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757067537000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"11.18&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757069131000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"11.45&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757069131000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"11.45&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"11.45","title":"Trump&rsquo;s LA national guard deployment cost taxpayers $120m, Newsom says","contributors":[{"name":"Dani Anguiano","imageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/18/Dani_Anguiano.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=62e5fc219f4860d52706db44b981b242","largeImageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/18/Dani_Anguiano.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=ff300417400de848bb8fafad1bbe5d80"}],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"},{"id":"68ba90878f08bfd6d85c14b8","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Good morning and welcome to our live coverage of US politics where <strong>opponents have criticised <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/trump-defense-war-department\"'>Donald Trump&rsquo;s expected move to rebrand the Department of Defense as the &ldquo;department of war</a>&rdquo;</strong>.</p>","elementId":"bbc7914f-68f8-4fb4-9a7b-a93326889e25"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The president is expected to sign an executive order on Friday authorizing the rebrand, the White House said, as part of an attempt to formalize the name change without an act of Congress.</p>","elementId":"ffa615c5-e2bc-4a3b-80ca-c293892d163a"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The order will designate &ldquo;department of war&rdquo; as a &ldquo;secondary title&rdquo;, an administration official said, as a way to get around the need for congressional approval to formally rename a federal agency.</p>","elementId":"6b0020a9-d55e-4008-8447-fd3a363882ac"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>But the order will instruct the rest of the executive branch to use the &ldquo;department of war&rdquo; name in internal and external communications, and allows the defense secretary <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/pete-hegseth\"'>Pete Hegseth</a> and other officials to use &ldquo;secretary of war&rdquo; as official titles.</p>","elementId":"0d0245f5-0582-4883-9ce6-a6f145d4b92c"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump and Hegseth have been publicly pushing for the rebrand for weeks, claiming the change would present the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/us-military\"'>US military</a> as more aggressive to the world by reverting to the name that was used when the US was victorious in the first and second world wars.</p>","elementId":"89d51a06-4197-4144-b127-c67fa5e4a3cd"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Everybody likes that we had an unbelievable history of victory when it was the Department of War,&rdquo; Trump told reporters in the Oval Office last week. &ldquo;Then we changed it to Department of Defense.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"f6843ec2-461c-4eb2-86c3-66d7f60f9d53"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The move could cost tens of millions of dollars, with letterheads and signs on buildings in the US and at bases worldwide possibly needing to be changed.</p>","elementId":"1407d353-d01b-4bdb-b70b-01f39e3392cc"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>But there has been criticism over the move. Democratic senator Tammy Duckworth &ndash; a war veteran who lost both her legs serving in Afghanistan and who is now a member of the armed services committee &ndash; said:</p>","elementId":"887c98f4-f762-4e37-8119-d12aaa0f9f76"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.BlockquoteBlockElement","html":"<blockquote>\n<p>Why not put this money toward supporting military families or toward employing diplomats that help prevent conflicts from starting in the first place?</p>\n<p>Because Trump would rather use our military to score political points than to strengthen our national security and support our brave servicemembers and their families - that&rsquo;s why</p>\n</blockquote>","elementId":"a5f00400-f3fa-4ecb-85cf-87ea3972ed63"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><em>Stay with us for the latest on this story:</em></p>","elementId":"2750096e-6d7d-4920-9bf8-71bfa7d123a9"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"Trump expected to order rebrand of Pentagon as &lsquo;Department of War&rsquo;","elementId":"5dc1dd1f-d467-49e3-bf90-fba1e9e44140","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/trump-defense-war-department"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>In other developments:</p>","elementId":"d99bb721-3956-43f1-a58b-890416c27a48"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<ul>\n <li>\n<p>The health secretary, <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong>, fended off calls for his resignation and spread vaccine misinformation during a contentious Senate hearing.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Susan Monarez</strong>, the ousted CDC director, rejected Kennedy&rsquo;s claim that she had lied about having been pressured to rubber-stamp vaccine recommendations from a panel of his anti-vaccine allies, and offered to repeat her claim under oath.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>Trump hosted an array of tech industry leaders for dinner in the White House state dinning room on Thursday night, including <strong>Mark Zuckerberg</strong>, <strong>Tim Cook</strong>, <strong>Bill Gates</strong>, <strong>Sam Altman</strong> and <strong>Sergey Brin</strong>, but his former first buddy, <strong>Elon Musk</strong>, was a notable absence.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> said Thursday that he thinks Democrat <strong>Zohran Mamdani</strong> is likely to become New York City&rsquo;s next mayor unless two of the three major candidates running against him drop out of the race. But the Republican didn&rsquo;t say which two candidates he&rsquo;d like to see quit.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>Demolition to build president Trump&rsquo;s new ballroom off the East Wing of the <strong>White House</strong> can begin without approval of the commission tasked with vetting construction of federal buildings, the Trump-appointed head of the panel said Thursday.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>As <strong>Trump </strong>accuses Federal Reserve governor <strong>Lisa Cook</strong> of criminal mortgage fraud, for allegedly obtaining more than one mortgage on a home designated as her primary residence, at least three members of his cabinet have multiple primary-residence mortgages, <a href='\"https://www.propublica.org/article/trump-cabinet-mortgage-fraud\"'>ProPublica reports</a>.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>The justice department has launched a criminal mortgage fraud inquiry into <strong>Cook</strong> and issued grand jury subpoenas out of both Georgia and Michigan.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p>New York&rsquo;s attorney general moved to have the state&rsquo;s highest court reinstate Trump&rsquo;s staggering civil fraud penalty, appealing a lower court decision that <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/aug/21/trump-civil-fraud-case-appeal-ruling\"'>slashed the potential half-billion dollar penalty to zero</a>.</p></li>\n</ul>","elementId":"07ecbd72-7cb4-462e-a5ca-3b48ac3a728a"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1757067537000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"11.18&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1757078787000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"14.26&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1757067537000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"11.18&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"11.18","title":"Trump faces criticism over to order to rebrand Pentagon as &lsquo;Department of War&rsquo;","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Sat 6 Sep 2025 03.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 5 Sep 2025 11.18 BST"}],"filterKeyEvents":false,"id":"key-events-carousel-mobile","absoluteServerTimes":false,"renderingTarget":"Web"}"&gt;<span><p>Key events</p></span><gu-island><p><label>Show key events only<p><span>Please turn on JavaScript to use this feature</span></p></label></p></gu-island><article><header><h2>Closing summary</h2></header><p>This brings our surreal-time coverage of the second <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration">Trump administration</a> to a close for the day. We will be back soon, but in the meantime, here are the latest developments:</p><ul> <li><p>Hundreds of people were arrested in an immigration raid at a Hyundai battery factory in Georgia, most of them Korean nationals, despite the fact that a warrant said that just four people, with Spanish names, were targeted.</p></li> <li><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> signed an executive order authorizing the US Department of Defense to refer to itself as the &ldquo;Department of War&rdquo;, as part of an attempt to formalize his rebranding effort without the legally required act of Congress.</p></li> <li><p>Trump announced that the US will host the 2026 meeting of the G20 at his privately owned Doral golf course and spa in Miami.</p></li> <li><p>Asked about Florida&rsquo;s move to lift mandates on vaccinations for schoolchildren, Trump said that officials have to &ldquo;be careful&rdquo; in removing access to vaccines he described as &ldquo;amazing&rdquo; and &ldquo;incredible&rdquo;.</p></li> <li><p>After watching a misleading report on small protests in Portland, Oregon over immigration, the president said that he might send troops there. A Fox News report on the protests used video recorded during a protest in 2020 and wrongly said it had been recorded in the city this summer.</p></li> <li><p><a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/trump-weighs-strikes-targeting-cartels-inside-venezuela">CNN reported</a> that Trump &ldquo;is weighing options for carrying out military strikes targeting drug cartels operating inside Venezuela, including possible strikes within the country&rdquo;.</p></li> <li><p>The Pentagon made some immediate cosmetic changes to signage on Friday, after <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> signed an executive order to rebrand the Department of Defense as the Department of War.</p></li> <li><p>Two leading Republican lawmakers, the House speaker <strong>Mike Johnson</strong> and <strong>Nancy Mace</strong>, both claimed this week that Trump had acted as an FBI informant to take down <strong>Jeffrey Epstein</strong>. They offered no evidence, but if it existed it would be in the files Trump has fought to keep from the public.</p></li> </ul></article><article><header><h2>Republican lawmakers push unsourced claim Trump was an 'FBI informant' against Epstein</h2></header><p>As the Republican leadership in the House continues to block a bipartisan effort to force the full release of files from the federal investigation into Jeffrey Epstein, the late sex offender who was once Donald Trump&rsquo;s friend, several of them have started to make the same unsourced claim: that Trump aided the federal effort to prosecute Epstein.</p><p>On Tuesday, Nancy Mace, the South Carolina congresswoman who has supported the petition to force the release of the files, told a reporter for the Independent that she had no reason to believe that Trump has opposed hte releae of the files because they might be embarrassing to him.</p><p>&ldquo;Donald Trump is the one who banned Jeffrey Epstein from Mar-a-Lago&rdquo;, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:e7gbntp2tzobn7cfi37viei3/post/3lxvcaihah22b?ref_src=embed&amp;ref_url=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.dailykos.com%252Fstories%252F2025%252F9%252F3%252F2341692%252F-WHOA-Nancy-Mace-Says-Trump-Was-an-FBI-Informant-So-Did-He-Flipped-on-Epstein-to-Save-Himself">she said</a>. &ldquo;He was an FBI informant, and he talked to the feds to get this guy turned over. So Donald Trump is a hero in this.&rdquo;</p><p>Then on Thursday, the House speaker, Mike Johnson, made the same claim in <a href="https://x.com/mkraju/status/1963640592514081026">an interview</a> with Manu Raju of CNN.</p><p>When the reporter said that Trump had called the effort to release the Epstein files &ldquo;a hoax&rdquo;, Johnson replied: &ldquo;He&rsquo;s not saying that what Epstein did is a hoax. It&rsquo;s a terrible, unspeakable evil. He believes that himself. When he first heard the rumor, he kicked him out of Mar-a-Lago. He was an FBI informant to try to take this stuff down.&rdquo;</p><p>As the conspiracy theory expert Mike Rothschild noted: &ldquo;This has been a supposition among QAnon believers for years. Maybe they could release the files and prove it!&rdquo;</p></article><article><header><h2>Sign on Hegseth's office door now says 'Secretary of War'</h2></header><p>The Pentagon made some immediate cosmetic changes to signage on Friday, after <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> signed an executive order to rebrand the Department of Defense as the Department of War.</p><p>A video clip <a href="https://x.com/SecWar/status/1964071478955032634">posted</a> on social media by the defense secretary, Pete Hegseth, showed workers replacing the sign on his office door with one that read &ldquo;Secretary of War&rdquo;.</p><div><p>Other images gathered by Pentagon reporters showed workers scraping letters that spelled out &ldquo;Department of Defense&rdquo; from the wall near Hegseth&rsquo;s office.</p><p>The URL of the Pentagon&rsquo;s official website was changed from from &ldquo;defense.gov &rdquo; to &ldquo;war.gov&rdquo;.</p></div><figure><div><figcaption><span>Pentagon workers changed signs on Friday.</span></figcaption></div></figure></article><article><header><h2>Trump promises to send federal troops to police Chicago and New Orleans</h2></header><p>Speaking at a dinner for Republican lawmakers on the newly paved-over lawn on the Rose Garden, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> boasted of what he called the success of his federal takeover of policing in the District of Columbia and promised to send troops to Chicago and New Orleans next.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to make Chicago like this&rdquo;, <a href="https://x.com/Acyn/status/1964123337741000952">Trump said</a>. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to come into New Orleans and we&rsquo;re gonna make that place so safe. It&rsquo;s got a little problem right now, a couple of headaches like murders. A lot of little murders going on, and we&rsquo;re not going to stand for it&rdquo;.</p></article><article><header><h2>Trump says he is 'not talking about' regime change in Venezuela, as he reportedly weighs air strikes</h2></header><p>Donald Trump refused to answer on Friday when a reporter asked him, amid reports of US ships and bombers massing in the Caribbean, if he would &ldquo;like to see regime change in Venezuela&rdquo;.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re not talking about that&rdquo;, the president said, &ldquo;but we are talking about the fact that you had an election which was a very strange election, to put it mildly&rdquo;.</p><p>He went on to say that &ldquo;billions of dollars of drugs are pouring into our country from Venezuela&rdquo;, in line with his administration&rsquo;s claim that it is now at war with drug cartels operating in the country.</p><p>The president&rsquo;s comments came after Fox News reported that the Pentagon is deploying 10 F-35 stealth fighter jets to Puerto Rico, joining eight US Navy destroyers. That prompted the Fox national security correspondent Jennifer Griffin to observe that there was no apparent reason that stealth fighter jets were needed for a counternarcotics mission.</p><p>&ldquo;The F35s being sent to Puerto Rico are usually used for large bombing missions like the targeting of Iran&rsquo;s nuclear facilities- a 5th generation supersonic fighter jet known for its lethality&rdquo;, Griffin <a href="https://x.com/JenGriffinFNC/status/1964001832172179733">wrote on X</a>. &ldquo;It looks to me like the US military is going to war.&rdquo;</p><p>Later on Friday, <a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/trump-weighs-strikes-targeting-cartels-inside-venezuela">CNN reported</a> that Trump &ldquo;is weighing options for carrying out military strikes targeting drug cartels operating inside Venezuela, including possible strikes within the country&rdquo;.</p><p>Such strikes would be an escalation from deadly attack on a boat from Venezuela in the Caribbean, which killed 11 people the administration suspected on smuggling drugs bound for the US.</p><p>During Trump&rsquo;s first term in office, according to his defense secretary, Mark Esper, the president asked him on at least two occasions if the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/us-military">US military</a> could &ldquo;shoot missiles into Mexico to destroy the drug labs.&rdquo;</p><p>Esper recounted the requests in his memoir, and wrote that when he objected, Trump suggested that &ldquo;no one would know it was us&rdquo; if the US fired &ldquo;some Patriot missiles&rdquo; and he would just deny that the US had carried out the strikes.</p><p>In 2019, when Trump reportedly considered forcing its president, Nicol&aacute;s Maduro, from office, a Democratic congresswoman opposed to what she called &ldquo;regime change wars&rdquo; objected very strongly. &ldquo;The United States needs to stay out of Venezuela&rdquo;, <a href="https://x.com/TulsiGabbard/status/1088531713649713153">Tulsi Gabbard wrote</a> at the time. &ldquo;Let the Venezuelan people determine their future. We don&rsquo;t want other countries to choose our leaders--so we have to stop trying to choose theirs.&rdquo;</p></article><article><header><h2>Misled by video of 2020 protests shown on Fox, Trump threatens to invade Portland and 'wipe out' protesters</h2></header><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> told reporters on Friday that he might send national guard troops to Portland, Oregon, apparently because he was misled about the scale of small protests outside an immigration detention facility there by a TV report which incorrectly presented video recorded during a protest in 2020 as having taken place in the city this summer.</p><p>&ldquo;I will say this, I watched today, I didn&rsquo;t know that was continuing to go on, but Portland is unbelievable, what&rsquo;s going on,&rdquo; <a href="https://youtu.be/_dTSbtfXwDg?si=EO06p1VSobt8fDJu&amp;t=1">Trump said</a>. He then claimed, incorrectly, that he had seen video evidence of &ldquo;the destruction of the city&rdquo;.</p><p>In fact, a handful of protesters have demonstrated outside an Immigration and Customs Enforcement facility in a remote area of Portland along the south waterfront this year, but the scale of the protests, which attract dozens at most, is nothing like the 2020 protests that regularly drew thousands or tens of thousands of demonstrators to a central part of the city.</p><p>&ldquo;Are you going into Portland?&rdquo; a reporter asked Trump.</p><p>&ldquo;Well, I&rsquo;m going to look at it now because I didn&rsquo;t know that was still going on; this has been going on for years,&rdquo; the president replied. He then explained how he had been misled into the entirely false belief that the large-scale protests from 2020 had continued.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;ll be able to stop that very easily, but that was not on my list, Portland, but when I watched television last night, this has been going on,&rdquo; Trump said.</p><figure><div><figcaption><span>Donald Trump threatened to invade Portland, Oregon during an Oval Office event on Friday.</span></figcaption></div></figure><p>The president did not cite the specific news report that he was basing his impression on, but his favorite channel, Fox News, broadcast <a href="https://x.com/KatieDaviscourt/status/1963819280249807236">a report</a> on Thursday that mixed images of a recent protest in Portland, attended by dozens of protesters, with <a href="https://x.com/PDXzane/status/1284726088187310080">a viral video clip</a> from 2020 of one protester, Christopher David, being pepper-sprayed in the face by a federal agent that was wrongly described as having been shot in June of this year.</p><p>The report focused mainly on one protest outside the facility on Tuesday, attended by dozens of protesters who brought a guillotine as a prop before being doused with chemical agents by federal officers.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Dozens of protesters rallied against Donald Trump&rsquo;s immigration policies, outside an Ice detention facility in Portland on Tuesday.</span> Photograph: John Rudoff/Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>&ldquo;These are paid terrorists,&rdquo; the president said, once again spreading <a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/06/04/white-house-forced-retract-claim-viral-videos-prove-antifa-plotting-violence/">a baseless conspiracy theory</a> his administration amplified about anti-fascist protesters in 2020.</p><p>&ldquo;These are paid agitators, these are professional. I watched that last night, I&rsquo;m very good at this stuff. These are paid agitators, they get paid money by radical left groups,&rdquo; the president claimed. He then went on to suggest that well-printed signs displayed by some protesters proved his theory.</p><p>&ldquo;These are paid agitators and they&rsquo;re very dangerous for our country and when we go there, if we go to Portland, we&rsquo;re going to wipe &lsquo;em out. They&rsquo;re going to be gone. They won&rsquo;t even stand to fight. They will not stay there. They&rsquo;ve ruined that city.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s like living in hell,&rdquo; the president said, describing an imaginary version of Portland that bears no resemblance to the actual city, in which fences around the federal courthouse that was the scene of mass protests in 2020 have now been removed and the central police headquarters no longer has boarded up windows.</p></article><article><header><h2>Trump says US must be 'very careful' in removing mandates for 'vaccines that are so amazing'</h2></header><p>Asked about Florida&rsquo;s move to lift mandates on vaccinations for schoolchildren, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> said that officials have to &ldquo;be careful&rdquo; in removing access to vaccines he described as &ldquo;amazing&rdquo; and &ldquo;incredible&rdquo;.</p><p>&ldquo;I think we have to be very careful&rdquo; Trump said in the Oval Office on Friday. &ldquo;Look, you have some vaccines that are so amazing. The polio vaccine, I happen to think, is amazing. A lot of people think that Covid is amazing. You know, there are many people that believe strongly in that. But you have some vaccines that are so incredible and I think that you have to be very careful when you say that some people don&rsquo;t have to be vaccinated&rdquo;.</p><p>Trump said that the position adopted by Florida was &ldquo;a tough stance&rdquo;, given the risks to the community by unvaccinated children attending school.</p><p>&ldquo;Look, you have vaccines that work; they just pure and simple work, they&rsquo;re not controversial at all, and I think those vaccines should be used, otherwise some people are going to catch it and they endanger other people&rdquo;, the president said.</p><p>&ldquo;When you don&rsquo;t have controversy at all, I think people should take it&rdquo;, Trump added.</p><p>His remarks come one day after his anti-vaccine health secretary, <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong>, told senators that he agrees with the views of an Israeli management professor he recently appointed to a key CDC vaccine advisory panel, <strong>Retsef Levi</strong>, who has said that mRNA vaccines against Covid-19 are deadly and should no longer be used.</p><p>At the same hearing, Bill Cassidy, a Republican senator who is also a medical doctor, suggested that Trump deserves a Nobel prize for Operation Warp Speed, which sped up the development of mRNA vaccines against Covid-19 in 2020.</p></article><article><header><h2>Trump announces US will host 2026 G20 meeting at his Doral resort in Miami</h2></header><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> just announced that the US will host the 2026 meeting of the G20 at his privately owned Doral golf course and spa in Miami.</p><p>The president was joined by Miami&rsquo;s mayor, <strong>Francis Suarez</strong>, for the announcement in the Oval Office.</p><p>Trump initially did not mention that his Doral resort was the location, but confirmed it in response to a question from a reporter. The president then quickly moved to downplay concerns that he was using his office for personal profit, claiming that &ldquo;we will not make any money on it&rdquo; and that the location was chosen because &ldquo;everybody wants it there&rdquo;.</p><p>The president was asked if he intends to invite Russia&rsquo;s president, Vladimir Putin, to attend as an observer. He initially said that he had not yet considered that possibility, but has previously claimed that excluding Russia, over its initial invasion of Ukraine in 2014, was a mistake.</p><p>Minutes later, Trump was asked again and said that both Putin and China&rsquo;s leader, Xi Jinping, were welcome to attend as observers. &ldquo;I&rsquo;d love them to, if they want to&rdquo;, the president said. &ldquo;If they want to, we can certainly talk&rdquo;.</p><figure><div><picture><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=700&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=700&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><img alt="Donald Trump announced on Friday that the US will host the G20 summit 2026 at his Doral resort in Miami. He was joined by Miami&rsquo;s mayor, Francis Suarez." src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/605bd6b023df68a7c838140fb065c7a4576364b8/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none" width="465" height="310"></source></source></source></source></picture></div><figcaption><span>Trump announced that the US will host the G20 summit 2026 at his Doral resort in Miami. He was joined by Miami&rsquo;s mayor, Francis Suarez.</span> Photograph: Brian Snyder/Reuters</figcaption></figure></article><article><header></header><p><strong>Eric Adams</strong>, the mayor of New York, just announced that he will not end his re-election campaign, despite reports that he was recently offered a position in the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration">Trump administration</a> if he would do so.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Eric Adams at an event in New York in August.</span> Photograph: Lev Radin/Shutterstock</figcaption></figure></article><article><header><h2>Trump claims 'a lot of illegal aliens' worked at raided Georgia plant, but warrant targeted just four</h2></header><p>Speaking to reporters in the Oval Office, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> just claimed that &ldquo;a lot of illegal aliens, some not the best of people&rdquo; were working at a factory in Georgia raided by immigration officers on Friday, resulting in nearly 500 arrests.</p><p>However, a warrant for the raid on the HL-GA battery factory, which is being built to make car batteries for South Korean electric vehicles, identified just four &ldquo;target persons&rdquo;. The warrant was obtained and <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26084943-hyundaisearchwarrant/">posted online by Politico</a>.</p></article><article><header><h2>Trump signs executive order directing Department of Defense to call itself 'Department of War'</h2></header><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> signed an executive order on Friday authorizing the US Department of Defense to refer to itself as the &ldquo;Department of War&rdquo;, as part of an attempt to formalize his rebranding effort without the legally required act of Congress.</p><p>According to a draft White House factsheet seen by the Guardian on Thursday, the order designates &ldquo;Department of War&rdquo; as a &ldquo;secondary title&rdquo;, as a way to get around the need for congressional approval to formally rename a federal agency.</p><p>The move, to have the executive branch use a name for the department Trump called &ldquo;much more appropriate&rdquo;, restores a name <a href="https://www.defense.gov/Multimedia/Experience/The-History-of-the-Department-of-Defense/#jul1947">used until 1947</a>, when Congress merged the previously independent war department and navy department with the air force into a single organization, known as the National Military Establishment. In 1949, Congress <a href="https://www.defense.gov/Multimedia/Experience/The-History-of-the-Department-of-Defense/#1949">changed the name</a> of the National Military Establishment to the Department of Defense, and made the army, navy and air force secretaries subordinate to a single, cabinet-level secretary of defense.</p><p>Referring to the creation of the defense department in 1949, <a href="https://x.com/cspan/status/1964064319714300314">the president said</a>: &ldquo;We decided to go woke and we changed the name to Department of Defense, so we&rsquo;re going Department of War&rdquo;.</p><p>Trump also introduced the defense secretary, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/pete-hegseth">Pete Hegseth</a>, as &ldquo;our secretary of war&rdquo; and claimed that the name change &ldquo;really it has to do with winning&rdquo;, suggesting that the US military had somehow been hampered by the choice &ldquo;to be politically correct, or wokey&rdquo; and, as a result, failed to win &ldquo;wars that we would&rsquo;ve won easily&rdquo;.</p><p>The draft White House factsheet on Trump&rsquo;s rebranding initiative implicitly acknowledged that only Congress can formally change the department&rsquo;s name, saying that the order would authorize the defense secretary to propose legislation that would make the change permanent.</p></article><article><header><h2>New York's mayor, Eric Adams to make 'important announcement regarding the future of his campaign'</h2></header><p>Eric Adams, the sitting mayor of New York, has <a href="https://x.com/bern_hogan/status/1964050160775795120">just announced</a> a hastily scheduled event to begin 30 minutes from now in which he will &ldquo;make an important announcement regarding the future of his campaign&rdquo;. The event is scheduled for 4.30pm ET.</p><p>Adams, who is running as an independent and trails in the polls, has previously <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/03/eric-adams-trump-new-york-mayor">denied reports</a> that he is in talks with the White House over taking a role in the Trump administration in exchange for ending his apparently doomed re-election campaign.</p><p>At a dinner with tech industry leaders last night, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> denied that he is encouraging Adams to drop out of the race to help New York&rsquo;s former governor, Andrew Cuomo, defeat Zohran Mamdani, the 33-year-old democratic socialist who is the frontrunner to be elected mayor in November. Trump then immediately said that he would like Adams to drop out for that reason.</p><p>The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/05/nyregion/eric-adams-saudi-arabia-ambassador.html">reported</a> on Friday that Adams met in person with Trump&rsquo;s friend and diplomatic envoy Steve Witkoff to discuss the possibility of being nominated as US ambassador to Saudi Arabia.</p><p>Last year, federal prosecutors <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/sep/26/eric-adams-bribes-turkey">accused</a> members of the Turkish government of a years-long influence campaign to cultivate and secure favors from Adams.</p><p>In the federal indictment, the US attorney for New York&rsquo;s southern district alleged that government officials and business leaders with ties to Recep Tayyip Erdo&#287;an, the Turkish president, showered Adams with thousands in illegal foreign campaign donations and free or heavily discounted luxury hotel stays and flights around the world.</p><p>Charges against Adams were dropped by the Trump justice department this year, over the strong objections of prosecutors who claimed that there was an explicit quid pro quo arrangement in which the mayor would cooperate with federal immigration enforcement in the city in return for corruption charges being dropped.</p><p>Should Adams become the US ambassador to Saudi Arabia, he would oversee diplomacy with the kingdom whose de-facto leader, crown prince Mohammed bin Salman, US intelligence believes approved the 2018 murder of the Washington Post journalist Jamal Khashoggi in Turkey.</p></article><article><header><h2>The day so far</h2></header><p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> plans to announce executive orders shortly in the Oval Office, with the theme we know most about so far being an instruction to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/trump-defense-war-department">rename</a> the Department of Defense the <strong>&ldquo;Department of War&rdquo;</strong>.</p><p>Until then, here&rsquo;s a quick recap of some of the day&rsquo;s key developments:</p><ul> <li><p><strong>Trump</strong> criticized the <strong>European Union</strong>&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/sep/05/google-fined-european-union">decision to fine</a> <strong>Google</strong> $3.46bn over antitrust concerns and threatened a wider trade probe against the EU in response to the move.</p></li> <li><p>Health secretary <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong> plans to announce that use of Kenvue&rsquo;s popular over-the-counter pain medication <strong>Tylenol</strong> in pregnant women is potentially linked to autism, without including evidence for the claims, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/health/healthcare/rfk-jr-hhs-to-link-autism-to-tylenol-use-in-pregnancy-and-folate-deficiencies-e3acbb4c?mod=hp_lead_pos2">the Wall Street Journal reported</a>, citing people familiar with the matter.</p></li> <li><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/state-of-georgia">Georgia</a></strong> is about to become the eighth state to send national guard troops to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/washington-dc">Washington DC</a> to support <strong>Trump</strong>&rsquo;s federal law enforcement big foot operation there, as the US capital <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/national-guard-washington-dc-lawsuit-trump-administration">sues the administration</a> over its actions.</p></li> <li><p><strong>Most of the 475 people</strong> arrested in a massive Immigration and Customs Enforcement (Ice) raid at a Hyundai factory construction site in southern Georgia <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb18108f085f50533e8841#block-68bb18108f085f50533e8841">are Korean</a> nationals.</p></li> <li><p><strong>The federal Ice raid</strong> is being <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb17068f08638a14b783ae#block-68bb17068f08638a14b783ae">described</a> as the biggest single Department of Homeland Security (DHS, the parent agency of Ice) enforcement operation at one side in the department&rsquo;s history. The DHS was created after <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/september11">9/11</a>.</p></li> <li><p><strong>Treasury secretary Scott Bessent</strong> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb12238f08638a14b7836c#block-68bb12238f08638a14b7836c">called for</a> renewed scrutiny of the Federal Reserve, including its power to set interest rates, as the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration">Trump administration</a> continues its efforts to exert control over the US central bank.</p></li> <li><p><strong>Vladimir Putin</strong> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bb032e8f087e152e27f403#block-68bb032e8f087e152e27f403">has said</a> any western troops placed in Ukraine would be &ldquo;legitimate targets&rdquo; for Russian strikes, upping the stakes for Kyiv as Donald Trump&rsquo;s efforts to forge a peace deal show little sign that are any closer to success.</p></li> <li><p><strong>Trump</strong> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/05/donald-trump-pentagon-department-of-war-immigration-tariffs-us-politics-live-news-updates?page=with%3Ablock-68bab3fe8f08305da53f837f#block-68bab3fe8f08305da53f837f">is sending</a> 10 F-35 stealth fighter jets to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/puerto-rico">Puerto Rico</a> to bolster US military operations against drug cartels in the Caribbean region. The action to send jets to be based in the US territory follows a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/02/trump-venezuela-boat-lethal-strike">deadly US missile strike</a> on Tuesday on a boat that the administration insisted was carrying 11 Venezuelan drug traffickers.</p></li> <li><p>And the big economics news of the day was that <strong>the US added just 22,000 jobs in August</strong>, continuing the slowdown amid Trump&rsquo;s tariff policy.</p></li> </ul></article><article><header><h2>Trump threatens trade investigation over EU antitrust fine against Google</h2></header><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> has criticized the <strong>European Union</strong>&rsquo;s decision to fine <strong>Google</strong> $3.46bn over antitrust concerns and threatened a wider trade probe against the EU in response to the move.</p><p>&ldquo;We cannot let this happen to brilliant and unprecedented American Ingenuity and, if it does, I will be forced to start a Section 301 proceeding to nullify the unfair penalties being charged to these Taxpaying American Companies,&rdquo; the president wrote on his Truth Social platform.</p><p>Google&rsquo;s fine for <strong>breaching the EU&rsquo;s competition rules by favoring its own digital advertising services</strong> marks the fourth such antitrust penalty for the company as well as a retreat from previous threats to break up the tech giant.</p><p>The <strong>European Commission</strong>, the 27-nation bloc&rsquo;s executive branch and top antitrust enforcer, also <strong>ordered the US company to end its &ldquo;self-preferencing practices&rdquo;</strong> and take steps to <strong>stop &ldquo;conflicts of interest&rdquo; along the advertising technology supply chain</strong>.</p><p>The commission&rsquo;s investigation found that <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/google">Google</a> had <strong>&ldquo;abused&rdquo; its dominant positions</strong> in the ad-technology ecosystem.</p><p>Google said the decision was &ldquo;wrong&rdquo; and that it would appeal.</p><figure><gu-island></gu-island></figure></article><article><header><h2>Kennedy and HHS to link Tylenol use in pregnancy to autism &ndash; report</h2></header><p>Health secretary <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong> plans to announce that use of Kenvue&rsquo;s popular over-the-counter pain medication <strong>Tylenol</strong> in pregnant women is potentially linked to autism, without including evidence for the claims, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/health/healthcare/rfk-jr-hhs-to-link-autism-to-tylenol-use-in-pregnancy-and-folate-deficiencies-e3acbb4c?mod=hp_lead_pos2">the Wall Street Journal reported</a>, citing people familiar with the matter.</p><p>Kennedy, in a report, will also suggest a medicine derived from folate called folinic acid can be used to treat symptoms of autism in some people, the WSJ reported.</p><p>Tylenol, whose active ingredient is <strong>acetaminophen</strong>, is a widely used pain reliever, including by pregnant women.</p><p>The report, expected this month from the US Department of Health and Human Services, is likely to highlight low levels of folate, an important vitamin, and Tylenol taken during pregnancy, as well as other potential causes of autism, the report said.</p><p>The health department and Kenvue did not immediately respond to a Reuters request for comment.</p><p>It is not the first time Kenvue or J&amp;J have faced questions about the link between Tylenol and the condition. In 2023, a judge rejected claims the drug causes autism if mothers take it during pregnancy.</p><p>The <strong>American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists</strong> says Tylenol is <a href="https://www.acog.org/womens-health/faqs/headaches-and-pregnancy">safe to use in pregnancy</a>, though it recommends pregnant women consult their doctors before using it, as with all medicines.</p><p><strong>Children&rsquo;s Health Defense</strong>, the anti-vaccine group formerly headed by Kennedy, has posted several times in recent weeks on social media site X about the potential link between Tylenol and autism.</p></article><article><header><h2>Georgia to send national guard troops to Washington</h2></header><p><strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/state-of-georgia">Georgia</a></strong> is about to become the eighth state to send national guard troops to <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/washington-dc">Washington DC</a> to support <strong>Donald Trump</strong>&rsquo;s federal law enforcement big foot operation there, as the US capital <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/04/national-guard-washington-dc-lawsuit-trump-administration">sues the administration</a> over its actions.</p><p>Georgia governor <strong>Brian Kemp</strong> announced he would be sending 316 members of the state national guard to Washington later this month, in the latest indication that Trump&rsquo;s law enforcement action there will drag on, the Associated Press reports.</p><p>Kemp, a Republican, said he will mobilize the roughly 300 troops in mid-September to take part in Trump&rsquo;s DC operation to relieve soldiers from elsewhere who deployed earlier.</p><blockquote><p>Georgia is proud to stand with the Trump administration in its mission to ensure the security and beauty of our nation&rsquo;s capital,&rdquo; Kemp said in a statement.</p></blockquote><p>Trump initially called up 800 members of the District of Columbia national guard to assist federal law enforcement in his unilateral action to impose federal resources on DC with the stated goal of cracking down on crime, homelessness and illegal immigration. Since then, seven other Republican-led states have sent troops &ndash; Louisiana, Mississippi, Ohio, South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee and West Virginia.</p><figure><div><picture><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=700&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=700&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><img alt="Train at station" src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/a26d68fe21a060f02fe0b2d67789a9f88f9999ab/0_0_6000_4000/master/6000.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none" width="465" height="310"></source></source></source></source></picture></div><figcaption><span>National guard military police at L&rsquo;Enfant Plaza station in Washington.</span> Photograph: Kent Nishimura/Getty Images</figcaption></figure></article><gu-island></gu-island></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/c5fa8746d48051d4fbd845faa640889c986dd2f5/0_0_5500_3667/master/5500.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"></p><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d4710db85849815af296993927d6b13dad62e770/0_0_3500_2333/master/3500.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 06:08:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/leading-billionaire-rambles-about-science-and-trump-had-to-take-it.html?outputType</link><title>Bill Gates rambles about vaccine and science — and Trump had to take it (nj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9bxdz/bill_gates_rambles_about_vaccine_and_science_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9bxdz/bill_gates_rambles_about_vaccine_and_science_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n9bxdz/bill_gates_rambles_about_vaccine_and_science_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><nav><ol><li><a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/" title="Navigate to Politics">Politics</a></li></ol></nav><ul><li><time>Updated: Sep. 05, 2025, 6:10 p.m.</time></li><li><time>Published: Sep. 05, 2025, 9:13 a.m.</time></li></ul></div><div><article><div><figure><div><picture><img alt="APTOPIX Trump" src="https://www.nj.com/resizer/v2/5X44ISCRZVG4JJMCFWILIE5WZY.jpg?auth=e42f0b2f37d25f59c0bd4d8edb5c0e6a54ff5db55b1e3e259bb89a6cf7c5c6ae&amp;width=1280&amp;quality=90" srcset="https://www.nj.com/resizer/v2/5X44ISCRZVG4JJMCFWILIE5WZY.jpg?auth=e42f0b2f37d25f59c0bd4d8edb5c0e6a54ff5db55b1e3e259bb89a6cf7c5c6ae&amp;width=500&amp;quality=90 500w, https://www.nj.com/resizer/v2/5X44ISCRZVG4JJMCFWILIE5WZY.jpg?auth=e42f0b2f37d25f59c0bd4d8edb5c0e6a54ff5db55b1e3e259bb89a6cf7c5c6ae&amp;width=800&amp;quality=90 800w, https://www.nj.com/resizer/v2/5X44ISCRZVG4JJMCFWILIE5WZY.jpg?auth=e42f0b2f37d25f59c0bd4d8edb5c0e6a54ff5db55b1e3e259bb89a6cf7c5c6ae&amp;width=1280&amp;quality=90 1280w"></picture><figcaption><span>President Donald Trump hosts a dinner with first lady Melania Trump in the State Dinning Room of the White House, Thursday, Sept. 4, 2025, in Washington. (AP Photo/Alex Brandon)<span>AP</span></span></figcaption></div></figure></div><div><p>President <a href="https://www.nj.com/topic/donald-trump/" title="https://www.nj.com/topic/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a> invited Bill Gates to the White House &mdash; and some in MAGA world did not take it well.</p><p>Trump hosted a dinner for top tech leaders on Thursday as he touted research on artificial intelligence and investments in the United States. More than a dozen executives attended &mdash; including Gates, the co-founder of Microsoft, as well as Meta&rsquo;s Mark Zuckerberg, Apple&rsquo;s Tim Cook, OpenAI&lsquo;s Sam Altman, Google&rsquo;s Sundar Pichai and Microsoft&rsquo;s Satya Nadella &mdash; who showered the president with praise and pledged to boost spending in the country.</p><p>Tech billionaire <a href="https://www.nj.com/topic/elon-musk/" title="https://www.nj.com/topic/elon-musk/">Elon Musk</a>, once a close ally of Trump before having a <a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/07/is-trump-getting-back-together-with-elon-musk-heres-what-he-said.html" title="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/07/is-trump-getting-back-together-with-elon-musk-heres-what-he-said.html">public breakup</a>, was notably absent. He <a href="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1963624123998896368" title="https://x.com/elonmusk/status/1963624123998896368">said</a> on his social media platform X that he had been invited, but was unable to attend, and sent a representative instead.</p><p>During the event, Trump asked Gates if he wanted to &ldquo;say a few words.&rdquo; Gates then proceeded to give a lengthy response, during which the president continued to nod cautiously. </p><p>&ldquo;Well, I&rsquo;m in the second phase of my career, giving away all the wonderful money that Satya&rsquo;s good work has helped multiply a lot. But I think the thing that ties my first career that I still spend some time on because AI is so phenomenal, and my second career, is innovation, and innovating in health in areas like vaccines or gene editing,&rdquo; Gates said.</p><p>&ldquo;The president and I are talking about taking American innovation to the next level to cure and even eradicate some of these diseases. He mentioned polio, which is one that we&rsquo;re close. We don&rsquo;t need new science on that one. For some like HIV and sickle cell, we do need new science, but the U.S. has the seeds,&rdquo; he added.</p><p>Gates went on to say that AI could help expand health care access, with the United States at the helm. </p><p>&ldquo;The work being done by the people at this table is changing the world,&rdquo; he added.</p><p>A band of MAGA faithful raged at Trump&rsquo;s spotlight on Gates, who has become a punching bag for conspiracy theories related to vaccines. A portion of the Gates Foundation&rsquo;s work focuses on vaccine development, with the goal of ensuring &ldquo;a secure and sustainable supply of consistently high-quality, appropriately priced vaccines&rdquo; to meet the &ldquo;needs of individuals in low- and middle-income countries,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/our-work/programs/global-health/vaccine-development" title="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/our-work/programs/global-health/vaccine-development">according to its website</a>.</p><p>Conservative influencer Robby Starbuck said it is &ldquo;infuriating&rdquo; to watch Gates &ldquo;in a position of honor.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;I want a future where we stop giving power to evil people like Gates. He&rsquo;s a globalist who hates the America First ideology. His God complex deserves nothing but contempt,&rdquo; Starbuck <a href="https://x.com/robbystarbuck/status/1963770318339842162" title="https://x.com/robbystarbuck/status/1963770318339842162">continued</a> on X.</p><p>Derrick Evans, a former West Virginia delegate and Jan. 6 rioter, <a href="https://x.com/DerrickEvans4WV/status/1963921784392073664" title="https://x.com/DerrickEvans4WV/status/1963921784392073664">said</a> that &ldquo;Trump hanging out with Bill Gates is concerning to me.&rdquo;</p><p>Conservative activist J.J. Carrell also <a href="https://x.com/JJCarrell14/status/1963771086287286301" title="https://x.com/JJCarrell14/status/1963771086287286301">weighed in</a>: &ldquo;What in the F@CK is going on in the Trump Administration! ... Gates is talking about vaccines and Trump just sits there!!!!&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;For the record I&rsquo;m not going to ever eat Bill Gates fake meat, bugs, take the never ending vaccines, or gene editing,&rdquo; Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene (R-Ga.) <a href="https://x.com/mtgreenee/status/1963917306792476957" title="https://x.com/mtgreenee/status/1963917306792476957">posted</a> on her personal account on Friday.</p><p>Right-wing media personality Mike Cernovich <a href="https://x.com/Cernovich/status/1963774776297808185" title="https://x.com/Cernovich/status/1963774776297808185">added</a>, &ldquo;There is no reason for Bill Gates to be in the White House.&rdquo;</p><p>Hours earlier, Health and Human Services Secretary <a href="https://www.nj.com/topic/robert-f-kennedy-jr/" title="https://www.nj.com/topic/robert-f-kennedy-jr/">Robert F. Kennedy Jr.</a> faced a <a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/trump-official-gets-hounded-and-maga-rushes-to-defend-his-honor-full-of-sh-.html" title="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/trump-official-gets-hounded-and-maga-rushes-to-defend-his-honor-full-of-sh-.html">grilling</a> from lawmakers of both parties on vaccine policy and other public health priorities of the Trump administration.</p><p>Sen. Bill Cassidy (R-La.) specifically <a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/gop-senator-delivers-epic-takedown-of-trump-health-czar-during-tense-hearing.html" title="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/gop-senator-delivers-epic-takedown-of-trump-health-czar-during-tense-hearing.html">criticized</a> Kennedy for narrowing the recommendation for the new COVID-19 shot, as well as <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/press-room/hhs-winds-down-mrna-development-under-barda.html" title="https://www.hhs.gov/press-room/hhs-winds-down-mrna-development-under-barda.html">slashing</a> $500 million in funding for the development of mRNA vaccines. And Sen. John Barrasso (R-Wyo.) said he has &ldquo;grown deeply concerned&rdquo; about Kennedy&rsquo;s tenure.</p><p>&ldquo;I support vaccines. Vaccines save lives. If we&rsquo;re going to make America healthy again, we can&rsquo;t allow public health to be undermined,&rdquo; Barrasso said.</p><p>Kennedy <a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/whos-the-most-popular-trump-official-polling-analyst-reveals-surprising-answer.html" title="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/whos-the-most-popular-trump-official-polling-analyst-reveals-surprising-answer.html">defiantly defended</a> the mission of his department and his <a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/08/exiting-officials-give-dire-warning-about-trump-czar-rfk-jr-millions-of-american-lives-at-risk.html" title="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/08/exiting-officials-give-dire-warning-about-trump-czar-rfk-jr-millions-of-american-lives-at-risk.html">recent firing</a> of Dr. Susan Monarez, who served as the director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for about a month.</p><p>&ldquo;We are the sickest country in the world. That&rsquo;s why we have to fire people at the CDC,&rdquo; Kennedy said during the hearing. &ldquo;They did not do their job. This was their job to keep us healthy. And I need to fire some of those people to make sure this doesn&rsquo;t happen again.&rdquo;</p><p>During later remarks, Trump stood by Kennedy, telling reporters, &ldquo;I like the fact that he&rsquo;s different.&rdquo; He acknowledged that he didn&rsquo;t watch the hearing, but had &ldquo;heard he did very well today.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;He means very well, and he&rsquo;s got some little different ideas,&rdquo; Trump said. &ldquo;I guarantee a lot of the people at this table like RFK Jr., and I do, but he&rsquo;s got a different take, and we want to listen to all of those takes.&rdquo;</p><p>Monarez, in an <a href="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/robert-f-kennedy-jr-the-cdc-and-me-b4ca2eaa?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAgeZZ-BwWgPjSlYDMFnarjgPM5xJlDAar0-ulLcExu_D2BlQtvCW-vWD2zMnWw%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68b9e896&amp;gaa_sig=TgF5x_CqnAJQTOIHgOn8369BRpzNEiu2ZWlq8TUW5ikHv9ZQWp7MVXzf-Nkum1k0LqY36_uVtKaqv23wkcipaw%3D%3D" title="https://www.wsj.com/opinion/robert-f-kennedy-jr-the-cdc-and-me-b4ca2eaa?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAgeZZ-BwWgPjSlYDMFnarjgPM5xJlDAar0-ulLcExu_D2BlQtvCW-vWD2zMnWw%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68b9e896&amp;gaa_sig=TgF5x_CqnAJQTOIHgOn8369BRpzNEiu2ZWlq8TUW5ikHv9ZQWp7MVXzf-Nkum1k0LqY36_uVtKaqv23wkcipaw%3D%3D">opinion piece</a> for The Wall Street Journal published Thursday, said that she had lost her job after 29 days, but &ldquo;America&rsquo;s children could lose far more.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;The CDC can&rsquo;t fulfill its obligation to the American people if its leader can&rsquo;t demand proof in decision-making. If discarding evidence for ideology becomes the norm, why should parents, physicians or the public trust the CDC&rsquo;s guidance?&rdquo; she wrote.</p><section><ul><li><a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/trump-just-hit-an-all-time-high-approval-rating-white-house-says-heres-where-he-stands.html">Trump just hit an all-time high approval rating, White House says. Here&rsquo;s where he stands</a></li><li><a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/popular-actress-fires-back-after-trump-threatens-to-revoke-her-citizenship-hes-like-a-cornered-rat.html">Popular actress fires back after Trump threatens to revoke her citizenship: &lsquo;He&rsquo;s like a cornered rat&rsquo;</a></li><li><a href="https://www.nj.com/politics/2025/09/trump-doj-issues-baffling-apology-after-official-gets-caught-in-epstein-trap-are-you-f-stupid.html">Trump DOJ issues baffling apology after official gets caught in Epstein trap: &lsquo;Are you f------ stupid?&rsquo;</a></li></ul></section><p><i>Our journalism needs your support. Please subscribe today to </i><a href="https://www.nj.com/"><i>NJ.com</i></a><i>.</i></p></div><p>If you purchase a product or register for an account through a link on our site, we may receive compensation.<span> By using this site, you consent to our <a href="https://www.advancelocal.com/advancelocalUserAgreement/user-agreement.html">User Agreement</a> and agree that your clicks, interactions, and personal information may be collected, recorded, and/or stored by us and social media and other third-party partners in accordance with our <a href="https://www.advancelocal.com/advancelocalUserAgreement/privacy-policy.html">Privacy Policy.</a></span></p></article></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 23:15:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wired.com/story/tech-ceos-donald-trump-white-house/</link><title>All the President’s Tech CEOs | At a White House dinner Thursday night, America’s tech executives put on an uncanny display of fealty to Donald Trump. (wired.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n96tub/all_the_presidents_tech_ceos_at_a_white_house/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n96tub/all_the_presidents_tech_ceos_at_a_white_house/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n96tub/all_the_presidents_tech_ceos_at_a_white_house/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.wired.com/photos/68ba2ddb68c1027d7bc61668/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/Tech-CEOs-Fawn-Over-Trump-Politics-2233060770.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><p><span>The scene opens</span> confusingly. The camera zooms too close to the president&rsquo;s face; the table at which the <a href="https://www.wired.com/tag/big-tech">tech executives</a> are seated seems far too long. <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/mark-zuckerberg-secretive-hawaii-compound-burial-ground/">Mark Zuckerberg</a> is there, and Bill Gates and Tim Cook and Satya Nadella and <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-leave-meta-superintelligence-labs-openai/">Sam Altman</a> and on and on, a baker&rsquo;s dozen or so of Silicon Valley&rsquo;s most powerful people&mdash;cutthroat competitors all&mdash;united here to pledge allegiance to Donald Trump.</p><p>The introduction from Trump is characteristically both overgilded and confusing: &ldquo;It's an honor to be here with this group of people. They're leading a revolution in business and in genius and every other word.&rdquo; And then, about 90 seconds in, the pandering begins.</p><p>This was Donald Trump&rsquo;s dinner with tech leaders at the State Dining Room in the White House on Thursday evening, broadcast in part for all to see <a href="https://www.c-span.org/program/white-house-event/president-trump-hosts-tech-leaders-for-white-house-dinner/665202">on C-SPAN</a>. It&rsquo;s in many ways a remarkable document, the culmination of months of <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/tech-ceos-trump-claims-are-courting-him/">Big Tech cozying up</a> to the administration.</p><p>One by one, Trump asked the executives how much they were investing in the United States. One by one, they obliged, praising Trump&rsquo;s leadership along the way. The president has run this play previously with his cabinet members, powerful people tripping over themselves in the race toward Trump&rsquo;s good graces. But there was an eeriness to seeing that same dynamic among Big Tech&rsquo;s braintrust, like passing a camera around to take turns wishing a distant, unloved uncle a very happy Thanksgiving.</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s going to be something like $600 billion through &rsquo;28,&rdquo; said <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/mark-zuckerberg-meta-offer-top-ai-talent-300-million/">Zuckerberg</a> about Meta&rsquo;s domestic infrastructure investments. Sergey Brin congratulated Trump on &ldquo;applying pressure&rdquo; in Venezuela, two days after a US drone operator <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/us-military-kills-11-people-strike-alleged-drug-boat-venezuela-trump-says-2025-09-03/">extrajudicially murdered</a> 11 people on an alleged drug cartel boat.</p><p>Everyone else praised the administration&rsquo;s AI policy. <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/microsofts-satya-nadella-is-betting-everything-on-ai/">Microsoft&rsquo;s Nadella</a> shouted out Melania Trump in particular for her leadership in &ldquo;skilling and economic opportunity that comes with AI.&rdquo; (The first lady launched a Presidential Artificial Intelligence Challenge last month and hosted an education-themed AI task force meeting prior to the dinner on Thursday.) <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/sundar-pichai-google-ai-microsoft-openai/">Google CEO Sundar Pichai</a> and <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/lisa-su-runs-amd-and-is-out-for-nvidias-blood/">AMD CEO Lisa Su</a> praised the Trump administration&rsquo;s AI initiatives.</p><p>&ldquo;I want to thank you for setting the tone such that we could make a major investment in the United States,&rdquo; said Cook, referring to Apple&rsquo;s pledge to put $600 billion into US manufacturing. Given that Apple made that commitment under <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/us-tariffs-could-make-smartphones-dumber/">threat of crippling tariffs on smartphones</a>, it was a bit like thanking the school bully for setting the tone such that you can give him your lunch money.</p><p>For enthusiasm it was hard to beat Oracle CEO Safra Catz, who had previously served as a member of Trump&rsquo;s transition team. &ldquo;You've unleashed American innovation and creativity. All the work you're doing in basically every cabinet post in addition to what's coming out of the White House is making it possible for America to win,&rdquo; Catz said. &ldquo;I think this is the most exciting time in America ever.&rdquo; And with that, after a quick joke about his rumored demise, Trump opened up the floor to questions from the media. If you watch closely, you can catch Zuckerberg giving someone across the table an eyebrow raise for the ages.</p></div><div><p>Trump loves a banquet, which presumably means he loves a seating chart. Zuckerberg sat directly to Trump&rsquo;s right, while Gates scored a chair next to Melania Trump on the left. Sergey Brin and his &ldquo;really wonderful MAGA girlfriend&rdquo;&mdash;Trump&rsquo;s words&mdash;Gerelyn Gilbert-Soto sat directly across from the president. (Gilbert-Soto comes by that praise honestly; in addition to being an ardent supporter of Trump online, she has <a href="https://x.com/Omggerelyn/status/1963326746322927926">posted</a> on X that &ldquo;this world is a spiritual battlefield built on pagan roots, you can&rsquo;t escape it,&rdquo; specifically calling out Burning Man, Halloween, Christmas, and the US government as evil. This was on Wednesday.)</p><p>Emily Post fans will have already read into the significance of who sat where. &ldquo;The host or hostess of an official luncheon or dinner seats the guests according to rank,&rdquo; according to the etiquette <a href="https://emilypost.com/advice/seating-at-an-official-luncheon-or-dinner">guide</a>. &ldquo;Guests who have no protocol ranking are seated according to the unspoken rank the host assigns to them.&rdquo; Pity Nadella, seated in the table&rsquo;s hinterlands.</p><p>(You may have noted the absence of <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/elon-musk-digital-coup-doge-data-ai/">Elon Musk</a>, <a href="https://www.wired.com/tag/jeff-bezos/">Jeff Bezos</a>, and <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nvidia-hardware-is-eating-the-world-jensen-huang/">Nvidia&rsquo;s Jensen Huang</a>. It&rsquo;s unclear whether they weren&rsquo;t invited or had a scheduling conflict, but between <a href="https://www.wired.com/tag/doge">DOGE</a>, The Washington Post&rsquo;s hard-right turn, and <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/nvidia-chips-export-controls-trump-h20-security/">Nvidia&rsquo;s dealmaking</a>, it&rsquo;s safe to say they&rsquo;re already in Trump&rsquo;s good graces.)</p><p>There&rsquo;s also the matter of who got to speak and who didn&rsquo;t. <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/sam-altman-says-chatgpt-is-on-track-to-out-talk-humanity/">OpenAI CEO Sam Altman</a> did, while <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/researchers-leave-meta-superintelligence-labs-openai/">Meta Superintelligence Labs leader Alexandr Wang</a> did not. White House <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/crypto-industry-hails-david-sacks-czar/">AI and crypto czar David Sacks</a> got prime speaking placement, while his <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/musk-trump-feud-venture-capitalists-pick-sides/">podcast cohost Chamanth Palihapitiya</a> stared quietly at his stemware.</p><p>Even more telling than who didn&rsquo;t speak is what wasn&rsquo;t said. The topic of immigration, critically important to the <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/uncanny-valley-podcast-why-silicon-valley-needs-immigration/">future of the US tech industry</a>&mdash;and surely of personal significance to the many immigrants seated at the table&mdash;went unmentioned. Other than Cook&rsquo;s rosy allusion, the potentially devastating <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/tariffs-are-going-to-make-your-electronics-more-expensive/">effect of tariffs on consumer tech prices</a> was off the table. And while it likely would have been too much to ask, particularly for this audience, the question of how exactly the US plans to power all of this AI innovation, and the accompanying, astronomical <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/ai-carbon-emissions-energy-unknown-mystery-research/">environmental and consumer costs</a>, didn&rsquo;t even amount to an afterthought.</p><p>For years, a convenient shorthand for the average person&rsquo;s relationship with Big Tech has been that you&rsquo;re the product. That&rsquo;s still true. But as the most powerful executives in America continue to kowtow to a president who is systematically dismantling the foundations of democracy, it may be time for another axiom: The only principle is power.</p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 20:00:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ft.com/content/31feb335-4945-475e-baaa-3b880d9cf8ce</link><title>Computer scientist Geoffrey Hinton: ‘AI will make a few people much richer and most people poorer’ (ft.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n94iku/computer_scientist_geoffrey_hinton_ai_will_make_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n94iku/computer_scientist_geoffrey_hinton_ai_will_make_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n94iku/computer_scientist_geoffrey_hinton_ai_will_make_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><div><p><span></span><span>Subscribe to unlock this article</span></p></div><div><h2><span><span>Join FT Edit</span></span></h2><h2><span><span>Only </span><span>Rs4490</span><span> a year</span></span></h2><p><span><span>Get 2 months free with an annual subscription at </span><span>was </span><span>Rs5388</span><span>now </span><span>Rs4490</span><span>. Access to eight surprising articles a day, hand-picked by FT editors. For seamless reading, access content via the FT Edit page on FT.com and receive the FT Edit newsletter.</span></span></p></div></div><div><h2>Explore more offers.</h2><div><div><div><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_trial.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg" alt></p><h3>Trial</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs100</span><span> for 4 weeks</span></span></p><p><span><span>Then </span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month. Complete digital access to quality FT journalism. Cancel anytime during your trial.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Standard Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs2850</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Essential digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Premium Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Complete digital access to quality FT journalism with expert analysis from industry leaders. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div></div></div><div><h2>Explore our full range of subscriptions.</h2><div><div><div><h3>For individuals</h3></div><p>Discover all the plans currently available in your country</p></div><div><div><h3> For multiple readers</h3></div><p>Digital access for organisations. Includes exclusive features and content.</p></div></div></div><div><div><h2>Why the FT?</h2><p>See why over a million readers pay to read the Financial Times.</p></div><p><a href="https://subs.ft.com/whytheft?ft-content-uuid=31feb335-4945-475e-baaa-3b880d9cf8ce">Find out why</a></p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_standard.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg"></p><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_premium.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:25:18 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/rfk-jr-trump-covid-mrna-vaccines-kill-people-senate-1235421601/</link><title>RFK Jr. Claims mRNA Vaccines Kill People in Heated Senate Hearing | RFK Jr. said he didn’t know how many Americans died from Covid-19 or whether Covid-19 vaccines saved any lives (rollingstone.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n8ne95/rfk_jr_claims_mrna_vaccines_kill_people_in_heated/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n8ne95/rfk_jr_claims_mrna_vaccines_kill_people_in_heated/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n8ne95/rfk_jr_claims_mrna_vaccines_kill_people_in_heated/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.rollingstone.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/RFK-Jr-heated-covid-vax-hearing.jpg?w=1600&h=900&crop=1' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Robert F. Kennedy Jr. said he didn&rsquo;t know how many Americans died from Covid-19 or whether Covid-19 vaccines saved any lives</p></div><div><p><a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/health/">Health</a> and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. claimed today that mRNA vaccines kill people during a tense <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/senate/">Senate</a> hearing. The most common <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/covid/">Covid</a>-19 jabs, such as those produced by <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/pfizer/">Pfizer</a> and <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/moderna/">Moderna</a>, are mRNA vaccines.</p><p>Sen. Michael Bennet (D-Colo.) asked Kennedy, <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a>&rsquo;s top health regulator, about his <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/rfk-jr-fires-cdc-vaccine-panel-1235360211/">firing</a> of every member of the Centers for Disease Control <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/vaccine/">vaccine</a> advisory committee, replacing them with his own picks.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;Are you aware that &hellip; one of these new members, Dr. [Retsef] Levy, wrote that &lsquo;evidence is mounting and indisputable that mRNA vaccines cause serious harm, including death, especially among young people,&rsquo;&rdquo; Bennet said. &ldquo;Yes or no, are you aware that he said that?&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;I wasn&rsquo;t aware. I agree with it,&rdquo; responded Kennedy, a longtime anti-vaxxer.</p><p>Levi is a professor of operations management at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and former intelligence official for the Israeli military. He does not have a medical background, and there is a <a href="https://actionnetwork.org/petitions/firelevi">petition</a> calling for his firing.&nbsp;&nbsp; </p><p>In January 2023, Levi <a href="https://x.com/RetsefL/status/1619945525670981632">posted on X</a> that mRNA vaccines cause harm: &ldquo;The evidence is mounting and indisputable that MRNA vaccines cause serious harm including death, especially among young people. We have to stop giving them immediately!&rdquo;</p><p>Kennedy&rsquo;s speech was raspy and labored throughout the Senate Finance Committee hearing, with viewers <a href="https://x.com/acyn/status/1963613755008577692?s=46">noting</a> that heavy breathing, which almost sounded like snoring, could be heard over the microphone. </p><p><a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/rfk-jr/">RFK Jr.</a> frequently sparred with Democratic senators, and he was also testy with Sen. <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/bill-cassidy/">Bill Cassidy</a> (R-La.), a physician who cast a key vote to confirm him to lead the Health and Human Services Department (<a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/hhs/">HHS</a>).&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;You just told Sen. Bennet that the Covid vaccine killed more people than Covid,&rdquo; Cassidy said.</p><p>&ldquo;I did not say that,&rdquo; Kennedy insisted.</p><p>Cassidy noted that patients are having trouble getting Covid vaccines, now that the Food and Drug Administration &mdash; which is part of HHS &mdash; <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/covid-vaccine-booster-fda-policy-1235345101/">has limited</a> access to annual booster shots to people over the age of 65 or those with certain medical conditions. </p><section> <h2> Editor&rsquo;s picks </h2> </section><p>&ldquo;I would say, effectively, we&rsquo;re denying people vaccines,&rdquo; Cassidy said.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;You&rsquo;re wrong,&rdquo; Kennedy responded.</p><p>Sen. <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/t/mark-warner/">Mark Warner</a> (D-Va.) asked if Kennedy accepted the statistic that a million Americans have died from Covid. The United States reached that mark in May 2022, according to <a href="https://coronavirus.jhu.edu/from-our-experts/u-s-officially-surpasses-1-million-covid-19-deaths">data</a> from John Hopkins University.</p><p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know how many died,&rdquo; Kennedy said, before attempting to blame the CDC. &ldquo;It was so much data chaos coming out of the CDC.&rdquo;</p><p>Warner seemed stunned. He asked Kennedy if he believes &ldquo;the vaccine did anything to prevent additional deaths.&rdquo; </p><section> <h2> Trending Stories </h2> </section><p>&ldquo;I would like to see the data and talk about the data,&rdquo; Kennedy replied.</p><p>&ldquo;The secretary of Health and Human Services doesn&rsquo;t know how many Americans died from Covid, know if the vaccine helped prevent any deaths, and you are sitting as secretary of Health and Human Services?&rdquo; Warner said, before pleading: &ldquo;How can you be that ignorant?&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 03:23:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://nypost.com/2025/09/03/us-news/lawyer-named-mark-zuckerberg-sues-meta-over-claims-hes-impersonating-founder/</link><title>Lawyer named Mark Zuckerberg sues Meta after repeated account shutdowns over claims he’s impersonating billionaire founder: ‘It’s offensive’ (nypost.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n8dat1/lawyer_named_mark_zuckerberg_sues_meta_after/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n8dat1/lawyer_named_mark_zuckerberg_sues_meta_after/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 13 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n8dat1/lawyer_named_mark_zuckerberg_sues_meta_after/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://nypost.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/09/iammarkzuckerberg-com-110623707.jpg?quality=75&strip=all&w=1024' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Mark-ing his territory in the most Meta way possible. </p><p>An Indiana lawyer who shares the name Mark Zuckerberg is suing Meta after the social media platform repeatedly shut down his personal and business profiles, claiming he was impersonating its founder. </p><p>Zuckerberg, an Indianapolis bankruptcy lawyer, has battled mistaken identity issues on Facebook for 15 years, sharing a name with the <a href="https://nypost.com/2025/08/20/business/senators-press-mark-zuckerberg-over-metas-ai-bots-sensual-chats-with-kids/">platform&rsquo;s billionaire creator. </a></p><p>His verified personal account has been shut down five times, and after losing $11,000 in ad funds to Meta when <a href="https://zucklaw.com/">his law firm&rsquo;s page</a> was taken down in May for the fourth time, he&rsquo;s taking his fight to court.</p><figure><figcaption>Indianapolis bankruptcy lawyer Mark Zuckerberg is taking his fight with Meta to court. <span>iammarkzuckerberg/com</span></figcaption></figure><p>&ldquo;Normally you would say, well, it&rsquo;s just Facebook and it&rsquo;s not a big deal, but this time it&rsquo;s affecting my bottom line because I was paying for advertising for my business to try and get clients,&rdquo; the aggrieved attorney told The Post Wednesday afternoon.</p><p>&ldquo;So they took my money, but then after they took my money, they shut me down for what they say is impersonating a celebrity, not using a true name and violating their community standards. And it&rsquo;s the same message I get every time they shut me down.&rdquo;</p><p>Zuckerberg filed his lawsuit Tuesday in Marion Superior Court, accusing <a href="https://nypost.com/2025/08/29/tech/meta-created-flirty-chatbots-using-likeness-of-taylor-swift-selena-gomez-and-more-without-permission/">Facebook&rsquo;s parent company</a> of negligence and breach of contract for suspending his accounts for baseless and improper reasons.</p><p>He said his Facebook page was first deactivated in 2010, and every time since, he&rsquo;s had to endure a painfully long appeals process &mdash; including submitting photos of himself, his license and his credit cards &mdash; to prove he&rsquo;s a real person who hasn&rsquo;t violated the platform&rsquo;s policies and get his accounts restored.</p><figure><div></div><figcaption>Billionaire Facebook founder and Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg. <span>Bloomberg via Getty Images</span></figcaption></figure><p>&ldquo;I think it&rsquo;s offensive that a company that is supposed to be so tech savvy in the world can&rsquo;t figure out how to flag my accounts and keep this from happening,&rdquo; said Zuckerberg, who has practiced bankruptcy law for 38 years.</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s like they&rsquo;re almost doing it on purpose, but I&rsquo;m sure they&rsquo;re not but it feels like it.&rdquo;</p><p><a href="https://nypost.com/tag/meta/">Meta</a> told The Post that it just received Zuckerberg&rsquo;s complaint and is reviewing it.</p><p>&ldquo;We know there&rsquo;s more than one Mark Zuckerberg in the world, and we are getting to the bottom of this,&rdquo; the spokesperson said, declining to answer any additional questions.</p><figure><figcaption>Meta said it is reviewing Zuckerberg&rsquo;s complaint but acknowledged there&rsquo;s more than one person in the world who shares its founder&rsquo;s name. <span>Bloomberg via Getty Images</span></figcaption></figure><p>The company later told The Post that the other Mark Zuckerberg&rsquo;s account had been reactivated.</p><p>&ldquo;We have reinstated Mark Zuckerberg&rsquo;s account, after finding it had been disabled in error. We appreciate Mr. Zuckerberg&rsquo;s continued patience on this issue and are working to try and prevent this from happening in the future,&rdquo; a spokesman said Thursday. </p><p>While Zuckerberg joked that sharing the <a href="https://nypost.com/2025/08/16/us-news/nj-senior-died-trying-to-meet-meta-ai-chatbot-big-sis-billie/">high-profile Meta CEO&rsquo;s name</a> has its perks &mdash; like scoring a good table at a restaurant after making a reservation &mdash; it has also caused headaches in his personal life, calling the identity mix-up a &ldquo;thorn in my side.&rdquo;</p><p>His law firm fields daily calls from Facebook users seeking help with their accounts, receives countless packages meant for the social media mogul, and in 2020, he was mistakenly sued by Washington State&rsquo;s Department of Social and Health Services for alleged financial exploitation.</p><p>The repeated cases of mistaken identity prompted Zuckerberg <a href="https://iammarkzuckerberg.com/">to launch a website tracking them</a> &mdash; yet he still relies on online platforms like Facebook to attract new clients and compete with other local legal practices also spending ad dollars on the social network.</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s the fact that they&rsquo;re affecting my business now, you know, my clients can&rsquo;t find me,&rdquo; the frustrated lawyer stressed, adding that he wants Meta to refund his money and pay his attorney fees, among other demands.</p><p>&ldquo;I want an injunction, I want them to not do it again, and I want [Mark Zuckerberg] to fly out here, hand me my check, shake my hands and say, &lsquo;I&rsquo;m sorry,&rsquo; but that&rsquo;s never gonna happen.&rdquo;</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://nypost.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/09/iammarkzuckerberg-com-110623413.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://nypost.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/09/2024-listeners-heard-meta-playing-110622939.jpg?w=1024"></p><p><img src="https://nypost.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/09/2025-meta-platforms-inc-scheduled-110623692.jpg?w=1024"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:57:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/09/in-win-for-infectious-diseases-florida-to-end-all-school-vaccine-requirements/</link><title>In win for infectious diseases, Florida to end all school vaccine requirements (arstechnica.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n7np6p/in_win_for_infectious_diseases_florida_to_end_all/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n7np6p/in_win_for_infectious_diseases_florida_to_end_all/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1n7np6p/in_win_for_infectious_diseases_florida_to_end_all/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GettyImages-2141961103-1152x648.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Florida is planning to end all vaccination requirements in the state, including requirements for school children to get routine childhood vaccinations that protect them and their communities from severe and life-threatening diseases, such as <em>Haemophilus influenzae</em> type b (Hib), pertussis (whooping cough), diphtheria, measles, tetanus, RSV, and polio.</p><p>Florida Surgeon General Joseph Ladapo made the announcement <a href="https://youtu.be/x3h_2VqcDJ4?t=2334">at a press conference</a> on Wednesday alongside Governor Ron DeSantis.</p><p>"What I'm most excited about is an announcement that we're making now, which is that the Florida Department of Health, in partnership with the governor, is going to be working to end all vaccine mandates in Florida law&mdash;all of them, all of them, all of them, every last one of them," Ladapo said. "Every last one of them is wrong and drips with disdain and slavery."</p><p>Ladapo, who has a history of <a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2023/03/florida-surgeon-general-wrong-on-vaccines-and-bad-at-his-job-cdc-and-fda-say/">being anti-vaccine and spreading misinformation</a>, went on to argue against the public aspect of public health, saying that there is "no ethical basis" for requiring vaccination to, in part, protect the most vulnerable from infectious diseases. That vulnerable people, such as newborns and the immunocompromised, may be unnecessarily exposed to vaccine-preventable, life-threatening diseases is just "part of the experience of life," Ladapo claimed. He also called mRNA COVID-19 vaccines, which saved millions of lives at the height of the pandemic, "poison."</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:31:43 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
