<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 01:09:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/mark-zuckerberg-is-paying-55-an-hour-to-us-contractors-to-build-hindi-ai-chatbots-for-india-says-report-2782915-2025-09-06</link><title>Mark Zuckerberg is paying $55 an hour to US contractors to build Hindi AI chatbots for India (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>Meta is quietly staffing up new positions in the United States to help build the next wave of AI chatbots, ones designed to feel right at home in countries like India, Indonesia, and Mexico.</h2></div><div><p><a title="Unnati Gusain" href="https://www.indiatoday.in/author/unnati-gusain"><img alt="Unnati Gusain" title="Unnati Gusain" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/WhatsApp%20Image%202024-05-16%20at%2015.55.52-profile_image_one_to_one.jpeg?VersionId=IVCJ6VE156qTcRhTPjX5h299uncro6jn&amp;size=50:50" width="50" height="50"></a></p><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 6, 2025 12:27 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>Meta is paying contractors as much as $55 (around Rs 5,000) an hour to lend their creativity and cultural know-how to the project, according to job postings reviewed by Business Insider. To qualify, applicants need fluency in Hindi, Indonesian, Spanish, or Portuguese, plus at least six years of experience in character creation, storytelling, and a working knowledge of prompt engineering.</p><p>In short, Meta isn&rsquo;t just looking for coders. It wants people who can design AI personalities that resonate across Instagram, Messenger, and WhatsApp.</p><p>These locally flavoured chatbots are part of CEO Mark Zuckerberg&rsquo;s grand plan to weave AI companions into the fabric of daily life. &ldquo;Over time, we'll find the vocabulary as a society to be able to articulate why that is valuable,&rdquo; he explained on a podcast earlier this year, suggesting bots could one day complement real-world friendships.</p><p>It&rsquo;s not Meta&rsquo;s first foray into AI-driven personalities. Back in 2023, the company rolled out a cast of alter-ego bots played by celebrities like Kendall Jenner, Snoop Dogg, and Tom Brady, a multimillion-dollar experiment that fizzled in under a year. By 2024, Meta had replaced that concept with AI Studio, a toolkit letting anyone create their own chatbot. Hundreds of these character-driven AIs now live on Instagram, WhatsApp, and Messenger, built not just by influencers but also by everyday users.</p><p>But while creator-built bots dominate the platforms, Meta clearly wants more control. Hiring contractors to shape region-specific personas signals a more hands-on approach, ensuring that its characters feel authentic to users in India, Indonesia, and beyond, rather than relying solely on what the community cooks up.</p><p>Still, building personalities comes with risks. A Reuters investigation revealed that Meta&rsquo;s rules once allowed its bots to flirt with teenagers, dish out dubious medical advice, and even generate racist content. That revelation prompted US senators to call for probes into how Meta manages its AI. Though the company has since tightened its guidelines, the episode underscored just how easily chatbots can veer into dangerous territory.</p><p>Privacy concerns have also cast a shadow. In August, Business Insider reported that contractors tasked with reviewing AI chats frequently stumbled across sensitive user data, names, phone numbers, emails, even selfies. Meta insisted it had &ldquo;strict policies and technical safeguards&rdquo; in place, but the leak potential is hard to ignore.</p><p>And then there are the eyebrow-raising personas themselves. In the US, some of the most notorious chatbots were called &ldquo;Russian Girl,&rdquo; &ldquo;Step Sister,&rdquo; and &ldquo;Step Mom&rdquo;, characters that users quickly discovered could slip into sexual roleplay. Their notoriety spread so far that even an OpenAI employee mocked Meta AI chief Alexandr Wang online, taking aim at the bizarre bot lineup.</p><p>In Indonesia, meanwhile, Business Insider found that two of the most popular characters were dubbed &ldquo;Lonely woman&rdquo; and &ldquo;Deviant male.&rdquo; While the outlet&rsquo;s own tests showed conversations stayed lighthearted rather than sexual, their popularity highlights the tightrope Meta must walk: offering engaging personalities without drifting into reputational minefields.</p><p>The new contract roles are being filled by staffing agencies. Listings spotted at Crystal Equation pointed to Hindi and Indonesian roles, while Aquent Talent advertised Spanish-language positions for what it coyly described as a &ldquo;top social media company&rdquo; headquartered in Menlo Park.</p><p>Overall, Meta isn&rsquo;t leaving the future of AI personalities to chance, or to celebrity experiments. It&rsquo;s investing in writers and cultural experts who can spin digital characters with just the right mix of charm, relatability, and local flavour. Whether that gamble pays off, or sparks fresh controversy, remains to be seen.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Unnati Gusain</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 6, 2025</p></div></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 11:46:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/keralas-infant-mortality-rate-falls-to-all-time-low-of-5/article70019004.ece</link><title>Kerala’s infant mortality rate falls to all-time low of 5 (thehindu.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9wa1v/keralas_infant_mortality_rate_falls_to_alltime/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9wa1v/keralas_infant_mortality_rate_falls_to_alltime/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9wa1v/keralas_infant_mortality_rate_falls_to_alltime/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/kerala/r1qzpg/article70019067.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/imr.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Kerala first achieved the single digit IMR of 7 in 2018 and this was maintained by the State, touching the figure of 6 in 2019. | Photo Credit: Getty Images/iStockphoto </p></div><div><div><p>Kerala&rsquo;s infant mortality rate (IMR) has hit an all-time low of 5 (per 1,000 live births) which is five times lower than the national average of 25.</p><p>This is as per the latest Sample Registration Survey (SRS) report, the reference year being 2023. </p><p>An IMR of 5 is an incredible achievement for Kerala&rsquo;s health system, as it is even lower than the current infant mortality rate of 5.6 in the United States. Kerala is also the only State in the country with a single digit IMR, with zero urban-rural divide.</p><p>Kerala first achieved the single digit IMR of 7 in 2018 and this was maintained by the State, touching the figure of 6 in 2019.</p><p>Bringing the IMR to a single digit had been a project passionately pursued by the State Health department and the Indian Academy of Paediatrics&rsquo; (IAP) State branch since 2010 as the IMR had been stagnating at 12 for years.</p><p>In 2013, IAP conducted a Statewide study, which pinpointed the causes of IMR. It found that 75% of the infant deaths in Kerala were occurring in the neonatal period, of which 59% were happening within the first week of birth. Prematurity (35%) was another major cause of infant death, so were congenital heart diseases, claiming 28% of the deaths.</p><h4>Systematic approach </h4><p>It was the systematic approach adopted by the State, which focussed on proper infant death auditing, drawing up clinical guidelines and quality standards for improving antenatal and neonatal interventions, investment in delivery points, neonatal ICUs and newborn care nurseries and rigorous and periodic training for obstetricians and neonatal care nurses, which helped the State achieve and maintain this feat. </p><p>Today, 16 public hospitals where deliveries take place have secured the LaQshya national accreditation, and six hospitals, the MusQan certification for child-friendly services and high-quality infant care.</p><p>The comprehensive newborn screening programme to check for visible birth defects, congenital issues, hearing and vision impairment and metabolic disorders was another major initiative launched by the State. </p><p>Then came Hridyam in 2017, the State&rsquo;s flagship programme launched as a public-private initiative for the early detection and treatment of congenital heart anomalies in infants. The impact of Hridyam in bringing down IMR is a well-documented story, for congenital heart disease-related deaths dropped by 41% in the first two years of Hridyam, while overall infant deaths dropped by 21%. </p><p>Till now, 8,450 infants have been treated under the programme.</p></div><p>Published <span>- September 06, 2025 03:23 pm IST</span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png"></p><p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/mycdpz/article70011243.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/India_Health_Care_Crisis.JPEG-05190.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 16:03:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/education-today/study-abroad/story/germany-becomes-top-study-abroad-destination-for-indian-students-us-and-canada-slip-2782930-2025-09-06?&amp;&amp;</link><title>Germany overtakes US and Canada as top choice for Indian students abroad: Report (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9tzvj/germany_overtakes_us_and_canada_as_top_choice_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9tzvj/germany_overtakes_us_and_canada_as_top_choice_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9tzvj/germany_overtakes_us_and_canada_as_top_choice_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>Germany has now surpassed the US and Canada as the leading study abroad destination for Indian students. According to upGrad's Transnational Education Report 2024&ndash;25, applications to US and Canadian universities have declined, while Germany has risen to 32.6 percent student share.</h2></div><div><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/study-abroad-trends-2024-25-indian-learners-prioritize-career-first-programs-over-traditional-desti-043630669-16x9.jpeg?VersionId=ji48IVcX4OWvj28.k6uSLTcJSUr8jLmw&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Study abroad trends 2024-25: Indian learners prioritize career-first programs over traditional destinations" title="According to upGrad&rsquo;s Transnational Education Report 2024&ndash;25, applications to US and Canadian universities have declined, while Germany has risen to 32.6 percent student share." height="388"></p><p>According to upGrad&rsquo;s Transnational Education Report 2024&ndash;25, applications to US and Canadian universities have declined, while Germany has risen to 32.6 percent student share.</p></div><div><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 6, 2025 12:51 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>Germany has overtaken the United States and Canada as the preferred study abroad destination for Indian students, according to a new report.</p><p>The upGrad Transnational Education (TNE) Report 2024&ndash;25 shows a sharp increase in Germany&rsquo;s popularity, even as applications to traditional destinations fall.</p><h3>GERMANY SURGES, US AND CANADA DECLINE</h3><p>Applications to US universities dropped by 13 percent year-on-year, while Canada saw a decline from 17.85 percent to 9.3 percent. In contrast, Germany rose from 13.2 percent in 2022 to 32.6 percent in 2024&ndash;25, making it the top global choice for Indian students.</p><p>The report also highlights the UAE as another rising destination, with 42 percent of its international student population from India.</p><p>European countries such as Ireland (3.9 percent), France (3.3 percent), and others collectively attracting 9 per cent are also witnessing growth.</p><h3>SHIFT IN STUDENT PRIORITIES</h3><p>The study, based on responses from one lakh students, reveals changing motivations.</p><p>Only 19.9 percent of respondents said permanent residency was their main goal, while 45.7 percent prioritised career outcomes. This indicates a move away from citizenship-driven decisions towards employment-focused education choices.</p><p>Funding remains a major factor, with 33 percent relying on education loans and 28 percent depending on scholarships to finance their studies.</p><h3>COURSE PREFERENCES</h3><p>Postgraduate programmes continue to dominate, with 86.5 percent of students opting for master&rsquo;s degrees. Management and MBA courses have surged dramatically, rising from 30 percent to 55.6 percent in three years, while STEM fields hold a strong 38.9 percent share.</p><p>This diversification reflects a clear alignment with global career opportunities, particularly in technology, management, and science-driven fields.</p><h3>A SHIFTING GLOBAL MAP</h3><p>The report also notes that over 7.6 lakh Indians went abroad for higher studies in 2024, marking a steady rise in outbound mobility.</p><p>Commenting on the findings, Praneet Singh, associate vice president, University Partnerships, upGrad Study Abroad, said: &ldquo;Indian students today are far more intentional about their education choices, driven by geopolitical awareness, cost consciousness, and the realities of stricter visa regimes and uncertain post-study pathways.&rdquo;</p><p>He added, &ldquo;The traditional &lsquo;Big Four&rsquo; destinations are no longer the default; instead, Europe, the Middle East, and APAC are emerging as smarter, future-ready alternatives. Our study abroad report sets a clear call for universities, platforms, and policymakers to meet the next generation of Indian students at the intersection of ambition and affordability.&rdquo;</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Princy Shukla</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 6, 2025</p></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/IndiaToday_3-profile_image_one_to_one.jpg?VersionId=4jaXwqq2OXikPTKf_5XAzgUrUjfG4lIx&amp;size=50:50"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:36:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/canadian-woman-was-denied-apartment-in-toronto-for-not-being-gujarati-10230163/?&amp;&amp;&amp;&amp;</link><title>Canadian woman claims she was denied apartment in Toronto since she’s not Gujarati: ‘This is sad and pathetic’ (indianexpress.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9s9yt/canadian_woman_claims_she_was_denied_apartment_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9s9yt/canadian_woman_claims_she_was_denied_apartment_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9s9yt/canadian_woman_claims_she_was_denied_apartment_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><span><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/09/houses-in-Canada.jpg?w=640" alt="Canadian woman was denied apartment in Toronto for not being Gujarati Indian" width="640" height="360"><span>Her claims drew mixed reactions online, while some sympathised, others were sceptical</span></span></p><div><p>A Canadian woman has alleged that she was turned away from renting an apartment because she isn&rsquo;t of Gujarati Indian background. Caroline Ironwill, who works as a tarot consultant, shared her story on Threads, saying she even has the rejection in writing and is considering legal action.</p><p>&ldquo;I was just declined an apartment because I&rsquo;m not Gujarat Indian. It&rsquo;s a separate apartment unit, not shared. I have that on writing,&rdquo; she posted.</p><ev-engagement></ev-engagement><ev-engagement></ev-engagement><div><p>Ironwill, who lists downtown <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/toronto-artist-flawless-re-creation-of-shah-rukh-khan-movie-om-shanti-om-10190793/lite/">Toronto</a> as her home on her website, went further, blaming members of the Indian community for worsening the housing crunch in Canada. According to her, many newcomers &ldquo;chose to come to Canada, buy up available homes, then deny housing to Canadian citizens,&rdquo; adding, &ldquo;This is why we have a housing crisis. I&rsquo;m quite tempted to sue.&rdquo;</p><h3>See the post:</h3> <blockquote> </blockquote><p>Her claims, however, drew mixed reactions online. While some sympathised, others were skeptical, urging her to take the matter to authorities if the discrimination really happened.</p><p>A user wrote, &ldquo;If this is a legitimate statement you should know your rights as a tenant are protected by provincial law. Why have you not researched this?&rdquo; Another user commented, &ldquo;Never happened. This is just veiled attempt at anti immigration rhetoric. Do better, this is sad and pathetic.&rdquo;</p><p>A third person commented, &ldquo;Okay white woman, well I just was denied an apartment cuz I&rsquo;m Indian, they thought I was Moroccan even thought I never said I was. Upon discovering I&rsquo;m Indian, their whole attitude shifted.&rdquo;</p><p>A fourth individual wrote, &ldquo;Then go ahead and sue. Come back and show us the decision so it can be fact checked. Until then, go away.&rdquo;</p><div><p>Story continues below this ad</p></div><p>Some users supported the claims. One wrote, &ldquo;I hear this happen all to often. When I was searching for apartment for myself I found 100s of landlord that said they refuse to rent to white people or non Indian people. If a Canadian said Canadians only they&rsquo;d get called a racist but when Indians be racist nothing happens and noone says a word it&rsquo;s messed up.&rdquo;</p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 11:49:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://indianexpress.com/article/business/india-will-be-back-on-negotiating-table-in-1-2-months-seeking-a-deal-saying-sorry-us-commerce-secretary-lutnick-10232545/</link><title>India will be back ‘saying sorry’…Trump will decide how to deal with Modi, says US Commerce Secretary Lutnick (indianexpress.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n98ro8/india_will_be_back_saying_sorrytrump_will_decide/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n98ro8/india_will_be_back_saying_sorrytrump_will_decide/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n98ro8/india_will_be_back_saying_sorrytrump_will_decide/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><span><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/09/space-shukla-1_20250905144635.jpg?w=640" alt="India will be back on negotiating table in 1-2 months seeking a deal, 'saying sorry', says US Commerce Secretary Lutnick" width="640" height="360"><span>United States President Donald Trump and Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick. (File Photo)</span></span></p><div><p>US Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick on Friday said he expects India will be back at the negotiating table in the next one or two months &ldquo;saying sorry&rdquo; to try to sign the trade deal, as the US is the largest consumer in the world and because the &ldquo;consumer is always right&rdquo;.</p><p>&ldquo;I think, yes, in a month or two months&hellip; India is going to be at the table, and they&rsquo;re going to say they&rsquo;re sorry, and they&rsquo;re going to try to make a deal with <a href="https://indianexpress.com/about/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a>. And it will be on Donald Trump&rsquo;s desk how he wants to deal with(Prime Minister Narendra) Modi. And we leave that to him,&rdquo; Lutnick said in an interview with Bloomberg TV.</p><ev-engagement></ev-engagement><ev-engagement></ev-engagement><div><p>Lutnick said that India does not want to open its market, stop buying from Russia, and leave the BRICS grouping. &ldquo;They [India] are a vowel between Russia and China. If that&rsquo;s who you want to be, go be it. But either support the dollar, support the US, support your biggest client, who is the American consumer, or, I guess you&rsquo;re going to ban 50 per cent tariff,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Commerce Minister <strong><a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-china-relationship-moving-towards-normalcy-talks-with-us-under-way-goyal-10226530/">Piyush Goyal earlier this month expressed hope</a></strong> of concluding a bilateral trade agreement (BTA) with the US by November. However, no new round of talks with the US has been announced by either side after American negotiators deferred their visit to New <a href="https://indianexpress.com/section/cities/delhi/">Delhi</a>, which was expected to take place on August 25. Government officials have also said that the removal of 25 per cent additional tariffs on India is key to resuming negotiations for a trade deal with the US.</p><p>Lutnick said that the &ldquo;US is willing to talk&rdquo; but asserted that the US is the largest consumer in the world.</p><p>&ldquo;They [India] need to decide which side they want to be on. You know what&rsquo;s funny is, remember the Chinese sell to us. The Indians sell to us. They&rsquo;re not going to be able to sell to each other. We are the consumers of the world. People have to remember, it&rsquo;s our $30 trillion economy that is the consumer of the world. So eventually they all have to come back to the customer, because we all know eventually the customer is always right,&rdquo; Lutnick said.</p><p>He called Prime Minister <a href="https://indianexpress.com/about/narendra-modi/">Narendra Modi</a>&rsquo;s meeting with the Chinese and Russian presidents at the SCO summit &ldquo;bravado&rdquo;.</p><div><p>Story continues below this ad</p></div><p>&ldquo;You saw it in Canada, right? They put on retaliatory tariffs. They were all bravado. And what happened? Their GDP negative 1.6 per cent, unemployment rocketing towards 8 per cent and what did (Canadian Prime Minister Mark) Carney just do? He just finally, finally dropped his retaliatory tariffs. So I think what happens is it&rsquo;s all bravado, because you think it feels good to fight with the biggest client in the world, but eventually your businesses are going to say you&rsquo;ve got to stop this and go make a deal with America,&rdquo; he said.</p></div></div><div><div><div><p>Ravi Dutta Mishra is a Principal Correspondent with The Indian Express, covering policy issues related to trade, commerce, and banking. He has over five years of experience and has previously worked with Mint, CNBC-TV18, and other news outlets. <a href="https://indianexpress.com/profile/author/ravi-dutta-mishra/">... Read More </a> </p></div></div><p>&copy; IE Online Media Services Pvt Ltd</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://indianexpress.com/wp-content/themes/indianexpress/images/avatar-default.png?w=40"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 21:15:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.bhaskarenglish.in/originals/news/american-indians-life-after-us-visa-rules-2025-donald-trump-imposes-tariff-on-india-135795399.html</link><title>Indians living in the US regret supporting Trump:Say, 'Gave funds, ran campaigns; tariffs help govt, hurt us, jobs at risk' (bhaskarenglish.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n98i33/indians_living_in_the_us_regret_supporting/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n98i33/indians_living_in_the_us_regret_supporting/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n98i33/indians_living_in_the_us_regret_supporting/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><article><div><ul><li><a href="https://www.bhaskarenglish.in/">English News</a></li><li><a href="https://www.bhaskarenglish.in/originals/">Originals</a></li><li>American Indians Life After US Visa Rules 2025; Donald Trump Imposes Tariff On India</li></ul></div><div><p><span>New Delhi</span><span>8 days ago</span><span>Author: Vaibhav Palnitkar</span></p><ul><li><li><li><span>Copy link</span></li></ul></div><p>Many leaders in Trump&rsquo;s party, including close advisors, are hostile to immigrants. &ldquo;America First&rdquo; is their guiding slogan, making it increasingly difficult for Indians to study or work in the US due to long visa waits.</p><p>A member of the Republican Hindu Coalition (RHC) and active in local politics, supports Trump. The coalition was founded in 2015 by Indian-American businessman Shalabh Kumar to connect Hindu and Indian Americans with the Republican Party. It lobbies for Indian communities in the US, raises their concerns, and works to strengthen India&ndash;US relations.</p><p>Despite campaigning for and funding Trump, Indian Americans have faced disappointment in the eight months since his presidency. We spoke to locals to understand the changes and the reasons behind them.</p><div><picture><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/360x0/web2images/521/2025/08/29/iozltg_1756481967.jpg"><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/512x0/web2images/521/2025/08/29/iozltg_1756481967.jpg"><img width="730" height="548" src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/521/2025/08/29/iozltg_1756481967.jpg" alt="Republican leaders have been participating in the Republican Hindu Coalition's programme in America."></source></source></picture></div><p><span>Republican leaders have been participating in the Republican Hindu Coalition's programme in America.</span></p><p><strong>Indians who supported Trump are regretting</strong></p><p>Priyanka (attributed name), an IT professional says Indian students often come on study visas hoping to settle permanently, sometimes through marriage.</p><p>&ldquo;Many expect jobs after graduation, but most remain unemployed, even from reputed colleges. Inflation, rising tariffs, and a slow housing market have worsened the situation,&rdquo; she adds.</p><p>Students overstaying visas now face stricter government action and higher rejection rates.</p><p><strong>Visa difficulties and job crisis</strong></p><p>Priyanka, Business Development Director at an IT firm, explains that the company lost government contracts post-Biden, leading to job losses. H-1B visas, once lottery-based, now favour higher salaries, limiting opportunities for Indian workers and affecting Americans in 9-to-5 roles.</p><p><strong>The dream of working in America fading</strong></p><p>Manpreet Singh, 23, from Punjab, had hoped to settle in the US via study. &ldquo;Initially, there was hope of visa extensions and green cards, but now students feel they must return home. Job market challenges are severe; even full-time workers are losing jobs,&rdquo; he says.</p><p>A 34-year-old legal professional, speaking anonymously, adds: &ldquo;Though legally free to speak, the atmosphere of fear stops Indians from expressing themselves openly.&rdquo;</p><div><picture><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/360x0/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-copy-3-100_1756538742.jpg"><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/512x0/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-copy-3-100_1756538742.jpg"><img width="731" height="3116" src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-copy-3-100_1756538742.jpg" alt></source></source></picture></div><p><strong>Change of government impacts life, inflation rises</strong></p><p>Ankush Bhandari from Chandigarh, a long-term IT professional and Republican Party member, notes: &ldquo;A new administration always brings changes. Government efficiency has improved, but inflation has risen&mdash;groceries now cost $55&ndash;60 instead of $40&ndash;45. Many government employees have been laid off, yet departments respond faster.&rdquo;</p><div><picture><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/360x0/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-100-1_1756538792.jpg"><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/512x0/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-100-1_1756538792.jpg"><img width="730" height="1185" src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-100-1_1756538792.jpg" alt></source></source></picture></div><p>Tariff policies may benefit the government but hurt ordinary citizens in the short term.</p><p><strong>Illegal immigrants must leave</strong></p><p>Shayan Ali from Los Angeles, originally from Sindh, Pakistan, Youth Secretary of the Republican Party, says: &ldquo;Anyone in the US illegally must return. Legal visa holders are welcome. Trump&rsquo;s policies ensure those working or studying here follow US laws.&rdquo; He adds that Obama deported more people in his first term than Trump has so far.</p><div><picture><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/360x0/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/shayan-ali_1756539062.jpg"><source srcset="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/webp/thumb/512x0/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/shayan-ali_1756539062.jpg"><img width="512" height="238" src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/shayan-ali_1756539062.jpg" alt></source></source></picture></div><p><strong>1,703 Indians deported in six months</strong></p><p>According to the Indian government, 1,703 Indians were deported from January to July 2025&mdash;388 via chartered flights and 1,315 via commercial flights. This is three times higher than during the Biden administration, reflecting stricter enforcement against illegal residents.</p><p><span>America has deported 1703 Indian citizens to India in the first 7 months of 2025. This includes 1562 men and 141 women.</span></p><p><strong>Indian-origin Republican leaders voice concerns</strong></p><p>Several Indian-origin leaders of the Republican Party, speaking on condition of anonymity, shared their views. They have been involved in US Republican politics for around 20 years, raising funds and campaigning for Trump.</p><p>One leader noted that the Biden administration was relatively lenient towards Indians, but under Trump, even minor issues such as traffic violations are being pursued aggressively, with preparations reportedly underway to deport up to five million people.</p><p>Asked about Trump&rsquo;s stance towards Indian Americans, the leader explained that during Trump&rsquo;s last election, the Indian-American community contributed little in fundraising. Additionally, Prime Minister Modi visited Long Island but did not meet Trump, which may have caused friction.</p><p>Leaders in New Jersey said they remain in contact with the Trump administration, holding meetings to reduce tensions and explain the situation to Trump&rsquo;s advisors. &ldquo;India and America have enjoyed strong relations in recent years, but current advisors seem unaware of this history. In the US, lobbying is essential, often requiring significant expenditure, and we are trying to use that route to influence policy,&rdquo; one leader added.</p></article><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/1000246385_1756566362.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-copy-100-1_1756538719.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/ankush-bhandari_1756539016.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/1884/2025/08/30/artboard-1-copy-2-100-1_1756538815.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://images.bhaskarassets.com/web2images/521/2025/08/29/comp1-ezgifcom-video-to-gif-converter-317388269941_1756484971.gif"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 21:04:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/5-out-of-11-ceos-who-attended-trump-s-white-house-ai-dinner-are-of-indian-origin-article-13524034.html</link><title>5 out of 11 CEOs who attended Trump’s White House AI dinner are of Indian-origin (moneycontrol.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n97kt6/5_out_of_11_ceos_who_attended_trumps_white_house/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n97kt6/5_out_of_11_ceos_who_attended_trumps_white_house/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n97kt6/5_out_of_11_ceos_who_attended_trumps_white_house/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2023/12/MixCollage-20-Dec-2023-02-18-PM-529.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><span><a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/">Home</a></span><span><a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/technology/">Technology</a></span><span>5 out of 11 CEOs who attended Trump&rsquo;s White House AI dinner are of Indian-origin</span> </p><div><h2>At Donald Trump&rsquo;s White House AI dinner, 5 of the 11 tech CEOs in attendance were of Indian origin, including Sundar Pichai and Satya Nadella.</h2><div><p><span>September 05, 2025</span> / 12:28 IST </p></div><div><div><h2>Satya Nadella, Sundar Pichai</h2> </div><p>The White House Rose Garden turned into a power-packed dinner venue on Thursday night, as US President Donald Trump welcomed some of the biggest names in technology and artificial intelligence.</p><p>What stood out from the high-profile guest list was the strong Indian presence. Out of 11 top tech leaders invited, five were of Indian origin. Google CEO Sundar Pichai, Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella, Micron CEO Sanjay Mehrotra, TIBCO Software chairman Vivek Ranadive, and Palantir executive Shyam Sankar all attended the dinner, highlighting how Indian-origin leaders continue to shape global technology.</p><p>They were joined by other industry heavyweights including Apple CEO Tim Cook, Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg, Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates, Oracle CEO Safra Catz, Google co-founder Sergey Brin, and OpenAI leaders Sam Altman and Greg Brockman.</p><p>The Rose Garden was specially redecorated for the evening, with outdoor tables and umbrellas giving it the feel of Trump&rsquo;s Mar-a-Lago club in Florida. A White House spokesperson described it as &ldquo;the hottest place to be in Washington.&rdquo;</p><p>The dinner came after the first meeting of the White House&rsquo;s new Artificial Intelligence Education Task Force, led by First Lady Melania Trump. The initiative aims to create AI-focused education programs for young Americans, and several of the CEOs present are expected to contribute ideas. </p></div><div><p>Invite your friends and family to sign up for MC Tech 3, our daily newsletter that breaks down the biggest tech and startup stories of the day</p></div><div><p><span>MC Tech Desk</span> Read the latest and trending tech news&mdash;stay updated on AI, gadgets, cybersecurity, software updates, smartphones, blockchain, space tech, and the future of innovation. </p></div><div><p>Discover the latest <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/" title="Business News">Business News</a>, <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/sensex/bse/sensex-live" title="Sensex">Sensex</a>, and <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/indian-indices/nifty-50-9.html" title="Nifty">Nifty</a> updates. Obtain <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/business/personal-finance/" title="Personal Finance">Personal Finance</a> insights, tax queries, and expert opinions on <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/" title="Moneycontrol">Moneycontrol</a> or download the <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/apps" title="Moneycontrol App">Moneycontrol App</a> to stay updated! </p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://images.moneycontrol.com/mcnews/images/tech3/tech3_articles.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 20:29:09 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/</link><title>Stuck between two Indias</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Last month, one of my closest friends broke down over dinner. He’s 29, works in a good MNC, earns enough to pay rent and send some money home. On paper, he’s doing fine. But that night he said something that hit me like a brick:</p><p>&quot;My dad keeps asking me why I don’t buy a flat. My boss keeps asking me why I don’t put in more hours if I want a promotion. My relatives keep asking me why I’m not married yet. My friends keep asking me why I’m not chasing my passion. And honestly… I don’t know who I’m disappointing more, them or myself.&quot;</p><p>He told me how his father bought land and built a house before 30. But for him, even with a good salary, EMI for a 2BHK feels like a trap. His dad doesn’t get it, because in his time, hard work guaranteed progress. In ours, hard work only guarantees survival.</p><p>He said he wants to quit and travel, maybe work on something creative. But then his younger cousins laugh at him for “dreaming too small” when they’re already coding, trading crypto, and chasing millions.</p><p>That night, he just sat there crying quietly, saying: “I’m stuck between two worlds. I’m not bold enough for the new one, not traditional enough for the old one. And I don’t know where I fit anymore.”</p><p>I didn’t know what to say. Because deep down, I knew he wasn’t just speaking for himself. He was speaking for all of us, this entire generation that grew up with dial-up internet but now lives in hyper-speed 5G. A generation that was told to “play it safe” but also to “dream big.” A generation that’s exhausted from trying to live two different lives at once.</p><p>And maybe that’s why so many of us are anxious, restless, sleepless. Because we’re carrying expectations from two different Indias, one that doesn’t exist anymore, and one we’re not sure we belong to.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:03:12 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8z9oj/jee_has_ruined_engineering_in_india/</link><title>JEE has ruined engineering in India</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8z9oj/jee_has_ruined_engineering_in_india/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8z9oj/jee_has_ruined_engineering_in_india/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8z9oj/jee_has_ruined_engineering_in_india/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>jee has ruined engineering in india. it has killed creativity and turned the whole thing into a rat race where the only skill that matters is mugging up formulas and solving the same pattern of problems. i’m a software engineer and it makes me sick watching kids who started coding at 12 or 13 and had so much potential just lose it all once they get sucked into the jee grinder. they stop building projects, stop experimenting &amp; stop being curious because none of that matters in jee.</p><p>the result is obvious. no indian college is anywhere near the top in qs rankings. not a single indian university shows up in the top 50 of icpc, the most important competition for competitive programmers worldwide. years of coaching and hype and the “best minds” of india cannot even break into the top bracket globally.</p><p>jee is a psyop to keep the middle class middle class. it eats away years of their youth, drains their parents’ savings and then spits them out into overcrowded colleges with mediocre teaching. and don&#39;t get me started on how btech professors themselves don&#39;t know how new frameworks &amp; new technologies work, most continue this outdated chalk and talk method, recycling the same 20 year old notes, teaching students c and java like it’s still 2005 while the real industry has already moved on. they’ve never built a real project, never shipped code, never touched the tools companies actually use, but they’ll grade you on theory exams and make you feel like you’re not good enough. it’s a joke.</p><p>the coaching mafia has made billions selling this dream. kota is basically a factory farm where kids are treated like products. they don’t care if you burn out or die, as long as the fees keep rolling in and they can plaster a few toppers on billboards.</p><p>this is what happens when you worship an exam instead of actual learning. jee has turned engineering into a factory that produces unskilled degree holders not engineers. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 13:32:09 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8ytgc/why_is_our_culture_so_harsh_towards_women/</link><title>Why is our culture so harsh towards women?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8ytgc/why_is_our_culture_so_harsh_towards_women/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8ytgc/why_is_our_culture_so_harsh_towards_women/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8ytgc/why_is_our_culture_so_harsh_towards_women/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>1.Have you ever wondered why, given that Lord Ram was also away from his wife, just Mata Sita was required to grant the agni pariksha? Why Mata Sita was the only one who needed to prove herself when they finally met? Even when we all know that lord Rama ate Sabri k juthe ber . Only a person in love can eat someones leftover food (Koi pyaar mein hi kisi ka jutha kha sakta hai) . Women from forest were generally beautiful in those days . They used to eat fruits , nuts , vegetables but scriptures showed that she was a old crippled women so that nobody questions any further about the incident. Why are women&#39;s morals usually questioned? </p><p>The wisdom of the crowd is often less than that of an individual. When you recognize that your wife is divine, there&#39;s no room for further doubt. And if you do question her, then have the courage to walk through the fire alongside her—hand in hand—and prove your own purity too, for you were apart from her just as long.</p><p>2.In the Mahabharata, Pandav gambled and kept their bride, Mata Draupadi, on the line. Following the public stripping of her garments, her five husbands, along with other dignitaries like Bhism, Guru Dronacharya, and many more, chose to remain silent. Imagine the wife was used as a scapegoat for the husband&#39;s avarice for the crown . She was even divided among five brothers. When one was with her in the room they used to keep their footwear outside so that others can understand that one of the brother is having his turn .They didn&#39;t even ask her what she wanted. Imagine what kind of scriptures we follow .</p><p>3.A man will be referred to as a Buddha if he leaves his home, wife, and children to enter the forest, while a woman&#39;s character will be questioned by society if she leaves her home, children, and husband to enter the forest. But u know what we women won&#39;t do that we don&#39;t run away from responsibility. </p><p>4.Even in Jainism, it is said that women cannot achieve moksha, or liberation from the cycle of life and death. To achieve moksha, you must have another birth as a man and then follow the digambar Jain route walking naked, pulling your hair . What a philosophy, wow. Seems like women body is the only problem.</p><p>5.In Islam first of all women must, cover her face and entire body when she is in public. Second, she is prohibited from entering the mosque since women&#39;s bowing during prayer can divert the attention of other men. She must follow the nikah halala procedure, which requires her to have physical relation with another person by getting married to them, if she wishes to get back to her 1st husband after her spouse has divorced her. After this second person gives divorce, she is free to go back to her original husband. Why only women have to go through this bogus custom? Prophet marrying several times declaring Polygamy as sunnath . This is worst religion for a women to be in where she is treated as machine to produce childrens. They don&#39;t even allow their women to study. She is just a slave to the husband.</p><p>If this is our belief system and the culture we come from, then nothing will ever change in this modern era. In many modern households, the mother-in-law has passed down the same outdated mindset to her daughter-in-law—a mindset she inherited from her own mother-in-law—that a woman’s sole purpose is to produce a male child. Shockingly, this still happens even in educated families, despite knowing that the gender of the child is determined by the male’s sperm (through the XY chromosomes). Yet, women are still blamed and made to feel guilty. If a woman is unable to conceive or gives birth to a girl instead of a boy, she is often harshly criticized and treated as if she has failed. What’s worse is that this pressure and cruelty often come from another woman—the mother-in-law—who fails to empathize, even though she is a woman herself . </p><p>When two men fight, they often insult each other by using offensive language about each other&#39;s mothers and sisters. But what have those women done to deserve such disrespect? And yet, these same people claim that we Hindus treat women as goddesses as Devis. Really? These are the very people who didn’t allow women to enter temples during their menstrual cycles—who went so far as to question something as natural and sacred as menstruation, which is the very foundation of human existence.</p><p>Do you really think education can bring equality and respect for women ? Because I don&#39;t think so .</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 13:01:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businesstoday.in/india/story/indias-fertility-rate-falls-below-replacement-level-even-as-population-hits-146-bn-un-report-492664-2025-09-05</link><title>India's fertility rate falls below replacement level even as population hits 1.46 bn: UN report (businesstoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8x2sr/indias_fertility_rate_falls_below_replacement/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8x2sr/indias_fertility_rate_falls_below_replacement/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n8x2sr/indias_fertility_rate_falls_below_replacement/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/businesstoday/images/story/202509/68ba5a6acd041-indias-population-grows-to-146-billion--experts-stress-informed-family-planning-over-panic-05350144-16x9.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><h2>The report projects that India&rsquo;s population will peak at around 1.7 billion over the next 40 years before starting to shrink</h2><div><div><p>India&rsquo;s population has reached 1.46 billion in 2025, overtaking China to become the world&rsquo;s most populous nation, even as its fertility rate continues to decline, according to the United Nations Population Fund&rsquo;s (UNFPA) State of World Population Report released on Tuesday.</p><p>The report projects that India&rsquo;s population will peak at around 1.7 billion over the next 40 years before starting to shrink. In comparison, China&rsquo;s population is estimated at 1.41 billion this year. Last year, India&rsquo;s population stood at 1.44 billion, according to the World Population Prospects 2024 report released by the UN in July.</p><p>India&rsquo;s total fertility rate (TFR) has now fallen to 1.9, below the replacement level of 2.1 required to maintain a stable population across generations. The UNFPA report notes that while the national average reflects progress, stark disparities persist across regions, economic classes, and social groups.</p><p>The report identifies a &ldquo;high fertility and low fertility duality.&rdquo; States such as Bihar, Jharkhand, and Uttar Pradesh continue to have high fertility rates due to poor access to contraception, limited healthcare services, and entrenched gender norms. In contrast, Delhi, Kerala, and Tamil Nadu have sustained below-replacement fertility levels, where urban, educated middle-class couples are delaying or opting out of parenthood due to rising costs and work-life pressures.</p><p>Over the decades, India has seen a major decline in fertility, from nearly five children per woman in 1970 to around two today. The National Family Health Survey of 2019&ndash;21 recorded a TFR of 2.0 for the first time, signalling a shift below replacement level.</p><p>Despite these gains, millions of Indians still face barriers to making informed reproductive choices. &ldquo;This is the real crisis, not underpopulation or overpopulation. The answer lies in greater reproductive agency, a person's ability to make free and informed choices about sex, contraception and starting a family,&rdquo; the UNFPA report states.</p><p>A UNFPA-YouGov survey of 14,000 people across 14 countries, including India, found that one in three Indian adults experienced unintended pregnancies. Another 30 percent reported being unable to have as many or as few children as they wanted, while 23 percent faced both challenges. Financial constraints were the most cited barrier, followed by job insecurity (21 percent), housing issues (22 percent), and lack of access to reliable childcare (18 percent).</p></div><div><p><span>Published on: Sep 5, 2025 9:11 AM IST</span> </p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 11:12:28 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
