<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 04:34:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/</link><title>What is Actually Happening in Nepal ?? Misinformation by Indian Media.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hello to my fellow neighbors in India.I am a <strong>Nepali citizen</strong> living near the border, connected to both our countries not only geographically but also culturally. That is why I feel it is my duty to share the truth with you about what is really happening here.</p><p>You may have seen headlines claiming that Nepal is facing <strong>“mass protests led by Gen Z against social media ban.”</strong>That is only a half-truth.</p><p><strong>Here is the real sequence of events:</strong></p><ul><li><p>Three days ago, the Nepal government suddenly banned 26 social media platforms including Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram, YouTube, and Reddit.</p></li><li><p>They claimed it was about registration and taxes. But these companies are already registered and paying taxes. The real motive is censorship: giving the government power to control online information, delete posts critical of them within 24 hours, and jail those who speak up.</p></li><li><p>In the next two days, criticism exploded across the country. A date was set—September 8—for nationwide protests. But it was never just about social media. That ban was only the spark.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Our patience had already run out.</strong></p><p>Soon, the “<strong>Nepo Babies</strong>” trend erupted in Nepal. It exposed the lavish lifestyles of politicians’ children—designer (clothes,bags, watches, attire )worth lakhs, luxury cars, million-rupee homes, weekly international flights, and even private jets—while ordinary Nepalis struggle daily for survival. Our PM has a salary less than 65k INR but what is owns is in million of $$$.</p><blockquote><p>This hit a nerve. Because Nepal has been under one form of tyranny or another for decades. From monarchy to so-called democracy, corruption and instability have never left us. Not a single prime minister has completed a full term in over 20 years.</p></blockquote><p>[The protests were organized in the name of Gen Z, but they welcomed everyone. We were not just protesting a social media ban. We were standing against corruption, nepotism, tyranny, suppression, and decades of betrayal. In a country of just 30 million people, every single day around 5,000 youths leave to work abroad because there are no jobs, no decent pay, and no basic livelihood at home.]</p><p>And then the tragedy struck. Today, during the protest, I witnessed &amp; carried something I will never forget. A 15-year-old schoolboy, still in uniform, was shot in the head by security forces—acting on orders from a minister. He was not the only one. Reports say more than 20 people have been killed, thousands injured, and the true numbers are being hidden.</p><p>I came home with blood still on my hands, only to see Indian news channels spinning a completely false narrative. They claimed it was all about social media and mocked our youths as being “<strong>addicted</strong>” to it. That angered me, but it didn’t surprise me. I know how the media can twist things.</p><p>That is why I am writing this here, to let you know the truth from the ground.</p><p>🙏</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:36:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/</link><title>Living in india is just exhausting honestly.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Where do I even begin. Honestly I feel it&#39;s just exhausting to really live in this country.</p><p>Infra is just pathetic. 9-5 jobs are actually 7-10 if you consider the time it takes to commute in metro cities. And when you do get home, you can&#39;t even have some quiet time because someone is doing a kirtan with loud music on. </p><p>You can&#39;t go outside because there aren&#39;t enough public parks or walkable spaces. And if you do happen to live nearby one, then either the road will be dug out or you just won&#39;t go outside because pollution.</p><p>When it&#39;s raining you just have to pray that you don&#39;t get into an open manhole or you get in vicinity of live wire.</p><p>They say to escape India in India you need to buy a place in gated societies. But wait, can you even afford a home in these gated societies ? Majority of the Middle class with even IT Benchmark salary cannot afford to buy home in this country. </p><p>And even if you can, you still can&#39;t escape the terrible Air Quality and the pathetic infra.</p><p>Job security doesn&#39;t exist in India, and if you&#39;re born in General category then basically you are on your own. The taxes you pay get you nothing in this country.</p><p>From birth till death life is just a rat race in this country. </p><p>I know my thoughts are all over the place. Some of you might not agree and that&#39;s okay. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 17:23:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/brain-eating-amoeba-kerala-reports-fifth-amoebic-meningoencephalitis-death-in-a-month/article70024977.ece</link><title>Brain-eating amoeba: Kerala reports fifth amoebic meningoencephalitis death in a month (thehindu.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbhgbp/braineating_amoeba_kerala_reports_fifth_amoebic/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbhgbp/braineating_amoeba_kerala_reports_fifth_amoebic/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbhgbp/braineating_amoeba_kerala_reports_fifth_amoebic/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Amoebic meningoencephalitis, a rare but fatal brain infection caused by free-living amoebae found in freshwater, lakes and rivers, has emerged as a public health concern in Kerala. | Photo Credit: Wikipedia </p></div><div><div><p>Kerala reported the fifth death due to amoebic meningoencephalitis in a month as a Malappuram native undergoing treatment at the Government Medical College Hospital, Kozhikode, died on Monday (September 8, 2025). </p><p>According to sources, Sobhana, 56, from Thiruvali near Wandoor in Malappuram district, was admitted to the hospital last week. She had been in a critical condition since then. </p><p>Since August 14, four people in the State have died from the infection, and this marks the fifth fatality.</p><p>The sources said that 11 persons are at present undergoing treatment for the disease at the Kozhikode MCH, and the condition of at least one of them is reported to be serious.</p><p>Ratheesh, 45, a native of Sulthan Bathery in Wayanad district, who had been undergoing treatment at Kozhikode MCH, succumbed to the infection on September 6, 2025.</p><p>Amoebic meningoencephalitis, a rare but fatal brain infection caused by free-living amoebae found in freshwater, lakes and rivers, has emerged as a public health concern in Kerala.</p></div><p>Published <span>- September 08, 2025 12:34 pm IST</span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 13:08:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chandigarh/26-year-old-jind-man-shot-dead-in-us-after-objecting-to-public-urination/articleshow/123752250.cms</link><title>'Entered via donkey route': Haryana man shot dead in US for objecting to public urination (timesofindia.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>JIND: A 26-year-old man from Haryana's Jind district was shot dead in California, US, after he objected to a man urinating in public on Saturday. The deceased, Kapil, was working as a security guard. Son of Ishwar from Barah Kalan village, Kapil was on duty when he confronted an individual for urinating outside the premises, village sarpanch Suresh Kumar Gautam told TOI.</p><p>The man, in response, shot him dead on the spot, the sarpanch added.<span></span></p><div><p>On Cam: Indian-Origin Sikh Man Shot Dead In Los Angeles; Video Released By US Police</p></div><p>Kapil, the only son of a farming family, had travelled to the US two-and-a-half years ago. He is said to have entered the country in 2022 through the "donkey route", crossing the jungles of Panama and scaling the Mexico border wall, a journey that cost his family around Rs 45 lakh. After his initial arrest, he was released through legal proceedings and had since been settled in the country.</p><div><p>Poll</p><p>Should stricter laws be implemented regarding public behavior?</p><div><p><label>Yes, definitely.</label><label>No, that is unnecessary.</label></p></div></div><p><span></span>The family was informed of the death by a relative living in the US. Kapil has two sisters, one of whom is married."The entire village is standing with the family, but they are deeply broken in this time of grief," said sarpanch Gautam. <span></span>He added that the family plans to meet with the deputy commissioner to demand that Kapil's body be brought back to India. "We hope for the govt's full support," he said.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123755348,imgsize-25480,width-400,height-225,resizemode-72/-.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:11:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/mark-zuckerberg-is-paying-55-an-hour-to-us-contractors-to-build-hindi-ai-chatbots-for-india-says-report-2782915-2025-09-06</link><title>Mark Zuckerberg is paying $55 an hour to US contractors to build Hindi AI chatbots for India (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>Meta is quietly staffing up new positions in the United States to help build the next wave of AI chatbots, ones designed to feel right at home in countries like India, Indonesia, and Mexico.</h2></div><div><p><a title="Unnati Gusain" href="https://www.indiatoday.in/author/unnati-gusain"><img alt="Unnati Gusain" title="Unnati Gusain" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/WhatsApp%20Image%202024-05-16%20at%2015.55.52-profile_image_one_to_one.jpeg?VersionId=IVCJ6VE156qTcRhTPjX5h299uncro6jn&amp;size=50:50" width="50" height="50"></a></p><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 6, 2025 12:27 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>Meta is paying contractors as much as $55 (around Rs 5,000) an hour to lend their creativity and cultural know-how to the project, according to job postings reviewed by Business Insider. To qualify, applicants need fluency in Hindi, Indonesian, Spanish, or Portuguese, plus at least six years of experience in character creation, storytelling, and a working knowledge of prompt engineering.</p><p>In short, Meta isn&rsquo;t just looking for coders. It wants people who can design AI personalities that resonate across Instagram, Messenger, and WhatsApp.</p><p>These locally flavoured chatbots are part of CEO Mark Zuckerberg&rsquo;s grand plan to weave AI companions into the fabric of daily life. &ldquo;Over time, we'll find the vocabulary as a society to be able to articulate why that is valuable,&rdquo; he explained on a podcast earlier this year, suggesting bots could one day complement real-world friendships.</p><p>It&rsquo;s not Meta&rsquo;s first foray into AI-driven personalities. Back in 2023, the company rolled out a cast of alter-ego bots played by celebrities like Kendall Jenner, Snoop Dogg, and Tom Brady, a multimillion-dollar experiment that fizzled in under a year. By 2024, Meta had replaced that concept with AI Studio, a toolkit letting anyone create their own chatbot. Hundreds of these character-driven AIs now live on Instagram, WhatsApp, and Messenger, built not just by influencers but also by everyday users.</p><p>But while creator-built bots dominate the platforms, Meta clearly wants more control. Hiring contractors to shape region-specific personas signals a more hands-on approach, ensuring that its characters feel authentic to users in India, Indonesia, and beyond, rather than relying solely on what the community cooks up.</p><p>Still, building personalities comes with risks. A Reuters investigation revealed that Meta&rsquo;s rules once allowed its bots to flirt with teenagers, dish out dubious medical advice, and even generate racist content. That revelation prompted US senators to call for probes into how Meta manages its AI. Though the company has since tightened its guidelines, the episode underscored just how easily chatbots can veer into dangerous territory.</p><p>Privacy concerns have also cast a shadow. In August, Business Insider reported that contractors tasked with reviewing AI chats frequently stumbled across sensitive user data, names, phone numbers, emails, even selfies. Meta insisted it had &ldquo;strict policies and technical safeguards&rdquo; in place, but the leak potential is hard to ignore.</p><p>And then there are the eyebrow-raising personas themselves. In the US, some of the most notorious chatbots were called &ldquo;Russian Girl,&rdquo; &ldquo;Step Sister,&rdquo; and &ldquo;Step Mom&rdquo;, characters that users quickly discovered could slip into sexual roleplay. Their notoriety spread so far that even an OpenAI employee mocked Meta AI chief Alexandr Wang online, taking aim at the bizarre bot lineup.</p><p>In Indonesia, meanwhile, Business Insider found that two of the most popular characters were dubbed &ldquo;Lonely woman&rdquo; and &ldquo;Deviant male.&rdquo; While the outlet&rsquo;s own tests showed conversations stayed lighthearted rather than sexual, their popularity highlights the tightrope Meta must walk: offering engaging personalities without drifting into reputational minefields.</p><p>The new contract roles are being filled by staffing agencies. Listings spotted at Crystal Equation pointed to Hindi and Indonesian roles, while Aquent Talent advertised Spanish-language positions for what it coyly described as a &ldquo;top social media company&rdquo; headquartered in Menlo Park.</p><p>Overall, Meta isn&rsquo;t leaving the future of AI personalities to chance, or to celebrity experiments. It&rsquo;s investing in writers and cultural experts who can spin digital characters with just the right mix of charm, relatability, and local flavour. Whether that gamble pays off, or sparks fresh controversy, remains to be seen.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Unnati Gusain</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 6, 2025</p></div></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 11:46:47 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
