<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=singularity&amp;averagePostsPerDay=4&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/singularity</title><description>Hot posts in /r/singularity (roughly 4 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 20:59:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh8m-styles-communityIcon_hmujz61wdga81-144x400.jpg</url><title>/r/singularity</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://i.redd.it/wjok4efslenf1.jpeg</link><title>Anthropic: Paying $1.5 billion in AI copyright lawsuit settlement (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fp0n/anthropic_paying_15_billion_in_ai_copyright/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fp0n/anthropic_paying_15_billion_in_ai_copyright/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n9fp0n/anthropic_paying_15_billion_in_ai_copyright/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://apnews.com/article/anthropic-copyright-authors-settlement-training-f294266bc79a16ec90d2ddccdf435164">https://apnews.com/article/anthropic-copyright-authors-settlement-training-f294266bc79a16ec90d2ddccdf435164</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/wjok4efslenf1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 01:42:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/mgu9fy21w2nf1</link><title>Casual conversation with the security robot dog (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n811zq/casual_conversation_with_the_security_robot_dog/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n811zq/casual_conversation_with_the_security_robot_dog/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n811zq/casual_conversation_with_the_security_robot_dog/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/mgu9fy21w2nf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1759771784%2CMjU5OWQxMWUzMjc3OGEwMTk1NWU4NjJlMzI1YjMzM2ZlNDgxNjk4MmRmMDNlMmZmMjUwM2UzNGViYzljMTQzNQ%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='720' height='1280'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 10:18:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/article/alexandr-wang-meta-scale-ai-entrepreneur-mark-zuckerberg/</link><title>Alexandr Wang is now leading Meta’s AI dream team. Will Mark Zuckerberg's big bet pay off? (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7yrlg/alexandr_wang_is_now_leading_metas_ai_dream_team/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7yrlg/alexandr_wang_is_now_leading_metas_ai_dream_team/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 12 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7yrlg/alexandr_wang_is_now_leading_metas_ai_dream_team/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>In the summer of 2016, Alexandr Wang was a 19-year-old building his data-labeling startup, Scale AI, in a Silicon Valley pool house with his cofounder, Lucy Guo, while the two participated in the Y Combinator startup accelerator. When not working, the two founders slept on air mattresses and pondered the fledgling business’s potential. Less than a decade later, the pool house project has reset expectations and plans across the tech industry’s highest levels. In June, Mark Zuckerberg handed the now 28-year-old Wang the keys to Meta’s entire AI operations as part of a $14.3 billion investment in Scale AI. As Meta’s first-ever chief AI officer, Wang now leads a newly formed superintelligence team packed with AI industry superstars paid like high-priced athletes, and oversees Meta’s other AI product and research teams—all under the umbrella of a new organization called Meta Superintelligence Labs.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://fortune.com/img-assets/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/AlexWang_A-1-social.jpg?resize=1200,600' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>In the summer of 2016, Alexandr Wang was a 19-year-old building his data-labeling startup, Scale AI, in a Silicon Valley pool house with his cofounder, Lucy Guo, while the two participated in the Y Combinator startup accelerator. When not working, the two founders slept on air mattresses and pondered the fledgling business&rsquo;s potential. Less than a decade later, the pool house project has reset expectations and plans across the tech industry&rsquo;s highest levels. In June, Mark Zuckerberg handed the now 28-year-old Wang the keys to Meta&rsquo;s entire AI operations as part of a $14.3 billion investment in Scale AI. As Meta&rsquo;s first-ever chief AI officer, Wang now leads a newly formed superintelligence team packed with AI industry superstars paid like high-priced athletes, and oversees Meta&rsquo;s other AI product and research teams&mdash;all under the umbrella of a new organization called <a href="https://fortune.com/company/facebook/">Meta</a> Superintelligence Labs.</p><div><p>This AI dream team, and Wang&rsquo;s role as its captain, mark the latest chapter in a Silicon Valley narrative that&rsquo;s practically a clich&eacute; by now: a new wunderkind rising in tandem with the next world-changing technology. In this case, however, rather than disrupting the old guard, Wang is leaping to action to help an established tech giant, which happens to be run by the previous generation&rsquo;s whiz kid. </p><p>Zuckerberg, the Facebook founder who was worth more than $1 billion by his 23rd birthday, is going all in on AI to maintain the dominance of his 3.4-billion-user-strong social media empire. In addition to spending tens of billions of dollars a year on infrastructure to build the data centers running its AI, the Meta CEO is writing big checks to recruit the world&rsquo;s most sought-after AI talent. Along- side Wang, whom Zuckerberg has called &ldquo;the most impressive founder of his generation,&rdquo; the superintelligence team includes former GitHub CEO Nat Friedman; Daniel Gross, who had been CEO and cofounder of buzzy startup Safe Superintelligence; as well as researchers poached from OpenAI, Anthropic, <a href="https://fortune.com/company/alphabet/">Google</a>, and <a href="https://fortune.com/company/apple/">Apple</a>, with compensation packages for some rumored to be north of $100 million. Ruoming Pang, the engineer in charge of Apple&rsquo;s foundation models team, is reportedly pocketing a whopping $200 million over four years. </p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m focused on building the most elite and talent-dense team in the industry,&rdquo; Zuckerberg wrote on his Threads app in July. </p><p>The goal of this extraordinary hiring spree? Most pressingly, to reverse Meta&rsquo;s recent struggles in the grueling week-to-week contest for AI market share and mindshare, and to lock in Meta&rsquo;s large language models at the front of the pack. But Wang and his team of super friends have also been tasked with accomplishing something far more ambitious, and something that will be much trickier to measure with ordinary KPIs: to attain the still entirely theoretical concept of &ldquo;superintelligence,&rdquo; leapfrogging ChatGPT-maker OpenAI&mdash;and all other frontier AI competitors&mdash;in the race to define the future of artificial intelligence.</p><hr><p>If the word &ldquo;superintelligence&rdquo; conjures images of omniscient science fiction machines, you&rsquo;re not too far off the mark. </p><p>There is no agreed-upon formal definition of superintelligence, though the term typically refers to an artificial intelligence that vastly surpasses human capabilities in virtually all domains, including scientific creativity, general wisdom, and social skills. </p><p>Superintelligence is generally perceived as going beyond artificial general intelligence, or AGI, which, though also vague, typically refers to an AI system with human-level intelligence across a wide range of work-related tasks. That is, it can reason, plan, solve problems, understand language, and learn in a generalizable way, much like a human. Estimates for achieving AGI vary widely, ranging from a few months to a decade or more; for superintelligence, the timeline ranges from a few years to never. </p><p>Among Silicon Valley&rsquo;s leaders, the mission is spoken about with the assurance of an airplane pilot giving passengers a flight update en route to their destination. </p><p>&ldquo;Developing superintelligence is coming into sight,&rdquo; Zuckerberg wrote in an internal memo obtained by <em>Fortune</em>, though he provided no specific estimate for the date. (OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, for his part, wrote in a June blog post that humanity is now &ldquo;close&rdquo; to building digital superintelligence.)</p><p>Zuckerberg&rsquo;s memo claimed that Meta is &ldquo;uniquely positioned to deliver superintelligence to the world,&rdquo; pointing to the computing power in its data centers versus smaller labs with fewer resources. </p><p>In his July Threads post, Zuckerberg touted Meta&rsquo;s investments in massive, multi-gigawatt data centers with grandiose names (&ldquo;Prometheus&rdquo; and &ldquo;Hyperion&rdquo;) and mind-boggling scale: One of the data centers, Zuck boasted, will have a footprint nearly as big as Manhattan. Meta will &ldquo;invest hundreds of billions of dollars into compute to build superintelligence,&rdquo; Zuckerberg declared. &ldquo;We have the capital from our business to do this.&rdquo; </p><figure><blockquote><p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s probably a handful of people in the world that you bet on,&rdquo; says a former Scale AI manager. Wang is one of them.</p></blockquote></figure><p>Of course, a few other notable tech giants have the capital too, and they are dead set on edging Meta out. <a href="https://fortune.com/company/microsoft/">Microsoft</a> and Google are both deploying tens of billions in capital expenditures to build out their AI infrastructure. And OpenAI, in addition to its partnership with Microsoft, has said it intends to invest $500 billion with partners including SoftBank to build out the Stargate network of AI data centers over the next few years. </p><hr><p>In making Wang Chief AI Officer, Meta has chosen someone who is an entrepreneur, not a computer scientist. Even more notable is the fact that the man leading Meta&rsquo;s quest for superintelligence comes from a company that was not in the business of actually building large language models.</p><p>That&rsquo;s not to say that Wang&mdash;a competitive &ldquo;mathlete&rdquo; in high school&mdash;is a cerebral slouch. He&rsquo;s &ldquo;11/10 smart and ambitious&rdquo; and &ldquo;superspecial,&rdquo; says Sarah Guo, founder of VC firm Conviction and former general partner at venture capital firm Greylock, when describing Wang. Guo (no relation to Scale AI cofounder Lucy Guo, who parted ways with Scale in 2018) got to know Scale&rsquo;s founders when they launched their startup from the pool house of her Portola Valley, Calif., home. </p><p>Will Meta&rsquo;s teams of AI PhDs and computer scientists be as impressed and find in Wang the inspiration that drives them to reach the land of superintelligence? </p><p>People close to Wang, including current and former Scale AI employees, investors, acquaintances, and competitors, have emphasized that Wang should not be underestimated in his ability to attract talent and lead Meta&rsquo;s AI organization into the future. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s probably a handful of people in the world that you bet on&rdquo; to build the kind of team Zuckerberg is looking for at Meta, and Wang is on that short list, says a former Scale AI manager who recently left the company. Wang &ldquo;is a great recruiter, a really savvy commercial person.&rdquo; </p><p>Conviction&rsquo;s Guo echoes the sentiment: &ldquo;I think people would be mistaken to underestimate Alex and Nat,&rdquo; she says, referring to Wang and his Meta teammate Nat Friedman. &ldquo;They are very, very smart, ambitious, technical people who are going to listen to their researchers. They are compelling recruiters with a lot of compute and have [Zuckerberg&rsquo;s] insane force of will behind them.&rdquo; An early Scale AI employee, who left in 2022, said that Wang em- bodied the startup&rsquo;s credo of &ldquo;Ambition shapes reality.&rdquo; </p><p>Perhaps that winds back to Wang&rsquo;s childhood as the son of immigrant parents who were nuclear physicists at Los Alamos National Laboratory in New Mexico. Wang, whose first name is spelled without the second &ldquo;e&rdquo; to give it the eight characters associated with good fortune in Chinese culture, dropped out of MIT after one year to pursue the startup dream. Wang and Guo had originally planned to create tech for a doctors&rsquo; concierge service, but after joining Y Combinator they saw an opportunity in data&mdash;specifically in the behind-the-scenes, labor- intensive work of tagging and organizing data so that AI models can learn from it.</p><p>Scale&rsquo;s pivot to data labeling, often considered the &ldquo;grunt work&rdquo; that powers AI&rsquo;s intelligence, proved to be perfectly timed and highly valuable because of how critical data is for AI models. &ldquo;Lucy&rsquo;s phone bricked from overheating because she&rsquo;d set up the phone with <a href="https://fortune.com/company/twilio/">Twilio</a> to get a text notification every time a new request came in, and they flooded in so fast once researchers decided they wanted the data,&rdquo; recalls Sarah Guo. </p><hr><p>Meta&rsquo;s relationship with Scale AI dates back to 2019, when the social media company began using Scale as a data provider for its AI efforts, and Meta was among the investors in Scale&rsquo;s $1 billion funding round in 2024. Zuckerberg and Wang began spending more time together beginning in April, when Zuckerberg reached out and expressed a desire to work more closely, according to a source familiar with the negotiations. </p><p>The Meta CEO began inviting Wang (who had become the world&rsquo;s youngest self-made billionaire before turning 25) to meet with him at his houses in Lake Tahoe and Palo Alto, with Zuckerberg soon coming to trust Wang&rsquo;s opinion. Advisors say that Zuckerberg would sometimes reference Wang&rsquo;s views in conversations with them, The Information reported. </p><p>The conversations between the two CEOs came at a time when Zuckerberg was growing frustrated with Meta&rsquo;s struggles keeping up with rival AI labs such as OpenAI, Anthropic, and Google <a href="https://fortune.com/company/deepmind/">DeepMind</a>. Meta had succeeded in creating a family of successful open-source AI models, called Llama, but never seemed able to stay ahead of the pack for long. OpenAI, Anthropic, and Google DeepMind would inevitably surge past Meta with each new update. </p><p>With the release of Llama 4 in April 2025, Meta&rsquo;s malaise became a crisis. Allegations of possibly inflated performance metrics, a rushed release, and a lack of transparency, along with indications that Meta was failing to keep pace with open-source AI rivals like China&rsquo;s DeepSeek, led many in the industry to proclaim Meta&rsquo;s latest AI model a flop. (Meta has called claims that it gamed performance metrics &ldquo;simply not true.&rdquo;)</p><p>And so, even as Wang pushes for future superintelligence, he has the challenging near-term assignment of reinvigorating Meta&rsquo;s current LLM efforts. In the Llama large language models, Meta has a valuable asset and vast resources to draw upon. But as competition intensifies, particularly with upstart rivals from China, Wang will need to make some important strategic decisions, including whether it still makes sense to keep Llama open-source, or whether the changing competitive landscape requires that Meta keep the models&rsquo; weights under lock and key. </p><p>With Wang&rsquo;s firsthand experience building a successful business in the AI sector, the perspective he acquired as a neutral data provider serving the top LLM makers, and his business savvy, fans say he could be the missing ingredient to take Meta&rsquo;s AI efforts to the next level. </p><p>Alex Ren, founding managing partner at Fellows Fund, says that Meta needed an entrepreneur to lead its AI organization&mdash;and it found that in Wang, as well as Friedman and Gross. Meta&rsquo;s AI teams had previously been led by scientists and product managers. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s wrong,&rdquo; says Ren, who counts several of the members of the new superintelligence team as friends. Pointing to OpenAI, and its business-oriented CEO, Sam Altman, Ren says that Meta &ldquo;should really be led by founders and entrepreneurs. Alex Wang is not a researcher, he is a leader.&rdquo; </p><hr><p>With more than $164 billion in annual revenue, Meta knows all too well that it takes something truly unique to move the needle in its business. And in paying up for Wang and his team, Zuckerberg is betting that the ultimate value transcends any simple categories. </p><p>If Wang strikes some as an unconventional choice, reckons one source close to the entrepreneur, it&rsquo;s because he does not fit into the typical tech-world archetypes: &ldquo;Silicon Valley is good at putting people into boxes. They like to say, &lsquo;This person is a technical person, this person is a businessperson.&rsquo; Alex is truly a man of one.&rdquo;</p><p>Few companies could justify pouring billions into speculative AI research and assembling a roster of top-tier talent armed with the latest secret recipes for model success. But Meta can&mdash;and has. Whether that bet pays off is still uncertain. Still, as one current Meta AI research scientist&mdash;who isn&rsquo;t on the new superintelligence team&mdash;told <em>Fortune</em>, if that group makes big leaps in frontier AI over the next six months, &ldquo;everything can be justified.&rdquo; </p><p><em>This article appears in the <a href="https://fortune.com/packages/august-september-2025/">August/September 2025</a> issue of </em>Fortune<em> with the headline &ldquo;Can Alexandr Wang bring Meta AI supremacy?&rdquo;</em></p></div><p><strong>Fortune Global Forum</strong> returns Oct. 26&ndash;27, 2025 in Riyadh. CEOs and global leaders will gather for a dynamic, invitation-only event shaping the future of business. <a href="https://conferences.fortune.com/event/global-forum-2025/summary">Apply for an invitation.</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 08:19:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/jb7p1aqwz0nf1.png</link><title>The internet will become increasingly automated and artificial (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7t02l/the_internet_will_become_increasingly_automated/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7t02l/the_internet_will_become_increasingly_automated/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7t02l/the_internet_will_become_increasingly_automated/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/jb7p1aqwz0nf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 03:56:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/jjplx5j3kzmf1</link><title>First video of Optimus 3 (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7lebe/first_video_of_optimus_3/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7lebe/first_video_of_optimus_3/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n7lebe/first_video_of_optimus_3/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/jjplx5j3kzmf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1759771784%2CYjc0NTkzOWEwYjMzYmRhODViZDM3ZTdhMzRmNDhhNjkwMjc3ZjY1YjI1ZjM4MzllMjM1ZWYzOTY3YjY3ZjVjNQ%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='720' height='1280'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 23:06:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/j61qai9kmsmf1</link><title>Geoffrey Hinton says he’s more optimistic now, after realizing that there might be a way to co-exist with super intelligent AI’s (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6r5bh/geoffrey_hinton_says_hes_more_optimistic_now/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6r5bh/geoffrey_hinton_says_hes_more_optimistic_now/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6r5bh/geoffrey_hinton_says_hes_more_optimistic_now/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/j61qai9kmsmf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1759771784%2CNDU2YmY4ODdkNWIyZTNkMTgxMWQ0YTBkYWY3ZDJmODMzZWI1ZDEzMzg3N2ZjMTBlYjljYmI3ODdkMjg2YTJjYQ%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='720' height='720'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 23:47:40 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1n6lexe</link><title>Used nano banana to "clean up" visuals for a document (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6lexe/used_nano_banana_to_clean_up_visuals_for_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6lexe/used_nano_banana_to_clean_up_visuals_for_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6lexe/used_nano_banana_to_clean_up_visuals_for_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/sqid5jigkrmf1.png?width=325&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=eec396cf897ad6d28ea196d3d7bde0b90c0c36c3" height="300" width="325" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/bs72kdngkrmf1.jpg?width=824&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f91c2f05f6cd834f08386d2bcc4bd5888448092b" height="800" width="824" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:14:05 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1n6gabs</link><title>Linkedin influencers already pumping nano banana selfies, we're fucked (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6gabs/linkedin_influencers_already_pumping_nano_banana/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6gabs/linkedin_influencers_already_pumping_nano_banana/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n6gabs/linkedin_influencers_already_pumping_nano_banana/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/l89apgfleqmf1.png?width=1179&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=0abaa29402215e69b5801f0b3d3d1bbc84c12afc" height="1993" width="1179" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/pwfadzlleqmf1.png?width=1179&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=720e109cd323a7dbccf1738051cca32c55433d43" height="1854" width="1179" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:23:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5mame/people_are_furious_that_openai_is_reporting/</link><title>People Are Furious That OpenAI Is Reporting ChatGPT Conversations to Law Enforcement</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5mame/people_are_furious_that_openai_is_reporting/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5mame/people_are_furious_that_openai_is_reporting/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5mame/people_are_furious_that_openai_is_reporting/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://futurism.com/people-furious-openai-reporting-police">Futurism reports</a>: Earlier this week, buried in the middle of a <a href="https://openai.com/index/helping-people-when-they-need-it-most/">lengthy blog post</a> addressing ChatGPT&#39;s propensity for <a href="https://tech.slashdot.org/story/25/08/29/1116218/a-troubled-man-his-chatbot-and-a-murder-suicide-in-old-greenwich">severe mental health harms</a>, OpenAI admitted that it&#39;s scanning users&#39; conversations and <a href="https://futurism.com/lawsuit-parents-son-suicide-chatgpt">reporting to police</a> any interactions that a human reviewer deems sufficiently threatening.  </p><p><em>&quot;When we detect users who are planning to harm others, we route their conversations to specialized pipelines where they are reviewed by a small team trained on our usage policies and who are authorized to take action, including banning accounts,&quot; it wrote. &quot;If human reviewers determine that a case involves an imminent threat of serious physical harm to others, we may refer it to law enforcement.&quot;</em>  </p><p>The announcement raised immediate questions. Don&#39;t human moderators judging tone, for instance, undercut the entire premise of an AI system that its creators say can solve broad, complex problems? How is OpenAI even figuring out users&#39; precise locations in order to provide them to emergency responders? How is it protecting against abuse by <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/purgatory-gores-swatting-us-universities/">so-called swatters</a>, who could pretend to be someone else and then make violent threats to ChatGPT in order to get their targets raided by the cops...? The admission also seems to contradict remarks by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, who <a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/07/25/sam-altman-warns-theres-no-legal-confidentiality-when-using-chatgpt-as-a-therapist/">recently called for privacy</a> akin to a &quot;therapist or a lawyer or a doctor&quot; for users talking to ChatGPT.</p><p><em>&quot;Others argued that the AI industry is hastily pushing poorly-understood products to market, using real people as guinea pigs, and adopting increasingly haphazard solutions to real-world problems as they arise...&quot;</em></p><p>Source: <a href="http://Slashdot.org">Slashdot.org</a>  </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 17:04:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5dib1/i_disagree_with_this_subs_consensus_ubi_is/</link><title>I disagree with this subs consensus: UBI IS inevitable</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5dib1/i_disagree_with_this_subs_consensus_ubi_is/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5dib1/i_disagree_with_this_subs_consensus_ubi_is/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n5dib1/i_disagree_with_this_subs_consensus_ubi_is/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>There’s been a lot of chatter on this sub about UBI and how many believe it’s just unlikely to happen. I personally disagree.</p><p>While it’s true that the U.S., for example, won’t even give its citizens basic medical coverage, it’s not true that the government won’t step in when the economy tanks. When a recession hits (2008, 2020… sort of), the wealthy push for the government to inject capital back into the system to restart things. I believe there will be a storm before the calm, so to speak. Most likely, we’ll see a devastating downturn—maybe even 1929 levels—as millions of jobs disappear within a few years. Companies’ profits will soar until suddenly their revenue crashes.</p><p>Any market system requires people who can actually afford to buy goods. When they can’t, the whole machine grinds to a halt. I think this will happen on an astronomical scale in the U.S. (and globally). As jobs dry up and new opportunities shrink, it’s only a matter of time before everything starts breaking down.</p><p>There will be large-scale bailouts, followed by stimulus packages. That probably won’t work, and conditions will likely worsen. Eventually, UBI will gain mainstream attention, and I believe that’s when it will begin to be implemented. It’ll probably start small but grow as leaders realize how bad things could get if nothing is done.</p><p>For most companies, it’s not in their interest for people to be broke. More people with spending power means more customers, which means more profit. That, I think, will be the guiding reason UBI moves forward. It’s probably not set up to help us out of goodwill, but at least we’ll get it ¯\_(ツ)_/¯</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 08:26:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/ex-openai-miles-brundage-ubi-ai-jobs-market-2025-8</link><title>Former OpenAI researcher says a $10,000 monthly UBI will be 'feasible' with AI-enabled growth (businessinsider.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n4xbpq/former_openai_researcher_says_a_10000_monthly_ubi/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n4xbpq/former_openai_researcher_says_a_10000_monthly_ubi/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n4xbpq/former_openai_researcher_says_a_10000_monthly_ubi/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.insider.com/68a8cd6bcfc04e97619be60c?width=1200&format=jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section> <section> <section><div><figure> <span> <span> <label> </label> <figcaption> <span>AI leaders are among the most outspoken supporters of a universal basic income.</span> <span> <span> alfexe/Getty Images </span> </span> </figcaption> </span> </span></figure> </div><div><ul> <li>AI leaders have long championed a universal basic income.</li> <li>Most basic income pilot programs range from $500 to $1,500 a month, no strings attached.</li> <li>Former OpenAI researcher Miles Brundage said those numbers should be much higher.</li> </ul> </div><section><p>Would you be interested in a $10,000 monthly check with no strings attached?</p><p>That's a reality that former OpenAI researcher <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/another-safety-researcher-is-leaving-openai-2024-10">Miles Brundage</a> said could be possible in the age of AI.</p><p>Tech leaders have long called for a <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/universal-basic-income-ubi">universal basic income</a>, or UBI, to offset job loss due to artificial intelligence.</p><p>A universal basic income is generally considered a monthly government stipend for the entire population. It differs from the guaranteed <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/universal-basic-income-politics">basic income programs</a> that many cities and states are experimenting with these days. Those typically provide recurring payments to a specific population based on socioeconomic status. So far, most of these experiments have offered cash payments between $500 and $1,500 a month.</p><p>Brundage said on X this week, however, that policymakers should be thinking bigger.</p><p>"I think that a significantly more generous UBI experiment than has been tried so far (say, $10k/month vs. $1k/month) would show big effects," he wrote.</p><p>Brundage said this would be possible due to the impacts AI will have on the economy.</p><p>"$1k/month is relevant to what's feasible policy-wise today," Brundage said. "$10k/month is relevant to what will be feasible policy-wise in a few years with AI-enabled growth."</p><p>AI Advancements are already <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/ai-wipe-out-most-jobs-2045-few-still-survive-researcher-2025-7">threatening some entry-level jobs</a>. Many <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/universal-basic-income-ai">AI industry leaders</a>, including Elon Musk, have championed<strong> </strong>basic income programs. OpenAI CEO Sam Altman<strong> </strong>helped fund one of the <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/sam-altman-basic-income-study-results-2024-7">largest basic income studies,</a> which gave recipients $1,000 monthly for three years.</p><p>Brundage resigned as OpenAI's senior policy advisor and head of the AGI readiness team in 2024. In a blog post at the time, he said labor disruptions caused by AI was top of mind for him.</p><p>"In the near-term, I worry a lot about AI disrupting opportunities for people who desperately want work, but I think it's simultaneously true that humanity should eventually remove the obligation to work for a living and that doing so is one of the strongest arguments for building AI and AGI in the first place," Brundage wrote.</p><p>Brundage said our current systems aren't prepared to address that reality right now.</p><p>"That is not something we're prepared for politically, culturally, or otherwise, and needs to be part of the policy conversation. A naive shift toward a post-work world risks civilizational stagnation (see: WALL-E), and much more thought and debate about this is needed," he said.</p></section> </section> <section> <section> <h2> Read next </h2> </section> <section> <vendor-taboola> </vendor-taboola> </section> </section> </section> <back-to-home> </back-to-home></section><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://i.insider.com/68a8ccef194a2d49b8af0d50?width=700"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 20:45:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/3z0b8mzay8mf1.png</link><title>"1m context" models after 32k tokens (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n4gkc3/1m_context_models_after_32k_tokens/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n4gkc3/1m_context_models_after_32k_tokens/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1n4gkc3/1m_context_models_after_32k_tokens/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/3z0b8mzay8mf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 05:38:33 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/s6555dgpn7hf1</link><title>Google Deepmind's new Genie 3 (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1miaoat/google_deepminds_new_genie_3/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1miaoat/google_deepminds_new_genie_3/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/singularity/comments/1miaoat/google_deepminds_new_genie_3/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://x.com/OfficialLoganK/status/1952732206176112915">https://x.com/OfficialLoganK/status/1952732206176112915</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/s6555dgpn7hf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1759771784%2COTYzNzVmY2MyYzk4ODgzZjJiM2I5ZWYzMjhjZjhiYjE4NjJlYmE0ZGRkOGI4YmRjM2NhNzM5ZWNlNGJiMDJkOQ%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1920' height='1080'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 19:56:30 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
