<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 07:34:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/</link><title>INDIANS are the most racist in the entire world and that too towards INDIANS!!!!!!!!!!! Especially living outside India!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>So this incident happened today.</p><p>I run a very small IT agency usually giving web development services. Recently I was talking to a US client to finalize a deal of $350. Everything was going good until the comes an Indian working at their company! </p><p>I politely smiled and was happy to see Indian. But things changed the moment he opened his mouth and started vomiting!!!!!!!!!</p><p>He started asking questions completely unrelated to the work like my surname, what my father do, why are you charging so much and why is your surname *** , are you running office from home!!!!!</p><p>I WANT TO ASK YOU NRIs!!!!! </p><p>WHAT THE FUCK DO YOU THINK YOU ARE!!!!!!! </p><p>WHY THE FUCK ARE YOU BEING SO RACIST TOWARDS PEOPLE OF YOUR OWN COUNTRY!!!!!!!!!!! </p><p>If I am running agency from India, that doesnt mean I cant go to US and work. Its because of my personal choice!! </p><p>WHO THE FUCK GIVE YOU RIGHT TO ASK SUCH CASTIEST QUESTIONS and BEING so JUDGEMENTAL!!!!!!!</p><p>True fact - I have dealt with NRIs , I dont understand why they have so much attitude and why the fuck they always try to demean other INDIANS!!!!!!!!! </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 02:16:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newsweek.com/h1-b-visa-program-fee-trump-requirements-2132718</link><title>Trump To Introduce $100k Fee For H-1B Visas: Report (newsweek.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2726307/president-donald-trump-speaks-presser.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>President <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a> announced that his administration is adding a $100,000 application fee for <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/h-1b-visas-immigration-workers-companies-2115698">the H-1B visa program</a>, a White House official confirmed to <em>Newsweek </em>on Friday.</p><p>Trump then signed a proclamation in the Oval Office on Friday afternoon.</p><p>The major <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/h-1b-visas">H-1B</a> reform would restrict entry under <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/h-1b-visas-immigration-trump-doj-2121365">the work visa</a> unless the hefty payment is made. The current fees to register for the visa lottery are $215, with an additional $780 fee for a Form I-129&mdash;a petition for a non-immigrant worker filed by an employer sponsor.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p>The work-based visa, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/map-states-h-1b-visas-immigration-2113555">popular with tech companies</a>, has come under increasing scrutiny in 2025 against a backdrop of tougher immigration enforcement by the Trump administration and a <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/indian-immigrants-us-visas-social-media-hate-racism-2121568">simmering anti-immigrant sentiment</a> in the U.S.</p><p>Trump has been <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/h1b-visa-immigrants-tech-jobs-impact-college-grads-2106392">under pressure to act on the H-1B</a>, despite being vocal in his support for the program over the years. The visa, which sees tens of thousands of new and renewed applications each year, has become a focal point for those seeking a more restrictionist approach.</p><figure><figcaption> <span>President Donald Trump speaks during a joint press conference with Britain's Prime Minister Keir Starmer at Chequers, near Aylesbury, England, on September 18.</span> <span>Evan Vucci/AP</span> </figcaption> </figure><h2><strong>Trump Expected to Sign Proclamation to Overhaul H-1B Visa Program</strong></h2><p><span>The president and Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick said the main change for the H-1B would be a new $100,000 fee. The current fee for an initial application is approximately $1,000.</span></p><p><span>Trump told reporters that tech companies were on board with the changes, which he said would mean the U.S. would keep immigrants who would be "productive" for the country.<br> </span></p><p>Another change could be to prevailing wage rules, meaning the amount employers must pay immigrant workers. This is an area critics have frequently pointed to, arguing that companies hire foreign workers because they can pay them less.</p><p>It was unclear what the wage level would be, but a briefing note seen by <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/bloomberg">Bloomberg</a> stated that American workers were being replaced with foreign labor, particularly in STEM fields.</p><p>Many immigration experts reacted to the initial reports of the change on social media, saying that it was unlikely the changes would be implemented with the stroke of Trump's pen.</p><p>Under immigration law, it is <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/congress">Congress</a> that has the power to change the fees charged by the <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/department-of-homeland-security">Department of Homeland Security</a>, not the Executive branch.</p><h2><strong>What Other Changes Are Coming to the H-1B Visa Program?</strong></h2><p>Earlier this week, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/republican">Republican</a> Senator Jim Banks <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/h-1b-visa-change-proposal-2132484">introduced legislation in Congress to also make changes to the H-1B</a> program.</p><p>His bill would increase the wage floor for H-1B workers from $60,000 to $150,000, eliminate the Optional Practical Training (OPT) program, and replace the current lottery-based selection process with a system based on the highest bidder.</p><p>Earlier in the summer, the White House approved a proposal for a new way of selecting H-1B visas. Details were not clear, but it was suggested that the current lottery system be replaced with one that <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/h1b-visa-changes-lottery-weighted-selection-2100828">selects candidates based on their wages</a>.</p><h2><strong>Current H-1B Visa Requirements: What To Know</strong></h2><p>Currently, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/republicans-push-expand-h-1b-visa-program-immigration-2073175">the H-1B</a> visa is allocated through a lottery system, which is not intended to favor one company or applicant over another.</p><p>However, larger companies can apply for more visas, resulting in a disproportionate number of H-1Bs being awarded to companies like <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/amazon">Amazon</a>, <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/meta">Meta</a>, and <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/microsoft-layoffs-h1b-visa-applications-2094370">Microsoft</a>.</p><p>Some employers are also not part of the lottery or cap system, including academic institutions.</p><p>Companies also do not have to prove that an American-born worker cannot do the job, another part of the program that has come under heavy criticism.</p><h2><strong>How Long Can Someone Stay in the US With an H-1B Visa?</strong></h2><p>The H-1B is issued initially for three years, with the option of renewing at the end of that term for another three.</p><p>Some H-1B holders then opt to apply for a green card, or lawful permanent residency.</p><h2><strong>What People Are Saying</strong></h2><p><strong>Jeremy Beck, co-president of NumbersUSA, an immigration reduction advocacy group, told <em>Newsweek</em>: </strong>"The Executive Branch can adjust fees, typically through the rulemaking process. We would have to see the precise details before giving a definitive response to this idea. In theory, however, this could be a significant step toward aligning the reality of the program with the stated intentions of its proponents.</p><p>"Charging a $100,000 fee would essentially call the bluff that so many corporations make when applying for H-1B workers, but it wouldn't block a necessary visa. If the guest worker truly possesses extraordinary skills that cannot be found in the domestic labor force, a $100,000 fee would be justified to fill a critical short-term gap until an American can be found."</p><p><strong>President Donald Trump, in the Oval Office, Friday: </strong>"We need workers. We need great workers. And this pretty much ensures this is going to happen."</p><p><strong>Democratic Washington Representative Pramila Jayapal, on X: </strong>"These are visas for skilled workers &mdash; doctors, scientists, and engineers. This move will hurt US innovation and exacerbate an already serious shortage of medical professionals. In what world does this make sense??"</p><p><strong>David Bier, director of immigration studies at the Cato Institute, on X: </strong>"The most anti-legal immigration administration in American history continues to threaten US prosperity and freedom. This action would kill the H-1B visa and ban some of the highest-value employees in America. Utterly incomprehensible."</p><p><strong>Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick said on a call with reporters,</strong> "So no longer will you put trainees on an H-1B visa. That it's just not economic anymore. If you're going to train people, you're going to train Americans. ... If you have a very sophisticated engineer and you want to bring them in ... then you can pay $100,000 a year for your H-1B visa."</p><h2><strong>What Happens Next</strong></h2><p>Trump said Friday evening that the new policy was backed by U.S. companies, which would pay the new fee. An implementation date has not been announced yet.</p><p><em>Update 9/19/25 3:21 p.m. ET: This article was updated with additional information. </em></p><p><em>Update 9/19/25, 4:39 p.m. ET: This article was updated with comment from Jeremy Beck.</em></p><p><em>Update 9/19/25, 5:47 p.m. ET: This article was updated with additional information.</em></p><p><em>Update 9/19/25, 7:55 p.m. ET: This article was updated with additional information and comment from Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick.</em></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2726307/president-donald-trump-speaks-presser.jpg?w=1200&amp;f=e345e13b49cc839d5fa34ac10c988c8b"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:36:28 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/delhi-bmw-crash-van-driver-victim-hopital-vehicle-seized-2788454-2025-09-17</link><title>Van seized, income hit: Man who rushed Delhi BMW crash victim to hospital (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>The van driver who took the BMW crash victim to the hospital following the deadly accident has claimed that the police have siezed his vehicle due to which his daily income is being affected. However, the police have denied this claim. </h2></div><div><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/did-what-felt-right--says-man-who-took-bmw-crash-victim--his-wife-to-hospital-151522884-16x9_1.jpg?VersionId=0plgRKp_skvvQB.lQm5I_L0HjTReSVmc&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="BMW crash" title="Mohammad Gulfam was returning from Faridabad after work when he came across the accident near Dhaula Kuan." height="388"></p><p>Mohammad Gulfam was returning from Faridabad after work when he came across the accident near Dhaula Kuan.</p></div><div><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 17, 2025 16:24 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>A van driver who rushed the victims of Sunday's BMW accident to hospital has claimed that his vehicle has been seized by police for investigation, depriving him of his daily income.</p><p>The Delhi Police, however, rejected the charge, saying the vehicle had not been seized.</p><p>Mohammad Gulfam, a resident of Sultanpuri, was returning from Faridabad after work when he came across the accident near Dhaula Kuan.</p><p>He said while several bystanders were making videos, he stopped his loading van and helped the four injured -- Deputy Secretary in the Department of Economic Affairs Navjot Singh, his wife, and the BMW occupants -- reach a hospital.</p><p>"I stopped my vehicle to help because people were injured and in serious condition. An ambulance was standing there too. People requested the ambulance driver, but I quickly shifted them into my van so they could get treatment on time," Gulfam told PTI over a phone call.</p><p>"Since Sunday, my vehicle has been parked at a police station as part of the investigation. Teams are taking samples from my vehicle, and every time they tell me that it will be released in a day or two. I am being called to the police station regularly," he further claimed.</p><p>The van driver, who earns between Rs 1,000 and Rs 1,500 daily, said that as the vehicle is with the police, he is left with no income.</p><p>"This is my only source of livelihood. I stay in a rented house, and I have a five-year-old daughter. My family is also worried," he said.</p><p>Gulfam added that despite the difficulties, he does not regret helping the victims. "I only wanted to save lives. They were all badly injured, and someone had to take them quickly to a hospital. I thought of nothing else at that moment," he said.</p><p>Meanwhile, Deputy Commissioner of Police (Southwest) Amit Goel said the vehicles of the rescuer have not been seized.</p><p>Singh, a resident of Hari Nagar, died in the crash while his wife sustained serious injuries. The woman who was allegedly driving the BMW was arrested on charges of culpable homicide not amounting to murder, rash driving and causing disappearance of evidence.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Harshita Das</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 17, 2025</p></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/reporter/201804/pti_new.jpeg?VersionId=Pom4kxkCWVIuguBJOksKEW0ArP_ICIQe&amp;size=50:50"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:51:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businesstoday.in/india/story/trying-to-create-bangladesh-nepal-like-situation-in-india-bjps-big-claim-after-rahul-gandhi-drops-hydrogen-bomb-494623-2025-09-18</link><title>'Trying to create Bangladesh, Nepal-like situation in India': BJP's big claim after Rahul Gandhi drops 'hydrogen bomb' (businesstoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><h2>Earlier in the day, Gandhi gave a PowerPoint presentation and documents he claimed proved large-scale voter fraud by the BJP and the Election Commission. </h2><div><p><img width="948" height="533" title="'Trying to create Bangladesh, Nepal-like situation in India': BJP's big claim after Rahul Gandhi drops 'hydrogen bomb'" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/businesstoday/images/story/202509/68cbd6d33a0b4-thakur-also-mocked-gandhis-dramatic-warning-of-a-hydrogen-bomb--saying-the-much-hyped-expos-fizz-185421295-16x9.png?size=948:533" alt="'Trying to create Bangladesh, Nepal-like situation in India': BJP's big claim after Rahul Gandhi drops 'hydrogen bomb'"><span>Thakur also mocked Gandhi&rsquo;s dramatic warning of a &ldquo;hydrogen bomb,&rdquo; saying the much-hyped expos&eacute; fizzled out: &ldquo;While he promised a hydrogen bomb, he came only with firecrackers.&rdquo;</span></p></div><div><div><p>BJP leader Anurag Thakur on Thursday tore into Rahul Gandhi after the Congress leader&rsquo;s fiery press conference on what he described as &ldquo;vote chori&rdquo;. Earlier in the day, Gandhi gave a PowerPoint presentation and provided documents. He claimed that this was proof of large-scale voter fraud by the BJP and the Election Commission.</p><p>&ldquo;While the Election Commission of India is functioning without bias, Rahul Gandhi is busy weakening democracy, misleading citizens, and trying to create a situation like Bangladesh and Nepal,&rdquo; Thakur said, accusing the Congress leader of undermining democratic institutions.</p><p>Thakur countered Gandhi&rsquo;s Karnataka example, saying: &ldquo;According to records, the Aland Assembly seat was won by the Congress candidate in 2023 with a margin of 10,348 votes. So, Mr Rahul Gandhi, did Congress win that seat through vote chori? Today Rahul Gandhi himself admitted something in his own words &mdash; it was like dropping a hydrogen bomb on himself. He said, &lsquo;I have not come to save democracy.&rsquo; Is he preparing to destroy democracy?&rdquo;</p><p>Taking a dig at Gandhi&rsquo;s repeated defeats, Thakur said that the Congress MP from Wayanad is getting frustrated day-by-day. He added that Rahul Gandhi has become habitual of making false and baseless statements.</p><p>&ldquo;The Congress has lost approximately 90 elections under the leadership of Rahul Gandhi. His frustration is increasing day-by-day... It has become a habit of Rahul Gandhi to make incorrect and baseless allegations. Seeking apology and being reprimanded by the courts have become a routine of Rahul Gandhi.&rdquo;</p><p>He mocked Gandhi&rsquo;s dramatic warning of a &ldquo;hydrogen bomb,&rdquo; saying the much-hyped expos&eacute; fizzled out: &ldquo;While he promised a hydrogen bomb, he came only with firecrackers.&rdquo;</p><p>At the presser, Gandhi alleged that voter lists were being manipulated through software and fraudulent applications, with minorities being deliberately targeted. He cited examples from Karnataka&rsquo;s Aland constituency, claiming that over 6,000 names had been deleted using phone numbers linked to people outside the state.</p><p>He further accused the poll body and Chief Election Commissioner Gyanesh Kumar of presiding over a &ldquo;systematic, mass deletion of voters&rdquo; in Congress-dominated pockets ahead of the 2023 Karnataka assembly polls.</p><p>The Election Commission, however, brushed off the claims, calling them &ldquo;incorrect and baseless.&rdquo; Officials clarified that voter deletions cannot be carried out online by the public and that no removal from the rolls takes place without notifying the individual concerned and giving them a chance to respond.</p></div><div><p><span>Published on: Sep 18, 2025 3:25 PM IST</span> </p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:12:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/</link><title>To anyone wondering why Rahul Gandhi is not taking the Vote Chori allegation to Supreme Court here is why</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>These two examples show why taking a matter to the Supreme Court is a no-win situation.</p><p><strong>Example 1: The Vantara Verdict</strong><br/>Two written applications were submitted to the courts, alleging that Vantara was unlawfully acquiring animals and mistreating them in captivity. In its verdict, however, <strong><em>&quot;the Supreme Court stated that the SIT’s “exhaustive investigation” found no violation of the law and asserted that it would not allow tarnishing news reports about the rescue park in Jamnagar, Gujarat&quot;</em></strong>. This decision effectively gave Vantara a clean chit and brought the matter to a definitive close. This decision was perceived by the public as favoring the powerful. [<em>No disrespect to the Rescue park folks and the Supreme Court here this is just my opinion and not a comment on your working or integrity</em>]</p><p><strong>Example 2: The Election CCTV Hearing</strong><br/>In another case, the Haryana and Punjab High Court directed the Election Commission to provide CCTV footage related to the Haryana Assembly elections, following a petition by counsel Mehmood Pracha. Within three days, the government amended the law to prevent public access to electronic documents and recordings connected to elections, justifying the change as a way to “ <em>preventing the misuse of electronic election records. This includes CCTV camera and webcasting footage, as well as video recordings of candidates, during the election process.&quot;</em> Doubling down on this , the retention period for election CCTV footage was also shortened—from 1year to just 45 days, after which the recordings would be deleted. This maneuver effectively rendered the High Court’s verdict meaningless.</p><p>Taken together, these examples suggest that even if Rahul Gandhi were to win his case in the Supreme Court, the government could simply introduce new legislation to block the release of critical data. And if he were to lose, public perception might lean toward suspicion of foul play [ <em>Again, no disrespect is intended toward the Supreme Court—I deeply appreciate its strong stance on issues like the electoral bonds case</em>] .It would also effectively end any further discussion on the matter once the Supreme Court has delivered its judgment.</p><p>As Rahul Gandhi himself emphasized during his press conference, he will just present the facts, and it will ultimately be up to the public and the country’s youth to decide what to do next.</p><p>P.S. I did use ChatGPT to make the post more understandable</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:01:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-names-afghanistan-india-china-pakistan-among-major-drug-transit-illicit-drug-producing-countries/article70064066.ece</link><title>Trump names Afghanistan, India, China, Pakistan among major drug transit, illicit drug producing countries (thehindu.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/q5dik3/article70064079.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-09-16T164503Z_1708444932_RC24BFAG57UT_RTRMADP_3_USA-TRUMP.JPG' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>President Donald Trump has named China, Afghanistan, India and Pakistan among 23 major drug transit or major illicit drug producing countries, saying that by manufacturing and trafficking illicit drugs and precursor chemicals, these nations are threatening the safety of the U.S. and its citizens.</p><p>In a &lsquo;Presidential Determination&rsquo; submitted to Congress on Monday (September 15, 2025), Mr. Trump said he has identified 23 countries as &ldquo;major drug transit or major illicit drug producing&rdquo; nations.</p><p>These nations are Afghanistan, The Bahamas, Belize, Bolivia, Burma, China, Colombia, Costa Rica, the Dominican Republic, Ecuador, El Salvador, Guatemala, Haiti, Honduras, India, Jamaica, Laos, Mexico, Nicaragua, Pakistan, Panama, Peru, and Venezuela.</p><p>Mr. Trump delivered the &ldquo;Major&rsquo;s List&rdquo; to Congress, designating these countries as responsible for sourcing and transporting illicit drugs into the U.S., the White House said.</p><p>The State Department announced the Presidential Determination of these 23 countries, with five countries &mdash; Afghanistan, Bolivia, Burma, Colombia, and Venezuela &mdash; listed as having &ldquo;failed demonstrably to make substantial efforts,&rdquo; calling upon them to improve their counternarcotics efforts.</p><div></div><p>By manufacturing and trafficking illicit drugs and precursor chemicals, these countries are threatening the safety of the United States and its citizens, the State Department said in a statement.</p><p>The State Department clarified that a country's presence on the list does not necessarily reflect its government's counterdrug efforts or level of cooperation with the United States.</p><p>The listing is based on "the combination of geographic, commercial, and economic factors that allow drugs or precursor chemicals to be transited or produced, even if a government has engaged in robust and diligent narcotics control and law enforcement measures,&rdquo; it said.</p><p>Mr. Trump said Afghanistan, Bolivia, Burma, Colombia, and Venezuela have failed &ldquo;demonstrably&rdquo; during the previous 12 months to both adhere to their obligations under international counternarcotics agreements and to take the relevant measures to combat the threat.</p><p>On China, Mr. Trump said the country's role as the "world's largest source&rdquo; of precursor chemicals fuelling illicit fentanyl production has been well documented.</p><p>Mr. Trump also said that China is also a major supplier fuelling global epidemics of other synthetic narcotics, including nitazenes and methamphetamine.</p><p>The Chinese leadership &ldquo;can and must take stronger and sustained action to cut down these chemical flows and prosecute the drug criminals facilitating them.&rdquo; </p><p>On Afghanistan, Mr. Trump said that despite the Taliban's announced ban on illegal drugs, drug stockpiles and ongoing production &mdash; including expanding production of methamphetamine &mdash; have sustained the flow of drugs to international markets.</p><p>"Revenue from this drug trade funds transnational criminal groups and supports international terrorists. Some members of the Taliban continue to profit from this trade, and I am once again designating Afghanistan as having failed demonstrably to uphold its drug control obligations given the serious threats to United States interests and international security,&rdquo; Mr. Trump said.</p><p>He said that transnational organised crime's trafficking of fentanyl and other deadly illicit drugs into the US has created a national emergency, including a public health crisis that remains the leading cause of death for Americans ages 18 to 44. </p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png"></p><p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/9b292a/article70058399.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/PTI05_16_2025_000350B.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/bcv5rx/article69378982.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/Trump_Immigration_61585.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:16:20 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/rahul-gandhi-intensifies-vote-chori-attack-presents-proof-against-cec-gyanesh-kumar-protecting-destroyers-of-democracy-13556143.html</link><title>Rahul Gandhi intensifies 'vote chori' attack, presents 'proof' against CEC Gyanesh Kumar: 'Protecting destroyers of democracy' (moneycontrol.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.moneycontrol.com/static-mcnews/2025/08/20250817101829_rahul-gandhi.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><h2>Rahul Gandhi</h2> </div><p>In a fresh attack directed at the Election Commission of India, Congress leader Rahul Gandhi said that chief election commissioner Gyanesh Kumar was protecting people who have destroyed Indian democracy.</p><p>&ldquo;I am going to show you... the youth of India, the people of India today proof that is black and white, absolutely clear that the Chief Election Commissioner of India is protecting the people who have destroyed Indian democracy. I am also going to show you the method by which votes are being added and deleted and how that is done,&rdquo; Congress leader <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/topic/rahul-gandhi/">Rahul Gandhi</a> said addressing a press conference on Thursday.</p><p>He stated that instead of ensuring free and fair elections, the poll body was acting in a biased manner.</p><p><strong>'Systematic targeting'&nbsp;</strong></p><p>The Congress leader claimed that some force or group of people have been&nbsp;systematically targeting millions of voters for deletion across India.&nbsp;Different communities -- mainly who were voting for the opposition, Dalits, Tribals, minorities, OBCs -- are targeted in particular. "We had heard this many times and now we found 100% proof of it," he alleged.</p><p><strong>What happened in Aland?</strong></p><p>Talking about the Aland constituency in Karnataka, Rahul Gandhi alleged that around 6 thousand votes were deleted fraudulently by unknown people who used software and impersonated real voters.</p><p>"We don't know the total number of votes that were deleted in Aland in the 2023 election. They're likely much higher than 6,018," he said.</p><p>"But somebody got caught deleting 6,018 votes, and it was caught, like most crimes, by coincidence. What happened was the booth-level officer noticed that her uncle's vote was deleted. So, she checked who deleted her uncle's vote and found it was a neighbor. However, neither the person deleting the vote nor the person whose vote was deleted knew; some other force hijacked the process and deleted the vote, and, as luck would have it, got caught," Gandhi stated further.</p><p><strong>Congress party targeted</strong></p><p>The Congress leader claimed that in Aland, 6,018 applications were filed, impersonating voters.&nbsp;The people who allegedly filed these applications never actually filed them.</p><p>The filing was done automatically using software, Gandhi claimed, adding that mobile numbers from outside Karnataka and from different states were used to delete votes in Aland. These deletions specifically targeted booths where the Congress party was winning, he alleged.<br></p><blockquote><br>Targeted deletions in strong Congress booths.<p>&#128073;The top 10 booths with maximum deletions were Congress strongholds.</p><p>&#128073;Congress won 8 out of the 10 booths in 2018.</p><p>&#128073; This was not a coincidence; this was a planned operation.</p><p>: LoP Shri <a href="https://twitter.com/RahulGandhi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@RahulGandhi</a></p><p>&#128205; Delhi <a href="https://t.co/DJV2YTIFv2">pic.twitter.com/DJV2YTIFv2</a></p><p>&mdash; Congress (@INCIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/INCIndia/status/1968559029791375766?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2025</a></p></blockquote><p><strong>Accusations against Gyanesh Kumar</strong></p><p>Targeting CEC Gyanesh Kumar, Rahul Gandhi said the CID of Karnataka has sent 18 letters in 18 months to the Election Commission, and they have asked them for some very simple facts.</p><p>"One, give us the destination IP from where these forms were filled. Number two, give us the device destination ports from where these applications were filed. And number three, most importantly, give us the OTP trails because when you file, you have to get OTP," Gandhi said.</p><p>"18 times in 18 months, the CID of Karnataka has written to the Election Commission for this, and they are not giving it. Why are they not giving it? Because this will lead us to where the operation is being done, and we are absolutely convinced where this is going to go," he added.</p><blockquote><br>Let's come to why I'm making such a direct accusation against the CEC, Gyanesh Kumar. There is an ongoing investigation on this matter in Karnataka. The CID of Karnataka has sent 18 letters in 18 months to the Election Commission. And they have asked the election commission for&hellip; <a href="https://t.co/V8aWBkfszj">pic.twitter.com/V8aWBkfszj</a><p>&mdash; Congress (@INCIndia) <a href="https://twitter.com/INCIndia/status/1968561873382686860?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 18, 2025</a></p></blockquote><p>Gandhi had on September 1 -- at the concluding event of his Voter Adhikar Yatra &ndash; said that his party would come out with a "hydrogen bomb" of revelations about "vote chori" and after that Prime Minister <a href="https://www.moneycontrol.com/topic/narendra-modi/">Narendra Modi</a> will not be able to show his face to the country.</p><p>However, in his conference today, the Congress leader said that this was not the "hydrogen bomb" of evidence and added that it would be revealed later.</p><p>Last month, Gandhi, citing data from the 2024 Lok Sabha polls, had claimed that over one lakh votes were "stolen" through manipulation in Mahadevapura assembly segment in Karnataka, and asserted that "vote chori" is an "atom bomb on our democracy". </p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:28:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businesstoday.in/personal-finance/real-estate/story/govt-takes-50-in-taxes-on-property-tata-realty-ceo-on-why-middle-class-india-cant-afford-homes-494305-2025-09-17</link><title>'Govt takes 50% in taxes on property': Tata Realty CEO on why middle class India can't afford homes - BusinessToday (businesstoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><h2>Industry estimates confirm that, once land premiums, approvals, compliance, and infrastructure charges are added in, the government&rsquo;s share can climb to 30&ndash;50% of project costs in urban markets.</h2><div><p><img width="948" height="533" title="'Govt takes 50% in taxes on property': Tata Realty CEO on why middle-class India can&rsquo;t afford homes" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/businesstoday/images/story/202509/68ca31b5880d6-despite-tax-benefits-for-developers--dutt-said-the-mismatch-persists-capital-remains-expensive--lan-175735655-16x9.jpg?size=948:533" alt="'Govt takes 50% in taxes on property': Tata Realty CEO on why middle-class India can&rsquo;t afford homes"><span>Despite tax benefits for developers, Dutt said the mismatch persists: capital remains expensive, land is scarce, and urban transport and roads are inadequate. </span></p></div><div><div><p>The biggest obstacle to affordable housing in India isn&rsquo;t just developers or construction costs&mdash;it&rsquo;s the government itself, says Sanjay Dutt, MD &amp; CEO of Tata Realty. Speaking at the India Today South Conclave, he argued that nearly 50% of a property&rsquo;s cost goes straight to government taxes and charges, leaving little room for affordability.</p><div><h4>Related Articles</h4></div><p>&ldquo;Government only takes away nearly 50% through the taxes on the property. So they need to first fix that,&rdquo; Dutt said, pointing to the many hidden levies stacked on top of GST.</p><p>While GST on under-construction affordable housing is just 1%, and 5% on other residential properties, that&rsquo;s only the beginning. Buyers also pay stamp duty (5&ndash;8%), registration charges, municipal fees, development cesses, and premiums for extra floor area. Industry estimates confirm that, once land premiums, approvals, compliance, and infrastructure charges are added in, the government&rsquo;s share can climb to 30&ndash;50% of project costs in urban markets.</p><p>Dutt also flagged land as a crippling factor, often accounting for 50&ndash;85% of project costs in metros. He said government bodies like the Railways, Defense, Port Trusts, and municipal corporations hold vast tracts of unused land that could be unlocked for housing. &ldquo;They need to monetize and unlock those, make land cheaper for affordable housing, and then allow private developers to build under tax benefits,&rdquo; he urged.</p><p>But high taxes and expensive land aren&rsquo;t the only issues. Financing remains costly, and infrastructure often fails to keep pace. &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the point of going 50 km from the city and doing affordable homes when people can&rsquo;t commute?&rdquo; Dutt asked.</p><p>Despite tax benefits for developers, Dutt said the mismatch persists: capital remains expensive, land is scarce, and urban transport and roads are inadequate. The result is that affordable housing schemes stall or get pushed far from where people actually work.</p><p>With buyers shouldering nearly half their property cost in government-related fees and developers squeezed by high land and capital costs, Dutt&rsquo;s message was blunt: until land is unlocked and taxes rationalized, affordable housing will remain out of reach.</p></div><div><p><span>Published on: Sep 17, 2025 9:27 AM IST</span> </p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:15:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/</link><title>Perspective of a corporate job Indian Muslim, surviving India</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey everyone, I wanted to share something personal. A lot of people in the Hindu community might not really know what day-to-day life feels like for Muslims in India, especially those of us who are educated, working in MNCs, or just trying to get by. I’ll also touch on the lives of many who do self-employment or menial jobs.</p><p>For most Muslims, life is very middle class or lower middle class. It’s about making ends meet, sending kids to school, and hoping they get a better future. Just like most families across India. But neighborhoods with higher Muslim populations often face systematic neglect. Sewage systems remain unchanged for decades, overflowing every monsoon. Garbage collection is patchy at best, and residents often pay out of pocket to a garbage collection man. Power and utility management is overlooked. Slowly, a neighborhood becomes a slum — not because the people don’t care, but because the system doesn’t. And when residents complain, things rarely move once it’s tagged as a “Muslim area.”</p><p>Then comes college. An average Muslim student, just 18, wants nothing more than education and a chance to uplift his family. Instead, he hears taunts: <em>“jihadi,”</em> &quot;university ko bomb se uda de, sab pass ho jayenge&quot; <em>“bomb the university and we’ll all pass,”</em> &quot;tumhe to ISIS join karna tha na, yahan kya kar rahe ho&quot; <em>“why aren’t you joining ISIS?”</em> No matter how hard he tries to prove himself, in everyone&#39;s eyes he&#39;s already a terrorist/anti national, a man who can never really assimilate into the community.</p><p>If he pushes through and lands interviews, sometimes offers vanish once the recruiter or interviewer gets to know that the candidate is a muslim. Even when he gets the job, that’s not the end. Some seniors or colleagues throw underhanded or double meaning taunts and remarks or make the environment hostile. You can’t always report it either — because you risk losing the job and starting the discrimanatory process all over again. So you keep your head down, swallow the insults, and try to move on. Not all is bad though, some colleagues are wonderful and supportive — but it hurts when even they go silent when remarks on you get thrown around. You wish someone sided with you but nobody really does. So you have to take the insults and ignore it.</p><p>Then comes housing. Landlords reject you outright. Some do it subtly (<em>“only vegetarians allowed”</em>), others say it plainly. The ones who do agree often hike the rent 20–30%. Which leaves many Muslims stuck in the same neglected neighbourhoods they wanted to escape through education and jobs. Like a perpetual cycle</p><p>And when projects like the Halal Housing community in Mumbai are launched to give Muslims dignity and a cleaner environment, opposition rises instantly. It honestly feels like <em>“jeene bhi nahi denge, marne bhi nahi denge.”</em></p><p>From education, to work, to housing — each step forward pulls you back. That’s the survival of the common Muslim man in India. Not a threat. Not an enemy. Just someone trying to live, in the shadow of a hate-driven separatist environment created by the BJP.</p><p>Me and you — we’re not that different. We both want stability, dignity, and safety. So ask yourself: would you still believe that Muslims are a threat to this nation if you lived this life? Would you live a happy life in you were in my shoes and be proud that you were born in India ?</p><p>This isn’t a rant. It’s a perspective. An attempt to open a window into a life many don’t see.</p><p>Signing off. Take care.</p><p>*Since a lot of people are saying &quot;AI Slop/Chatgpt content&quot;, My actual passage was incredibly lengthy due to it being a lot more more heartfelt and emotional. I used Chatgpt to trim down the post for reddit because people usually scroll away when they see an incredibly long post.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:58:30 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
