<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=ObsidianMD&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/ObsidianMD</title><description>Hot posts in /r/ObsidianMD (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:51:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2mz3dr-styles-communityIcon_l538j35ftd3b1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/ObsidianMD</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://i.redd.it/6yogygnzvhpf1.png</link><title>current personal vault homepage (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nico1r/current_personal_vault_homepage/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nico1r/current_personal_vault_homepage/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nico1r/current_personal_vault_homepage/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/6yogygnzvhpf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:53:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/ky1ul4gu7epf1</link><title>Templater makes my life so much easier (V2) (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhyw7u/templater_makes_my_life_so_much_easier_v2/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhyw7u/templater_makes_my_life_so_much_easier_v2/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhyw7u/templater_makes_my_life_so_much_easier_v2/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><strong>Hi All!</strong></p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1mc2zd5/templater_makes_my_life_so_much_easier">I made a post about 2 months ago</a> sharing my personal monthly todo <a href="https://github.com/SilentVoid13/Templater">templater</a> template for public use. I hope some people got some use out of it!</p><p>Today I decided to share my v2 of that templater template with added features including:</p><ul><li>Improved outline navigation formats (much easier to navigate on mobile with live preview active, while on the note just swipe left and choose the outline menu to enter the outline panel)</li><li>Importance based tasks highlights</li><li>Custom dashboard callouts</li><li>Weekly log reference reviews</li><li>Built in frontmatter</li><li>and more..</li></ul><p><strong>The Source Code:</strong></p><p><a href="https://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/main/Templater_Todo_v2">Templater - Monthly Todo v2</a></p><p><a href="http://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/main/Templater_Todo_v2_custom_callouts">Monthly Todo v2 Custom CSS callouts</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/245cc4ef434a3c6d178c52b8356d0c09519ee7ae/Templater_Todo_v2_dailyorweeklymove">Monthly Todo v2 Daily and Weekly Note Auto Move</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/245cc4ef434a3c6d178c52b8356d0c09519ee7ae/Templater_Todo_v2_weekly_note_tem">Monthly Todo v2 Weekly Note Template</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/e5b19271c8a926486a1632e91884d8d789961330/Templater_Todo_v2_BillsPaid_Table">Monthly Todo v2 BillsPaid Table</a></p><p><strong>Additional Details:</strong></p><ul><li>You have to add the custom css callouts, to your Settings -&gt; Appearance -&gt; CSS snippets, in order to get the correct icons and colors. I added a kanban one that isn&#39;t featured in the example video, as well as a way to call a callout with only the icon (check out the code above to check that out). Feel free to change the CSS callout colors or icons if you want. All icons come from <a href="https://lucide.dev/">https://lucide.dev/</a> .</li><li>This template uses the calendar plugin [ obsidian://show-plugin?id=calendar ] to generate weekly notes with a template - <a href="https://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/eea5151209eb200936d87a60e81efa131a1ad6b2/CalendarPluginSetup.png">My Calendar Plugin Settings</a> . To get the weekly template to apply to the weekly note, you must select it from the calendar plugin - clicking create note from the reference wont apply the template.</li><li>I haven&#39;t set up templater automation for the bills paid table, you&#39;ll have to edit that note yourself</li><li>I was having some issues with Daily and Weekly notes ending up in my base directory when generating them so I added a templater auto move script to the &quot;Folder Templates&quot; in the Templater Settings. <a href="https://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/main/TemplaterFolderAuto.png">My Templater Settings</a> (make sure to turn on &quot;Trigger Templater on new file creation&quot;). The code for this is above (you&#39;ll have to edit the code for the correct daily and weekly note folder destinations)</li><li>Besides the importance based highlights for every days tasks, &quot;Happenings&quot; are meant for anything else that happened during your day that needs context. You could add that to your daily note but this helped my personal flow.</li><li>Every Callout is minimized by default - I found this beneficial for most callouts, especially when referencing long daily notes (also for privacy), but if you want to expand one by default simple change the &quot;-&quot; to &quot;+&quot; in the callout like &quot;<code>&gt;[!abstract]-</code>&quot; to &quot;<code>&gt;[!abstract]+</code>&quot; .</li><li>(Since someone asked) Theme: <a href="https://github.com/Akifyss/obsidian-border">Border</a> w/ custom styles via &quot;<a href="https://github.com/mgmeyers/obsidian-style-settings">Style Settings</a>&quot; plugin. <a href="https://github.com/patricksthannon/Obisidian_Templates/blob/main/Obsidian_StyleSettings_Export">My Style Settings Plugin Export.</a> I only use the dark theme so the light them styles might be a little wonky. </li></ul><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> I probably didn&#39;t cover everything but I hope it helps some folks with monthly task organization!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/ky1ul4gu7epf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760638919%2CZDZlMGY5MGY3YzllMGVlNzc1MWExYjA1ZGEyYjYzMjk1M2Y0N2VkYTgzODdkZDZlYmNiMTM5NWE3YjFlZmU2Nw%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='972' height='720'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:05:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1nhrcp2</link><title>Cupertino 2 is beautiful, delightful, and familiar across your devices. (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhrcp2/cupertino_2_is_beautiful_delightful_and_familiar/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhrcp2/cupertino_2_is_beautiful_delightful_and_familiar/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhrcp2/cupertino_2_is_beautiful_delightful_and_familiar/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/1xky6wwtzcpf1.png?width=1920&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=a9ef2d5e05dfbb1829ed6f7f2e5dad236b0cedfe" height="1080" width="1920" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/uy3w7vwtzcpf1.png?width=1920&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d86cf00f5ad26be580802bce797c2c080d893048" height="1080" width="1920" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/re3qhwwtzcpf1.png?width=1920&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d1f7b250ae94e9938ebd8a446e294b618b6c2b8c" height="1080" width="1920" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/00hw9vwtzcpf1.png?width=1920&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=e7d2f927a3a2fc9d763060b9dae96b7934b1aa46" height="1080" width="1920" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 22:26:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/ajqh2oz1hcpf1.png</link><title>Notebook Navigator is now available! Meet your new Obsidian interface! (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhojyi/notebook_navigator_is_now_available_meet_your_new/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhojyi/notebook_navigator_is_now_available_meet_your_new/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nhojyi/notebook_navigator_is_now_available_meet_your_new/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><em>The speed of Apple Notes. The beauty of Bear. The productivity of Evernote. The extensibility of Obsidian.</em></p><p>After countless hours of work and huge amounts of help from the fantastic Obsidian community ❤️, <strong>Notebook Navigator</strong> is now available for download in the <strong>Obsidian Community Plugin</strong> list!</p><p><strong>Notebook Navigator</strong> is a <strong>user interface replacement</strong> that transforms Obsidian into what can best be described as a mashup of all the best features from <strong>Apple Notes</strong>, <strong>Bear</strong> and <strong>Evernote</strong> but with <strong>tons</strong> of new productivity features that those older applications miss!</p><p><strong>Want to work 100% with tags?</strong> You got it. You have favorite tags, hidden tags, hierarchical tag trees, tag icons, tag colors, quick commands to add and remove tags, drag-to-tag, and so much more, such as the unique <strong>clickable tags</strong> displayed next to each file name. <strong>Show tags on top</strong>, make it your default interface!</p><p><strong>Love folders?</strong> You got it too. You have folder notes, folder icons, folder colors, thumbnail previews, drag-and-drop, quick actions on hover, quick search, show files from subfolders, excluded folders, custom sort orders, custom appearances for each folder, pinned notes, middle-click to open note in new tab, and so much more!</p><p>Do you use <strong>Dataview</strong> or <strong>Templater</strong>? Or do you <strong>develop plugins</strong>? Notebook Navigator has a <strong>comprehensive API</strong> that allows you to retrieve the user&#39;s selected folder, react to navigation changes with event listeners, and pin files - opening up possibilities that Obsidian&#39;s standard API doesn&#39;t provide. Full documentation included!</p><p>Full <strong>theme</strong> and <strong>Style Settings</strong> support! All colors and visual styles are available in the <strong>Style Settings</strong> plugin so you can make Notebook Navigator look and feel just the way you like it! Complete CSS documentation included!</p><p>There is so much work behind this plugin that it is actually difficult just to write down all the features. Did I mention that it’s also super optimized for mobile devices including all phones and tablets? And available in six languages, including RTL! ノート管理の新時代が始まります！让你的笔记焕然一新！</p><p><strong>Notebook Navigator is FREE and open source!</strong></p><p><a href="https://notebooknavigator.com/">https://notebooknavigator.com/</a></p><p>Try it out and let me know if you love using it as much as I do!</p><p><strong>Under the hood</strong>, Notebook Navigator is built for speed. It uses <strong>React</strong> with <strong>TanStack Virtual</strong> to deliver smooth scrolling even with 100,000+ notes. A dual-layer cache system (IndexedDB + RAM cache) provides instant metadata access for all files. It’s touch-optimized, mobile-friendly, and written in clean, type-safe TypeScript with zero ESLint warnings across 35,000 lines of code.</p><p><strong>About myself.</strong> I’m Johan Sanneblad, have a PhD in software development, and have the past decades created over 100 apps and services together with companies like Apple, Electronic Arts, Google, Lego, Microsoft, SKF, Volvo Cars, Yamaha and many others. I love creating small details in software applications and making applications that appear simple but have lots of thoughtful logic under the hood. I use Obsidian every day for my weekly AI newsletter Tech Insights and plan to support and develop <strong>Notebook Navigator</strong> as long as there are people using it. Notebook Navigator is my third Obsidian plugin, I have also developed <strong>Featured Image</strong> and <strong>Pixel Perfect Image</strong>.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/ajqh2oz1hcpf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 20:42:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1nh3izx</link><title>Bases is absolutely awesome for tracking games! (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nh3izx/bases_is_absolutely_awesome_for_tracking_games/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nh3izx/bases_is_absolutely_awesome_for_tracking_games/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nh3izx/bases_is_absolutely_awesome_for_tracking_games/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>For movies, I just use IMDb - rate it, maybe write a few thoughts, and I’m done. Same with books on Goodreads: rate it, maybe a short review, done. But for games, I need some more features. I like to make notes, add screenshots, artworks, guides, promo material, trailers or manuals from older games.</p><p>Obsidian absolutely nails this. I can basically build my own tracking site. I used to organize everything in a spreadsheet, but this looks so much nicer and is way more dynamic. I have three Bases for games: <em>Beaten</em>, <em>Playing</em>, and <em>Want to Play</em>.</p><p>With the game search plugin they automatically move to <em>Want to Play</em>. I just set the difficulty property (e.g., normal, hard…) when I start playing. It automatically moves into <em>Playing</em>, and once I beat it, I add the beaten date - it moves into <em>Beaten</em>. Seriously, such an awesome feature.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/91t2glko77pf1.png?width=1919&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=0d03ef5dfe3a01304ab3eb51c9d1e1408e612fd8" height="1079" width="1919" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/ghlp54jq77pf1.png?width=1919&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=06b0022e68b45cc45edade12a1ca47c52592e228" height="1079" width="1919" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/k8v949as77pf1.png?width=1919&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c9fa973f7f18488c06131065de9a88eb43b145c2" height="1079" width="1919" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 03:00:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://youtu.be/4xcEc4_qxJs</link><title>Finally a plugin that makes the graph useful! (youtu.be)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nh1yyh/finally_a_plugin_that_makes_the_graph_useful/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nh1yyh/finally_a_plugin_that_makes_the_graph_useful/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nh1yyh/finally_a_plugin_that_makes_the_graph_useful/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Found this plugin a couple of weeks ago but I didn&#39;t get to test it until a few days ago and lemme tell ya, it finally made me enable back the graph core plugin. (all that you need to know is said on the two videos in the creator&#39;s channel, but here&#39;s what I like personally that makes the graph useful for me, just thought spitting so if u wanna, feel free to skip it and go to the showcase video)</p><p>How it comes without the plugin, the graph is really only useful-ish as the local graph, and as a global graph, to find orphan notes. when I found about obsidian some years ago, the graph was the gimmick that made me try it and I expected it to be able to see at a glance, as redundant as it is, graphically, what a note was about, not only by title but contextually, and this plugin adds so much context... </p><p>The most basic stuff, you now can change the shape of nodes, and display images from the note via embedded inside the note or frontmatter(or if it&#39;s an attachment node, itself), or emojis, also has iconize/iconic compat.Then you can see color coded bars around the node for the tags it has, not only one color like the basic graph.Also if you have links inside properties in the note, it will show as a connection type, and you can display multiple connection types! Other plugins do that but in a really cumbersome or opinionated way like the breadcrumbs plugin i think was called, it might work for some people but imo this is way more native feeling. </p><p>Finally on what I use, is folder groups, they are like canvas groups, but in the graph based on your folders, it makes the folders feel so much more integrated! On the base graph you can do one color coding on the node itself and that&#39;s it, here every obsidian organization feature is clearly expressed in it&#39;s own way, and everything is modular, configurable and toggleable based on profiles (more on that in the showcase, I only use one profile so nothing much to say about that)Everything can be color coded with customizable color palettes, and although the dev says it can be slow, so far on my 200 notes vault it&#39;s going pretty smoothly. it&#39;s not big, but by default the plugin is disabled if u have more than 20 nodes displayed, soo-</p><p>With more to say, but fearing this is getting too long lol, I want this plugin to get some love so the dev can keep working on it and see it grow into the community, give it a try and comment if u see the potential too, or if u already tried it and what use-case do you have for it, wanna hear your thoughts on this</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><iframe width="356" height="200" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4xcEc4_qxJs?feature=oembed&enablejsapi=1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Obsidian - Extended Graph - 7 Examples"></iframe></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 01:58:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1ngp5rz</link><title>Here's a formula that can count how many days remained untill birthday (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngp5rz/heres_a_formula_that_can_count_how_many_days/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngp5rz/heres_a_formula_that_can_count_how_many_days/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngp5rz/heres_a_formula_that_can_count_how_many_days/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><pre><code>((number(  date(today().format(&quot;YYYY&quot;) + &quot;-&quot; + Birthday.format(&quot;MM-DD&quot;)) +  if(date(today().format(&quot;YYYY&quot;) + &quot;-&quot; + Birthday.format(&quot;MM-DD&quot;)) &lt; today(), &quot;1y&quot;, &quot;0y&quot;)) - number(today())) / 86400000).round()</code></pre></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/7z0jcdj6b4pf1.png?width=487&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1c910b9a0057de690dc92097d2f0cd729318a0b0" height="418" width="487" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/lovtni78b4pf1.png?width=505&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=71a72a57f4a865632919f58ffc9dcd909b7aa51d" height="379" width="505" /></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 17:14:11 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/t8paq3xnu1pf1</link><title>I was confused about what is bases so I made this i hop it help other as well. (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nggqy7/i_was_confused_about_what_is_bases_so_i_made_this/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nggqy7/i_was_confused_about_what_is_bases_so_i_made_this/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nggqy7/i_was_confused_about_what_is_bases_so_i_made_this/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/t8paq3xnu1pf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760638919%2CYTdkNDM0NjJjYzc5NTY1NjA3OTE1ZmE3NTRhNmZkYmJhNjAyZTJkYjJjNGU4NTA0N2Y5MGJjZWJhMzFmMTljYw%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1280' height='720'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 08:58:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/n3hye3zbl1pf1.png</link><title>Thanks Obsidian for Helping Me Pass the AWS Exam (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngfunk/thanks_obsidian_for_helping_me_pass_the_aws_exam/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngfunk/thanks_obsidian_for_helping_me_pass_the_aws_exam/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngfunk/thanks_obsidian_for_helping_me_pass_the_aws_exam/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>When I first studied AWS, it was so overwhelming. There are so many AWS services, but thanks to the Graph View and bi-directional backlinks, they gave me a high-level overview of all the services and how they connect to each other.  I could simply click a link to instantly navigate to that note. Plus, the markdown format is such a natural fit for me with a low learning curve. I can add different code blocks or mermaid diagrams to my notes. Seeing the growth of my note network also gives me a sense of fulfillment!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/n3hye3zbl1pf1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 08:11:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://v.redd.it/3xk419szv0pf1</link><title>Been into obsidian for a while. Only recently occurred to me that I can make my notes tools too. Example: A plugin I made to send http requests to a listener in minecraft to handle redstone (Video)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngcxrc/been_into_obsidian_for_a_while_only_recently/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngcxrc/been_into_obsidian_for_a_while_only_recently/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ngcxrc/been_into_obsidian_for_a_while_only_recently/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='embedded-media'><video controls preload='auto' autoplay='false'><source src='https://v.redd.it/3xk419szv0pf1/HLSPlaylist.m3u8?a=1760638919%2CYTM2NjBkMjI0Zjk1YjAzNzAxNGFjZTBiNTE1NzQzN2NiZWI1OTRiMzRhNzIyYjcwNTM3ZjkxODg0ZDQ2NjBlNQ%3D%3D&amp;v=1&amp;f=sd' type='video/mp4' width='1920' height='1080'><img src='' alt='' /></video></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 05:44:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/gyluon0z5zof1.png</link><title>Book cards since everyone is doing them (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ng4xyy/book_cards_since_everyone_is_doing_them/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ng4xyy/book_cards_since_everyone_is_doing_them/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1ng4xyy/book_cards_since_everyone_is_doing_them/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>i gave in since everyone else is doing them instead of hard linking like i did before bases. However, I have 400 books to go...sigh. the one time having a huge obsidian early on sucks. btw this my 3rd book tracker lol</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/gyluon0z5zof1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 23:58:00 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/vwev6lne4uof1.png</link><title>Oh my god, it's done. An entire book written in Obsidian 119k words (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nfks80/oh_my_god_its_done_an_entire_book_written_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nfks80/oh_my_god_its_done_an_entire_book_written_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/ObsidianMD/comments/1nfks80/oh_my_god_its_done_an_entire_book_written_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/vwev6lne4uof1.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 06:57:59 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
