<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 08:43:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/</link><title>INDIANS are the most racist in the entire world and that too towards INDIANS!!!!!!!!!!! Especially living outside India!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>So this incident happened today.</p><p>I run a very small IT agency usually giving web development services. Recently I was talking to a US client to finalize a deal of $350. Everything was going good until the comes an Indian working at their company! </p><p>I politely smiled and was happy to see Indian. But things changed the moment he opened his mouth and started vomiting!!!!!!!!!</p><p>He started asking questions completely unrelated to the work like my surname, what my father do, why are you charging so much and why is your surname *** , are you running office from home!!!!!</p><p>I WANT TO ASK YOU NRIs!!!!! </p><p>WHAT THE FUCK DO YOU THINK YOU ARE!!!!!!! </p><p>WHY THE FUCK ARE YOU BEING SO RACIST TOWARDS PEOPLE OF YOUR OWN COUNTRY!!!!!!!!!!! </p><p>If I am running agency from India, that doesnt mean I cant go to US and work. Its because of my personal choice!! </p><p>WHO THE FUCK GIVE YOU RIGHT TO ASK SUCH CASTIEST QUESTIONS and BEING so JUDGEMENTAL!!!!!!!</p><p>True fact - I have dealt with NRIs , I dont understand why they have so much attitude and why the fuck they always try to demean other INDIANS!!!!!!!!! </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Went to USA for the first time in 2000 and went to visit a family friend who had moved there 4 years ago    He showed me around San Francisco and his tone was as if he was the one who built it from scratch. Condescending as hell.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/nf51ncq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Working under an Indian boss outside India, is a nightmare in 99% of the cases. The moment they know they’re in power and have the upper hand, they change into the most shrewd humans. I hear ya man.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/nf54t7x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In such situations, my advise is to charge the &quot;personal inconvenience fee&quot; (not literally billed as that) in your invoice for your troubles. This is a business transaction. You will face many good as well as bad people and you always have a choice to work or not work with them. I have seen an instance similar to yours personally once in my life. I could be rattled, but I just found a way to make folks pay for this inconvenience. It&#39;s smarter than bothering your brain. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/nf51iz6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As NRI, agree 100%. </p><p>Because there is nothing called Indian. There is no unified identity with mutual respect and integrity. It’s all “You Reddy, Patel ..my caste…my tribe, let’s earn some money together”</p><p>Surname is the biggest clue to measure someone in the caste-and-Varna hierarchy. And that’s tendency is more among NRIs than hard-working cross section of people from Mainland India.</p><p>In fact, caste-and-mercantile (profit at any cost) networks have been rewired to sustain Brit imperialism, fully knowing Brits were exploiting country. Caste-and-mercantile networks didn’t actually care about the country (as there was never an unified identity) and colluded with Brits, at every level.</p><p>C.A. Bayly – Indian Society and the Making of the British Empire: Richly detailed on how Indian pre-colonial networks (baniya credit, caste alliances, princely states) were re-wired to sustain Company and Crown rule.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/nf53t2s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Back in my 20s, I used to work in the development sector and a lot of my work was based in rural areas in north and west India. The amount of times I got asked my surname, what my father does and even outright my caste was insane. I was privileged enough to grow up not knowing or caring about my caste but I finally ended up asking my mom at 24 what I am because of all the incessant questions. </p><p>It’s everyone bro. The stupid thing is, people should leave this mentality behind once they leave the country but they keep holding on to it so much that now companies like Google have had to introduce anti caste discrimination employee guidelines. Such a sad state of affairs.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/nf54eio/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Living in the US for the last 8 years. Most of the judgmental, skewed attitude personalities I see here are..you guessed it right, NRIs. That includes restaurant workers in an Indian restaurant in the US. The number of nice NRIs I met is very, very few. Like I can count on one hand.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/nf54h9h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It is these NRIs that moved to the US during the initial IT boom, and advised their American colleagues to underpay remote Indian workers in USD because of the purchasing power. It&#39;s like they have a god complex</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlf01k/indians_are_the_most_racist_in_the_entire_world/nf53wp4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 02:16:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newsweek.com/h1-b-visa-program-fee-trump-requirements-2132718</link><title>Trump To Introduce $100k Fee For H-1B Visas: Report (newsweek.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Tech companies will just straight up offshore those jobs</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/nf4g537/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>more jobs offshored!! Yay!! I just doubt if they can actually do it and stick it at least for an year.</p><p>Edit: grammar</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/nf4ifuv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hot damn! I&#39;m grabbing my popcorn and getting ready for the inevitable lawsuits that will follow. I don&#39;t even think Trump himself can mandate this, it will have to follow the rulemaking process. Or maybe even require Congressional approval. This is just year 1 folks, God knows what else is in store 😢</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/nf4fcxe/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tech CEOs will not allow it</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/nf4fkq1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Wild shit.. Costs $8500 AUD for an Australian permanent residency. $100k USD for a temp visa?!!?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/nf4wext/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s his wet dream but can never come true. Let alone companies, Universities will kill it or will go bust if this were to happen</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/nf4hjmy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I am surprised with the amount of US tech jobs after COVID. I thought everything would get offshored.</p><p>By the way, this won&#39;t pass and if passes, will distort the economy.</p><p>Anyway chaotic back and forth and &quot;Lobbying&quot; will take place.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nlcg1f/trump_to_introduce_100k_fee_for_h1b_visas_report/nf5i9ni/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:36:28 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/delhi-bmw-crash-van-driver-victim-hopital-vehicle-seized-2788454-2025-09-17</link><title>Van seized, income hit: Man who rushed Delhi BMW crash victim to hospital (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>He said while several bystanders were making videos, he stopped his loading van and helped the four injured -- Deputy Secretary in the Department of Economic Affairs Navjot Singh, his wife, and the BMW occupants -- reach a hospital.</p><p>&quot;I stopped my vehicle to help because people were injured and in serious condition. An ambulance was standing there too. People requested the ambulance driver, but I quickly shifted them into my van so they could get treatment on time,&quot; Gulfam told PTI over a phone call.</p><p>&quot;Since Sunday, my vehicle has been parked at a police station as part of the investigation. Teams are taking samples from my vehicle, and every time they tell me that it will be released in a day or two. I am being called to the police station regularly,&quot; he further claimed.</p></blockquote></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/nf0sf1h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Stupid system that prevents people from helping others because they know they will get in trouble one way or another if they meddle in.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/nf0w96g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And this is why no one helps victims or have a civic sense..</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/nf0vd0u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>No good deed goes unpunished</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/nf0xzli/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Ours is the worst country in the planet to help anyone! Let&#39;s be clear....</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/nf10pwp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Indian Bureaucracy is Corrupt and Inefficient from TOP To BOTTOM.</p><p>Need to rebuild the Bureaucracy from Scratch.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/nf0xwru/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Forget others, I doubt they have sympathy for others. But why can’t they put themselves in that situation? imagine if they or their loved ones were in an accident and no one stepped in to help. imagine the emotions of knowing they could have been saved if only someone had rushed them to the hospital.</p><p>Why these corrupt officers never face any karma, no idea.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nkuzyx/van_seized_income_hit_man_who_rushed_delhi_bmw/nf10k30/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:51:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businesstoday.in/india/story/trying-to-create-bangladesh-nepal-like-situation-in-india-bjps-big-claim-after-rahul-gandhi-drops-hydrogen-bomb-494623-2025-09-18</link><title>'Trying to create Bangladesh, Nepal-like situation in India': BJP's big claim after Rahul Gandhi drops 'hydrogen bomb' (businesstoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Why is Anurag Thakur still talking like he has any credibility left? 😂</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/nevru93/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You know BJP is guilty as sin and lying through their teeth when Anurag Thakur, the very same guy who made his vote fraud allegations a month ago, now accuses others of undermining democracy </p><p>Has the BJP apologised for their allegations if they claim there is no fraud ??</p><p>Unfortunately most people in this country do not have the ability to think logically</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/nevpq5m/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So, they are indirectly accepting that they are corrupted fascist dictators ?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/nevo5hr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Question: When will Modi start giving press conferences?</p><p>Answer: When he becomes leader of the Opposition.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/nevtc5o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&#39;BJP take accountability for anything&#39; challenge - Impossible</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/nevpoqq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>At this point, if anyone doubts that eci is complicit with govt and very incompetent at that, they aren’t blind, just pretending to be blind.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/nevyfv6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah right. They cant answer the questions. They definitely are scared of nepal.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk78il/trying_to_create_bangladesh_nepallike_situation/nevmz7d/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:12:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/</link><title>To anyone wondering why Rahul Gandhi is not taking the Vote Chori allegation to Supreme Court here is why</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>These two examples show why taking a matter to the Supreme Court is a no-win situation.</p><p><strong>Example 1: The Vantara Verdict</strong><br/>Two written applications were submitted to the courts, alleging that Vantara was unlawfully acquiring animals and mistreating them in captivity. In its verdict, however, <strong><em>&quot;the Supreme Court stated that the SIT’s “exhaustive investigation” found no violation of the law and asserted that it would not allow tarnishing news reports about the rescue park in Jamnagar, Gujarat&quot;</em></strong>. This decision effectively gave Vantara a clean chit and brought the matter to a definitive close. This decision was perceived by the public as favoring the powerful. [<em>No disrespect to the Rescue park folks and the Supreme Court here this is just my opinion and not a comment on your working or integrity</em>]</p><p><strong>Example 2: The Election CCTV Hearing</strong><br/>In another case, the Haryana and Punjab High Court directed the Election Commission to provide CCTV footage related to the Haryana Assembly elections, following a petition by counsel Mehmood Pracha. Within three days, the government amended the law to prevent public access to electronic documents and recordings connected to elections, justifying the change as a way to “ <em>preventing the misuse of electronic election records. This includes CCTV camera and webcasting footage, as well as video recordings of candidates, during the election process.&quot;</em> Doubling down on this , the retention period for election CCTV footage was also shortened—from 1year to just 45 days, after which the recordings would be deleted. This maneuver effectively rendered the High Court’s verdict meaningless.</p><p>Taken together, these examples suggest that even if Rahul Gandhi were to win his case in the Supreme Court, the government could simply introduce new legislation to block the release of critical data. And if he were to lose, public perception might lean toward suspicion of foul play [ <em>Again, no disrespect is intended toward the Supreme Court—I deeply appreciate its strong stance on issues like the electoral bonds case</em>] .It would also effectively end any further discussion on the matter once the Supreme Court has delivered its judgment.</p><p>As Rahul Gandhi himself emphasized during his press conference, he will just present the facts, and it will ultimately be up to the public and the country’s youth to decide what to do next.</p><p>P.S. I did use ChatGPT to make the post more understandable</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Do you watch meghnerd channel ?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/nevj711/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In example 1) Closed Envelope of the Report was given. Like wtf is this Justice</p><p><a href="https://thewire.in/environment/no-foul-play-animal-acquisitions-as-per-law-supreme-court-gives-vantara-clean-chit-after-sit-report">https://thewire.in/environment/no-foul-play-animal-acquisitions-as-per-law-supreme-court-gives-vantara-clean-chit-after-sit-report</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/nevcuu5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/jcjosyc31zpf1.png?width=1032&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=90dbd9beee65980f54b1cb72fc52b16e7099aac1">https://preview.redd.it/jcjosyc31zpf1.png?width=1032&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=90dbd9beee65980f54b1cb72fc52b16e7099aac1</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/nexrzyl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Supreme Court is a joke. They have sold their spines long ago. They are just for their own interest. They care a a $hit about people. RG is correct to avoid court route. I suspect some Bhakta NGO will go in SC against EC via a dummy petition citing same allegations only to get rejected, thereby giving victory to BJP</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/newlb24/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Also the RTI was made weak by BJP govt.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/nevs35v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The decline started long back. </p><p>The farm bills were passed through a voice vote. The petitions challenging this were never heard by the Supreme Court. </p><p>The changes to UIDAI Act were made by labeling it as a money bill, thus restricting the powers of Rajya Sabha. The petitions challenging this were bunched with others, and no decision taken on this aspect.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/nevg6yv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We all will continue with our fake outrage here on Reddit. Hum logon ki g**nd mein dum nahi hai raste par aane ka.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk5qu9/to_anyone_wondering_why_rahul_gandhi_is_not/ney32zd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:01:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/international/trump-names-afghanistan-india-china-pakistan-among-major-drug-transit-illicit-drug-producing-countries/article70064066.ece</link><title>Trump names Afghanistan, India, China, Pakistan among major drug transit, illicit drug producing countries (thehindu.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Anything breathes on one side of the planet - white man says “omg this is threatening me” - start bombing</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/neumfxe/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Didn&#39;t know drug sector in india is so big</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/neuml26/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Damn dude at least let me get some of these drugs. I even received a call from the Mumbai Narcotics crime division multiple times and they told me a parcel being sent to me from foreign countries has been intercepted, I asked them to split the drugs 50-50 and they said no! So any help procuring these drugs would be greatly appreciated.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/neuu0hr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;President Donald Trump has named China, Afghanistan, India and Pakistan among 23 major drug transit or major illicit drug producing countries, saying that by manufacturing and trafficking illicit drugs and precursor chemicals, these nations are threatening the safety of the U.S. and its citizens.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/neum7d8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>the irreparable damage this mf is doing to his country&#39;s reputation. kinda feel bad for them but they elected him lmao</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/neuolkk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Adani port?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/neumnko/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They are targeting the pharma industry because of affordable drug options.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk23uw/trump_names_afghanistan_india_china_pakistan/neuqxan/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:16:20 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.moneycontrol.com/news/india/rahul-gandhi-intensifies-vote-chori-attack-presents-proof-against-cec-gyanesh-kumar-protecting-destroyers-of-democracy-13556143.html</link><title>Rahul Gandhi intensifies 'vote chori' attack, presents 'proof' against CEC Gyanesh Kumar: 'Protecting destroyers of democracy' (moneycontrol.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The fact that the EC ignored requests from the CID about such a serious matter, and decided to shield the accused is insane to think of.</p><p>The highest of democratic processes being undermined by the very institute that is supposed to protect it is extremely serious for our country</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/neuc4bt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m sorry but this is of no use if our fellow countrymen are already brainwashed to think whatever Rahul Gandhi says is false. Vote chori aside, a huge percentage of our population actually does support BJP and they are very vocal. This will also be ignored. I have no hope for this country tbh.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/neugf14/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>this is very sophisticated operation, looks like we are doomed</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/neufq7h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>there is nothing that can convince a bjp supporter that this happened. If they&#39;re illiterate , they lack the capacity to understand this. If they&#39;re literate, they refuse to understand this.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/nex8o77/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Gyanesh in process of getting Malta citizenship.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/nev5vg3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s difficult if not impossible to open the eyes of the population blinded by religion and hate for other religions.I see in my social circle facts don&#39;t matter anymore.</p><p>A very unfortunate choice we are making as a nation, less blame to the BJP and more to the distracted population.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/neujigy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What do you mean &#39;protecting the destroyers&#39;? Gyanesh is himself the destroyer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nk0dv0/rahul_gandhi_intensifies_vote_chori_attack/neuumav/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 11:28:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businesstoday.in/personal-finance/real-estate/story/govt-takes-50-in-taxes-on-property-tata-realty-ceo-on-why-middle-class-india-cant-afford-homes-494305-2025-09-17</link><title>'Govt takes 50% in taxes on property': Tata Realty CEO on why middle class India can't afford homes - BusinessToday (businesstoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This is on top of the 30% income tax that we pay</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/netfhi8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Housing cost has gone up disproportionately to wages in the last 30 to 40 years</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/netc25i/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><em>The biggest obstacle to affordable housing in India isn’t just developers or construction costs—it’s the government itself, says Sanjay Dutt, MD &amp; CEO of Tata Realty. Speaking at the India Today South Conclave, he argued that nearly 50% of a property’s cost goes straight to government taxes and charges, leaving little room for affordability.</em></p><p><em>While GST on under-construction affordable housing is just 1%, and 5% on other residential properties, that’s only the beginning. Buyers also pay stamp duty (5–8%), registration charges, municipal fees, development cesses, and premiums for extra floor area. Industry estimates confirm that, once land premiums, approvals, compliance, and infrastructure charges are added in, the government’s share can climb to 30–50% of project costs in urban markets.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/netb9de/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>These mofo are selling you parking, destroying lakes . There crore rupee are built on sewers that flood in an hour of rain.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/netfbt8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sher pala hai 🦁, just compare wages to housing costs in 2000s vs today. Apparently “mehengai” is okay now according to chaddis. It’s basic economics!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/netg7tr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Property can be dirt cheap if you have the right contacts.</p><h1>Over 1,020 acres, mostly agricultural land, leased at ₹1 per year for Adani power project in Bihar</h1><p><a href="https://thekashmiriyat.co.uk/over-1020-acres-mostly-agricultural-land-leased-at-re-1-per-year-for-adani-power-project-in-bihar/?noamp=available#google_vignette">https://thekashmiriyat.co.uk/over-1020-acres-mostly-agricultural-land-leased-at-re-1-per-year-for-adani-power-project-in-bihar/?noamp=available#google_vignette</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/nethdk0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Rich people should not be allowed to own more than two houses. Houses are basic necessity and riches treat them as Investments.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njvmw1/govt_takes_50_in_taxes_on_property_tata_realty/netlnci/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:15:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/</link><title>Perspective of a corporate job Indian Muslim, surviving India</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey everyone, I wanted to share something personal. A lot of people in the Hindu community might not really know what day-to-day life feels like for Muslims in India, especially those of us who are educated, working in MNCs, or just trying to get by. I’ll also touch on the lives of many who do self-employment or menial jobs.</p><p>For most Muslims, life is very middle class or lower middle class. It’s about making ends meet, sending kids to school, and hoping they get a better future. Just like most families across India. But neighborhoods with higher Muslim populations often face systematic neglect. Sewage systems remain unchanged for decades, overflowing every monsoon. Garbage collection is patchy at best, and residents often pay out of pocket to a garbage collection man. Power and utility management is overlooked. Slowly, a neighborhood becomes a slum — not because the people don’t care, but because the system doesn’t. And when residents complain, things rarely move once it’s tagged as a “Muslim area.”</p><p>Then comes college. An average Muslim student, just 18, wants nothing more than education and a chance to uplift his family. Instead, he hears taunts: <em>“jihadi,”</em> &quot;university ko bomb se uda de, sab pass ho jayenge&quot; <em>“bomb the university and we’ll all pass,”</em> &quot;tumhe to ISIS join karna tha na, yahan kya kar rahe ho&quot; <em>“why aren’t you joining ISIS?”</em> No matter how hard he tries to prove himself, in everyone&#39;s eyes he&#39;s already a terrorist/anti national, a man who can never really assimilate into the community.</p><p>If he pushes through and lands interviews, sometimes offers vanish once the recruiter or interviewer gets to know that the candidate is a muslim. Even when he gets the job, that’s not the end. Some seniors or colleagues throw underhanded or double meaning taunts and remarks or make the environment hostile. You can’t always report it either — because you risk losing the job and starting the discrimanatory process all over again. So you keep your head down, swallow the insults, and try to move on. Not all is bad though, some colleagues are wonderful and supportive — but it hurts when even they go silent when remarks on you get thrown around. You wish someone sided with you but nobody really does. So you have to take the insults and ignore it.</p><p>Then comes housing. Landlords reject you outright. Some do it subtly (<em>“only vegetarians allowed”</em>), others say it plainly. The ones who do agree often hike the rent 20–30%. Which leaves many Muslims stuck in the same neglected neighbourhoods they wanted to escape through education and jobs. Like a perpetual cycle</p><p>And when projects like the Halal Housing community in Mumbai are launched to give Muslims dignity and a cleaner environment, opposition rises instantly. It honestly feels like <em>“jeene bhi nahi denge, marne bhi nahi denge.”</em></p><p>From education, to work, to housing — each step forward pulls you back. That’s the survival of the common Muslim man in India. Not a threat. Not an enemy. Just someone trying to live, in the shadow of a hate-driven separatist environment created by the BJP.</p><p>Me and you — we’re not that different. We both want stability, dignity, and safety. So ask yourself: would you still believe that Muslims are a threat to this nation if you lived this life? Would you live a happy life in you were in my shoes and be proud that you were born in India ?</p><p>This isn’t a rant. It’s a perspective. An attempt to open a window into a life many don’t see.</p><p>Signing off. Take care.</p><p>*Since a lot of people are saying &quot;AI Slop/Chatgpt content&quot;, My actual passage was incredibly lengthy due to it being a lot more more heartfelt and emotional. I used Chatgpt to trim down the post for reddit because people usually scroll away when they see an incredibly long post.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I’m a Muslim doctor, while I’ve never ever gone through any of this.I do agree that I come from an upper middle class priviledged upbringing.I’ve never stayed in muslim neighbourhood. I’ve stayed in a mixed society with all religions.I’ve went to a private school where almost all my best friends were of different religion and never have I ever felt different.I’ve went to MBBS in a college where there were almost very less Muslims and I’ve worked in places which where run by Hindu missions but I’ve never felt like I was ostracised.On the other hand, I did work for a while in a Muslim hospital, it was run by Muslim charity, and I was time and again, told indirectly by Muslim colleagues, that a female should always wear an abaya or hijab if she’s a good Muslim.Approached for nikah, only because of looks.Given looks if I didn’t say assalamwalequm and instead said good morning.I don’t know about middle class and lower middle class issues, but the real issue with our community as a Muslim is, we just don’t want to get out of our cocoon. I’ve only met ONE decent Muslim man in my entire life till now. Other than that, all either would preach or try to dominate me.Mind you, I’m coming from Uttar Pradesh and I’ve worked in extreme rural areas also and never felt the so called divide from non Muslims, but always felt attacked by our own Muslim people for being different. I don’t drink or smoke. Or wear provocative clothes. I’m just another Muslim doctor who isn’t married yet, and working with normal clothes.Isn’t it so awful, that most of us, especially gen Z Muslims aren’t even able to find a partner because none of the Muslim men or women are sane even after studying a lot?I had a female surgeon, beautiful, amazing but forcibly gotten married to a maulvi sahab because well Deen is more important!all I want to say is, let us all first try to change our community. Our preachy nature, our inability to separate religion from work, normal life.We can be good Muslims without telling non Muslims that oh it’s only our religion that’s fine.Without telling them things.I’m a practicing Muslim, but unfortunately Islam isn’t the issue, Muslims are!Majority of Muslims are!I’ve had a Muslim roommate who wouldn’t even have laddu prasad and would tell me you don’t know it’s haraam what if they mix gaumutra, is this how you try to mix with another religion?There is a huge issue with our religion and it’s high time we change certain things.I’ve worked in UP, AP and many many states and cities and it’s the same everywhere.It’s high time we realize if we don’t change our obsession with our religion and our superiority complex nothing will change.I know I’ll get a lot of hate on this.But as a gen z indian muslim female, a doctor that’s literally my experience.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/nepu7t9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Been working in Mumbai corporate for 8 years, have never faced any discrimination based on my religion. Yes the finding house for rent part is true. Moved to Bangalore for 8 months and have faced all the things mentioned about negative comments and prejudices here. </p><p>For Mumbai, I never feel out of place or that I am not able to uplift myself or my family. We started in the slums and worked our way out of it and MORE. </p><p>We as a family are more than comfortable now, and have been helping people, not just muslims get out of poverty (mostly my father is). </p><p>About the cleanliness part, I have lived in Mumbai Muslim slums first 15 years of my life and let me tell you that Muslim slum areas are disgusting BECAUSE of Muslims. Thats it. Me and my family used to run cleanliness drives and try and clean the surroundings. To which we used to hear comments from the community and no support. </p><p>One time we brought the Kachra dabba closer to the chawl so people don’t throw garbage anywhere they want. And we planted plants everywhere people usually dump garbage. U know what happened? People started dumping garbage in the plants pots!!!!! Thats where I personally gave up and just moved out. </p><p>Calling Muslims out on cleanliness is important for other Muslims to do. Its naming and shaming. Which will make it better.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/netyjyt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yes I had a childhood friend, a Goan Muslim girl that I worked with for some years. Very nice person. I was friends with her husband too (also Goan Muslim) and later when we were in different cities I stayed over at their place a few times when I visited Pune. Some years back she got a good job offer in Mumbai. I can&#39;t begin to tell you the discrimination she faced just trying to find a safe clean place to live that was convenient for her job. In the end after less than a year she quit and moved back to Pune.</p><p>It was the first time I was aware of the blatant discrimination Muslims face. Very sad state of affairs. </p><p>Also to add - she and her husband have lived in other parts of India like Chennai, Bangalore, Hyderabad and Pune and I did not hear such stories about those places. Not saying that they did not face discrimination, maybe they did and just didn&#39;t mention, but yeah .. the Bombay stories were very sad and blatant.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/nepexaq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I actually got to know about the struggle and got empathy once i started studying in Uzbekistan with a majority muslim batch of students, mind you uzbekistan is a secular state and government does its best to control the role of religion, but people just directly ask you which country and then ask are you musalman  , and my friends answer yes and say for example im Abdul jabbar and their eyes glow , and i just respond with im not a muslim and it’s a weird forceful smile , and it’s almost as if why aren’t you a muslim , and there’s always talks about religion in class and my friends both from India and Pakistan debate about stuff and i just sit there and listen, that’s when i realised f::k is this how my muslim friends feel in india except generally people aren’t that direct with religion atleast in my place in south and obviously nobody asks you to become hindu but still kind of exclude you from conversations ig.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/nequos1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I have heard various versions of similar struggles across different age groups and different times in my life.</p><p>Takes a toll for sure. More power to you OP.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/nepfty7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Okay my honest question would be lets say we have owaisi representing old city in Hyderabad hes the mp here and old city is a muslim populated area and have you ever looked at old city’s condition like literally despite having a solid muslim representative old city is a shit hole in terms of infrastructure and everything my question is what exactly are muslims doing to solve this?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/nepmms9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Why not just practise Islam at home and keep it yourself then? No need to live and endure the discrimination? It’s about survival right?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1njd6gx/perspective_of_a_corporate_job_indian_muslim/nevwqha/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:58:30 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
