<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=selfhosted&amp;averagePostsPerDay=4&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/selfhosted</title><description>Hot posts in /r/selfhosted (roughly 4 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 22:56:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_32hch-styles-communityIcon_b2t5inv46z331-144x400.png</url><title>/r/selfhosted</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n9hx4a/campfire_the_selfhosted_group_chat_just_became/</link><title>Campfire (the self-hosted group chat) just became free and open source!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n9hx4a/campfire_the_selfhosted_group_chat_just_became/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n9hx4a/campfire_the_selfhosted_group_chat_just_became/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n9hx4a/campfire_the_selfhosted_group_chat_just_became/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hi!</p><p>DHH (co-founder of Basecamp) <a href="https://x.com/dhh/status/1963675999012552970">announced yesterday</a> that they&#39;re making their group chat software open source and free for everyone to use. This is fantastic news, especially considering this piece of software previously required a $299 payment just to access the codebase (far too expensive, in my opinion).</p><p>It looks like we now have another excellent <a href="https://openalternative.co/campfire">open source alternative to Slack and Microsoft Teams</a>, thanks to this move. I really hope more companies will follow this trend soon.</p><p>What are your thoughts?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 03:11:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n93ht2/selfhost_weekly_5_september_2025/</link><title>Self-Host Weekly (5 September 2025)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n93ht2/selfhost_weekly_5_september_2025/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n93ht2/selfhost_weekly_5_september_2025/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n93ht2/selfhost_weekly_5_september_2025/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Happy Friday, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a>! Linked below is the latest edition of <em>Self-Host Weekly</em>, a weekly newsletter recap of the latest activity in self-hosted software and content (published weekly but shared directly with this subreddit the first Friday of each month).</p><p>This week&#39;s features include:</p><ul><li>Responses to recent newsletter feedback</li><li>Commentary on this week&#39;s stories</li><li>Software updates and launches (emphasis on <em>launches</em> this week)</li><li>A spotlight on <a href="https://github.com/fccview/rwMarkable?ref=selfh.st">rwMarkable</a> -- a self-hosted checklist and to-do app (<a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/riofriz">u/riofriz</a>)</li><li>Other guides, videos, and content from the community</li></ul><p>Thanks, and as usual, feel free to reach out with feedback!</p><hr/><p><a href="https://selfh.st/weekly/2025-09-05/?ref=reddit">Self-Host Weekly (5 September 2025)</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:38:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8od9o/dockpeek_v158_lots_of_new_features_for_your/</link><title>Dockpeek v1.5.8 – lots of new features for your Docker dashboard!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8od9o/dockpeek_v158_lots_of_new_features_for_your/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8od9o/dockpeek_v158_lots_of_new_features_for_your/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8od9o/dockpeek_v158_lots_of_new_features_for_your/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><h1>Lots of Cool New Features!</h1><p>Hey everyone! Just wanted to share some exciting news for selfhosters 😏  – Dockpeek has gotten a bunch of new goodies lately.</p><p>For those who don’t know, <strong>Dockpeek is a lightweight web dashboard for Docker</strong> that gives you a clear overview of all your containers and their published ports. Its main goal is to provide easy access to your services through these ports, making it super handy for managing Docker locally or across multiple hosts. Here’s the repo: <a href="https://github.com/dockpeek/dockpeek#readme">dockpeek/dockpeek</a>.</p><p>A few highlights from the latest updates:</p><ul><li><strong>New container labels:</strong> You can now use labels like <code>dockpeek.https=9001,8090</code> to force selected ports to open in HTTPS mode, and <code>dockpeek.link=https://address</code> to turn container names into clickable links – super handy for apps behind a reverse proxy. The new <code>dockpeek.ports</code> label lets you manually define ports dockpeek should display as clickable URLs, which is especially useful for containers running with <code>--net=host</code> or on VPNs.</li><li><strong>Stack column &amp; filtering:</strong> The container table now shows a <em>Stack</em> column, so you can see which Docker Compose project each container belongs to.</li><li><strong>Improved search &amp; UI:</strong> The interface and search features have been polished, making it easier to find containers, navigate the dashboard, and interact with links. Small UI tweaks make everything cleaner and more intuitive.</li></ul><p>In short: Dockpeek is getting more flexible and easier to use. Configuring access to your services is simpler than ever – you can enforce HTTPS, add external links, or manually set ports, and the interface makes managing containers a breeze. Check it out and let me know what you think!</p><p>Repo: <a href="https://github.com/dockpeek/dockpeek">GitHub – dockpeek/dockpeek</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 04:04:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8ntzb/i_wired_up_an_ai_assistant_to_my_asterisk_server/</link><title>I wired up an AI assistant to my Asterisk server so I can literally call it from any phone</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8ntzb/i_wired_up_an_ai_assistant_to_my_asterisk_server/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8ntzb/i_wired_up_an_ai_assistant_to_my_asterisk_server/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8ntzb/i_wired_up_an_ai_assistant_to_my_asterisk_server/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’ve been tinkering on a personal side project I call <em>Afriend</em> — basically a self-hosted AI that lives on my home linux server and acts like a phone contact I can dial.</p><p>The stack looks like this:</p><ul><li><strong>Asterisk + Callcentric SIP</strong> for the telephony backbone</li><li><strong>AGI/ARI integration</strong> to capture audio and control playback</li><li><strong>Whisper</strong> for transcription (running locally on GPU)</li><li><strong>Mistral/LLM</strong> for responses (served via FastAPI)</li><li><strong>Coqui TTS</strong> for generating the voice</li><li>Hardware: <strong>HP DL380 Gen10</strong> w/ dual Xeon + NVIDIA T4 &amp; P4</li></ul><p>Some features I’ve got working:</p><ul><li>Interruptible playback (it stops talking when you speak)</li><li>Caller ID memory (e.g., “Welcome back, Lee” vs “Nice to meet you”)</li><li>Runs fully local — no cloud APIs, just my gear</li><li>I can dial in from the car on speakerphone and chat like it’s a real friend</li></ul><p>It’s been fun experimenting.</p><p>I’m curious how others in this sub would approach:</p><ul><li>Reducing latency on the audio loop</li><li>Handling larger LLMs with limited GPU (T4 class)</li><li>Clean ways to persist caller memory beyond in-RAM dicts</li></ul><p>Would love to hear your thoughts, and happy to share more detail if anyone’s interested in the plumbing.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 03:41:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8l96x/selfhosted_music_stack/</link><title>Self-Hosted Music Stack</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8l96x/selfhosted_music_stack/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8l96x/selfhosted_music_stack/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8l96x/selfhosted_music_stack/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>So I&#39;ve seen a lot of posts about moving to self-hosted music solutions lately and specifically moving from Spotify.<br/>I thought I&#39;d share my current setup in case it&#39;s a useful starting point for others!</p><p>Up until recently I have been using Navidrome for my music needs, but recently made the change to Jellyfin for music needs for a number of reasons, namely as my list of services I self-host has grown I wanted to find some ways to combine some of my services where I was able, but also a few new tools/plugins have released recently that has made me believe that Jellyfin may be a better option than Navidrome as a complete Spotify/Apple Music/YouTube Music replacement (insert your service of choice).</p><p>I have put together a stack of plugins/Services that:<br/>Has dynamically created genre, artist and discovery playlists via the super easy to use JellyJams Dashboard (<a href="https://github.com/jonasmore/JellyJams">https://github.com/jonasmore/JellyJams</a>)<br/>Scrobbles to ListenBrainz (<a href="https://github.com/lyarenei/jellyfin-plugin-listenbrainz">https://github.com/lyarenei/jellyfin-plugin-listenbrainz</a>)<br/>Creates local AI assisted instant mixes simply by clicking the &quot;instant mix&quot; button/option next to any song, album or artist using the awesome AudioMuse AI project with the included Jellyfin Plugin (<a href="https://github.com/NeptuneHub/AudioMuse-AI">https://github.com/NeptuneHub/AudioMuse-AI</a>) Note: AudioMuse AI can also do dynamic playlists, but I found the experience much easier with JellyJams for this<br/>Grabs metadata from MusicBrainz and Discogs (Apple Music is also an option for those who would prefer it)</p><p>Player support is great!<br/>The two options I have been most impressed with is the excellent open source Jellyfin music app Jellify which recently got an Android release (Already been on iOS for some time) (<a href="https://github.com/Jellify-Music/App?tab=readme-ov-file">https://github.com/Jellify-Music/App?tab=readme-ov-file</a>) and Symphonium has a direct login option for Jellyfin as well!<br/>All of the listed services are available via docker or docker-compose making deployment easy, and the plugins for Jellyfin are all easy to configure via the Jellyfin GUI once you&#39;ve added the repositories.  </p><p>This stack, at least with what I have tried so far has been the easiest and most complete feeling replacement to a traditional  streaming service I have tried. You can also hook up a service like Explo to dynamically download music for you automatically based on your ListenBrainz listens if you&#39;re into that: (<a href="https://github.com/LumePart/Explo">https://github.com/LumePart/Explo</a>)</p><p>Hopefully this helps someone with their self-hosted music journey!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 01:58:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8dvpg/selfhosting_in_a_disaster/</link><title>Self-hosting in a disaster</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8dvpg/selfhosting_in_a_disaster/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8dvpg/selfhosting_in_a_disaster/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n8dvpg/selfhosting_in_a_disaster/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Yesterday my area had a level 1 evacuation notice (&quot;be ready&quot;), and I spent about six hours shoving all my important stuff in my car. We&#39;re still at level 1, the people on the other side of the fire aren&#39;t so lucky, but packing my server up (after all the actually important stuff) got me thinking...</p><p>A lot of why I self-host is to get away from the bullshit peddled by Google / etc, but another part is &quot;just in case&quot;, having my own intranet of digital tools in a bad situation. And here I&#39;ve got this great little mini PC and a bunch of resources, but no way to power it on-the-go or during a black out...</p><p>So today to pass the time waiting for the evac notice to clear, I&#39;m considering what I&#39;d want to host during a disaster and what kind of hardware setup I&#39;d need to actually do that...</p><p>Has anyone got plans/experience with actually running their setup during an emergency?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 21:19:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n87xho/why_i_ditched_spotify_and_self_hosted_my_own/</link><title>Why I ditched Spotify and self hosted my own music stack</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n87xho/why_i_ditched_spotify_and_self_hosted_my_own/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n87xho/why_i_ditched_spotify_and_self_hosted_my_own/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n87xho/why_i_ditched_spotify_and_self_hosted_my_own/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Spotify’s convenient, but it’s also rotten:- They pay artists fractions of a cent per stream, with most never seeing a dime.- They pad playlists with ghost artists and AI-generated garbage to cut royalty costs.- They’re slow to act on AI impersonators even dead artists have had fake albums published under their names.- In the UK, they’re rolling out biometric/ID checks just to listen to explicit tracks.</p><p>why keep feeding this system when the alternatives are right there?</p><p>I built my own stack with Navidrome + Lidarr + Docker, and detailed the whole process here:</p><p><a href="https://leshicodes.github.io/blog/spotify-migration/">https://leshicodes.github.io/blog/spotify-migration/</a></p><p>Would love feedback this is my first proper tech blog write up</p><p>EDIT:I wanna also state that this is all my personal decision. If you want to continue to use spotify for easy of use / convenience, then do so. Nothing is meant to be &quot;holier than thou&quot;</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:18:10 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7udli/i_made_a_door_opener_portal_so_my_neighbors_can/</link><title>I made a door opener portal so my neighbors can open the building's door remotely</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7udli/i_made_a_door_opener_portal_so_my_neighbors_can/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7udli/i_made_a_door_opener_portal_so_my_neighbors_can/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7udli/i_made_a_door_opener_portal_so_my_neighbors_can/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>ever wanted to give people access to one switch inside HA but did not want to give them access to your full home? now you can! i have built a web portal with PIN auth to open the front door of our apartment building, and gave my neighbors individual PINs. now they can open the door for visitors even when they&#39;re not home or forget their keys. Amazing right?</p><p>Source here: <a href="https://github.com/Sloth-on-meth/DoorOpener">https://github.com/Sloth-on-meth/DoorOpener</a></p><h1>edit: yes I&#39;ll try to make it into an addon. I don&#39;t know how though.</h1></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 04:55:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7nrfz/handy_free_tool_i_made_for_tracking_ethernet_port/</link><title>Handy free tool I made for tracking Ethernet port connections</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7nrfz/handy_free_tool_i_made_for_tracking_ethernet_port/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7nrfz/handy_free_tool_i_made_for_tracking_ethernet_port/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7nrfz/handy_free_tool_i_made_for_tracking_ethernet_port/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’ve been tinkering with my home lab and client setups (I do freelance IT Support work), and I often run into the same problem: keeping track of what’s plugged into what. I wanted a simple way to map Ethernet ports, label them, and keep everything visual — but couldn’t find a tool that did exactly that.</p><p>I’m not a developer, but with the help of AI (and a lot of late-night tweaking), I built this little web app and uploaded it to GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/bijomaru78/eccm">Ethernet Cable Connection Manager</a></p><p>Sample screenshot <a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bijomaru78/eccm/main/eccm_screenshot.png">here</a>.</p><p>It runs entirely in the browser, works offline, lets you save/export JSON layouts, and even print neat diagrams of your rack/gear (although I am still tweaking the print layout as it&#39;s having some minor alignment issues).</p><p>I mainly made it to help myself, but I thought some of you might also find it handy for your setups. Happy to take any feedback on board, as it&#39;s my first time &#39;developing&#39; a tool and sharing it with any community :)</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:33:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7e53q/budget_board_v250_is_out_new_automatic_update/</link><title>Budget Board v2.5.0 is out! New automatic update rules.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7e53q/budget_board_v250_is_out_new_automatic_update/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7e53q/budget_board_v250_is_out_new_automatic_update/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1n7e53q/budget_board_v250_is_out_new_automatic_update/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hi everyone,</p><p>I just published the v2.5.0 release for <a href="https://github.com/teelur/budget-board">Budget Board</a>.</p><p>Budget Board is an app designed to help manage and track your personal finances by organizing budgets, expenses, and financial goals in an intuitive interface. The app supports automatic bank sync via SimpleFIN, and as of a few releases ago, now supports importing CSV files.</p><p>New features for v2.5.0:</p><ul><li>Added a new feature to specify automatic rules that apply on each sync<ul><li>Rules will filter on a set of conditions and apply a specified set of changes (i.e. assign a category, change the amount, etc.)</li></ul></li><li>Added some detailed views for budgets and goals to view trends from the past few months.</li></ul><p>My last post was over <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1jyg2sl/budget_board_my_selfhosted_mint_alternative_for/">4 months ago</a>, so here are some other features that have been added since:</p><ul><li>Import transactions via a CSV file</li><li>Two factor authentication</li><li>Ability to change display currency</li><li>Include interest rates in goal completion calculations</li><li>Improved budgets heirarchy</li><li>...And probably some more I am forgetting</li></ul><p>The docker compose and overrides files are included in the repo, and should be able to launch a quick demo as-is. More configuration options can be found in the <a href="https://github.com/teelur/budget-board/wiki/Deploying-via-Docker-Compose">wiki</a>.</p><p>I got a lot of great feature requests and suggestions last time around, so feel free to give it a try and thanks in advance for everyone&#39;s input!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 18:29:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1m67csm/summer_update_2025_ai_flair_and_mods/</link><title>Summer Update - 2025 | AI, Flair, and Mods!</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1m67csm/summer_update_2025_ai_flair_and_mods/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1m67csm/summer_update_2025_ai_flair_and_mods/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1m67csm/summer_update_2025_ai_flair_and_mods/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hello, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">/r/selfhosted</a>!</p><p>It has been a while, and for that, I apologize. But let&#39;s dig into some changes we can start working with.</p><h2>AI-Related Content</h2><p>First and foremost, the official subreddit stance:</p><p><strong><em><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">/r/selfhosted</a> allows the sharing of tools, apps, applications, and services, assuming any post related to AI follows all other subreddit rules</em></strong></p><p>Here are some updates on how posts related to AI are to be handled from here on, though. </p><p>For now, there seem to be 4 major classifications of AI-related posts. </p><ol><li>Posts <em>written</em> with AI. </li><li>Posts about vibe-coded apps with minimal/no peer review/testing</li><li>AI-built apps that otherwise follow industry standard app development practices</li><li>AI-assisted apps that feature AI as part of their function. </li></ol><p><strong><em>ALL 4 ARE ALLOWED</em></strong></p><p>I will say this again. None of the above examples are disallowed on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">/r/selfhosted</a>. If someone elects to use AI to write a post that they feel better portrays the message they&#39;re hoping to convey, that is their perogative. Full-stop. </p><p>Please stop reporting things for &quot;AI-Slop&quot; (inb4 a bajillion reports on this post for AI-Slop, unironically). </p><p>We do, however, require flair for these posts. In fact...</p><h2>Flair Requirements</h2><p>We are now enforcing flair across the board. Please report unflaired content using the new report option for <a href="https://mort.cc/074fw217d25.png">Missing/Incorrect flair.</a></p><p>On the subject of Flair, if you believe a flair option is not appropriate, or if you feel a different flair option should be available, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/selfhosted&amp;subject=Post%20Flair%20Request">message the mods</a> and make a request. We&#39;d be happy to add new flair options if it makes sense to do so.</p><h2>Mod Applications</h2><p><strong>As of 8/11/2025, we have brought on the desired number of moderators for this round.</strong> Subreddit activity will continue to be monitored and new mods will be brought on as needed. </p><p>Thanks all!</p><p><del>Finally, we need mods. Plain and simple. The ones we have are active when they can be, but the growth of the subreddit has exceeded our team&#39;s ability to keep up with it.</del></p><p><del>The primary function we are seeking help with is mod-queue and mod mail responses.</del> </p><p><del>Ideal moderators should be kind, courteous, understanding, thick-skinned, and adaptable. We are not perfect, and no one will ever ask you to be. You will, however, need to be slow to anger, able to understand the core problem behind someone&#39;s frustration, and help solve that, rather than fuel the fire of the frustration they&#39;re experiencing.</del></p><p><del>We can help train moderators. The rules and mindset of how to handle the rules we set are fairly straightforward once the philosophy is shared. Being able to communicate well and cordially under any circumstance is the harder part; difficult to teach.</del></p><p><del><a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/selfhosted&amp;subject=Moderator%20Interest">message the mods</a> if you&#39;d like to be considered. I expect to select a few this time around to participate in some mod-mail and mod-queue training, so please ensure you have a desktop/laptop that you can use for a consistent amount of time each week. Moderating from a mobile device (phone or tablet) is possible, but difficult.</del> </p><h2>Wrap Up</h2><p>Longer than average post this time around, but it has been...a while. And a lot has changed in a very short period. Especially all of this new talk about AI and its effect on the internet at large, and specifically its effect on this subreddit. </p><p>In any case, that&#39;s all for today!</p><p>We appreciate you all for being here and continuing to make this subreddit one of my favorite places on the internet. </p><p>As always, </p><p>happy (self)hosting. ;)</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 12:37:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</link><title>Welcome to /r/SelfHosted! Please Read This First</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><h1>Welcome to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">/r/selfhosted</a>!</h1><p>We thank you for taking the time to check out the subreddit here! </p><h2>Self-Hosting</h2><p>The concept in which you host your own applications, data, and more. Taking away the &quot;unknown&quot; factor in how your data is managed and stored, this provides those with the willingness to learn and the mind to do so to take control of their data without losing the functionality of services they otherwise use frequently. </p><h2>Some Examples</h2><p>For instance, if you use dropbox, but are not fond of having your most sensitive data stored in a data-storage container that you do not have direct control over, you may consider NextCloud</p><p>Or let&#39;s say you&#39;re used to hosting a blog out of a Blogger platform, but would rather have your own customization and flexibility of controlling your updates? Why not give WordPress a go. </p><p>The possibilities are endless and it all starts here with a server. </p><h2>Subreddit Wiki</h2><p>There have been varying forms of a wiki to take place. While currently, there is no <em>officially</em> hosted wiki, we do have a <a href="https://github.com/r-selfhosted/wiki">github repository</a>. There is also at least one unofficial mirror that showcases the live version of that repo, listed on the index of the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki">reddit-based wiki</a></p><h2>Since You&#39;re Here...</h2><p>While you&#39;re here, take a moment to get acquainted with our few but important <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki/rules">rules</a></strong></p><p>And if you&#39;re into Discord, <a href="https://discord.gg/UrZKzYZfcS">join here</a></p><p>When posting, please apply an appropriate flair to your post. If an appropriate flair is not found, please let us know! If it suits the sub and doesn&#39;t fit in another category, we will get it added! <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fselfhosted">Message the Mods</a></strong> to get that started.</p><p>If you&#39;re brand new to the sub, we highly recommend taking a moment to browse a couple of our awesome self-hosted and system admin tools lists.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/Kickball/awesome-selfhosted">Awesome Self-Hosted App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/n1trux/awesome-sysadmin">Awesome Sys-Admin App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/veggiemonk/awesome-docker">Awesome Docker App List</a></p><p>In any case, lot&#39;s to take in, lot&#39;s to learn. Don&#39;t be disappointed if you don&#39;t catch on to any given aspect of self-hosting right away. We&#39;re available to help! </p><p>As always, happy (self)hosting!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 06:59:15 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
