<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:24:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/such-surrender-in-front-of-trump-is-insult-to-1-4-billion-indians-arvind-kejriwal-on-pms-india-us-partnership-remarks/articleshow/123804014.cms</link><title>Such surrender in front of Trump is insult to 1.4 billion Indians: Arvind Kejriwal on PM's 'India-US partnership' remarks (timesofindia.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ndaqmn/such_surrender_in_front_of_trump_is_insult_to_14/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ndaqmn/such_surrender_in_front_of_trump_is_insult_to_14/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ndaqmn/such_surrender_in_front_of_trump_is_insult_to_14/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123803978,width-1070,height-580,imgsize-45512,resizemode-75,overlay-toi_sw,pt-32,y_pad-40/photo.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) National Convenor Arvind Kejriwal on Wednesday launched a sharp attack on Prime Minister Narendra Modi after he said that trade talks between India and the United States would help "unlock the limitless potential" of the partnership.</p><p>Kejriwal said that to "please Trump," cotton farmers across the country were being put at stake.PM Modi's remarks came after US President Donald Trump called for addressing "trade barriers" between the two nations.<span></span>In a post shared on X, questioning the nature of the ongoing negotiations between India and the US, Kejriwal wrote, "What kind of negotiation is going on between the two countries? Only one-sided talks? Keeping our farmers, traders, and the employment of youth on the line, the Indian market is being completely opened up for the Americans. If the entire Indian market comes under the control of the Americans, where will our people go?"He further said that such remarks amount to a "surrender" before the United States. </p><p>"Such a surrender in front of Trump is not only fatal for the Indian economy but also an insult to 1.4 billion Indians," Kejriwal added.<span></span>Kejriwal further urged the Prime Minister not to weaken and to protect the honour of the nation.Kejriwal's remarks came amid Prime Minister Narendra Modi's X post on Wednesday, in which he described New Delhi and Washington as "natural partners" and said he was confident about the progress of the negotiations. </p><p>The PM also expressed his willingness to speak to Trump.<span></span>"India and the US are close friends and natural partners. I am confident that our trade negotiations will pave the way for unlocking the limitless potential of the India-US partnership. Our teams are working to conclude these discussions at the earliest. I am also looking forward to speaking with President Trump. We will work together to secure a brighter, more prosperous future for both our people," PM Modi said in the X post.This comes following a statement by Trump on Tuesday (local time) via Truth Social, where he expressed enthusiasm about continuing negotiations to tackle trade barriers between the two nations. He also expressed confidence in reaching a "successful conclusion" and looked forward to speaking with PM Modi in the upcoming weeks.<span></span>"I am pleased to announce that India and the United States of America are continuing negotiations to address the Trade Barriers between our two Nations. </p><p>I look forward to speaking with my very good friend, Prime Minister Modi, in the upcoming weeks. I feel certain that there will be no difficulty in coming to a successful conclusion for both of our Great Countries!" Trump stated in his post.Trump's remark comes days after he called the India-US ties a "very special relationship" and affirmed that he and PM Modi would always be friends, asserting that there is "nothing to worry about".<span></span>New Delhi is facing global uncertainties due to heightened economic tensions following the US imposition of a 50 per cent tariff on Indian imports, including an additional 25 per cent due to its purchase of Russian crude oil, which, according to Washington, fuels Moscow's efforts in its conflict with Ukraine.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123803978,imgsize-45512,width-400,resizemode-4/123803978.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:12:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/planned-an-islamic-india-by-2047-chargesheet-in-chhangur-religious-conversion-case-2783320-2025-09-07</link><title>Planned an Islamic India by 2047: Chargesheet in Chhangur religious conversion case (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ncjhkv/planned_an_islamic_india_by_2047_chargesheet_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ncjhkv/planned_an_islamic_india_by_2047_chargesheet_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ncjhkv/planned_an_islamic_india_by_2047_chargesheet_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/chhangur-baba-072607752-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=8ZRxQcDBUxQhJl.Wu1mVLRabkrqxdMyC' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>The Uttar Pradesh Anti-Terrorism Squad (ATS) has filed a chargesheet against two prime accused, self-styled godman Jalaluddin alias Chhangur Baba, and his son Mehboob, in connection with an alleged <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/uttar-pradesh-chhangur-baba-funded-more-than-1000-muslim-men-to-trap-hindu-girls-sources-2755048-2025-07-13">illegal mass religious conversion racket in UP's Balrampur</a>.</p><p>The duo is accused of funding more than 1,000 Muslim men to trap Hindu girls for conversion over the past three years, sources told India Today TV.</p><p>The ATS cracked down on <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/chhangur-baba-conversion-racket-hindu-women-converted-islam-son-swiss-bank-up-police-2753724-2025-07-10">Chhangur Baba, who allegedly received Rs 500 crore from Muslim countries</a> during this period to operate a conversion racket that systematically targeted poor, widowed, and vulnerable women.</p><p>The investigation claims that the group was working on a long-term plan to convert people by inducement and threats, with the ultimate aim of turning India into an Islamic nation by 2047.</p><p>According to officials, the chargesheet includes statements from 29 witnesses, of which 10 are victims who directly faced pressure or coercion.</p><p>Among them is a woman who has accused Mehboob and his associate, Naveen Rohra, of sexual exploitation and harassment in the name of conversion.</p><p>The remaining witnesses include police officers and other government personnel who were involved in the investigation.</p><p>The ATS report states that victims consistently testified about the use of both financial enticements and intimidation to push them towards adopting Islam.</p><p>One victim recalled being repeatedly told that the "entire country must be made Islamic by 2047".</p><p>Another woman alleged she was lured to a private room under the pretext of collecting a saree from a shop, where she was allegedly assaulted and later pressured to change her faith.</p><p>Investigators also identified Naveen Rohra as another central figure in the operation.</p><p>Formerly based in Dubai, Rohra is said to have abandoned his business abroad to focus entirely on conversion activities in India.</p><p>ATS records reveal that he <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/conversion-racket-mastermind-chhangur-baba-rss-affiliated-outfit-member-2758123-2025-07-19">received approximately Rs 16.50 crore from foreign sources</a>.</p><p>Of this amount, Rs 1.30 crore was allegedly transferred to Changur and Mehboob, who then used the funds to purchase land in Balrampur, Bahraich, and neighboring districts.</p><p>The chargesheet notes that the accused were preparing to establish Islamic Dawa Centres and Madrasas on these properties to further their activities.</p><p>The ATS investigation portrays the group as a well-financed and organised network that targeted vulnerable individuals through a mix of financial incentives, manipulation, and threats.</p><p>The victims&rsquo; testimonies have been highlighted as crucial evidence, particularly the accounts of exploitation and coercion.</p><p>Authorities emphasise that the chargesheet is a significant step in unraveling the larger network behind the Balrampur operation.</p><p>With funds traced to international sources and properties already being acquired, the ATS suggests that the activities of Changur, Mehboob, and their associates went beyond isolated incidents, pointing instead to a systematic plan.</p><p>The case is expected to move forward in court based on the <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/uttar-pradesh/video/chhangur-baba-case-up-government-to-act-against-4-officers-in-corruption-probe-2756733-2025-07-16">collected witness testimonies, financial records, and evidence</a> of land purchases.</p><p>The ATS maintains that the chargesheet exposes a deliberate conspiracy to carry out mass religious conversions under a long-term ideological agenda.</p><p>The case has national and international ramifications, with allegations of foreign travel using Nepal-issued passports and a "hate toolkit" reportedly discovered, containing plans to publish anti-Hindu scripts.</p><p>The Uttar Pradesh Chief Minister Yogi Adityanath has termed Chhangur Baba's activities "anti-social" and "anti-national," indicating the seriousness with which the authorities are pursuing the multi-agency probe involving the ATS, ED, and potentially the National Investigation Agency (NIA).</p><p>Meanwhile, Chhangur Baba has pleaded innocence in the case. "I am innocent. I don't know anything".</p><p>- Ends</p><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 7, 2025</p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 19:21:12 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nchg8r/a_worker_died_in_my_neighborhood_this_is_the/</link><title>A worker died in my neighborhood. This is the deplorable condition of workers in India.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nchg8r/a_worker_died_in_my_neighborhood_this_is_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nchg8r/a_worker_died_in_my_neighborhood_this_is_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nchg8r/a_worker_died_in_my_neighborhood_this_is_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>So this happened in my neighborhood today. Two workers were fixing a lift in an apartment just a 5 floor building and the lift had water stuck underground since it’s near the park also because the drainage system here is a joke and we all know how Delhi is actually flooded rn. Now anyone with normal common sense would have TURNED OFF THE ELECTRICITY before sending people down there but nope these people didn’t. One poor guy got ELECTROCUTED and died instantly. The other was trapped with him in that lift for more than 3 hours before police and fire brigade could get them out. Imagine being stuck there watching your co worker’s dead body lying next to you for HOURS. And here’s the part that made me rage even more there was NO AMBULANCE. None. Although there were like 3 cars of police , even a fire brigade team, but didn&#39;t even call one ambulance .They just brought a dirty tempo like a small truck shoved the body inside and the surviving guy himself covered his dead friend with a white cloth. Like WHAT THE FUCK. That’s the “respect” they gave him. This is what it means to be a daily wage worker in India. No safety gear no basic precautions no dignity in life or in death. If it was a rich person from that same building the response would have been completely different ambulances doctors news channels everyone. But since it was a worker they just dumped him in a tempo and moved on. Disgusting and heartbreaking. When are we going to start valuing every single human life the same.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:54:22 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://theobserverpost.com/rti-reveals-pm-modis-12-hour-saudi-trip-cost-%E2%82%B915-54-crore-%E2%82%B910-crore-on-hotels-alone/</link><title>RTI Reveals PM Modi’s 12-Hour Saudi Trip Cost ₹15.54 Crore, ₹10 Crore on Hotels Alone (theobserverpost.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ncfw0l/rti_reveals_pm_modis_12hour_saudi_trip_cost_1554/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ncfw0l/rti_reveals_pm_modis_12hour_saudi_trip_cost_1554/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ncfw0l/rti_reveals_pm_modis_12hour_saudi_trip_cost_1554/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://theobserverpost.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Modi-MBS_11zon-1024x576.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Prime Minister Narendra Modi&rsquo;s short visit to Saudi Arabia in April this year cost the Indian government over &#8377;15.54 crore, according to information released under the Right to Information (RTI) Act. The details were shared by the Consulate General of India in Jeddah in response to an RTI filed by activist Ajay Basudev Bose from Maharashtra.</p><p>The biggest chunk of the expenditure &mdash; more than &#8377;10.26 crore &mdash; was spent on hotel rentals, while transport arrangements cost another &#8377;4.05 crore. The remaining amount of around &#8377;1.21 crore has not been broken down in the RTI reply.</p><p>&ldquo;What the Consulate has provided shows that the government spent an unusually high amount on just a few hours in Jeddah,&rdquo; Bose told reporters after receiving the response.</p><figure><div><blockquote><p>RTI reply recvd 4m <a href="https://twitter.com/CGIJeddah?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@CGIJeddah</a> on PM Modi visit in April 25 to Saudi Arabia, Total Amount spent,Rs 15Cr,54L,3K,792,but what is Shocking Rs 10Cr,26L,39K,658 spent on Hotel Rental Charges alone, Will anybody Question Modi about this Extravagance <a href="https://twitter.com/narendramodi?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@narendramodi</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/DrSJaishankar?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@DrSJaishankar</a>&hellip; <a href="https://t.co/yrarDUQofQ">pic.twitter.com/yrarDUQofQ</a></p>&mdash; AJAY Basudev Bose (@AjayBos93388306) <a href="https://twitter.com/AjayBos93388306/status/1961263415877669151?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 29, 2025</a></blockquote> </div></figure><p>The Prime Minister was scheduled to be in Saudi Arabia for two days, April 22 and 23. However, after a terror attack in Pahalgam, Jammu and Kashmir, he cut his trip short and returned to Delhi in less than 12 hours. Modi had landed in Jeddah on the afternoon of April 22 but flew back by the morning of April 23, skipping the official state dinner.</p><p>Critics are questioning why so much money was spent on hotels when, in state visits, the host country is usually responsible for providing accommodation. &ldquo;If the Saudi government was prepared to handle hospitality, why did we spend over ten crore rupees on hotels alone?&rdquo; asked a senior opposition leader.</p><p>When compared with Modi&rsquo;s other foreign trips this year, the Saudi visit stands out as one of the costliest. A four-day trip to France in February cost &#8377;25.59 crore, which averages to about &#8377;6.40 crore per day. A one-day visit to the United States cost &#8377;16.54 crore, while a one-day Thailand trip cost &#8377;4.92 crore. In comparison, Modi&rsquo;s brief stay of just over 12 hours in Saudi Arabia cost &#8377;15.54 crore, making it the second most expensive foreign visit of 2025 so far.</p><figure><div><blockquote><div><p>Vote Chor Narendra Modi spent 15.54 Cr on his two trip to Saudi Arabia.</p><p>Hotel rentals alone is 10.26 Cr. What kind of hotel was he staying?</p><p>Transportation arrangements is 4.05 Cr. Other than cutting deals for Adani &amp; Ambani what has he achieved with this trip? Time to ask him&hellip; <a href="https://t.co/i4pEphIFzE">pic.twitter.com/i4pEphIFzE</a></p></div>&mdash; Congress Kerala (@INCKerala) <a href="https://twitter.com/INCKerala/status/1961345189941055769?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 29, 2025</a></blockquote> </div></figure><p>The high expenses have revived debates about government spending on prime ministerial foreign tours. Historical records show that former Prime Minister Manmohan Singh&rsquo;s visits were far less expensive. For example, his 2011 trip to the United States cost &#8377;10.74 crore, and his 2013 trip to Russia cost &#8377;9.95 crore.</p><p>Rights activists and opposition parties are now demanding greater transparency and accountability. &ldquo;Citizens have a right to know why taxpayers&rsquo; money is being spent in this manner,&rdquo; said Bose, adding that he plans to file further RTIs to get detailed answers.</p><p>The Ministry of External Affairs and the Prime Minister&rsquo;s Office have yet to issue an official comment.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:36:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nceipn/post_office_showed_me_what_digital_india_has/</link><title>Post office showed me what Digital India has become.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nceipn/post_office_showed_me_what_digital_india_has/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nceipn/post_office_showed_me_what_digital_india_has/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nceipn/post_office_showed_me_what_digital_india_has/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I have just completed my process for Passport Updation. I have updated my address to my Nagpur&#39;s house on my passport.</p><p>Now I get the tracking details on SMS a few days ago. Good we&#39;re high tech now.</p><p>I open the website on my phone. 2 scrolls of just politician faces, then I find the required text box.</p><p>Enter captcha - captcha not visible. Server error. Great start!</p><p>Captcha is shown after 2 hours, thank god.</p><p>I try to track it - Item not booked. Okay.<br/>I try it the next day - Item not booked.<br/>I try it the day after - Item not booked.<br/>4th day - Delivered to BENGALURU (?)</p><p>It&#39;s my old address, I call up the person I sold my flat to. They have not received it. Awesome!</p><p>Search for India post Electronic City S.O - Nobody bothers to pickup the phone.</p><p>Customer care might help.</p><p>Track / Trace category.</p><p>&quot;I did not get it&quot;</p><p>&quot;Sorry, I could not understand. Could you please rephrase?&quot;</p><p>&quot;Wrong delivery&quot;</p><p>&quot;Sorry, I could not understand. Could you please rephrase?&quot;</p><p>tried a few times, same message.<br/>Raise a support ticket. No response obviously.</p><p>So yeah, thank you <em>Digital India</em> for delivering my passport to the Bermuda Triangle of Bengaluru. 🥳</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:15:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nc5b92/hi_im_a_foreigner_stuck_in_delhi_need_help_to_get/</link><title>Hi. I'm a foreigner stuck in Delhi. Need help to get outta here.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nc5b92/hi_im_a_foreigner_stuck_in_delhi_need_help_to_get/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nc5b92/hi_im_a_foreigner_stuck_in_delhi_need_help_to_get/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nc5b92/hi_im_a_foreigner_stuck_in_delhi_need_help_to_get/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hi. Here is my story.  It is a long one, so, if you wanna read it takes  take your seat. Hope I can find some real help here. At least this is the purpose of this post.</p><p>Im Russian guy, 26 yo, I am from Ukraine border myself originally (Taganrog,  Rostov region. It is 20km away from the Ukraine,  you can google map it if u like), and I came to India in the beginning of the war, for safety reasons. Got a student visa, to study yoga and vedic culture, and its extendable, I extended once but couldnt do it second time (there was a whole another long story. But I did not intentionally overstay here, cause I obviously didn&#39;t want to break immigration laws). So visa started to expire, then started to overstay. I didnt go back that time cause of low income (spent last everything just to relocate to India, cause was afraid of draft.)and because of forceful drafts that were going on that time (late 2022). So I had to live there, in WB, with no valid visa for a while. Again, its not thatbi wanted to overstay, I just could not prolong it. There was, unfortunately, a reason for it.</p><p>Then, on top of all that I lost my passport and documents. I got robbed basically, and whole backpack with all my docs, my military certificate, my old phone, was gone. I had to come to delhi for seeking help from my embassy. </p><p>I came to Delhi months and MONTHS ago to get help from my embassy, but they are not VERY much helpful. (Cant expect much from Russian govt structures, if they send their own citizens to fight and die in Ukraine only for their political and economic interests.)</p><p>My embassy is KIND OF helping me, but only by giving me a temporary flight document. They dont provide neither place to stay, nor flight tickets eventhough they understand that I have no support from neither my family members, nor from old friends or anything. My own mom was informed as soon as my passport got stolen, and we asked her to send money for flight tickets and for paying my fine to frro (i didnt have money that moment. I was selling books and was only getting enough money to get by) , but she refused, although she had money. She hung up the phone on me, saying that she &quot;loves me&quot;, although she was informed that i may get into serious difficulties without her urgent help. I never talked to noone from my family eversince... I always had bad relationships w them, but now i just feel as if I have no family. Anyways... </p><p>I&#39;m stuck mostly because of insufficient funds and second reason is that I need to get a paper from FRRO (foreign regional registration office, or Indian bureau of immigration) called exit permit to be able to flight back. They are not giving it to me for months now. &quot;Your case is difficult&quot; , they say.</p><p>One reason for it also is that I cannot give them any residence proof document, (called C form). And that is because I literally cannot rent ANY place whatsoever. I had to live in the railway station, in the waiting area for so long that it just drove me crazy. I lost hell lot of my weight and nervous cells there. They allowed me to stay there cause i explained to local that no hostels, hotels, or landlords allow me without passport. And papers from my embassy are not working at all on them. So its a vicious circle.</p><p>At the end, when one member of their staff (just a cleaner guy) stabbed me there in the arm during the fight (he picked it), police of that new delhi railway station, pf1, just decided to throw me away because I wanted to file an FIR ( that could convince my russian embassy to finally help me with something). They didnt want to fire that guy who stabbed me, and didnt want any trouble or any scandal, so they just kicked me out. so i had to just roam around, from 1 place to another, for months after that. This is my situation even now. </p><p>Embassy guys did look concerned when they saw me with my arm bleeding but couldnt do much still. They do not provide neither place to stay, nor, again, are very active in helping me to return back. I mean, they do whatever is there in the script of their job, and I can see that its NOT that much. :/</p><p>So, back to the exit permit... I have no passport and visa to rent any flat or room or hotel or hostel, and I need a document from the house/hostel owner, and without that document I cannot get exit permit feom FRRO🤦‍♂️. At least I cannot get it easily. That may be one of the main reasons why they take way too long in my case. I explained all of it to them ofc, and 1 worker there seemed to be understanding my situation and she offered me some way that MAY work even in the absence of C form, but she was the only 1 in the whole structure who really were getting me and understanding my situation. So its going extremely slow and dull. </p><p>Now I am in the process of getting that exit permit, but it takes extremely long. I may have a chance of getting it still, I believe I just need to push them more, like, make some final push, so to speak, but I have very difficult time doing it while I am having to just always be in a constant search for place to stay, food, medicines and other bare necessities. I was hosted by few indians here in delhi, but noone can do it for long time, which is understandable. Still I need a place to stay for at least 1 or 2 months, to finalise my docs and be ready for a flight. </p><p>Last time I got some nice place i was hosted by a guy from Meghalaya, but he had to fly to his hometown for his uni studies. And I am in the IGIA airport, in the waiting room for last 4 days as Im writing this. I have no money, and only survive here cause that guy from Meghalaya sends me something for water and some food. Rn I have 2 rs in the pocket. Couldn&#39;t contact him this evening.</p><p>Really, really hope to get some support here on reddit. At least i should try anything I can. Im a real person and this story is too. You can come meet me in IGIA in waiting area, to get to know me closer, or write me here, or by links in my profile. Even you can call my russian embassy and ask them if they know me (I&#39;ll give you my name), everyone will surely recognise me. From the phone operator up to the head of the embassy, i think. </p><p>So why im writing here... Im trying to find some host here, even for a few days or a week, or cpl weeks. or, better, to find someone who can help me get any kind of flat, at least for 1 2 months. I need help to finalise my document shit and get back to my country. Any help with getting </p><p>Please reach out to me if something can be done. </p><p>P.s. yes, I tried gurdwaras. They ask for document and the only thing free there is a place on the balcony (on the street basically) and a mat. I tried living in temple too, cant do it no more. What else... yes, NGOs are also asking for documents, however paradoxal it may sound, and don&#39;t allow a foreigner w no documents in. Yes, I filed a lost report about my documents and all. No, police does not help, I spoke with too many of them. No, I cannot just get a job here (without documents) , and I don&#39;t want to be engaged in scamming or drug dealing. If there would be some other option which would work, id accept it. Didnt see any so far. </p><p>So this is my only option rn - simply ask for help in resolving this. I am posting and writing everyone I can in my insta, in my contact list and so on - but no response at all. </p><p>Pray and Hope this message finds someone who really would care. 🙏 </p><p>Thank you for your attention. If anything - please check my profile page. Reach me here or in insta/telegram . Any help appreciated, however insignificant. </p><p>P.p.s: Idk why I cant attach photos here, but i do have scans of some documents and some other things to show. I uploaded them on my profile. Please visit and check</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 06:27:51 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/</link><title>What is Actually Happening in Nepal ?? Misinformation by Indian Media.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nboonh/what_is_actually_happening_in_nepal/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hello to my fellow neighbors in India.I am a <strong>Nepali citizen</strong> living near the border, connected to both our countries not only geographically but also culturally. That is why I feel it is my duty to share the truth with you about what is really happening here.</p><p>You may have seen headlines claiming that Nepal is facing <strong>“mass protests led by Gen Z against social media ban.”</strong>That is only a half-truth.</p><p><strong>Here is the real sequence of events:</strong></p><ul><li><p>Three days ago, the Nepal government suddenly banned 26 social media platforms including Facebook, WhatsApp, Instagram, YouTube, and Reddit.</p></li><li><p>They claimed it was about registration and taxes. But these companies are already registered and paying taxes. The real motive is censorship: giving the government power to control online information, delete posts critical of them within 24 hours, and jail those who speak up.</p></li><li><p>In the next two days, criticism exploded across the country. A date was set—September 8—for nationwide protests. But it was never just about social media. That ban was only the spark.</p></li></ul><p><strong>Our patience had already run out.</strong></p><p>Soon, the “<strong>Nepo Babies</strong>” trend erupted in Nepal. It exposed the lavish lifestyles of politicians’ children—designer (clothes,bags, watches, attire )worth lakhs, luxury cars, million-rupee homes, weekly international flights, and even private jets—while ordinary Nepalis struggle daily for survival. Our PM has a salary less than 65k INR but what is owns is in million of $$$.</p><blockquote><p>This hit a nerve. Because Nepal has been under one form of tyranny or another for decades. From monarchy to so-called democracy, corruption and instability have never left us. Not a single prime minister has completed a full term in over 20 years.</p></blockquote><p>[The protests were organized in the name of Gen Z, but they welcomed everyone. We were not just protesting a social media ban. We were standing against corruption, nepotism, tyranny, suppression, and decades of betrayal. In a country of just 30 million people, every single day around 5,000 youths leave to work abroad because there are no jobs, no decent pay, and no basic livelihood at home.]</p><p>And then the tragedy struck. Today, during the protest, I witnessed &amp; carried something I will never forget. A 15-year-old schoolboy, still in uniform, was shot in the head by security forces—acting on orders from a minister. He was not the only one. Reports say more than 20 people have been killed, thousands injured, and the true numbers are being hidden.</p><p>I came home with blood still on my hands, only to see Indian news channels spinning a completely false narrative. They claimed it was all about social media and mocked our youths as being “<strong>addicted</strong>” to it. That angered me, but it didn’t surprise me. I know how the media can twist things.</p><p>That is why I am writing this here, to let you know the truth from the ground.</p><p>🙏</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:36:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/</link><title>Living in india is just exhausting honestly.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nblnic/living_in_india_is_just_exhausting_honestly/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Where do I even begin. Honestly I feel it&#39;s just exhausting to really live in this country.</p><p>Infra is just pathetic. 9-5 jobs are actually 7-10 if you consider the time it takes to commute in metro cities. And when you do get home, you can&#39;t even have some quiet time because someone is doing a kirtan with loud music on. </p><p>You can&#39;t go outside because there aren&#39;t enough public parks or walkable spaces. And if you do happen to live nearby one, then either the road will be dug out or you just won&#39;t go outside because pollution.</p><p>When it&#39;s raining you just have to pray that you don&#39;t get into an open manhole or you get in vicinity of live wire.</p><p>They say to escape India in India you need to buy a place in gated societies. But wait, can you even afford a home in these gated societies ? Majority of the Middle class with even IT Benchmark salary cannot afford to buy home in this country. </p><p>And even if you can, you still can&#39;t escape the terrible Air Quality and the pathetic infra.</p><p>Job security doesn&#39;t exist in India, and if you&#39;re born in General category then basically you are on your own. The taxes you pay get you nothing in this country.</p><p>From birth till death life is just a rat race in this country. </p><p>I know my thoughts are all over the place. Some of you might not agree and that&#39;s okay. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 17:23:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/brain-eating-amoeba-kerala-reports-fifth-amoebic-meningoencephalitis-death-in-a-month/article70024977.ece</link><title>Brain-eating amoeba: Kerala reports fifth amoebic meningoencephalitis death in a month (thehindu.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbhgbp/braineating_amoeba_kerala_reports_fifth_amoebic/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbhgbp/braineating_amoeba_kerala_reports_fifth_amoebic/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbhgbp/braineating_amoeba_kerala_reports_fifth_amoebic/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Amoebic meningoencephalitis, a rare but fatal brain infection caused by free-living amoebae found in freshwater, lakes and rivers, has emerged as a public health concern in Kerala. | Photo Credit: Wikipedia </p></div><div><div><p>Kerala reported the fifth death due to amoebic meningoencephalitis in a month as a Malappuram native undergoing treatment at the Government Medical College Hospital, Kozhikode, died on Monday (September 8, 2025). </p><p>According to sources, Sobhana, 56, from Thiruvali near Wandoor in Malappuram district, was admitted to the hospital last week. She had been in a critical condition since then. </p><p>Since August 14, four people in the State have died from the infection, and this marks the fifth fatality.</p><p>The sources said that 11 persons are at present undergoing treatment for the disease at the Kozhikode MCH, and the condition of at least one of them is reported to be serious.</p><p>Ratheesh, 45, a native of Sulthan Bathery in Wayanad district, who had been undergoing treatment at Kozhikode MCH, succumbed to the infection on September 6, 2025.</p><p>Amoebic meningoencephalitis, a rare but fatal brain infection caused by free-living amoebae found in freshwater, lakes and rivers, has emerged as a public health concern in Kerala.</p></div><p>Published <span>- September 08, 2025 12:34 pm IST</span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 13:08:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chandigarh/26-year-old-jind-man-shot-dead-in-us-after-objecting-to-public-urination/articleshow/123752250.cms</link><title>'Entered via donkey route': Haryana man shot dead in US for objecting to public urination (timesofindia.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>JIND: A 26-year-old man from Haryana's Jind district was shot dead in California, US, after he objected to a man urinating in public on Saturday. The deceased, Kapil, was working as a security guard. Son of Ishwar from Barah Kalan village, Kapil was on duty when he confronted an individual for urinating outside the premises, village sarpanch Suresh Kumar Gautam told TOI.</p><p>The man, in response, shot him dead on the spot, the sarpanch added.<span></span></p><div><p>On Cam: Indian-Origin Sikh Man Shot Dead In Los Angeles; Video Released By US Police</p></div><p>Kapil, the only son of a farming family, had travelled to the US two-and-a-half years ago. He is said to have entered the country in 2022 through the "donkey route", crossing the jungles of Panama and scaling the Mexico border wall, a journey that cost his family around Rs 45 lakh. After his initial arrest, he was released through legal proceedings and had since been settled in the country.</p><div><p>Poll</p><p>Should stricter laws be implemented regarding public behavior?</p><div><p><label>Yes, definitely.</label><label>No, that is unnecessary.</label></p></div></div><p><span></span>The family was informed of the death by a relative living in the US. Kapil has two sisters, one of whom is married."The entire village is standing with the family, but they are deeply broken in this time of grief," said sarpanch Gautam. <span></span>He added that the family plans to meet with the deputy commissioner to demand that Kapil's body be brought back to India. "We hope for the govt's full support," he said.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123755348,imgsize-25480,width-400,height-225,resizemode-72/-.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:11:01 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
