<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:56:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://thewire.in/communalism/muslim-teens-suicide-spotlights-gujarats-controversial-disturbed-areas-act</link><title>Muslim Teen's Suicide Spotlights Gujarat's Controversial Disturbed Areas Act (thewire.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nicpd0/muslim_teens_suicide_spotlights_gujarats/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nicpd0/muslim_teens_suicide_spotlights_gujarats/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nicpd0/muslim_teens_suicide_spotlights_gujarats/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cms.thewire.in/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/WhatsApp-Image-2025-09-02-at-15.07.06-1.jpeg' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:55:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businesstoday.in/india/story/mugging-up-random-trivia-for-500-seats-founder-slams-upsc-iit-system-for-killing-talent-494110-2025-09-16</link><title>'Mugging up random trivia for 500 seats': Founder slams UPSC, IIT system for killing talent (businesstoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni90np/mugging_up_random_trivia_for_500_seats_founder/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni90np/mugging_up_random_trivia_for_500_seats_founder/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni90np/mugging_up_random_trivia_for_500_seats_founder/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><h2>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not just unfair. It&rsquo;s stupid. It&rsquo;s destructive,&rdquo; Suhag concludes. &ldquo;India kills its own talent before the world even gets to see it.&rdquo; </h2><div><p><img width="948" height="533" title="'Mugging up random trivia for 500 seats': Founder slams UPSC, IIT system for killing talent" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/businesstoday/images/story/202509/68c8c6893545c-his-post-strikes-a-chord-in-a-country-where-education-is-often-the-only-perceived-route-to-successb-160803429-16x9.jpg?size=948:533" alt="'Mugging up random trivia for 500 seats': Founder slams UPSC, IIT system for killing talent"><span>His post strikes a chord in a country where education is often the only perceived route to success&mdash;but the process itself, he warns, is turning ambition into disillusionment.</span></p></div><div><div><div><p>India is quietly bleeding talent&mdash;not through brain drain, but through its own brutal entrance test obsession, says startup founder Akhil Suhag in a LinkedIn post.</p><p>His critique? A system that filters future engineers through chemistry papers, shoves coders into textile degrees, and rewards memorization over mastery.</p></div><p>&ldquo;A 13-year-old obsessed with coding wants to be the best in the world,&rdquo; Suhag writes. &ldquo;What does the system do? It forces him to waste 4&ndash;5 years memorizing chemistry and physics just to get into IIT/NIT.&rdquo;</p><div><h4>Related Articles</h4></div><p>Even if they clear the entrance exams, Suhag says students are often assigned random branches&mdash;Textile, Mining, Metallurgy&mdash;not because of aptitude, but because their rank wasn't &ldquo;high enough.&rdquo; This, he argues, derails not only individual potential but the country&rsquo;s long-term innovation pipeline.</p><p>In his post, Suhag dismantles the deeply entrenched belief that elite college tags are the only markers of intelligence. &ldquo;We test how good a computer engineer one can be based on his chemistry skills,&rdquo; he writes, adding that fever, anxiety, or one bad day can derail an entire career trajectory.</p><p>He also points out the ripple effect on career pivots like MBA admissions: &ldquo;Your college determines your first job, your first job determines your MBA profile.&rdquo; In a system where where you studied overshadows what or how well you learned, Suhag says the odds are stacked against even the brightest minds.</p><p>His criticism extends to the UPSC exam, India&rsquo;s gateway to its most prestigious civil services. &ldquo;Hundreds of thousands of brilliant young people waste their prime years mugging up random trivia for 500 seats,&rdquo; he writes. &ldquo;Even the army does psychological testing&mdash;not UPSC.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not just unfair. It&rsquo;s stupid. It&rsquo;s destructive,&rdquo; Suhag concludes. &ldquo;India kills its own talent before the world even gets to see it.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p><span>Published on: Sep 16, 2025 7:38 AM IST</span> </p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:00:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://share.google/fkja23REA66xFGrC6</link><title>India brags about having 1.4 billion people but won't buy one bushel of U.S. corn: Lutnick - The Hindu (share.google)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni8ahd/india_brags_about_having_14_billion_people_but/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni8ahd/india_brags_about_having_14_billion_people_but/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ni8ahd/india_brags_about_having_14_billion_people_but/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/26z95g/article70049800.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/2025-09-11T160336Z_1151754268_RC2QPGA4SITS_RTRMADP_3_USA-STOCKS.JPG' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>U.S. Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutnick. File. | Photo Credit: Reuters </p></div><div><div><p>India brags about having 1.4 billion people but won&rsquo;t buy even a small amount of American corn, United States Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick has said, asserting that New Delhi must bring down its tariffs or face a &ldquo;tough time&rdquo; doing business with the U.S.</p><p>Mr. Lutnick made the comments during an interview on Saturday (September 13, 2025) when he was asked whether the U.S. is mismanaging &ldquo;very valuable relationships&rdquo; with &ldquo;important allies&rdquo; like India, Canada and Brazil with the tariffs imposed on these countries.</p><p><strong> Editorial |<a href="https://www.thehindu.com/opinion/editorial/doublespeak-on-the-trump-administrations-actions-and-india/article70042525.ece"> &#8203;Doublespeak: On the Trump administration&rsquo;s actions and India &nbsp;</a></strong></p><p>&ldquo;The relationship is one way, they sell to us and take advantage of us. They block us from their economy, and they sell to us while we are wide open for them to come in [and] take advantage,&rdquo; Mr. Lutnick said. &ldquo;The president says, &lsquo;fair and reciprocal trade&rsquo;,&rdquo; he added.</p><p>&ldquo;India brags that they have 1.4 billion people. Why won't 1.4 billion people buy one bushel of U.S. corn? Doesn't that rub you the wrong way that they sell everything to us and they won't buy our corn. They put tariffs on everything,&rdquo; Mr. Lutnick said.</p><h4>&lsquo;President's model&rsquo;</h4><p>He added that President Donald Trump has said &ldquo;&lsquo;bring down your tariffs, treat us the way we treat you&rsquo;&rdquo;. The Commerce Secretary further added &ldquo;we&rsquo;ve got to right years of wrong so we want a tariff going the other way until we fix this&rdquo;.</p><p>&ldquo;That's the President's model, and you either accept it or you're going to have a tough time doing business with the world's greatest consumer,&rdquo; Mr. Lutnick said.</p><p>The Trump administration has imposed 50% tariffs on India, including 25% for Delhi&rsquo;s purchases of Russian oil, among the highest imposed on any country in the world.</p><p>India has described the U.S. action as &ldquo;unfair, unjustified and unreasonable&rdquo;. Defending its purchase of Russian crude oil, India has been maintaining that its energy procurement is driven by national interest and market dynamics.</p></div><p>Published <span>- September 14, 2025 08:39 pm IST</span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:19:18 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/delhi-woman-driving-bmw-that-killed-senior-finance-ministry-official-taken-into-cutody/articleshow/123896440.cms</link><title>Delhi woman driving BMW that killed senior Finance ministry official taken into cutody (economictimes.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhm2bv/delhi_woman_driving_bmw_that_killed_senior/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhm2bv/delhi_woman_driving_bmw_that_killed_senior/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhm2bv/delhi_woman_driving_bmw_that_killed_senior/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://img.etimg.com/thumb/msid-123896446,width-1200,height-630,imgsize-2310386,overlay-economictimes/articleshow.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A day after a senior <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/topic/finance-ministry-official">Finance Ministry official</a> was killed when a <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/industry/bmw-india">BMW</a> hit his motorcycle in the Delhi Cantonment area, an ANI report on Monday said that the woman driving the car, Gagandeep Kaur (38), has been taken into custody.</p><p>Police earlier today registered a case of culpable homicide. </p><p>Deputy Secretary in the Department of Economic Affairs, Navjot Singh (52), a resident of Hari Nagar, was killed in the accident on Sunday afternoon, while his wife sustained serious injuries.</p><br><p>The couple was returning home after visiting the Bangla Sahib Gurdwara.</p><p>The BMW, which was being driven by a woman with her husband by her side, who were also injured in the incident. According to police, the couple, residents of Gurugram, are in the business of manufacturing leather saddles, seats, covers, belts and other products.</p><p>They have been admitted to a hospital and their statements are yet to be recorded, police said.</p><p>According to a Delhi Police official, the case has been registered under Bharatiya Nyaya Sanhita sections sections 281 (rash driving or riding on a public way), 125B (acts endangering life or personal safety of others), 105 (culpable homicide not amounting to murder) and 238 (causing disappearance of evidence of offence, or giving false information to screen offender).</p><p>Police said the BMW and the motorcycle have been seized. The accident spot was examined by the crime team and forensic experts.</p><p>Further investigation into the case is underway, police said.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:06:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/sports/cricket/asia-cup/handshake-row-takes-ugly-turn-as-pakistan-threaten-to-withdraw-from-asia-cup-2025/articleshow/123900093.cms</link><title>Handshake row takes ugly turn as Pakistan threatens to withdraw from Asia Cup 2025 (timesofindia.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhjg5u/handshake_row_takes_ugly_turn_as_pakistan/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhjg5u/handshake_row_takes_ugly_turn_as_pakistan/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhjg5u/handshake_row_takes_ugly_turn_as_pakistan/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123900299,width-1070,height-580,imgsize-54072,resizemode-75,overlay-toi_sw,pt-32,y_pad-40/photo.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><section><div><p><span title="India vs Pakistan (AP Photo) ">India vs Pakistan (AP Photo) </span></p></div></section><p><span>TimesofIndia.com in Dubai:</span> Pakistan are highly likely to withdraw from the remaining matches of the Asia Cup if match referee <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/andy-pycroft">Andy Pycroft</a> is not removed from the tournament&rsquo;s panel, PCB Chairman Mohsin Naqvi has warned.TimesofIndia.com understands that the latest warning of withdrawal is the result of the controversy over the missing handshakes in the high-voltage Asia Cup clash between India and Pakistan on Sunday evening. <span></span>The situation has escalated into a full-blown row, with the Pakistan Cricket Board (PCB) formally lodging a complaint with the International Cricket Council (ICC). </p><div><p>Suryakumar Yadav statement on Pahalgam to handshake drama: How India HUMILIATED Pakistan</p></div><p><span></span>Naqvi confirmed on Monday that the board has demanded &ldquo;an immediate removal of the Match Referee from the Asia Cup&rdquo; over alleged violations of the ICC Code of Conduct and MCC Laws pertaining to the Spirit of Cricket.&ldquo;The PCB has lodged a complaint with the ICC regarding violations by the Match Referee of the ICC Code of Conduct and the MCC Laws pertaining to the Spirit of Cricket. The PCB has demanded an immediate removal of the Match Referee from the Asia Cup,&rdquo; Naqvi posted on X.<span></span>The flashpoint occurred at the Dubai International Cricket Stadium during the toss when Pakistan captain Salman Ali Agha and Indian skipper <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/suryakumar-yadav">Suryakumar Yadav</a> avoided the customary handshake. According to the PCB, Pycroft had specifically instructed Salman to refrain from shaking hands.</p><p>&ldquo;The match referee Andy Pycroft had asked captain Salman Ali Agha, at the time of the toss, not to shake hands with his Indian counterpart. The Pakistan team management has lodged a protest, calling the behaviour against the spirit of sports,&rdquo; the board said.<span></span>The situation worsened after India&rsquo;s emphatic seven-wicket win, when Suryakumar shook hands only with batting partner Shivam Dube and walked off without acknowledging the Pakistani players. </p><p>Pakistan coach Mike Hesson voiced his disappointment.&ldquo;Obviously, we were ready to shake hands at the end of the game. We were disappointed that our opposition didn't do that. We sort of went over there to shake hands and they were already going to the changing room. That was a disappointing way for the match to end. In a match where we were already disappointed with the way we played, we were at least willing to go and shake hands,&rdquo; Hesson said.<span></span></p><div><p>PCB Chairman Mohsin Naqvi's social media posts </p></div><p>In protest, captain Salman Ali Agha skipped the post-match presentation ceremony.<span></span>Suryakumar, however, stood firm, linking the gesture to India&rsquo;s solidarity with the victims of the <a href="https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/topic/pahalgam-terror-attack">Pahalgam terror attack</a> and the armed forces.&ldquo;Perfect occasion, taking the time out, we stand by the victims and families of the Pahalgam terror attack. We express our solidarity. I want to dedicate the win to all our armed forces who showed a lot of bravery,&rdquo; he said.<span></span>&ldquo;I feel a few things in life are ahead of sportsmanship. I said at the presentation as well that we stand with all the victims of the Pahalgam terror attack. And we stand with their families too, expressing our solidarity. Also, as I said at the post-match presentation, we dedicate this win to our brave armed forces who took part in Operation Sindoor.&rdquo;The PCB&rsquo;s complaint now sits at the ICC headquarters chaired by Jay Shah, creating fresh diplomatic and sporting tensions between the two rivals. </p><p>The board&rsquo;s stance has been further hardened by the fact that Pycroft is also listed as the referee for Pakistan&rsquo;s next match against UAE on Wednesday.<span></span>&ldquo;There is nothing more important to me than the honour and prestige of my country,&rdquo; Naqvi posted later.Pakistan and India are likely to clash again in the Super Four stage if both sides progress. India have virtually sealed their spot with two wins, while Pakistan face a must-win encounter against UAE. Their potential rematch is scheduled for Sunday in Dubai.<span></span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123900299,imgsize-54072,width-400,resizemode-4/india-vs-pakistan-ap-photo.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/photo/83033472.cms"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 17:09:33 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/india-prime-minister-narendra-modi-spared-china-xi-jinping-the-new-villain-in-donald-trumps-latest-tariff-post-2786985-2025-09-14</link><title>India spared, China the new villain in Trump's latest tariff post (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhh6ky/india_spared_china_the_new_villain_in_trumps/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhh6ky/india_spared_china_the_new_villain_in_trumps/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nhh6ky/india_spared_china_the_new_villain_in_trumps/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>After months of berating India as Moscow's enabler, Donald Trump has found a bigger villain in Beijing. In shifting his fury eastward, he spares New Delhi &ndash; but only to keep it from slipping deeper into Russia's embrace.</h2></div><div><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/trump-lobbies-nato-to-sanction-russia-and-hit-china-with-50-100-tariffs-140625523-16x9_0.jpg?VersionId=whC8KD_FNJGDYchiE__pADFlxDe1DGqB&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Trump lobbies Nato to sanction Russia and hit China with 50-100% tariffs." title="Trump lobbies Nato to sanction Russia and hit China with 50-100% tariffs." height="388"></p><p>Trump lobbies Nato to sanction Russia and hit China with 50-100% tariffs.</p></div><div><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 14, 2025 08:50 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>Donald Trump has found a new villain. After months of railing against India for buying Russian oil and hammering New Delhi with punitive tariffs, the US president is now training his guns on China. In his latest Truth Social post, Trump thundered that Nato nations must "stop buying oil from Russia" and unite to<strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/ready-to-do-major-sanctions-on-russia-when-all-nato-nations-agree-and-do-the-same-thing-says-trump-2786834-2025-09-13"> impose "major sanctions" on Moscow </a></strong>&ndash; while also calling for devastating 50 per cent to 100 per cent tariffs on Beijing.</p><p>In a fiery letter addressed to Nato members and "the world", Trump declared: "I am ready to do major sanctions on Russia when all Nato nations have agreed, and started, to do the same thing, and when all Nato Nations STOP BUYING OIL FROM RUSSIA. As you know, Nato's commitment to win has been far less than 100 per cent, and the purchase of Russian Oil, by some, has been shocking! It greatly weakens your negotiating position, and bargaining power, over Russia."</p><p>Trump urged the alliance to act collectively, insisting he was prepared to "go" once Nato members align on sanctions: "Anyway, I am ready to 'go' when you are. Just say when?" he wrote.</p><p>In his most direct remarks yet, Trump said he is "ready" to move on the sanctions, which could have a devastating impact on Russia's finances &ndash; but ultimately left the decision in the hands of Nato allies.</p><p>The sharpest edge of his demand, though, was reserved for Beijing. "I believe that this, plus Nato , as a group, placing 50 per cent to 100 per cent TARIFFS ON CHINA, to be fully withdrawn after the WAR with Russia and Ukraine is ended, will also be of great help in ENDING this deadly, but RIDICULOUS, WAR," he added.</p><p>Trump stressed that "China has a strong control, and even grip, over Russia, and these powerful Tariffs will break that grip".</p><h3>TRUMP SHIFTS HIS ATTENTION TO CHINA</h3><p><strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/donald-trump-softening-stance-india-ties-tariff-trade-deal-after-harsh-criticism-2781316-2025-09-03">The demand marks a stark reversal</a></strong>: until recently, Trump had spared China with a lighter 30 per cent tariff while punishing India with a bruising 50 per cent duty, often lumping the two in the same breath as Moscow's biggest enablers.</p><p>After US President Donald Trump pressed Nato nations to impose tariffs on Russian oil purchasers in a bid to pressure Moscow, China on Saturday said that it <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/china-hits-back-at-trump-100-per-cent-tariff-call-india-sanctions-russia-ukraine-war-2786934-2025-09-13">neither plots nor participates in wars</a></strong>, in a stern and clear message to Washington.</p><p>Beijing's dig at the US came just hours after Trump's post urging Nato members to halt Russian oil purchases and impose sanctions of up to 100 per cent on China, one of Moscow's biggest buyers.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/g7-finance-ministers-discuss-tariffs-possible-sanctions-to-increase-pressure-on-russia-glbs-2786586-2025-09-13">Additionally, the US has been urging G7 countries</a></strong> &ndash; including Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, and the United Kingdom, most of whom are also Nato members &ndash; to step up pressure on Russia by imposing tariffs on India and China, both major buyers of Russian oil.</p><p>This shift in target comes after weeks of acrimony in India-US ties. Washington had unleashed some of its harshest rhetoric in decades, with Trump aides branding India the "Kremlin's laundromat" and even <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/modis-war-white-house-adviser-navarro-links-india-to-ukraine-war-glbs-2777904-2025-08-28">dismissing the Russia-Ukraine conflict as "Modi's war".</a></strong></p><p>Trade advisor Peter Navarro went further, lacing his attacks with casteist undertones by accusing "Brahmins" of profiteering at the expense of ordinary Indians.</p><p><strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/weve-lost-india-russia-to-darkest-china-trump-shares-pic-of-modi-putin-xi-together-from-sco-summit-2782533-2025-09-05">Trump himself grumbled that the US had "lost" India to "the darkest China" </a></strong>after images from the Shanghai Cooperation Organisation (SCO) summit showed Prime Minister Narendra Modi chatting amiably with Xi Jinping and Vladimir Putin.</p><p>The optics of the SCO summit clearly rattled Washington. PM Modi's visible camaraderie with Putin &ndash; walking hand-in-hand, holding candid conversations, even sharing a car ride in Tianjin &ndash; and his warm exchanges with Xi, symbolised a deepening comfort between the world's three biggest powers.</p><p>For a US administration banking on India as the democratic counterweight to China, the sight of New Delhi leaning on Moscow and Beijing through multilateral forums was nothing short of alarming.</p><p>India's firmness has only added to Washington's unease. Despite the barrage of US criticism, New Delhi has refused to yield on what it considers red lines &ndash; particularly opening its dairy and agricultural sectors, which could devastate millions of farmers.</p><p>Trump's imposition of a 25 per cent tariff on Indian goods and an additional 25 per cent penalty over Russian oil imports deepened the chill, and stalled trade talks languished in deadlock. Yet, the government held its ground, signalling that no amount of hectoring would shake India's stance.</p><p>Faced with that resolve &ndash; and the nightmare scenario of India, China, and Russia banding together, Washington has begun to soften its tone.</p><p>Last week, Trump abruptly changed tack, calling <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/will-speak-to-pm-modi-trump-says-india-us-to-continue-trade-talks-glbs-2784767-2025-09-10">PM Modi a "great Prime Minister" and a "dear friend"</a></strong>. PM Modi reciprocated swiftly, describing the US as a "close friend and natural partner", and expressing confidence that the trade negotiations would soon unlock the <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/india-us-natural-partners-pm-modi-says-he-too-is-looking-forward-to-speaking-with-president-trump-2784778-2025-09-10">"limitless potential" of the partnership.</a></strong></p><h3>REASON BEHIND WASHINGTON'S RECALIBRATION</h3><p>Trump's lieutenants, too, have recalibrated. Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent, who<strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/world/us-news/story/scott-bessent-backs-us-india-ties-hits-russian-oil-trade-glbs-2780400-2025-09-02"> once led the charge against India's Russian oil purchases</a></strong>, now plays the conciliator.</p><p>"Two great countries will get this solved," he said, emphasising the personal rapport between Trump and PM Modi. Even he brushed off SCO optics as manageable, though conceding that the relationship was "very complicated." By contrast, Navarro has continued his barrage &ndash; but his vitriol now looks increasingly isolated.</p><p>The reasons for this pivot are both external and domestic. At home, Trump has been hammered by Democrats, former officials, and even Republican rivals like Nikki Haley for imperilling two decades of painstakingly built ties with India. Alienating Indian-Americans &ndash; a demographic increasingly warming to Trump &ndash; also carries political risks. Abroad, the idea of India tilting closer to China and Russia is a strategic nightmare that the US can ill afford.</p><p>By shifting the spotlight to Beijing, Trump is signalling a recalibration: China, with its USD 7.2 billion purchase of Russian fossil fuels in July and its "grip" over Moscow, is the real prize. India, with its USD 3.6 billion in imports and an <strong><a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/india-us-trade-talks-agriculture-dairy-sector-donald-trump-explain-bilateral-trade-gm-crops-subsidy-explained-2749828-2025-07-03">uncompromising government unwilling to bend on trade red lines</a></strong>, has effectively forced Washington's hand.</p><p>The softer tone towards New Delhi and the tougher rhetoric against Beijing reveal a US strategy in transition &ndash; one that acknowledges India's leverage and the costs of pushing it further into the arms of Moscow and Beijing.</p><p>For now, Trump insists he is "ready" to devastate Russia's finances with sanctions &ndash; but only when Nato nations unite and stop buying Russian oil. More telling, though, is his demand that China face up to 100 per cent tariffs. In Trump's calculus, sparing India and targeting Beijing may be the only way to break what he calls China's "grip" over Russia &ndash; and to ensure that America does not lose India for good.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Nakul Ahuja</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 14, 2025</p></div></div><p>Tune In</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/Nakul-profile_image_one_to_one.jpeg?VersionId=38FoOGLj4yavzOeKV44CGYATC92xdZir&amp;size=50:50"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:58:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ndtv.com/india-news/missing-truck-driver-rescued-from-sacked-ias-officer-puja-khedkars-pune-home-9276453?pfrom=home-ndtv_topscroll</link><title>Missing Truck Driver Rescued From Sacked IAS Officer Puja Khedkar's Pune Home (ndtv.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngx3gf/missing_truck_driver_rescued_from_sacked_ias/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngx3gf/missing_truck_driver_rescued_from_sacked_ias/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngx3gf/missing_truck_driver_rescued_from_sacked_ias/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 22:50:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/sikh-woman-raped-by-2-men-in-uk-oldbury-told-go-back-to-your-country-9269438</link><title>"Go Back To Your Country": Sikh Woman Raped, Faced Racist Abuse In UK (ndtv.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nguaow/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_raped_faced/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nguaow/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_raped_faced/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nguaow/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_raped_faced/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 21:02:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/</link><title>Got cheated by Niva Bupa Insurance + Ombudsman + IRDAI</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngpbs7/got_cheated_by_niva_bupa_insurance_ombudsman_irdai/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’m sharing my experience with <strong>Niva Bupa Health Insurance</strong> and the regulators in India because it’s been a nightmare of <strong>fraud, collusion, and cover-up.</strong> Posting here to spread awareness and also get suggestions on what legal action I can take.</p><h1>Background</h1><ul><li>I took a Niva Bupa policy in 2021 and renewed it in 2022, and then for 3 years in Sept 2023.</li><li>The policy always included a <strong>free annual health checkup,</strong> which could be claimed on a reimbursement basis. I successfully claimed it in 2022 and 2023.</li></ul><p><strong>The Fraudulent Change</strong></p><ul><li>In the 2023 renewal, Niva Bupa <strong>secretly changed the terms</strong>: “This benefit is available ONLY on cashless, and no reimbursement is allowed.”</li><li>As per the earlier policy wording, they were <strong>legally required to give 3 months&#39; prior notice</strong> of such changes. They never did.</li><li>When I filed a reimbursement claim in Aug 2024, it was rejected using the new wording. I only came to know about the change after this rejection.</li></ul><h1>Failed Complaints</h1><ul><li>I complained twice on <strong>IRDAI’s Bima Bharosa site</strong>. Both were closed within days without addressing the actual issue.</li><li>I went to the <strong>Insurance Ombudsman (Delhi)</strong>. Despite me sending all documents (email + courier), they falsely closed my case, saying I didn’t submit documents.</li><li>I later got proof through RTI that they had indeed received them.</li></ul><h1>The “Fake” Hearing &amp; Award</h1><ul><li>In December 2024, they called me for a hearing, but with the <strong>wrong case number, the wrong insurer name, and the wrong policy number.</strong></li><li>At the hearing, I clearly said it was about breach of contract (changing terms without notice). The Niva Bupa rep asked for more time. Nothing was settled.</li><li>Later, I suddenly received an “Award” from the Ombudsman office stating:<ul><li>That I had <strong>accepted an offer</strong> from Niva Bupa (a lie).</li><li>The case was settled through conciliation.</li><li>That only ₹4,194 was awarded against my relief request of ₹1,00,000.</li><li>It mentions that “<em>At this stage, Insurers agreed to consider the claim and review the continuation of the Policy on the basis of terms and conditions of previous insurance policies for the renewed period. The Complainant accepted this offer. Thus complaint is resolved by way of Conciliation and Mediation under Rule 16 of the Insurance Ombudsman Rules, 2017</em>.”</li></ul></li><li>RTI replies later claimed I had “verbally accepted” in the online hearing 🤯. No proof, no recording.</li></ul><h1>More Stonewalling</h1><ul><li>I escalated through the <strong>PG Portal</strong> (DARPG). Instead of sending it to IRDAI/Ombudsman, they wrongly forwarded my complaints back to <strong>Niva Bupa</strong> 🤦🏻‍♂️. All were closed without action.</li><li>Appeals were also closed the same way.</li><li>Even after the Ombudsman’s own award saying the insurer should honour previous terms, <strong>Niva Bupa rejected my reimbursement claims again in Aug 2025.</strong></li></ul><h1>Where I Stand Now</h1><ul><li>Niva Bupa = Breached contract, lied, ignored Ombudsman order.</li><li>IRDAI = Closed complaints blindly.</li><li>Ombudsman = Issued a false award, colluded with insurer.</li><li>PG Portal = Mishandled and misrouted complaints.</li></ul><p>This is a <strong>systemic failure</strong>. Feels like the regulator, redressal system, and insurer are all hand-in-glove.</p><h1>What I’m Considering:</h1><ul><li>Filing a <strong>Consumer Court case</strong> for breach of contract, deficiency of service, and harassment.</li><li>Filing a <strong>Writ Petition in the High Court</strong> for regulatory failure and misconduct by IRDAI &amp; Ombudsman.</li><li>Exploring the possibility of a <strong>class action suit</strong> since this likely affects many other Niva Bupa customers.</li></ul><p>👉 Has anyone here fought something similar with an insurance company or the Ombudsman? What worked for you?</p><p>👉 Should I start with Consumer Court, or directly go for High Court since IRDAI + Ombudsman are involved?</p><p>Any advice, guidance, or even visibility would help 🙏</p><p>(All documents, RTI replies, emails, and even the hearing video are with me for proof.)</p><p>------</p><p>⚡ TL;DR: Niva Bupa secretly changed policy terms, IRDAI closed my complaints without looking, Ombudsman fabricated a false award, and PG Portal misrouted grievances. Complete collapse of the system. Thinking of going to the Consumer Court/High Court.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 17:22:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/world/story/sikh-woman-raped-by-two-men-in-uk-park-oldbury-told-go-back-to-your-country-racial-attack-hate-crime-sikh-community-abroad-2786721-2025-09-13</link><title>Go back to your country, Sikh woman told after being raped at UK park (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngjkdf/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_told_after/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngjkdf/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_told_after/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1ngjkdf/go_back_to_your_country_sikh_woman_told_after/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>A Sikh woman was told to "go back to her own country" by two men who allegedly raped her at a park in Oldbury, UK.&nbsp;Police are treating the assault as a racially aggravated hate crime and launched a manhunt for the suspects.</h2></div><div><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/uk-police-1226477-16x9.jpg?VersionId=xlvn.P5zJRNBmqi5WuP8naBCqzuZumaG&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="UK police" title="Image used for representational purpose only" height="388"></p><p>Image used for representational purpose only</p></div><div><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 13, 2025 17:02 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>A Sikh woman in her 20s was allegedly raped by two men in broad daylight at a park in Oldbury, UK, and told to &ldquo;go back to your country&rdquo; during the assault.</p><p>The attack took place just before 8.30am on Tuesday in an area off Tame Road. Police said they were treating the assault as a racially aggravated hate crime and have launched a manhunt for the suspects.</p><p>Both attackers are described as white men. One is heavy-built with a shaven head and was wearing a dark sweatshirt and gloves; the other was seen in a grey top with a silver zip.</p><p>Officers have appealed for CCTV, dashcam or mobile footage from the area and have urged anyone with information to come forward.</p><p>&ldquo;This was a horrific attack. We are appealing to anyone who saw two men in the area or has CCTV or dashcam footage to contact us urgently,&rdquo; West Midlands Police said in a statement.</p><p>The assault has triggered anger and fear among the Sikh community, which has reported rising incidents of racism in recent months.</p><p>Labour MP Preet Kaur Gill condemned the attack, calling it &ldquo;an act of extreme violence and racism.&rdquo; She wrote in a post on X: &ldquo;She does belong here. Racism and misogyny have no place in Oldbury or anywhere in Britain,&rdquo; and pledged to work with police to ensure justice and improve safety for the Sikh community.</p><p>Police have stepped up patrols in the area, and the victim is receiving specialist support as investigations continue.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Priyanka Kumari</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 13, 2025</p></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/IndiaToday_8-profile_image_one_to_one_2.jpg?VersionId=YHWhNjkqMc4flF9vvzdfMRFJETGjKZY9&amp;size=50:50"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 11:40:29 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
