<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 20:26:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://newrepublic.com/article/200471/peter-thiel-obsession-antichrist-religion</link><title>What’s Up With Peter Thiel’s Obsession With the Antichrist? (newrepublic.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.newrepublic.com/b0701cad31869b310dd5255c8c3ae0648d712613.jpeg?w=1200&h=630&crop=faces&fit=crop&fm=jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article><div><div><p>In yet another troubling sign of these times, Peter Thiel can&rsquo;t stop talking up the Antichrist. This month, the tech billionaire is delivering a four-part, closed-door <a href="https://luma.com/antichrist">lecture</a> on the topic, which he is framing as &ldquo;political theology,&rdquo; in San Francisco. It&rsquo;s part of what you might call an &ldquo;Antichrist World Tour&rdquo; by the PayPal and Palantir co-founder, who has already given off-the-record Antichrist lectures at Oxford, Harvard, and Bari Weiss&rsquo;s ersatz college, the University of Austin.</p><p>It&rsquo;s not clear why Thiel needs secrecy to hold forth on his latest obsession. He&rsquo;s been pontificating about the Antichrist in public talks for years. During a June <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/26/opinion/peter-thiel-antichrist-ross-douthat.html">interview</a> with <i>The</i> <i>New York Times,</i> Thiel offered extended thoughts on the shadowy figure, barely mentioned in the Bible, who according to legend (and countless pulp horror movies) will arise to help Satan kick off Armageddon. He even named a suspect: Greta Thunberg. (The interview went viral when Thiel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/LXpc1YiXDoQ">struggled</a> to answer a question about whether he wants the human race to endure.)</p></div><div><p>Thiel is not a theologian, scholar, or prophet. So why pay attention to his biblical musings? Because Thiel is one of the world&rsquo;s most influential men and his Antichrist speeches reveal his deep belief that religion is a weapon for political warfare&mdash;and he&rsquo;s right.</p><p>Thiel&rsquo;s Antichrist fixation fits a long tradition in American politics. Since the nation&rsquo;s founding, Americans have sought to name the Antichrist&mdash;usually by pointing the finger at their political enemies. &ldquo;The symbol of the Antichrist has played a surprisingly significant role in shaping Americans&rsquo; self-understanding,&rdquo; wrote historian Robert Fuller in 1995&rsquo;s <a href="https://archive.org/details/namingantichrist0000full_w6k9"><i>Naming the Antichrist</i></a><i>: The History of an American Obsession. &ldquo;</i>Because they tend to view their nation as uniquely blessed by God, they have been especially prone to demonize their enemies.&rdquo;</p><p>Over time, the identity of Satan&rsquo;s Little Helper has shifted from Native Americans to Communists, Hitler and Saddam Hussein and Barack Obama&mdash;even barcodes and microchips have been implicated. From colonial days to the AI era, the hunt for the Antichrist continues. Today&rsquo;s QAnon conspiracy theorists believe they are battling a cabal of cannibalistic Satanists. <i>Unhumans</i>, a 2024 book <a href="https://www.thenerdreich.com/unhumans-jd-vance-and-the-language-of-genocide/?ref=theframelab.org">praised by JD Vance</a>, equated <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/05/opinion/jd-vance-fascism-unhumans.html">progressives</a> with bloodthirsty &ldquo;unhuman&rdquo; creatures. This turns politics into a zero-sum holy war.</p></div><div><p>&ldquo;Once we label our adversaries in these cosmic terms&mdash;all good versus all evil&mdash;now there&rsquo;s going to be no compromise,&rdquo; said Fuller.</p><p>Thiel understands this. He frames his interest in the Antichrist as part of his own &ldquo;political theology,&rdquo; a term he borrows from <a href="https://claremontreviewofbooks.com/the-nazi-jurist/">Carl Schmitt</a>, a Nazi philosopher who defined the practice of politics as a struggle against an existential enemy, arguing that politics is just religion in disguise. Thiel also draws on Ren&eacute; Girard, a Catholic thinker (and one of Thiel&rsquo;s Stanford professors) who warned that human societies tend to spiral toward violence in a hunt for scapegoats.</p><p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s always a question of whether politics is like a market &hellip; or is it something like a scapegoating machine, where the scapegoating machine only works if you don&rsquo;t look into the sausage factory?&rdquo; Thiel <a href="https://youtu.be/vfbndRTlsg4?si=7sAtBdMnzlyDFaMv&amp;t=2302">said</a>, during a 2024 talk at Stanford. He explained the mechanism: &ldquo;If, say, we&rsquo;re having a lot of conflicts in our village and we have to find some random elderly woman and accuse her of witchcraft so that we&rsquo;ll achieve some psychosocial unity as a village &hellip; this sort of thing doesn&rsquo;t really work if you&rsquo;re self-aware.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>Thiel knows these dynamics well, but it&rsquo;s not clear whether he&rsquo;s horrified or impressed. His talks stop short of providing solutions. Instead, they meld Schmitt, Girard, and scripture into an incisive meditation on the power of apocalyptic ideas. Thiel positions himself as someone trying to help the world navigate a &ldquo;narrow path&rdquo; between Armageddon and Antichrist. But his rhetoric also sketches a playbook for holy war, scapegoating, crisis, and power&mdash;since Schmitt famously argued that power consolidates during existential crises, when constitutions can be suspended.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re told that there&rsquo;s nothing worse than Armageddon, but perhaps there is,&rdquo; said Thiel during a <a href="https://youtu.be/fQ4rc7npiXQ?si=giiMtr0qT7kdE5xR&amp;t=1661">talk at Oxford</a> in 2023. &ldquo;Perhaps we should fear the Antichrist, perhaps we should fear the one-world totalitarian state more than Armageddon.&rdquo;</p><p>He is already experimenting with this doomsday script: In January, he wrote an <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a46cb128-1f74-4621-ab0b-242a76583105">op-ed</a> framing Donald Trump&rsquo;s return to power as an &ldquo;<i>apok&aacute;lypsis</i>&rdquo;&mdash;an &ldquo;unveiling&rdquo; of hidden truth and a chance to cleanse the nation&rsquo;s &ldquo;sins.&rdquo; And in his religion talks, Thiel does not hesitate to name potential Antichrists, including Greta Thunberg, communism, and even tech regulation. This reveals a telling urge to wield scripture as political weaponry.</p></div><div><p>Yet his approach has major flaws. For example, Thiel claims the Antichrist will be someone focused on existential threats and apocalypse, and who will usher in a totalitarian world government under the slogan of &ldquo;peace and safety.&rdquo; But Thiel&rsquo;s Antichrist checklist&mdash;a paranoid obsession with apocalypse, control, and surveillance&mdash;describes Thiel himself.</p><p>Thiel co-founded <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/05/30/technology/trump-palantir-data-americans.html">Palantir</a>, a software company literally named after an all-seeing orb controlled by an evil wizard in <i>The Lord of the Rings</i>. Palantir is partnering with the Trump administration to supercharge government surveillance at a moment when the president openly embraces authoritarianism. The irony is so striking it almost seems like a confession. As comedian Tim Dillon quipped on Joe Rogan&rsquo;s podcast recently: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s so strange.&hellip; You build domestic surveillance technology to surveil our friends and neighbors&mdash;and then your other pet passion is the Antichrist.&rdquo;</p><p>Thiel isn&rsquo;t alone in mimicking religious themes. Billionaire Nicole Shanahan recently declared <a href="https://www.thenerdreich.com/demonic-silicon-valley-billionaire-blasts-burning-man/">Burning Man</a> &ldquo;demonic,&rdquo; while Andreessen Horowitz partner <a href="https://x.com/KTmBoyle/status/1894133112881516994?ref=thenerdreich.com">Katherine Boyle</a> has invoked Christ&rsquo;s crucifixion to argue that governments destroy families. Trae Stephens, a Thiel ally and self-proclaimed &ldquo;arms dealer&rdquo; who co-founded the drone warfare company <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/christians-silicon-valley-religion-venture-capital/">Anduril</a> (another warped <i>Lord of the Rings</i> reference), frames his work as part of a quest to &ldquo;carry out God&rsquo;s command to bring his Kingdom to earth as it is in Heaven.&rdquo; Stephens&rsquo;s wife, Michelle, co-founded ACTS 17 Collective (Acknowledging Christ in Technology and Society), which evangelizes to tech workers and is hosting Thiel&rsquo;s Antichrist lectures.</p></div><div><p>Meanwhile in Russia, Alexander Dugin&mdash;an ultranationalist philosopher and propagandist known as &ldquo;Putin&rsquo;s brain&rdquo;&mdash;is the only other major political figure who fixates on the Antichrist as much as Thiel. In Dugin&rsquo;s version, Russia is at war with the Antichrist, which is liberal modernity emanating from the &ldquo;<a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/311974964_Alexander_Dugin_Building_a_Bridge_between_Eschatology_and_Conspiracy">country of apocalypse</a>&rdquo;&mdash;the United States.</p><p>Not everyone is convinced by Silicon Valley&rsquo;s pivot to piety. At the National Conservatism Conference this month, some traditional religious conservatives railed against their would-be tech brethren. Conservative firebrand Geoffrey Miller blasted artificial intelligence developers as &ldquo;betrayers of our species&rdquo; and &ldquo;apostates to our faith,&rdquo; calling for what <a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/773154/maga-tech-right-ai-natcon">The Verge</a> described as a &ldquo;literal holy war&rdquo; against tech. </p><p>After all, if we&rsquo;re hunting for existential enemies, Silicon Valley&rsquo;s diabolically greedy tech billionaires&mdash;who wish to create &ldquo;godlike&rdquo; AI systems powerful enough to destroy humanity&mdash;top the list. But we must avoid falling into the Antichrist name-calling trap. Instead of asking, &ldquo;Who is the Antichrist?&rdquo; we must ask, &ldquo;Why is a tech billionaire trying to convince us we&rsquo;re on the brink of apocalypse?&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>These rehashed <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/31/us/satanic-panic.html">Satanic panic</a> tactics must be exposed for what they are: a cynical ploy to further inflame political divisions. It also seems like an awkward effort to cement an alliance with religious nationalists in the Republican Party, who also use apocalyptic language to frame their political goals. Journalist Matthew D&rsquo;Ancona described Thiel&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.thenewworld.co.uk/matthew-dancona-peter-thiel-and-the-antichrist/">Antichrist theories</a> as a &ldquo;highbrow version of MAGA End-Times theology.&rdquo;</p><p>But naming the Antichrist is a dangerous tactic that often leads to crisis and violence.</p><p>&ldquo;The whole concept of the Antichrist &hellip; fosters a crisis mentality,&rdquo; said Fuller, the Antichrist historian. &ldquo;And with the crisis mentality, now we put aside all other differences. There&rsquo;s a tribal cohesion, a tribal unity, and it justifies even immoral acts because, to defeat an evil enemy, a Satanic enemy, you must do whatever is necessary.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>Last week, in the hours after Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s assassination, the words &ldquo;demon&rdquo; and &ldquo;evil&rdquo; trended on X as some on the right portrayed his murder as the work of supernaturally possessed Democrats and leftists. Major right-wing influencers echoed Carl Schmitt&rsquo;s ideas, calling for a <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/far-right-reactions-charlie-kirk-shooting-civil-war/">political crackdown</a> on Kirk&rsquo;s critics. Chris Rufo, a prominent right-wing propagandist, called on law enforcement to &ldquo;infiltrate, disrupt, arrest, and incarcerate&rdquo; the &ldquo;radical left.&rdquo;</p><p>This is where apocalyptic rhetoric always leads. When political opponents become evil, cosmic enemies, persecution, and violence become a sacred duty. This surge in demon and devil talk showed that Thiel has correctly identified a potent but perilous impulse in our politics. </p><p>But if tech billionaires seek to spread Christianity, they should stop hunting Antichrists and reflect on the words of Jesus Christ, who urged his followers to practice empathy and forgiveness and to care for people rather than exploit and surveil them. Instead of worrying about Armageddon, Thiel should heed the Gospels, which warn that &ldquo;it is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich man to enter the kingdom of God.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>Now there&rsquo;s scripture worth dwelling on&mdash;and it&rsquo;s a problem that no AI, no surveillance, no power, no money can fix.</p></div></div></article></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:22:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.404media.co/doj-deletes-study-showing-domestic-terrorists-are-most-often-right-wing/</link><title>DOJ Deletes Study Showing Domestic Terrorists Are Most Often Right Wing (404media.co)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.404media.co/content/images/size/w1200/2025/09/pam-bondi.jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>The Department of Justice has removed a study showing that white supremacist and far-right violence &ldquo;continues to outpace all other types of terrorism and domestic violent extremism&rdquo; in the United States.&nbsp;</p><p>The study, which was conducted by the National Institute of Justice and hosted on a DOJ website was available there at least until September 12, 2025, according to an archive of the page saved by the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250911165140/https://www.ojp.gov/pdffiles1/nij/306123.pdf"><u>Wayback Machine</u></a>.</p><p>&ldquo;The Department of Justice's Office of Justice Programs is currently reviewing its websites and materials in accordance with recent Executive Orders and related guidance,&rdquo; reads a message on the page where the study was formerly hosted. &ldquo;During this review, some pages and publications will be unavailable. We apologize for any inconvenience this may cause.&rdquo;</p></div><div><div><h2>This post is for paid members only</h2><p>Become a paid member for unlimited ad-free access to articles, bonus podcast content, and more.</p><p><a href="https://www.404media.co/membership/">Subscribe</a> </p></div><div><h2>Sign up for free access to this post</h2><p>Free members get access to posts like this one along with an email round-up of our week's stories.</p><p><a href="https://www.404media.co/signup/">Subscribe</a> </p></div><p>Already have an account? <a href="https://www.404media.co/signin/">Sign in</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 22:14:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://rockenhaus.com</link><title>Man held 3 years in jail by FBI  for refusing to decrypt TOR NODES (rockenhaus.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 19 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><main> <article><div><figure><img width="1024" height="435" src="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-1024x435.jpeg" alt srcset="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-1024x435.jpeg 1024w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-300x127.jpeg 300w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-768x326.jpeg 768w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1.jpeg 1290w"></figure><p><strong>UPDATE: September 8, 2025: NEW VIDEO: U.S. Marshals Smash Windows in Retaliatory Raid on Disabled Vet</strong></p><figure></figure><p>This is what (Detroit) U.S. Marshals did to the home of Conrad Rockenhaus, a 100% disabled combat veteran, on September 4, 2025. The only warrant on the public record was a simple <strong><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.20.0.pdf">ARREST warrant</a></strong> for a fabricated, non-violent probation violation.</p><p>But as this video shows, they did not come for a standard arrest. They came to terrorize a family.</p><p>They smashed windows and beat him in the head. He is now suffering with a head injury in Livingston County Jail, where he is receiving inadequate medical care. To make it worse, a federal judge has stripped him of his constitutional right to an attorney. This is the price of speaking out against a corrupt federal officer.</p><p>For the full story, the judge&rsquo;s order, and all the evidence, visit the <strong><a href="https://rockenhaus.com/press-kit/">Press Kit</a></strong>.</p><p><strong>UPDATE: September 4, 2025 &ndash; A VIOLENT RETALIATORY ARREST</strong></p><p>On the morning of September 4, 2025, a U.S. Marshals Fugitive Task Force executed a fraudulent warrant, raiding the temporary home I was forced to rent out of fear for my safety. This raid was the direct result of a retaliatory campaign orchestrated by U.S. Probation Officers <strong>Stylianos Agapiou</strong>, Supervisor <strong>Jeffry Konal</strong>, and Chief <strong>Dion Thomas</strong>. The Marshals refused to produce a warrant.</p><p>According to a neighbor, the Marshals had been surveilling the home for days. During the raid, which was captured on video, they broke down the door, used excessive force, and physically beat my husband, a 100% disabled combat veteran.</p><p>During his initial court appearance later that day, my husband suffered a grand mal seizure in the courtroom as a result of the officer&rsquo;s violent arrest, and was rushed to the hospital.</p><p>Marshals had NO warrant, beat Conrad in the head (he later had a seizure in court) and held the door shut preventing me from leaving my home.</p><p>WATCH THE LIVE VIDEO NOW</p><figure></figure><p>Prior to his arrest, Conrad&rsquo;s retained attorney, <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/the-role-of-attorney-marc-r-lakin-p41147-in-a-constitutional-crisis/">Marc Lakin</a>, unethically refused to withdraw from the case after being fired. This forced Conrad to file his own motions with the court, asking the judge to intervene and appoint new counsel.</p><p>On August 29, 2025, Judge Stephen J. Murphy, III, issued an order striking these motions from the record.</p><p>Citing a rule against &ldquo;hybrid representation,&rdquo; Judge Murphy refused to address Conrad&rsquo;s constitutional right to effective counsel, stating the issue would be handled at the next hearing. This order created a procedural trap, leaving Conrad legally bound to an attorney who refused to act, while simultaneously making it impossible for him to hire a new one.</p><p>As a direct result of this order, Conrad was forced to appear in court today following his violent arrest without any legal representation&mdash;a crisis that culminated in his medical emergency in the courtroom.</p><p><a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/motion-to-strike.pdf">READ JUDGE MURPHY&rsquo;S ORDER.</a></p><p><strong>UPDATE SEPT 5, 2025:</strong> After having a seizure in court yesterday, Conrad Rockenhaus&rsquo;s <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.17.0.pdf">hearing was postponed to Sept. 30th</a> by Judge Stephen J. Murphy, III. What&rsquo;s worse is the court is fully aware of Conrad&rsquo;s medical status since the hearing.</p><p>Judge Murphy knows Conrad&rsquo;s previous lawyer, Marc Lakin, has abandoned him and is out of the country, but he refuses to appoint a new one. This is a deliberate violation of his Sixth Amendment rights.</p><p><strong>ANN ARBOR, MI &ndash; On August 28, 2025</strong>, A federal civil rights lawsuit filed in the Eastern District of Michigan details a sustained campaign of retaliatory prosecution against a 100% medically retired U.S. combat veteran and his wife. This was after his wife filed a formal complaint against a U.S. Probation Officer for serious misconduct, harassment, and illegal seizure of her business property.&nbsp;His wife is a private citizen with no criminal record, and the officers have no jurisdiction over her.</p><p>The retaliation, as documented in the filings, was swift and severe. It culminated in the U.S. Probation Office authoring a fraudulent arrest warrant based on a verifiably false claim that the veteran, Conrad Rockenhaus, was an &ldquo;absconder,&rdquo; despite having written proof he was hospitalized in a VA mental health facility.&nbsp;</p><p>This led to a <a href="https://youtu.be/E4WlPdNhzjM?si=XSdj9PdyurFPyybQ">traumatic raid</a> where the couple was held at gunpoint in their own driveway. </p><p>This public record, supported by official court documents, video evidence, and internal communications, exposes a pattern of fabricated evidence. It also shows a malicious prosecution designed to punish a private citizen for speaking out and to exploit the known medical vulnerabilities of a disabled veteran.</p><ul> <li><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.388083/gov.uscourts.mied.388083.1.0.pdf"><em>See Conrad&rsquo;s Lawsuit: Rockenhaus v. Agapiou (2:25-cv-12716)</em></a></li> <li><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.388138/gov.uscourts.mied.388138.1.0.pdf"><em>See Adrienne&rsquo;s Lawsuit: Rockenhaus v. Agapiou (2:25-cv-12736)</em></a></li> </ul> <figure><img width="1024" height="451" src="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-1024x451.jpeg" alt srcset="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-1024x451.jpeg 1024w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-300x132.jpeg 300w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-768x338.jpeg 768w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2.jpeg 1290w"></figure><p>[WATCH: <a href="https://youtu.be/E4WlPdNhzjM?si=XSdj9PdyurFPyybQ">Feds Hold Up Disabled Couple on False Warrant</a>]</p><p>The complete public record for this case, including the official lawsuits, a detailed timeline, and all supporting evidence, is available in the <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/press-kit/">comprehensive press kit</a>.</p><h3><strong>An Impossible Mandate: The Supervision &lsquo;Catch-22&rsquo;</strong></h3><p>At the heart of the federal case is the &ldquo;Catch-22&rdquo; of Conrad&rsquo;s supervision: a set of impossible and contradictory conditions imposed on a 100% medically retired and disabled combat veteran with a TBI.</p><p>The U.S. Probation Office demands that Conrad &ndash; a man certified as 100% disabled and unable to work by both the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Social Security Administration &ndash; simultaneously maintain a full-time job and pay $800 per month in restitution from his disability income.</p><p>At the same time, the officers have actively sabotaged his ability to even attempt to comply with this mandate. On two separate occasions, they have conducted unannounced visits and illegally seized his authorized work equipment, owned by his wife&rsquo;s company, which were the essential tools he used for his approved employment as a software developer.</p><p>They have then used this manufactured non-compliance as a basis for fraudulent violation petitions, effectively punishing him for failing to achieve a goal they themselves made impossible. This strategy of entrapment is a core feature of the Bivens civil rights complaint.</p><h3><strong>The Foundation of Injustice (Texas, 2019&ndash;2022)</strong></h3><p>The ordeal in the Eastern District of Michigan is the second chapter in a multi-year saga that began in Texas. In early 2019, Conrad Rockenhaus, a supporter of free speech and online privacy, refused to help federal agents decrypt traffic on <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/an-american-invention-for-global-freedom-the-true-story-of-tor/">Tor exit nodes</a> he operated for journalists and activists. Months later, on a pretextual, non-violent computer crime (CFAA) charge, he was arrested.</p><p>His three-year pre-trial detention was triggered by a single, provably false claim. The <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/U.S.-v.-Rockenhaus-2-20-20-2.pdf">official court transcript from a February 20, 2020, hearing</a> provides an irrefutable record of Texas Probation Officer Tiffany Routh testifying under oath that Conrad had installed a &ldquo;Linux operating system&rdquo; that &ldquo;knocked out their monitoring software&rdquo;.</p><p><strong>The Verifiable Lie:</strong> The software was, in reality, a pre-approved SPICE graphics driver for his Ph.D. program &ndash; not an operating system. It did not, nor could it, disable the monitoring software. Routh used this false claim to baselessly suggest Conrad might be accessing &ldquo;dark web sites,&rdquo; an inflammatory accusation she was forced to admit under oath she had no evidence to support.</p><p>This false testimony was fueled by a malicious campaign. We have documented proof that Conrad&rsquo;s then-wife, Ashley Luster, was actively working to keep him incarcerated for her own financial gain. While he was imprisoned, she illegally made herself the representative payee for his Social Security disability benefits, directing the funds to her own account after divorce proceedings had begun. Financial records further document how she systematically drained his bank accounts, maxed out his credit cards, and spent his monthly pension and disability payments. </p><p><strong>The Smoking Gun Confession: </strong>In a letter to her parents, Luster confessed, &ldquo;I had some tricks up my sleeve to keep him in there&rdquo;.</p><p><strong>Documented Collusion: </strong>Emails reveal Luster colluding with Conrad&rsquo;s own attorney, Walter Reaves, to secretly prolong his detention.&nbsp;</p><p>Based on this foundation of false testimony and conspiracy, Conrad was held for three years in horrific county jail conditions, where he was regularly beaten by guards and denied his life-sustaining seizure medication. The grueling ordeal ended only when he felt forced to accept a coerced guilty plea.</p><h3><strong>The Price of Speaking Out (Michigan, 2024&ndash;Present)</strong></h3><p>After his release to Michigan, Conrad&rsquo;s supervision under his first probation officer was stable and compliant. The crisis began in September 2024, when his case was reassigned to Officer Stylianos Agapiou, who immediately created a hostile environment. After months of harassment, illegal property seizures, and threats against Adrienne, she did what any citizen is supposed to do.</p><p><strong>The Trigger: </strong>On February 13, 2025, Adrienne Rockenhaus filed a <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Formal-Complaint-and-Demand-for-Investigation-Regarding-Probation-Officer-Stylianos-Agapiou_Redacted.pdf">detailed, 10-point formal complaint against Officer Agapiou</a> with his supervisors, including Chief Dion Thomas.</p><p>The response was not an investigation. It was retaliation.</p><p><strong>The Retaliation Begins:</strong> Just seven days later, on February 20, 2025, Chief Dion Thomas personally engaged in an act of intimidation by calling Adrienne&rsquo;s ex-husband and <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Dion-Thomas-Voicemail-to-EX-husband.mp3">leaving an unnerving and intimidating voicemail</a>, despite having just been given her contact information in an email.</p><h3><strong>The First Fraudulent Warrant</strong></h3><p><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.3.0.pdf">The April 29, 2025, arrest warrant</a>, signed by Supervisor Jeffry W. Konal, is a fraudulent document built on a foundation of demonstrable lies, malicious omissions, and the deliberate misrepresentation of facts. The petition&rsquo;s central claim, that Conrad was an &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; whose &ldquo;current whereabouts are unknown&rdquo;, is systematically dismantled by the probation office&rsquo;s own communications records.</p><p>The warrant also falsely accused Conrad of opening seven new lines of credit. This allegation was later disproven by an investigation that uncovered identity theft against both Conrad and Adrienne, for which a police report was filed. The petition was not an act of supervision; it was an attempt to punish the victim of a crime.</p><p>The warrant contains a misleading claim of illicit drug use based on a positive marijuana screen, while deliberately omitting the fact that Conrad has a legal prescription for Marinol (dronabinol), a medication known to cause such a result.</p><p>The evidence proves the office was not just aware of Conrad&rsquo;s hospitalization, but was in active, continuous communication about it.</p><p><strong>The Official Notification:</strong> Phone records provide irrefutable proof that on February 20, 2025, Adrienne Rockenhaus placed a six-minute call to Chief Dion Thomas&rsquo;s office at 11:21 AM to formally discuss Conrad&rsquo;s admission to a VA mental health facility.</p><p><strong>The Acknowledged Plan &amp; Continuous Updates: </strong>Text messages show the follow-up communication was with Konal himself. He not only acknowledged the plan for Conrad&rsquo;s doctor to send verification but continued to solicit and receive direct updates from Adrienne from February 24 through at least March 1, 2025. Konal&rsquo;s sworn statement in the warrant that Adrienne &ldquo;failed to&hellip;provide&rdquo; updates is a blatant falsehood, contradicted by his own phone&rsquo;s records.</p><p><strong>The Deceptive Misrepresentation of Privacy Laws: </strong>Konal&rsquo;s claim that the VA hospital told him on March 14 that Conrad was not a patient is a deliberate deception. Due to federal HIPAA laws protecting mental health patients, the VA would provide a standard, privacy-compliant &ldquo;no comment&rdquo; to an unauthorized caller. Konal, a federal officer, would have known this. He weaponized this privacy law, twisting a legally required non-answer into false &ldquo;proof&rdquo; that Conrad was a fugitive when he had already been told to expect a discharge. Conrad&rsquo;s doctor had been in contact with the probation office as well.</p><p>The &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; status was manufactured. Supervisor Konal possessed phone records, text messages, and direct knowledge of Conrad&rsquo;s medical crisis. He chose to ignore all of it, misrepresent the facts, and fabricate a basis for a traumatic arrest.</p><p><strong>The Traumatic Raid:</strong> On May 5, 2025, U.S. Marshals executed the fraudulent warrant in a raid on the family&rsquo;s home. <a href="https://youtu.be/E4WlPdNhzjM?si=XSdj9PdyurFPyybQ">Home security footage</a> provides an irrefutable record of officers holding the complying couple at gunpoint and threatening, &ldquo;If you do anything, I&rsquo;m gonna release the dog, he&rsquo;s gonna bite you&rdquo;. The transporting &ldquo;John Doe&rdquo; U.S. Marshal later showed Conrad a sexually harassing text he wrote about Adrienne while he drove recklessly down the shoulder of the highway.</p><h4><strong>A Suspicious Removal and Punitive Reinstatement</strong></h4><p>The retaliation was not limited to intimidation. Shortly after Adrienne filed her formal complaint on February 13, Officer Agapiou was quietly placed &ldquo;on leave&rdquo; and removed from the case. However, this was not a corrective measure. The timeline suggests a coordinated effort: Agapiou was sidelined while his supervisor, Jeffry Konal, authored the fraudulent &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; warrant that led to Conrad&rsquo;s arrest. Then, just days after the coerced guilty plea was secured on May 13, Agapiou was immediately reinstated to Conrad&rsquo;s case, a move the family alleges was a punitive measure and a continuation of the harassment.</p><h3><strong>The Betrayal by Counsel: The Misconduct of Marc Lakin</strong></h3><p>A central objective of the legal fight is the withdrawal of the guilty plea Conrad entered on May 13, 2025. This plea was not a legitimate admission of the fabricated violations; it was the direct result of a calculated ethical breach and coercion by his own retained attorney, <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/the-role-of-attorney-marc-r-lakin-p41147-in-a-constitutional-crisis/">Marc Lakin</a>.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>The Coerced Plea: </strong>The record shows that Lakin knowingly coerced his client into pleading guilty despite possessing clear evidence of his innocence. On May 7, 2025, six days before the hearing, Lakin was provided with a detailed &ldquo;<a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Responses-to-Alleged-Violations-Rockenhaus-Conrad-05-07-2025-2.pdf">Defense Summaries</a>&rdquo; document, which contained point-by-point exculpatory evidence refuting the &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; claim. Despite having this proof, Lakin ambushed his client moments before the hearing on May 13. After separating Conrad from Adrienne at the courthouse to isolate him, Lakin threatened him with more jail time if he refused to plead guilty. This last-minute, high-pressure tactic was a direct and cynical exploitation of Conrad&rsquo;s known combat-related TBI.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Harassment and Refusal to Withdraw: </strong>Lakin&rsquo;s misconduct continued after he was fired in August 2025. He demanded an exorbitant payment after already having received a large sum for a retainer. When Conrad told him he was unable to pay, Lakin refused to withdraw from the case and engaged in a series of harassing text messages. He made manipulative financial demands, pressuring Conrad to &ldquo;borrow the money from your wife&rdquo;. When his withdrawal was formally requested, he issued a direct threat, stating that if forced to file a motion, he &ldquo;would have to state the reasons, which frankly might put you in a bad light&rdquo;. This pattern of coercion, threats, and a refusal to withdraw constitutes a profound violation of Conrad Rockenhaus&rsquo;s Sixth Amendment right to the effective assistance of counsel and is the primary basis for the motion to withdraw the coerced guilty plea.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Forced Legal Action: </strong>As a result of this misconduct, Conrad was forced to act as his own attorney, filing pro se motions with the court on August 21 and August 27 asking the judge to order Lakin&rsquo;s removal. A comprehensive formal grievance has since been filed against Marc Lakin with the Michigan Attorney Grievance Commission and was confirmed as received on August 27, 2025.</p><p><strong>The Procedural Trap: A Motion Struck from the Record: </strong>The procedural trap Conrad is caught in was perfectly illustrated on August 29, 2025. After his attorney, Marc Lakin, refused to withdraw from the case, Conrad was forced to take the only action available to him and file his own <em>pro se</em> motions asking the judge to intervene. In response, <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.16.0.pdf">Judge Stephen J. Murphy III struck the filings</a>, citing the standard court rule against &ldquo;hybrid representation,&rdquo; which prevents a defendant from acting for themselves while they have an attorney of record. This created a legal Catch-22: Conrad was required to act through a lawyer who refused to act, and was blocked from acting for himself. The judge deferred a final decision, stating that the issue of Conrad&rsquo;s legal representation will now be addressed at the upcoming supervised release hearing on September 30, 2025, transforming it into a crucial showdown over his constitutional right to effective counsel.</p><h3><strong>The Second Fraudulent Warrant</strong></h3><p>After Lakin&rsquo;s coerced plea put Conrad back under his supervision, <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.12.0.pdf">Officer Agapiou filed a second warrant petition</a> on August 20, 2025, filled with a new set of demonstrably false claims:</p><ul> <li>A fabricated story that Conrad used his vehicle&rsquo;s OnStar service to instruct Adrienne to wipe a seized phone. Official OnStar records prove this call never happened.</li> </ul> <ul> <li>A false claim that his restitution payments had &ldquo;bounced&rdquo;. Verifiable debit card receipts prove the payments were successful.</li> </ul> <ul> <li>A misleading claim of illicit drug use from a positive marijuana screen, while deliberately omitting the fact that Conrad has a legal prescription for Marinol, a medication known to cause such a result.</li> </ul> <h3><strong>A Documented Double Standard: The Case of U.S. v. Jalen Johnson</strong></h3><p>The claim that these punitive actions were standard procedure is verifiably false. <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/65414945/united-states-v-johnson/">Official court records from the case of U.S. v. Jalen Johnson</a>, supervised by the same officer, Jeffry Konal, reveal a stark double standard. Johnson, on supervision for a firearm charge, committed numerous severe and admitted violations, including repeated positive drug tests for marijuana, codeine, morphine, and alcohol, as well as committing new crimes.</p><p>Instead of a punitive warrant, Konal&rsquo;s office responded with a therapeutic approach, referring him to therapy and using a summons to bring him to court. This documented disparate treatment is hard evidence that the actions against Conrad were not procedural, but personal and retaliatory.</p><h3><strong>The &ldquo;Computer Expert&rdquo; Lie: A Fraudulent Basis of Authority</strong></h3><p>From his first interaction, Officer Agapiou built his authority on a lie, misrepresenting himself to Conrad as the probation office&rsquo;s &ldquo;computer forensic expert&rdquo;. This claim is not only verifiably false, but his actual, verified background consists of a Master&rsquo;s degree in Criminal Justice from an online college, and employment as a state corrections agent. This is completely inconsistent with the specialized qualifications of a computer forensic expert.</p><p>It is also irreconcilable with the documented reality of his personal finances. The profile of a highly compensated federal forensics specialist is fundamentally at odds with the need to work a secondary job as an Amazon Flex driver to make ends meet. This deception about his own professional and financial standing establishes a clear pattern of untrustworthiness, calling into question the veracity of every claim made in his official reports.</p><h3><strong>A Fight for Accountability</strong></h3><p>This is not just a case about one veteran. It is about the right of every American to hold government officials accountable without being terrorized.</p><p>&ldquo;When I witnessed a federal officer engage in what I believed to be serious misconduct, I did what any citizen is supposed to do: I filed a detailed, formal complaint through the proper channels,&rdquo; said Adrienne Rockenhaus. &ldquo;The retaliation from the officer&rsquo;s supervisors was immediate and terrifying. We will not be intimidated into silence&rdquo;.</p><p>&ldquo;As a 100% disabled veteran, I was told that supervised release was a process to help me reintegrate,&rdquo; said Conrad Rockenhaus. &ldquo;Instead, my disabilities, especially my Traumatic Brain Injury, have been used as weapons against me. We are fighting for a system that offers veterans justice&hellip; not one that exploits their vulnerabilities for the sake of punishment&rdquo;.</p><p><br>The evidence is clear, the timeline is documented, and the injustice is irrefutable. The question now is one of accountability. Is this the standard of conduct we expect from our federal officers? Contact the <a href="https://www.miep.uscourts.gov/directory.cfm">U.S. Probation Office for the Eastern District of Michigan</a> and ask them.</p></div></article> </main> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:15:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/2025/09/15/zoom-ceo-eric-yuan-three-day-workweek-ai-automation-human-jobs-replaced-future-of-work/</link><title>Zoom’s CEO agrees with Bill Gates, Jensen Huang, and Jamie Dimon: A 3-day workweek is coming soon thanks to AI | Fortune (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://fortune.com/img-assets/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GettyImages-2175654021-e1757947434614.jpg?resize=1200,600' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>However, as more chatbots and automated assistants <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/09/06/godfather-of-ai-geoffrey-hinton-massive-unemployment-soaring-profits-capitalist-system/">take over the</a> duties of human roles, there&rsquo;s a growing cohort of executives who see shorter workweeks on the horizon&mdash;and <a href="https://fortune.com/company/zoom/">Zoom</a> CEO <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/10/09/zoom-ceo-eric-yuan-interview-says-ai-workplace-future-challenge-microsoft-google/">Eric Yuan</a> can even see staffers only clocking in a few days a week.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;I feel like if A.I. can make all of our lives better, why do we need to work for five days a week?&rdquo; Yuan told <em>The New York Times </em>in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/14/business/zoom-meetings-eric-yuan.html">a recent interview</a>. &ldquo;Every company will support three days, four days a week. I think this ultimately frees up everyone&rsquo;s time.&rdquo; </p><p>It&rsquo;s music to the ears of Americans stuck in corporate <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/09/11/what-is-the-great-lock-in-gen-z-millennial-hustle-culture-burnout/">hustle culture</a>, enviously watching their <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/08/28/netherlands-four-day-workweek-europe-us-staffers-grindset-working-women-flexible-schedules-rto-wfh/">European peers</a> trial four-day workweeks <a href="https://fortune.com/europe/2024/11/05/german-workers-4-day-workweek-trial-sleep-exercise-stress/">with major success</a>. And when U.S. performance coaching company Exos <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/04/16/4-day-workweek-success-lower-turnover-more-productivity/">experimented with</a> schedules one workday shorter, it proved to be good for business; employee burnout was cut in half, and productivity soared by 24%. And CEOs agree shorter workweeks born from these automation gains will be terrific for human workers&mdash;even if it means fewer of them have jobs in general.&nbsp; </p><p><em>Fortune </em>reached out to Zoom for comment. </p><h2>Other CEOs including Gates, Huang, and Dimon see a shorter workweek ahead</h2><p>AI tools can be immensely useful for staffers, cutting out everything from menial tasks like emailing to more tedious <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/07/14/goldman-sachs-ai-powered-software-engineer-devin-new-employee-increase-productivity-fears-of-job-replacement/">jobs like coding</a>. Tech leaders are seeing the gains from AI firsthand, and they&rsquo;re promoting the possibility that employees will no longer have to clock in five days a week.&nbsp; </p><p><a href="https://fortune.com/company/microsoft/">Microsoft</a> cofounder Gates first pioneered technology back in the 1970s and 1980s; and now, the billionaire <a href="https://fortune.com/2023/11/23/bill-gates-microsoft-3-day-work-week-machines-make-food/">predicted that</a> AI&rsquo;s current pace of innovation <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/03/27/billionaire-bill-gates-two-day-workweek-ai-replacing-humans/">will remove the need</a> for humans for &ldquo;most things&rdquo; in the next 10 years. When people are no longer needed, those who are left on staff won&rsquo;t have to swipe in daily.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;What will jobs be like? Should we just work like 2 or 3 days a week?&rdquo; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uHY5i9-0tJM">Gates told</a> Jimmy Fallon on <em>The Tonight Show</em> in February. &ldquo;If you zoom out, the purpose of life is not just to do jobs.&rdquo; </p><p><a href="https://fortune.com/company/nvidia/">Nvidia</a> CEO Huang is also on board with the idea of fewer workdays&mdash;but has a catch. The leader of the $4 trillion GPU company <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/08/29/nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-4-day-work-week-productivity/">said that</a> we&rsquo;re just &ldquo;at the beginning of the AI revolution,&rdquo; and if industries continue to adopt artificial intelligence at the current rapid rate, it could &ldquo;probably&rdquo; bring about a four-day workweek. However, that work may only be crammed into a condensed schedule, as Huang predicts that we&rsquo;re going to be &ldquo;busier in the future than now.&rdquo; </p><p>Even the financial industry&mdash;known for putting its workers <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/09/12/jpmorgan-cap-junior-bankers-hours/">through 80-hour workweeks</a>&mdash;may finally get some relief from AI automation. <a href="https://fortune.com/company/jpmorgan-chase/">JPMorgan Chase</a> CEO Dimon predicted years ago that the technology may bring about better work-life balance, although it would &ldquo;of course&rdquo; replace some jobs.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;Your children are going to live to 100 and not have cancer because of technology,&rdquo; Dimon said <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-10-02/dimon-sees-ai-giving-a-3-1-2-day-workweek-to-the-next-generation?sref=2jPYL79S">in an interview</a> with <em>Bloomberg</em> TV back in 2023. &ldquo;And literally they&rsquo;ll probably be working 3 and a half days a week.&rdquo; </p><h2>Zoom CEO admits that some jobs will be erased</h2><p>While workers globally will finally have the opportunity to clock in fewer days per week, not everyone will be enjoying the shortened schedules. Leaders are open to the fact that there will be a massive upheaval in the jobs market, with some roles inevitably automated in the shift. Zoom&rsquo;s CEO doesn&rsquo;t shy away from the reality that some humans will be fired&mdash;but it&rsquo;s just another adjustment, just like the industrial revolution and birth of the internet.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;Whenever there&rsquo;s a technology paradigm shift, some job opportunities are gone, but it will create some new opportunities,&rdquo; Yuan admitted in the interview. &ldquo;For some jobs, like entry-level engineers, we can use A.I. to write code. However, you still need to manage that code. You also create a lot of digital agents, and you need someone to manage those agents.&rdquo; </p><p>Other chief executives like Ford <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/07/05/ford-ceo-jim-farley-ai-white-collar-jobs-essential-economy-skilled-trade-jobs-shortage/">CEO Jim Farley</a> and Klarna leader <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/02/03/klarna-ceo-ai-replacing-human-workers/">Sebastian Siemiatkowski</a> agree that some roles will be erased in the change&mdash;but some, like Huang, think it <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/07/15/jensen-huang-nvidia-ai-layoffs-jobs/">could actually bolster</a> employment. Instead of humans being replaced by AI, the chip leader <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/05/29/billionaire-nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-ai-replace-jobs-if-technology-not-embraced/">claimed that</a> people&rsquo;s roles will be taken over by others who can actually use the advanced tech.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;Over the course of the last 300 years, 100 years, 60 years, even, in the era of computers, not only did productivity go up, employment also went up,&rdquo; Huang <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/07/13/business/video/gps0713-ai-workforce-nvidia-productivity">told <em>CNN</em></a><em> </em>this year. &ldquo;Now the reason for that is if we have an abundance of ideas, ways that we could build a better future, if we were more productive, we could realize that better.&rdquo;</p></div><p><strong>Fortune Global Forum</strong> returns Oct. 26&ndash;27, 2025 in Riyadh. CEOs and global leaders will gather for a dynamic, invitation-only event shaping the future of business. <a href="https://conferences.fortune.com/event/global-forum-2025/summary?utm_source=fortunecom&amp;utm_medium=plealink">Apply for an invitation.</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 02:02:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2025-09-15/california-covid-surge-is-peaking-but-the-battle-over-vaccine-access-is-just-beginning</link><title>California says it can no longer trust Washington on COVID vaccines. A major battle is looming (latimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhn3n1/california_says_it_can_no_longer_trust_washington/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhn3n1/california_says_it_can_no_longer_trust_washington/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 9 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhn3n1/california_says_it_can_no_longer_trust_washington/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://ca-times.brightspotcdn.com/dims4/default/01fd508/2147483647/strip/true/crop/3000x1575+0+213/resize/1200x630!/quality/75/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fcalifornia-times-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Ff0%2F58%2F8f84f20642be95b689007188f656%2F1473411-me-kaiser-covid-vaccines02-cs.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>California&rsquo;s late summer COVID surge is showing signs of peaking, but the state&rsquo;s war with the Trump administration over vaccines is just beginning.</p><p>Coronavirus levels in California&rsquo;s wastewater remain &ldquo;<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nwss/rv/COVID19-national-data.html">very high</a>,&rdquo; according to the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, as they are in much of the country. But some other COVID-19 indicators are starting to fall in the Golden State.</p><p>The shift comes as California state officials and mainstream medical organizations are breaking from the Trump administration&rsquo;s recent revisions to federal vaccine guidelines. </p><p>The changes, made under the leadership of vaccine-skeptic Health and Human Services Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr., have been so dramatic that a number of medical experts and officials now express little to no confidence in two key agencies within that department &mdash; the CDC and Food and Drug Administration. </p><p>A key turning point came in June, when Kennedy <a href="https://www.latimes.com/world-nation/story/2025-06-09/rfk-jr-ousts-entire-cdc-vaccine-advisory-committee">ousted everyone on the</a> CDC&rsquo;s respected Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, which issues recommendations on who should receive various types of vaccines. </p><p>Their replacements &mdash; some of whom have criticized vaccines and spread misinformation, according to the Associated Press &mdash; have led officials and other experts in some states to doubt or dismiss the latest CDC guidance. </p><p>The CDC&rsquo;s immunization committee &ldquo;is no longer a trusted source for vaccine guidance,&rdquo; Dr. Matt Willis, the former public health officer for Marin County, <a href="https://yourlocalepidemiologistca.substack.com/p/measles-death-covid-hospitalizations">wrote</a> on the blog Your Local Epidemiologist in California. </p><p>In the past, medical and scientific groups were confident in the CDC&rsquo;s data analysis and trusted the agency&rsquo;s vaccine guidelines. And so that guidance informed key matters including which vaccines should be covered by insurance, and professional medical societies were aligned on immunization recommendations, according to Dr. Erica Pan, the director of the California Department of Public Health and state health officer. </p><p>&ldquo;Now what we&rsquo;re seeing is a divergence,&rdquo; Pan <a href="https://youtu.be/JfEbRVAvIys?si=xcamtcNPvT-TMlyG&amp;t=107">said</a> during a webinar Tuesday. </p><p>California is moving away from the CDC&rsquo;s guidance and toward recommendations issued by medical groups, such as professional organizations of pediatricians, family physicians, obstetricians and gynecologists. </p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;ll be aligning our immunization recommendations with trusted national medical professional organizations,&rdquo; rather than the CDC, Pan said, &ldquo;given the termination of the vaccine experts with that subject matter expertise.&rdquo; </p><p>A number of local health departments, including from Los Angeles, Orange and San Francisco counties, are endorsing the California Department of Public Health&rsquo;s vaccine guidance.</p><p>A Reuters/Ipsos poll <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/just-1-4-americans-believe-100430636.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly90LmNvLw&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAALKrBUlF4BDB4HTa-L-cnjgk279exuLAe0t27Sqi9YjUc7W8QlV8sHi9WmZtttthgPp_ZJfKrn90MGtnJciVKP4pLmi7E5JGb66svGPuCQTrsH8lkIpzdxoPM62yJd9iBPIae3eaS8wL6oKjaECYYWEab6VxR-geePp_mny7HAaD">said</a> that just 1 in 4 Americans believe that the recommendations for fewer vaccines from the Trump administration were based on scientific evidence and facts.</p><p>California, Washington, Oregon and Hawaii have also united to establish the West Coast Health Alliance, which is intended to provide science-based immunization guidance. Pan said the alliance isn&rsquo;t intended to be a competitor to the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, but to evaluate guidance from other professional medical groups &ldquo;to make recommendations for our states and for our insurers.&rdquo; </p><p>Already, compared with the CDC, the California Department of Public Health has far more expansive recommendations on who should get the now-available updated COVID vaccine. </p><p><a href="https://www.cdph.ca.gov/Programs/CID/DCDC/Pages/COVID-19/Covid19Vaccines.aspx">It recommends</a> that all adults get vaccinated, as the <a href="https://www.aafp.org/news/media-center/statements/aafp-announces-fall-immunization-recommendations-reaffirming-commitment-to-vaccine-safety-and-public-health.html">American Academy of Family Physicians</a> recently endorsed; that those who are pregnant get vaccinated, as endorsed by the <a href="https://www.acog.org/news/news-releases/2025/08/acog-releases-updated-maternal-immunization-guidance-covid-influenza-rsv">American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists</a>; and that the youngest children &mdash; ages 6 months to 23 months &mdash; get vaccinated, as endorsed by the <a href="https://publications.aap.org/aapnews/news/32836">American Academy of Pediatrics</a>. </p><p>California and the pediatricians group also recommend all children with underlying health conditions get vaccinated. They also say any child should be able to get the vaccine if their parents wish. </p><p>The FDA, on the other hand, has approved COVID-19 vaccines only for those ages 65 and older, as well as younger individuals with underlying medical conditions. That means non-senior-age adults may need to either talk with a medical provider before they can get vaccinated or &ldquo;attest&rdquo; to a pharmacy that they have an underlying medical condition that makes them eligible.</p><p>The CDC also recently said that it now has &ldquo;no guidance&rdquo; on whether pregnant women should get the vaccine. </p><p>Some experts have noted that the guidance is contradictory, given that the CDC also says people who are at risk of severe illness if they get COVID-19 should get vaccinated &mdash; and pregnant women are.</p><p>In some states, pharmacy chains are being forced to ask people to bring in a prescription authorizing them to get the COVID-19 vaccine, at least for another week. As of Friday, CVS said that was the case in Arizona, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Maine, North Carolina, Oregon, Utah and West Virginia, as well as the District of Columbia. </p><p>The CDC could be poised to make getting a vaccine even more difficult for some Americans. The Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices is weighing a plan to recommend the COVID-19 vaccine only for those ages 75 and older, and instruct younger people to speak with a healthcare provider before they get the vaccine, the Washington Post <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2025/09/12/covid-vaccine-child-death-cdc/">reported</a> Friday. That could mean an additional hurdle for even younger seniors to get the vaccine. </p><p>The Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices is expected to meet Thursday and Friday. </p><p>There is some indication that vaccine providers are taking an expansive view of who can be inoculated, however. </p><p>Kaiser Permanente unveiled a <a href="https://healthy.kaiserpermanente.org/health-wellness/coronavirus-information/vaccine-appointments?kp_shortcut_referrer=kp.org/covidvaccine">website</a> announcing that its members ages 6 months and older can get the updated COVID vaccine at its facilities at no cost. </p><p>&ldquo;Vaccination remains one of the safest and most effective ways to help protect against severe illness. This includes children and families whose health would be at risk if they got COVID-19,&rdquo; Kaiser says. </p><p>On its site for California members, Kaiser said people don&rsquo;t need to provide additional documentation to get the vaccine, nor do they need an individual prescription. </p><p>The official CDC <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/covid/hcp/clinical-care/underlying-conditions.html">list</a> of conditions that could justify getting the vaccine is also extensive, including risk factors like being overweight, physically inactive or having ever smoked. </p><p>A Times reporter visiting a large retail pharmacy was also told that a qualifying reason for a person under the age of 65 to get the COVID-19 vaccine was if they had a family member who was at risk of severe illness. </p><p>Some Californians were subjected to <a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2025-09-06/vaccine-chaos-even-some-vulnerable-seniors-cant-get-covid-shots-amid-spiking-cases">tough</a> eligibility questions in the first days the shots were available. But Dr. Peter Chin-Hong, a UC San Francisco infectious diseases expert, said that everybody he&rsquo;s talked to recently &ldquo;seem to have been getting it without problems, which is reassuring to me, because I want to get one, too.&rdquo; </p><p>The California Legislature is also taking action. State lawmakers on Friday <a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billNavClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB144">passed</a> Assembly Bill 144, which would <a href="https://leginfo.legislature.ca.gov/faces/billAnalysisClient.xhtml?bill_id=202520260AB144">allow</a> the California Department of Public Health to not just rely on the federal government to outline what kinds of vaccines insurance providers are required to cover, but also take into account guidance from professional medical societies.</p><p>&ldquo;At a time when misinformation is fueling fear and mistrust, we must safeguard the proven standards that keep families and communities healthy,&rdquo; California Medical Assn. President Dr. Shannon Udovic-Constant said in a <a href="https://www.cmadocs.org/newsroom/news/view/ArticleId/50978/CMA-introduces-legislation-to-safeguard-vaccine-access-in-California">statement</a> supporting the legislation.</p><p>Pan <a href="https://youtu.be/JfEbRVAvIys?si=SyMOd7Mo91uvJtpG&amp;t=313">said</a> she expects COVID-19 cases to decline statewide by October. Flu and respiratory syncytial virus are expected to begin ramping up by early October, and the combined respiratory viral season is expected to peak at the end of December and the start of January in California. </p><p>One of the changes to vaccine recommendations this year is <a href="https://www.latimes.com/science/story/2023-05-03/us-approves-1st-vaccine-for-rsv-after-decades-of-attempts">that the RSV vaccine</a> is now recommended for adults as young as 50 who are at increased risk of severe illness, Pan said. Previously, the recommendation was for adults ages 60 to 74 at increased risk for severe illness. All adults ages 75 and older are also recommended to get the RSV vaccine. </p><p>Another disease to watch out for is pertussis, also known as whooping cough. Sen. Bill Cassidy (R-La.), who is also a physician, <a href="https://x.com/SenBillCassidy/status/1966252751400341809">said</a> on social media Thursday that his state is suffering its worst whooping cough outbreak in 35 years, with 368 cases this year, including two infants who died. &ldquo;Most hospitalized were not up-to-date on vaccines,&rdquo; Cassidy wrote. </p><div><h3>More to Read </h3> </div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:47:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://mastodon.social/@chatcontrol/115204439983078498</link><title>Danish Minister of Justice: "We must break with the totally erroneous perception that it is everyone's civil liberty to communicate on encrypted messaging services." (mastodon.social)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhhw1k/danish_minister_of_justice_we_must_break_with_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhhw1k/danish_minister_of_justice_we_must_break_with_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhhw1k/danish_minister_of_justice_we_must_break_with_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://files.mastodon.social/media_attachments/files/115/204/429/589/501/969/original/6cb579f59a0a0da4.png' /></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:42:19 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
