<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;comments=3&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://sbgi.net/sinclair-says-kimmel-suspension-is-not-enough-calls-on-fcc-and-abc-to-take-additional-action/</link><title>Sinclair Says Kimmel Suspension is Not Enough, Calls on FCC and ABC to Take Additional Action (sbgi.net)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><b>Sinclair&rsquo;s ABC stations to air a special in remembrance of Charlie Kirk during Jimmy Kimmel Live timeslot on Friday</b></p><div><p><span>BALTIMORE &ndash; </span>Sinclair, the nation&rsquo;s largest ABC affiliate group, objects to recent comments made by Mr. Kimmel concerning the assassination of Charlie Kirk.</p><p>As discussed with ABC earlier today, Sinclair decided to indefinitely preempt &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; beginning tonight. Following these discussions, ABC has suspended production of &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Mr. Kimmel&rsquo;s remarks were inappropriate and deeply insensitive at a critical moment for our country,&rdquo; said Vice Chairman Jason Smith. &ldquo;We believe broadcasters have a responsibility to educate and elevate respectful, constructive dialogue in our communities. We appreciate FCC Chairman Carr&rsquo;s remarks today and this incident highlights the critical need for the FCC to take immediate regulatory action to address control held over local broadcasters by the big national networks.&rdquo;</p><p>Sinclair&rsquo;s ABC stations will air a special in remembrance of Charlie Kirk this Friday, during Jimmy Kimmel Live&rsquo;s timeslot. The special will also air across all Sinclair stations this weekend. In addition, Sinclair is offering the special to all ABC affiliates across the country.</p><p>Sinclair will not lift the suspension of &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; on our stations until formal discussions are held with ABC regarding the network&rsquo;s commitment to professionalism and accountability.</p><p>Sinclair also calls upon Mr. Kimmel to issue a direct apology to the Kirk family. Furthermore, we ask Mr. Kimmel to make a meaningful personal donation to the Kirk Family and Turning Point USA.</p><p>Regardless of ABC&rsquo;s plans for the future of the program, Sinclair intends not to return &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; to our air until we are confident that appropriate steps have been taken to uphold the standards expected of a national broadcast platform.</p><p><b>About Sinclair:</b></p><p>Sinclair, Inc. (Nasdaq: SBGI) is a diversified media company and a leading provider of local news and sports. The Company owns, operates and/or provides services to 178 television stations in 81 markets affiliated with all major broadcast networks; owns Tennis Channel, the premium destination for tennis enthusiasts; multicast networks CHARGE, Comet, ROAR and The Nest. Sinclair&rsquo;s AMP Media produces a growing portfolio of digital content and original podcasts. Additional information about Sinclair can be found at <a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.sbgi.net%2F&amp;esheet=54326232&amp;newsitemid=20250917446021&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=www.sbgi.net&amp;index=1&amp;md5=3bc3e386c1020c2d9425126f5eab3c3a">www.sbgi.net</a>.</p><p>Category: General</p><p><span>View source version on businesswire.com: </span><span><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250917446021/en/">https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250917446021/en/</a></span></p><p>Media contact: Jessica Bellucci <a href="https://sbgi.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#573d35323b3b2234343e7a341724353023217934383a"><span>[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This company never addressed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_J._Mitchell">that they had a Chairman who abused Virginia Giuffre</a> and suddenly they are conservative?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/netgv0p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Sinclair will not lift the suspension of “Jimmy Kimmel Live!” on our stations until formal discussions are held with ABC regarding the network’s commitment to professionalism and accountability.</p><p>Sinclair also calls upon Mr. Kimmel to issue a direct apology to the Kirk family. Furthermore, we ask Mr. Kimmel to make a meaningful personal donation to the Kirk Family and Turning Point USA.</p></blockquote><p>Not just censorship, but extortion for wrongthink now.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/netdzjm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It. Will. Never. Be. Enough. For. These. People.</p><p>Appeasement of this authoritarian political movement is a bottomless pit.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/netgfu5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:29:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nbcnews.com/pop-culture/tv/disneys-abc-pulls-jimmy-kimmel-live-fcc-chair-blasts-hosts-charlie-kir-rcna232033</link><title>Disney's ABC pulls 'Jimmy Kimmel Live!' after FCC chair criticizes the host's comments | The network confirmed to NBC News it is "indefinitely" pulling the show. (nbcnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630,f_auto,q_auto:best/rockcms/2025-09/250917-jimmy-kimmel-ew-645p-1c7ecc.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Disney&rsquo;s ABC said Wednesday it has pulled &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; off the air &ldquo;indefinitely&rdquo; following the late-night host&rsquo;s comments Monday about the motivations of the man who authorities say fatally shot <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/charlie-kirk-rose-teenage-activist-maga-star-rcna230943">conservative activist Charlie Kirk</a>.</p><p>During his monologue Monday night, Kimmel criticized Republicans for how they responded to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/suspect-charlie-kirk-shooting-tyler-robinson-rcna230504">Kirk&rsquo;s killing</a>.</p><p>&ldquo;The MAGA gang [is] desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them and doing everything they can to score political points from it,&rdquo; Kimmel said.</p><p>Kimmel&rsquo;s representative did not immediately respond to a request for comment on ABC&rsquo;s decision.</p><p>Tyler Robinson is accused of fatally shooting Kirk during an event at Utah Valley University. Kirk was a co-founder of the prominent conservative activist organization Turning Point USA and a high-profile ally of President Donald Trump.</p><p>In the wake of the killing, some on the left had sought to label Robinson a member of the far right. Text messages from Robinson <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/tyler-robinson-text-messages-roommate-charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect-rcna231732">released Tuesday by authorities</a> said he targeted Kirk because Robinson &ldquo;had enough of his hatred.&rdquo;</p><p>Trump lauded the news about Kimmel&rsquo;s suspension, posting on <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115222372625104790">Truth Social</a>, in part: &ldquo;Congratulations to ABC for finally having the courage to do what had to be done.&rdquo;</p><p>ABC's move comes just hours after Federal Communications Commission Chair Brendan Carr threatened to &ldquo;take action&rdquo; against Disney and ABC over Kimmel's remarks. </p><p>In an <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968359685045838041?s=46&amp;t=op3KnRWayVQwe0Xuza3lqQ">interview with conservative commentator Benny Johnson</a>, Carr described Kimmel&rsquo;s remarks as &ldquo;the sickest conduct possible,&rdquo; adding that the FCC could move to revoke ABC affiliate licenses as a punishment.</p><p>In an interview with Fox News host Sean Hannity on Wednesday night, Carr repeatedly referred to Trump&rsquo;s election and said, &ldquo;There&rsquo;s more work to go." The "legacy media," he said, "threw everything" at Trump.</p><p>&ldquo;We at the FCC are going to enforce the public interest obligation,&rdquo; Carr said. &ldquo;If there&rsquo;s broadcasters out there that don&rsquo;t like it, they can turn their license in to the FCC.&rdquo; </p><p>FCC member Anna Gomez, a Biden appointee and the lone Democrat on the panel, <a href="https://x.com/AGomezFCC/status/1968406707484144057">sharply criticized Carr on X, </a>saying, &ldquo;This Administration is increasingly using the weight of government power to suppress lawful expression.&rdquo;</p><p>Following Carr's comments to Johnson, Nexstar Media Group Inc. <a href="https://www.nexstar.tv/nexstar-abc-affiliates-to-preempt-jimmy-kimmel-live-indefinitely-beginning-tonight/">announced that the company&rsquo;s</a> ABC affiliates will pre-empt &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; for the foreseeable future, beginning with Wednesday night&rsquo;s show. Nexstar has more than 200 stations in the United States and is waiting on FCC approval for <a href="https://www.nexstar.tv/nexstar-media-group-inc-enters-into-definitive-agreement-to-acquire-tegna-inc-for-6-2-billion-in-accretive-transaction/">a $6.2 billion acquisition of Tegna</a>.</p><p>Carr <a href="https://x.com/BrendanCarrFCC/status/1968449919221416427">thanked Nexstar on X </a>"for doing the right thing."</p><p>"Local broadcasters have an obligation to serve the public interest," he wrote. "While this may be an unprecedented decision, it is important for broadcasters to push back on Disney programming that they determine falls short of community values." </p><p>Asked for comment, a spokesperson for the FCC referred NBC News to Carr's post on X. </p><p>The American late-night television landscape is embattled amid sagging ratings and other pressures. Two months ago, CBS announced it was permanently ending &ldquo;The Late Show with Stephen Colbert,&rdquo; saying the move was &ldquo;purely a financial decision against a challenging backdrop in late night.&rdquo; Many of Colbert&rsquo;s fans suggested he was being punished for his long history of criticizing Trump.</p><p>Some on the right have called for people who spoke out against Kirk following his killing to face consequences. Since Kirk was killed, institutions from airlines to schools have moved quickly to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/charlie-kirk-death-teachers-professors-nationwide-fired-disciplined-s-rcna230845">discipline employees</a> accused of celebrating or mocking his death. </p><p>Steve Bannon, a right-wing pundit and former Trump adviser, called for mass arrests and a crackdown on universities, while<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/national-security/hegseth-pentagon-staff-negative-charlie-kirk-posts-service-members-rcna230915"> Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth</a> has directed staff members to identify and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/military">discipline service members </a>who mocked or condoned Kirk&rsquo;s killing, two defense officials told NBC News.</p><p>But Kimmel&rsquo;s removal is by far the highest-profile move yet, even as <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/justice-department/attorney-general-pam-bondi-backlash-right-hate-speech-rcna231713">some on the right have criticized the idea</a> of cracking down on people who spoke against Kirk.</p><p>&ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; debuted in 2003, and Kimmel has since cemented himself in the late-night space, becoming one of the highest-profile comedians on television, hosting the Academy Awards and the Emmy Awards. </p><p>He also emerged as a staunch critic of Trump, with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2024/mar/10/trump-oscars-truth-jimmy-kimmel">Trump at times biting back</a>. </p><p>Trump, who in recent years has ramped up pressure on major media organizations with a series of lawsuits, sued ABC, ABC News and George Stephanopoulos for defamation over an interview with Rep. Nancy Mace, R-S.C. ABC settled the lawsuits for $15 million.</p><p>The president of the American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada, the union that represents musicians employed by Kimmel&rsquo;s show, accused the Trump administration of an attack on free speech.</p><p>&ldquo;This is not complicated: Trump&rsquo;s FCC identified speech it did not like and threatened ABC with extreme reprisals,&rdquo; union President Tino Gagliardi <a href="https://www.afm.org/2025/09/statement-kimmel-live/">said in a statement Wednesday night</a>. &ldquo;This is state censorship. It&rsquo;s now happening in the United States of America, not some far-off country. It&rsquo;s happening right here and right now.&rdquo;</p><p>In their own statements, the Writers Guild of America, Screen Actors Guild and the American Civil Liberties Union also condemned Kimmel&rsquo;s suspension and framed it as government overreach. </p><p>&ldquo;If free speech applied only to ideas we like, we needn&rsquo;t have bothered to write it into the Constitution,&rdquo; the WGA said, adding that it &ldquo;stands with Jimmy Kimmel and his writers.&rdquo;</p><p>Comedian Wanda Sykes <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DOuYySkCfPB/?hl=en">said in an Instagram video</a> that she was supposed to be on Kimmel's show Wednesday, and she criticized Trump.</p><p>&ldquo;So, let&rsquo;s see: He didn&rsquo;t end the Ukraine war or solve Gaza within his first week, but he did end freedom of speech within his first year,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;Hey, for those of you who pray, now&rsquo;s the time to do it. Love you, Jimmy.&rdquo;</p></div><div><div><p><span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/author/rebecca-keegan-ncpn1312732">Rebecca Keegan</a></span></p><p>Rebecca Keegan is the senior Hollywood reporter for NBC News Digital, where she covers the entertainment industry.</p></div><div><p><span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/author/daniel-arkin-ncpn1206">Daniel Arkin</a></span></p><p>Daniel Arkin is a national reporter at NBC News.</p></div><div><p>Emilie Dorn</p><p>, </p><p>Mirna Alsharif</p><p>, </p><p>Jason Abbruzzese</p><p>and </p><p>Phil Helsel</p><p>contributed</p><p>.</p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_focal-60x60,f_auto,q_auto:best/newscms/2024_47/3669551/241118-daniel-arkin.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Hey do you all remember last month or so when Colbert was cancelled and Trump said &quot;Kimmel is next&quot;? </p><p>The people who claim free speech is being targeted are targeting free speech.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/neso5l4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Brian Kilmeade just said on Fox News we should forcefully euthanize the homeless and he still has his job. If people don’t start making these corporations pay we will lose everything. Boycott Disney, Boycott ABC, Boycott Paramount and start preparing for a General Strike. Power to the people!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/nesrmr4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We&#39;re seeing the erosion of the First Amendment in real time. FCC pressure as a condition of the Paramount merger is leading <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/10/business/media/cbs-news-bari-weiss-free-press.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mk8.CQD7.wxXBlHNkn3tD&amp;smid=url-share">CBS to cede editorial control to the right wing as a demonstration of loyalty</a>.</p><p>Years down the line, even if things get better, I&#39;m never going to forget how easily our legacy media bent to the will of illiberalism.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/nesn0c3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:46:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/fcc-jimmy-kimmel-charlie-kirk-monologue-1236373708/</link><title>FCC Chair Threatens Jimmy Kimmel Over Monologue Comments (hollywoodreporter.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/174499_0888-H-2025.jpg?w=1296&h=730&crop=1' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/e/live-feed/"> <span>Logo text</span> </a> </p><p><a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/t/jimmy-kimmel/">Jimmy Kimmel</a>&lsquo;s latest monologue has ignited a political firestorm and resulted in ABC suspending the show. </p><p>Kimmel&rsquo;s comments about the <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/t/charlie-kirk/">Charlie Kirk</a> shooting during Tuesday&rsquo;s show drew condemnation from Federal Communications Commission chair <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/t/brendan-carr/">Brendan Carr</a>. That, in turn, prompted one group of ABC affiliates, owned by Nexstar Media Group, to declare they will not air <em>Jimmy Kimmel Live!</em> for the immediate future, which then led ABC to announce the show was being taken off the air &ldquo;indefinitely.&rdquo; </p><p>The uproar started after Kimmel said suspected Kirk assassin Tyler Robinson was a MAGA Republican. &ldquo;We hit some new lows over the weekend with the MAGA gang desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them and doing everything they can to score political points from it,&rdquo; Kimmel said. </p><p>Carr was interviewed by <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968359685045838041">YouTuber</a> <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968359685045838041">Benny Johnson</a> on Wednesday (video also below), where he appeared to threaten ABC affiliate licenses over the comments, which he called &ldquo;the sickest conduct possible.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;[This] appears to be an action by Jimmy Kimmel to play into the narrative that this was somehow a MAGA or Republican-motivated person,&rdquo; Carr said. &ldquo;What people don&rsquo;t understand is that the broadcasters &hellip; have a license granted by us at the FCC, and that comes with it an obligation to operate in the public interest. When we see stuff like this, look, we can do this the easy way or the hard way. These companies can find ways to change conduct, on Kimmel, or there&rsquo;s going to be additional work for the FCC ahead.&rdquo;</p><p>Johnson said he&rsquo;d like to see an apology from Kimmel to Kirk and his family and asked Carr what other punitive steps the FCC might take. </p><p>&ldquo;I think what you said strikes me as a very reasonable, minimal step that can be taken,&rdquo; Carr said. &ldquo;Calls for Kimmel to be fired &mdash; I think, you could certainly see a path forward for a suspension over this. You know, the FCC is going to have remedies.&rdquo;</p><p>Carr then ran down some of the media earthquakes that have transpired under the second Trump administration, from Stephen Colbert&rsquo;s <em>The Late Show</em> being canceled next year, to NPR and PBS being defunded, to CBS News taking steps to be more &ldquo;fact based.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;So I think you see some lashing out from people like Kimmel, who are frankly talentless and are looking for ways to get attention,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Their grip on the narrative is slipping. That doesn&rsquo;t mean that it&rsquo;s not still important to hold the public interest standard &hellip; We have a rule on the book that interprets the public interest standard that says &lsquo;news distortion&rsquo; is something that is prohibited &hellip; the FCC has stepped back from enforcing it &hellip; I think it&rsquo;s past time these [affiliates] themselves push back on Comcast and this and say, &lsquo;Listen, we&rsquo;re not going to run Kimmel anymore until you straighten this out because we&rsquo;re running the possibility of license revocation from the FCC if we continue to run content that ends up being a pattern of news distortion.&rsquo; So I think again, Disney needs to see some change here.&rdquo; (Note: Comcast owns NBC Universal; Disney owns ABC.)</p><p>Nexstar then issued the following statement in response to Carr&rsquo;s comments: &ldquo;Nexstar&rsquo;s owned and partner television stations affiliated with the ABC Television Network will preempt <em>Jimmy Kimmel Live!</em> for the foreseeable future beginning with tonight&rsquo;s show. Nexstar strongly objects to recent comments made by Mr. Kimmel concerning the killing of Charlie Kirk and will replace the show with other programming in its ABC-affiliated markets.&rdquo; Nexstar currently operates 28 ABC affiliates across the country, mostly in small or midsize markets, though they include the ABC stations in New Orleans and Salt Lake City. </p><p>&ldquo;Mr. Kimmel&rsquo;s comments about the death of Mr. Kirk are o&#64256;ensive and insensitive at a critical time in our national political discourse, and we do not believe they reflect the spectrum of opinions, views, or values of the local communities in which we are located,&rdquo; added Andrew Alford, President of Nexstar&rsquo;s broadcasting division. &ldquo;Continuing to give Mr. Kimmel a broadcast platform in the communities we serve is simply not in the public interest at the current time, and we have made the di&#64259;cult decision to preempt his show in an e&#64256;ort to let cooler heads prevail as we move toward the resumption of respectful, constructive dialogue.&rdquo;</p><div><p>The affiliate group pulling Kimmel was quickly followed by ABC announcing the show had been suspended. A network spokesperson said&nbsp;<em>Jimmy Kimmel Live!</em>&nbsp;will be &ldquo;pre-empted indefinitely.&rdquo;</p><p>Yet Carr&rsquo;s tactics drew fire from within the department itself as FCC Commissioner Anna Gomez responded on social media by criticizing the Chair&rsquo;s threats.</p></div><p>&ldquo;An inexcusable act of political violence by one disturbed individual must never be exploited as justification for broader censorship or control,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/AGomezFCC/status/1968406707484144057">Gomez wrote</a>. &ldquo;This Administration is increasingly using the weight of government power to suppress lawful expression, not because it glorifies violence or breaks the law, but because it challenges those in power or reflects views they oppose.&nbsp;We must stand firm against every attempt to silence dissent, punish satirists and government critics, and erode individual liberty. To surrender our right to speak freely is to accept that those in power, not the people, will set the boundaries of debate that define a free society.&rdquo;</p><figure></figure> <figure><p><iframe title="Jimmy Kimmel LIES About Charlie Kirk Killer, Blames Charlie For His Murder!? Disney Must Fire Kimmel" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uTyX9JC-rhA?feature=oembed"></iframe> </p></figure> </div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Now apply the same standards to Fox News.  Oh what, crickets?  Surprising.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/nerj5yc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How’s that free speech going over there?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/neri956/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The FCC Chair threatening to pull ABC affiliate licensees over content he didn’t like? Now THAT sounds like an actual first amendment violation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/nerjd7k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:18:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.polygon.com/steam-discord-twitch-reddit-congress-politics/</link><title>Steam, Discord, and Twitch execs called to testify before Congress over 'radicalization' of users (polygon.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article> <header><p>House Oversight Committee to grill CEOs over platforms being 'exploited for nefarious purposes'</p><h2>Steam, Discord, and Twitch execs called to testify before Congress over 'radicalization' of users</h2> <a><p>Sign in to your <span>Polygon</span> account</p></a><div><figure><picture> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=49&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=480&amp;dpr=2"> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=49&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=767&amp;dpr=2"> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=49&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=943&amp;dpr=2"> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=70&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1140&amp;dpr=1"> <img width="1600" height="900" alt="Photo of Rep. James Comer speaking" src="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?w=1600&amp;h=900&amp;fit=crop"> </source></source></source></source></picture> <small>Photo: Office of James Comer</small> </figure> </div></header><div><p>The CEOs of Discord, Steam, Twitch, and Reddit have been called to Congress to testify about the "radicalization of online forum users" on those platforms, the <a href="https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-invites-ceos-of-discord-steam-twitch-and-reddit-to-testify-on-radicalization-of-online-forum-users/">House Oversight and Government Reform Committee announced Wednesday</a>.</p><p>"Congress has a duty to oversee the online platforms that radicals have used to advance political violence," said chairman of the House Oversight Committee James Comer, a Republican from Kentucky, in a statement. "To prevent future radicalization and violence, the CEOs of Discord, Steam, Twitch, and Reddit must appear before the Oversight Committee and explain what actions they will take to ensure their platforms are not exploited for nefarious purposes."</p><p>Letters from the House Oversight Committee have been sent to Humam Sakhnini, CEO of Discord; Gabe Newell, president of Steam maker Valve; Dan Clancy, CEO of Twitch; and Steve Huffman, CEO of Reddit, requesting their testimony on Oct. 8. "The hearing will examine radicalization of online forum users, including incidents of open incitement to commit violent politically motivated acts," Comer said in a letter to each CEO.</p><p>The catalyst for Comer's request is the killing of Charlie Kirk, the right-wing political activist and media personality who was shot at Utah Valley University last week. The suspect in that case, Tyler Robinson, is <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/2025/09/15/charlie-kirk-shooter-suspect-discord-chat/">reported to have used Discord</a> to discuss the killing after the fact, and is alleged to have been <a href="https://www.polygon.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-helldivers-2-meme-tyler-robinson/">steeped in online meme culture</a>.</p><p>Steam and Discord have long been homes for extremists to gather, coordinate, and harass their perceived enemies, despite both platforms being aimed at gamers and designed originally for non-political purposes. The 2017 white supremacist rally Unite the Right in Charlottesville, Virginia was planned through Discord, and the platform was used by far-right mass shooters in the 2022 Buffalo shooting and the Highland Park Parade shooting. In 2024, the <a href="https://www.adl.org/resources/report/steam-powered-hate-top-gaming-site-rife-extremism-antisemitism">Anti-Defamation League</a> reported that Steam was "rife with extremism and antisemitism" across Steam Community groups. Congress has <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/senator-asks-gabe-newell-why-steam-hosts-so-much-neo-nazi-content/">previously pressed Newell</a> on the "significant presence of users displaying and espousing neo-Nazi, extremist, racial supremacist, misogynistic, and other hateful sentiments" on Steam.</p><p>Discord, Steam, Twitch, and Reddit execs will have the chance to deliver five-minute opening statements prior to answering questions posed by members of the committee during October's testimony.</p></div></article> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress%2Fwp-content%2Fauthors%2F685c4d7dc4454-Michael-McWhertor-Green-Purple-2.jpg?fit=crop&amp;w=90&amp;h=90"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Born too late for McCarthyismBorn just in time for McCarthyism</p><p>Edited spelling</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/ner0oa8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here comes the censorship hammer, I was wondering what the long game was, shocker it’s the erosion of freedom</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/ner16ax/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s funny that X (formerly Twitter) isn&#39;t included in this, even though that&#39;s arguably the worse out of all of them. I wonder why...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/neqz8ie/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:52:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/09/16/she-pushed-to-overturn-trumps-loss-in-the-2020-election-now-shell-help-oversee-u-s-election-security/</link><title>She Pushed To Overturn The Loss In The 2020 Election | Now She’ll Help Oversee U.S. Election Security. (techdirt.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: Heather Honey, a high-profile denier of Donald Trump’s loss in the 2020 election, has been appointed to a senior position in the U.S. Department of Homeland Security in which she’ll help oversee the nation’s election infrastructure.</p><p>Honey is a protege of Cleta Mitchell, a lawyer who tried to help Trump overturn the 2020 election results. In 2024, ProPublica reported that Honey had played a key role in Mitchell’s behind-the-scenes effort to change Georgia’s election rules to allow Republican officials to contest a potential Trump loss in that year’s presidential race. Honey also promoted election conspiracy theories, including one Trump cited in a speech to his followers before they stormed the Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021.</p><p>Though states do the on-the-ground work of running elections, DHS supports them with tasks beyond their capacities, such as protecting IT infrastructure and voter databases from foreign intrusions. The agency, with bipartisan support, took on this role in the aftermath of Russia’s interference in the 2016 election.</p><p>Experts on voting and state election officials warned that Honey’s appointment as DHS’ deputy assistant secretary of election integrity could erode trust between state and federal officials, prompting states not to share information with the agency.</p><p>“We are witnessing a dangerous trend: the elevation of known bad-faith actors like Heather Honey,” said Adrian Fontes, Arizona’s Democratic secretary of state, in a statement, citing Honey’s “well-documented history of spreading election lies that have been debunked in court.”</p><p>Fontes called her involvement with DHS “deeply troubling” and said “when the agency gives a platform to individuals who have actively worked to erode public trust, it becomes harder to view DHS as a reliable partner in election security.”</p><p>A DHS spokesperson did not answer questions from ProPublica on Honey’s appointment or the exact nature of her responsibilities. Honey didn’t respond to calls or emails. The White House also didn’t respond to a request for comment. Her name is listed on the organization’s leadership structure online, and her appointment was first reported by the website Democracy Docket.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/nep852u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s not who votes that counts. It&#39;s who counts the votes. - Stalin</p><p>Who else would you use if the only thing that matters is the result, not the integrity of the election?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/nep9ugv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Finally, Trump is keeping a campaign promise. If you voted for him, you’ll never have to vote again. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/nepb82t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:47:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/china/oracle-silver-lake-consortium-control-80-stake-tiktok-us-wsj-reports-2025-09-16/</link><title>TikTok US will be sold to Oracle, Silver Lake, A16Z, with a US based board including a US gov member. Will require users to shift to a new App (reuters.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nj5c7p/tiktok_us_will_be_sold_to_oracle_silver_lake_a16z/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nj5c7p/tiktok_us_will_be_sold_to_oracle_silver_lake_a16z/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nj5c7p/tiktok_us_will_be_sold_to_oracle_silver_lake_a16z/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>So, the US will get one app, the rest of the world a different one? Seems like there will be a lot more to unpack from that kinda throw away line...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nj5c7p/tiktok_us_will_be_sold_to_oracle_silver_lake_a16z/neo1wkk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tiktok are getting paid to exit the US market, while Oracle gets to use their name to set up a new app that nobody will use</p><p>Art of the deal</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nj5c7p/tiktok_us_will_be_sold_to_oracle_silver_lake_a16z/neo40wf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Soooo... US is getting a dedicated social media app controller by the government (at least partially). Where have I seen that...</p><p>Also, Oracle 🤮</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nj5c7p/tiktok_us_will_be_sold_to_oracle_silver_lake_a16z/neoanbw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 11:39:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2025/09/mods-react-as-reddit-kicks-some-of-them-out-again-this-will-break-the-site/</link><title>Reddit will force some mods to quit, sparking fear of lies, slurs running “amok” (arstechnica.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nitgbv/reddit_will_force_some_mods_to_quit_sparking_fear/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nitgbv/reddit_will_force_some_mods_to_quit_sparking_fear/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nitgbv/reddit_will_force_some_mods_to_quit_sparking_fear/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GettyImages-2203349473-1024x648.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Ars asked Reddit if the new limits are a response to power mods, and Reddit spokesperson Tim Rathschmidt responded:</p><blockquote><p>This is not a judgment of any specific moderator or mod practices; it&rsquo;s a structural change. Establishing limits sitewide creates a solution for both the present and the future that is not tied to any individual mods.</p></blockquote> <h2>Reporting changes</h2><p>In addition to concerns about the new mod limits, several mods I spoke to worry that Reddit will announce that it will no longer reply to reports about user behavior or removed content. Also, moderator-removed comments will automatically disappear from user profiles. Currently, "that content continues to appear on the user profile until it&rsquo;s reported and additionally removed by Reddit," per Go_JasonWaterfalls. They noted that Reddit will still review all mod reports.</p><p>"[M]ost violative content is already caught by our automated and human review systems," the admin said. "And in the event we make a mistake and miss something, mods are empowered to remove it."</p><p>There's concern among mods that these changes will result in users not being actioned against when they should be, and Reddit missing things that warrant alerting authorities.</p><p>In response, Rathschmidt told Ars via&nbsp;email:</p><blockquote><p>Keeping Reddit safe and healthy is our highest priority, and a goal we share with&nbsp;<span>mods</span>. This will not change how we action users who break&nbsp;<a href="https://support.reddithelp.com/hc/en-us/articles/360043503951-What-are-Reddit-s-rules">Reddit Rules</a>.</p></blockquote><p>However, there remains concern about Reddit overlooking bad content.</p><p>&ldquo;They are claiming that... they correctly action the vast majority of reports they get, but experience from our mod team suggests that isn't the case," a mod who requested to be referred to by their username, Gregory_K_Zhukov, for privacy, told Ars. They said that they've seen problems with Holocaust denial and "clearly aggressive and racist" use of the n-word persisting on subreddits.</p><p>The second mod, who requested anonymity, shared a similar view and perceives Reddit's recent policy changes as attempts to "eschew responsibility."</p><p>"Xenophobia, slurs, transphobia, outright death threats and hate speech, calls for violence, disinformation, and spam are let to run amok because of these policy decisions," they said.</p><p>Gregory_K_Zhukov also questioned whether Reddit automatically deletes mod-removed comments from profiles. They argued that this makes modding harder by limiting the amount of information available, including whether or not Reddit has previously punished a user for similar behavior.</p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Further, subreddits will stop displaying subscriber counts and instead show their “unique number of unique visitors over the last seven days, based on a rolling 28-day average,” Reddit’s rep said. Notably, old.reddit.com will not get these new stats but will still lose subscriber counts.</p></blockquote><p>curious change of pace there</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nitgbv/reddit_will_force_some_mods_to_quit_sparking_fear/nelg72x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>, a small number of users will be required to leave some of their moderator posts so that they aren’t moderating more than five subreddits with 100,000 monthly visitors.</p></blockquote><p>Does anyone but the eternally online powermods who “control” HUNDREDS of subreddits have a problem with this?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nitgbv/reddit_will_force_some_mods_to_quit_sparking_fear/nelntyl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sounds like a good thing to me, it&#39;s weird that there are some apparent power mods who moderate tons of large subreddits.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nitgbv/reddit_will_force_some_mods_to_quit_sparking_fear/nell6zs/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 02:22:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newrepublic.com/article/200471/peter-thiel-obsession-antichrist-religion</link><title>What’s Up With Peter Thiel’s Obsession With the Antichrist? (newrepublic.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.newrepublic.com/b0701cad31869b310dd5255c8c3ae0648d712613.jpeg?w=1200&h=630&crop=faces&fit=crop&fm=jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article><div><div><p>In yet another troubling sign of these times, Peter Thiel can&rsquo;t stop talking up the Antichrist. This month, the tech billionaire is delivering a four-part, closed-door <a href="https://luma.com/antichrist">lecture</a> on the topic, which he is framing as &ldquo;political theology,&rdquo; in San Francisco. It&rsquo;s part of what you might call an &ldquo;Antichrist World Tour&rdquo; by the PayPal and Palantir co-founder, who has already given off-the-record Antichrist lectures at Oxford, Harvard, and Bari Weiss&rsquo;s ersatz college, the University of Austin.</p><p>It&rsquo;s not clear why Thiel needs secrecy to hold forth on his latest obsession. He&rsquo;s been pontificating about the Antichrist in public talks for years. During a June <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/26/opinion/peter-thiel-antichrist-ross-douthat.html">interview</a> with <i>The</i> <i>New York Times,</i> Thiel offered extended thoughts on the shadowy figure, barely mentioned in the Bible, who according to legend (and countless pulp horror movies) will arise to help Satan kick off Armageddon. He even named a suspect: Greta Thunberg. (The interview went viral when Thiel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/LXpc1YiXDoQ">struggled</a> to answer a question about whether he wants the human race to endure.)</p></div><div><p>Thiel is not a theologian, scholar, or prophet. So why pay attention to his biblical musings? Because Thiel is one of the world&rsquo;s most influential men and his Antichrist speeches reveal his deep belief that religion is a weapon for political warfare&mdash;and he&rsquo;s right.</p><p>Thiel&rsquo;s Antichrist fixation fits a long tradition in American politics. Since the nation&rsquo;s founding, Americans have sought to name the Antichrist&mdash;usually by pointing the finger at their political enemies. &ldquo;The symbol of the Antichrist has played a surprisingly significant role in shaping Americans&rsquo; self-understanding,&rdquo; wrote historian Robert Fuller in 1995&rsquo;s <a href="https://archive.org/details/namingantichrist0000full_w6k9"><i>Naming the Antichrist</i></a><i>: The History of an American Obsession. &ldquo;</i>Because they tend to view their nation as uniquely blessed by God, they have been especially prone to demonize their enemies.&rdquo;</p><p>Over time, the identity of Satan&rsquo;s Little Helper has shifted from Native Americans to Communists, Hitler and Saddam Hussein and Barack Obama&mdash;even barcodes and microchips have been implicated. From colonial days to the AI era, the hunt for the Antichrist continues. Today&rsquo;s QAnon conspiracy theorists believe they are battling a cabal of cannibalistic Satanists. <i>Unhumans</i>, a 2024 book <a href="https://www.thenerdreich.com/unhumans-jd-vance-and-the-language-of-genocide/?ref=theframelab.org">praised by JD Vance</a>, equated <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/08/05/opinion/jd-vance-fascism-unhumans.html">progressives</a> with bloodthirsty &ldquo;unhuman&rdquo; creatures. This turns politics into a zero-sum holy war.</p></div><div><p>&ldquo;Once we label our adversaries in these cosmic terms&mdash;all good versus all evil&mdash;now there&rsquo;s going to be no compromise,&rdquo; said Fuller.</p><p>Thiel understands this. He frames his interest in the Antichrist as part of his own &ldquo;political theology,&rdquo; a term he borrows from <a href="https://claremontreviewofbooks.com/the-nazi-jurist/">Carl Schmitt</a>, a Nazi philosopher who defined the practice of politics as a struggle against an existential enemy, arguing that politics is just religion in disguise. Thiel also draws on Ren&eacute; Girard, a Catholic thinker (and one of Thiel&rsquo;s Stanford professors) who warned that human societies tend to spiral toward violence in a hunt for scapegoats.</p><p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s always a question of whether politics is like a market &hellip; or is it something like a scapegoating machine, where the scapegoating machine only works if you don&rsquo;t look into the sausage factory?&rdquo; Thiel <a href="https://youtu.be/vfbndRTlsg4?si=7sAtBdMnzlyDFaMv&amp;t=2302">said</a>, during a 2024 talk at Stanford. He explained the mechanism: &ldquo;If, say, we&rsquo;re having a lot of conflicts in our village and we have to find some random elderly woman and accuse her of witchcraft so that we&rsquo;ll achieve some psychosocial unity as a village &hellip; this sort of thing doesn&rsquo;t really work if you&rsquo;re self-aware.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>Thiel knows these dynamics well, but it&rsquo;s not clear whether he&rsquo;s horrified or impressed. His talks stop short of providing solutions. Instead, they meld Schmitt, Girard, and scripture into an incisive meditation on the power of apocalyptic ideas. Thiel positions himself as someone trying to help the world navigate a &ldquo;narrow path&rdquo; between Armageddon and Antichrist. But his rhetoric also sketches a playbook for holy war, scapegoating, crisis, and power&mdash;since Schmitt famously argued that power consolidates during existential crises, when constitutions can be suspended.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re told that there&rsquo;s nothing worse than Armageddon, but perhaps there is,&rdquo; said Thiel during a <a href="https://youtu.be/fQ4rc7npiXQ?si=giiMtr0qT7kdE5xR&amp;t=1661">talk at Oxford</a> in 2023. &ldquo;Perhaps we should fear the Antichrist, perhaps we should fear the one-world totalitarian state more than Armageddon.&rdquo;</p><p>He is already experimenting with this doomsday script: In January, he wrote an <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/a46cb128-1f74-4621-ab0b-242a76583105">op-ed</a> framing Donald Trump&rsquo;s return to power as an &ldquo;<i>apok&aacute;lypsis</i>&rdquo;&mdash;an &ldquo;unveiling&rdquo; of hidden truth and a chance to cleanse the nation&rsquo;s &ldquo;sins.&rdquo; And in his religion talks, Thiel does not hesitate to name potential Antichrists, including Greta Thunberg, communism, and even tech regulation. This reveals a telling urge to wield scripture as political weaponry.</p></div><div><p>Yet his approach has major flaws. For example, Thiel claims the Antichrist will be someone focused on existential threats and apocalypse, and who will usher in a totalitarian world government under the slogan of &ldquo;peace and safety.&rdquo; But Thiel&rsquo;s Antichrist checklist&mdash;a paranoid obsession with apocalypse, control, and surveillance&mdash;describes Thiel himself.</p><p>Thiel co-founded <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/05/30/technology/trump-palantir-data-americans.html">Palantir</a>, a software company literally named after an all-seeing orb controlled by an evil wizard in <i>The Lord of the Rings</i>. Palantir is partnering with the Trump administration to supercharge government surveillance at a moment when the president openly embraces authoritarianism. The irony is so striking it almost seems like a confession. As comedian Tim Dillon quipped on Joe Rogan&rsquo;s podcast recently: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s so strange.&hellip; You build domestic surveillance technology to surveil our friends and neighbors&mdash;and then your other pet passion is the Antichrist.&rdquo;</p><p>Thiel isn&rsquo;t alone in mimicking religious themes. Billionaire Nicole Shanahan recently declared <a href="https://www.thenerdreich.com/demonic-silicon-valley-billionaire-blasts-burning-man/">Burning Man</a> &ldquo;demonic,&rdquo; while Andreessen Horowitz partner <a href="https://x.com/KTmBoyle/status/1894133112881516994?ref=thenerdreich.com">Katherine Boyle</a> has invoked Christ&rsquo;s crucifixion to argue that governments destroy families. Trae Stephens, a Thiel ally and self-proclaimed &ldquo;arms dealer&rdquo; who co-founded the drone warfare company <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/christians-silicon-valley-religion-venture-capital/">Anduril</a> (another warped <i>Lord of the Rings</i> reference), frames his work as part of a quest to &ldquo;carry out God&rsquo;s command to bring his Kingdom to earth as it is in Heaven.&rdquo; Stephens&rsquo;s wife, Michelle, co-founded ACTS 17 Collective (Acknowledging Christ in Technology and Society), which evangelizes to tech workers and is hosting Thiel&rsquo;s Antichrist lectures.</p></div><div><p>Meanwhile in Russia, Alexander Dugin&mdash;an ultranationalist philosopher and propagandist known as &ldquo;Putin&rsquo;s brain&rdquo;&mdash;is the only other major political figure who fixates on the Antichrist as much as Thiel. In Dugin&rsquo;s version, Russia is at war with the Antichrist, which is liberal modernity emanating from the &ldquo;<a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/311974964_Alexander_Dugin_Building_a_Bridge_between_Eschatology_and_Conspiracy">country of apocalypse</a>&rdquo;&mdash;the United States.</p><p>Not everyone is convinced by Silicon Valley&rsquo;s pivot to piety. At the National Conservatism Conference this month, some traditional religious conservatives railed against their would-be tech brethren. Conservative firebrand Geoffrey Miller blasted artificial intelligence developers as &ldquo;betrayers of our species&rdquo; and &ldquo;apostates to our faith,&rdquo; calling for what <a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/773154/maga-tech-right-ai-natcon">The Verge</a> described as a &ldquo;literal holy war&rdquo; against tech. </p><p>After all, if we&rsquo;re hunting for existential enemies, Silicon Valley&rsquo;s diabolically greedy tech billionaires&mdash;who wish to create &ldquo;godlike&rdquo; AI systems powerful enough to destroy humanity&mdash;top the list. But we must avoid falling into the Antichrist name-calling trap. Instead of asking, &ldquo;Who is the Antichrist?&rdquo; we must ask, &ldquo;Why is a tech billionaire trying to convince us we&rsquo;re on the brink of apocalypse?&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>These rehashed <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/31/us/satanic-panic.html">Satanic panic</a> tactics must be exposed for what they are: a cynical ploy to further inflame political divisions. It also seems like an awkward effort to cement an alliance with religious nationalists in the Republican Party, who also use apocalyptic language to frame their political goals. Journalist Matthew D&rsquo;Ancona described Thiel&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.thenewworld.co.uk/matthew-dancona-peter-thiel-and-the-antichrist/">Antichrist theories</a> as a &ldquo;highbrow version of MAGA End-Times theology.&rdquo;</p><p>But naming the Antichrist is a dangerous tactic that often leads to crisis and violence.</p><p>&ldquo;The whole concept of the Antichrist &hellip; fosters a crisis mentality,&rdquo; said Fuller, the Antichrist historian. &ldquo;And with the crisis mentality, now we put aside all other differences. There&rsquo;s a tribal cohesion, a tribal unity, and it justifies even immoral acts because, to defeat an evil enemy, a Satanic enemy, you must do whatever is necessary.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>Last week, in the hours after Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s assassination, the words &ldquo;demon&rdquo; and &ldquo;evil&rdquo; trended on X as some on the right portrayed his murder as the work of supernaturally possessed Democrats and leftists. Major right-wing influencers echoed Carl Schmitt&rsquo;s ideas, calling for a <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/far-right-reactions-charlie-kirk-shooting-civil-war/">political crackdown</a> on Kirk&rsquo;s critics. Chris Rufo, a prominent right-wing propagandist, called on law enforcement to &ldquo;infiltrate, disrupt, arrest, and incarcerate&rdquo; the &ldquo;radical left.&rdquo;</p><p>This is where apocalyptic rhetoric always leads. When political opponents become evil, cosmic enemies, persecution, and violence become a sacred duty. This surge in demon and devil talk showed that Thiel has correctly identified a potent but perilous impulse in our politics. </p><p>But if tech billionaires seek to spread Christianity, they should stop hunting Antichrists and reflect on the words of Jesus Christ, who urged his followers to practice empathy and forgiveness and to care for people rather than exploit and surveil them. Instead of worrying about Armageddon, Thiel should heed the Gospels, which warn that &ldquo;it is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich man to enter the kingdom of God.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>Now there&rsquo;s scripture worth dwelling on&mdash;and it&rsquo;s a problem that no AI, no surveillance, no power, no money can fix.</p></div></div></article></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Interesting article, but I think it should have covered the viewpoint that Thiel is an insane fucking weirdo with practically infinite resources and no leash.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/nekp1oa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>He&#39;s a narcissist. Utterly self interested.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/nekqpgj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>He thinks he might be it</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1niq8kw/whats_up_with_peter_thiels_obsession_with_the/neknl7f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:22:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.404media.co/doj-deletes-study-showing-domestic-terrorists-are-most-often-right-wing/</link><title>DOJ Deletes Study Showing Domestic Terrorists Are Most Often Right Wing (404media.co)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.404media.co/content/images/size/w1200/2025/09/pam-bondi.jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>The Department of Justice has removed a study showing that white supremacist and far-right violence &ldquo;continues to outpace all other types of terrorism and domestic violent extremism&rdquo; in the United States.&nbsp;</p><p>The study, which was conducted by the National Institute of Justice and hosted on a DOJ website was available there at least until September 12, 2025, according to an archive of the page saved by the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250911165140/https://www.ojp.gov/pdffiles1/nij/306123.pdf"><u>Wayback Machine</u></a>. Daniel Malmer, a PhD student studying online extremism at UNC-Chapel Hill, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/malmer.com/post/3lypvmsr2qc2u?ref=404media.co">first noticed</a> the paper was deleted. </p><p>&ldquo;The Department of Justice's Office of Justice Programs is currently reviewing its websites and materials in accordance with recent Executive Orders and related guidance,&rdquo; reads a message on the page where the study was formerly hosted. &ldquo;During this review, some pages and publications will be unavailable. We apologize for any inconvenience this may cause.&rdquo;</p></div><div><div><h2>This post is for paid members only</h2><p>Become a paid member for unlimited ad-free access to articles, bonus podcast content, and more.</p><p><a href="https://www.404media.co/membership/">Subscribe</a> </p></div><div><h2>Sign up for free access to this post</h2><p>Free members get access to posts like this one along with an email round-up of our week's stories.</p><p><a href="https://www.404media.co/signup/">Subscribe</a> </p></div><p>Already have an account? <a href="https://www.404media.co/signin/">Sign in</a></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>“We are all domestic terrorists”</p><p>—Conservative Political Action Conference (CPAC) 2022</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/nejxhu5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s still here-- <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250911165140if_/https://www.ojp.gov/pdffiles1/nij/306123.pdf">https://web.archive.org/web/20250911165140if_/https://www.ojp.gov/pdffiles1/nij/306123.pdf</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/nejy5h2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They also deleted Cancer Research</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nimpmu/doj_deletes_study_showing_domestic_terrorists_are/nejwvyp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 22:14:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://rockenhaus.com</link><title>Man held 3 years in jail by FBI  for refusing to decrypt TOR NODES (rockenhaus.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 19 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><main> <article><div><figure><img width="1024" height="435" src="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-1024x435.jpeg" alt srcset="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-1024x435.jpeg 1024w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-300x127.jpeg 300w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1-768x326.jpeg 768w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-1.jpeg 1290w"></figure><p><strong>UPDATE: September 8, 2025: NEW VIDEO: U.S. Marshals Smash Windows in Retaliatory Raid on Disabled Vet</strong></p><figure></figure><p>This is what (Detroit) U.S. Marshals did to the home of Conrad Rockenhaus, a 100% disabled combat veteran, on September 4, 2025. The only warrant on the public record was a simple <strong><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.20.0.pdf">ARREST warrant</a></strong> for a fabricated, non-violent probation violation.</p><p>But as this video shows, they did not come for a standard arrest. They came to terrorize a family.</p><p>They smashed windows and beat him in the head. He is now suffering with a head injury in Livingston County Jail, where he is receiving inadequate medical care. To make it worse, a federal judge has stripped him of his constitutional right to an attorney. This is the price of speaking out against a corrupt federal officer.</p><p>For the full story, the judge&rsquo;s order, and all the evidence, visit the <strong><a href="https://rockenhaus.com/press-kit/">Press Kit</a></strong>.</p><p><strong>UPDATE: September 4, 2025 &ndash; A VIOLENT RETALIATORY ARREST</strong></p><p>On the morning of September 4, 2025, a U.S. Marshals Fugitive Task Force executed a fraudulent warrant, raiding the temporary home I was forced to rent out of fear for my safety. This raid was the direct result of a retaliatory campaign orchestrated by U.S. Probation Officers <strong>Stylianos Agapiou</strong>, Supervisor <strong>Jeffry Konal</strong>, and Chief <strong>Dion Thomas</strong>. The Marshals refused to produce a warrant.</p><p>According to a neighbor, the Marshals had been surveilling the home for days. During the raid, which was captured on video, they broke down the door, used excessive force, and physically beat my husband, a 100% disabled combat veteran.</p><p>During his initial court appearance later that day, my husband suffered a grand mal seizure in the courtroom as a result of the officer&rsquo;s violent arrest, and was rushed to the hospital.</p><p>Marshals had NO warrant, beat Conrad in the head (he later had a seizure in court) and held the door shut preventing me from leaving my home.</p><p>WATCH THE LIVE VIDEO NOW</p><figure></figure><p>Prior to his arrest, Conrad&rsquo;s retained attorney, <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/the-role-of-attorney-marc-r-lakin-p41147-in-a-constitutional-crisis/">Marc Lakin</a>, unethically refused to withdraw from the case after being fired. This forced Conrad to file his own motions with the court, asking the judge to intervene and appoint new counsel.</p><p>On August 29, 2025, Judge Stephen J. Murphy, III, issued an order striking these motions from the record.</p><p>Citing a rule against &ldquo;hybrid representation,&rdquo; Judge Murphy refused to address Conrad&rsquo;s constitutional right to effective counsel, stating the issue would be handled at the next hearing. This order created a procedural trap, leaving Conrad legally bound to an attorney who refused to act, while simultaneously making it impossible for him to hire a new one.</p><p>As a direct result of this order, Conrad was forced to appear in court today following his violent arrest without any legal representation&mdash;a crisis that culminated in his medical emergency in the courtroom.</p><p><a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/motion-to-strike.pdf">READ JUDGE MURPHY&rsquo;S ORDER.</a></p><p><strong>UPDATE SEPT 5, 2025:</strong> After having a seizure in court yesterday, Conrad Rockenhaus&rsquo;s <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.17.0.pdf">hearing was postponed to Sept. 30th</a> by Judge Stephen J. Murphy, III. What&rsquo;s worse is the court is fully aware of Conrad&rsquo;s medical status since the hearing.</p><p>Judge Murphy knows Conrad&rsquo;s previous lawyer, Marc Lakin, has abandoned him and is out of the country, but he refuses to appoint a new one. This is a deliberate violation of his Sixth Amendment rights.</p><p><strong>ANN ARBOR, MI &ndash; On August 28, 2025</strong>, A federal civil rights lawsuit filed in the Eastern District of Michigan details a sustained campaign of retaliatory prosecution against a 100% medically retired U.S. combat veteran and his wife. This was after his wife filed a formal complaint against a U.S. Probation Officer for serious misconduct, harassment, and illegal seizure of her business property.&nbsp;His wife is a private citizen with no criminal record, and the officers have no jurisdiction over her.</p><p>The retaliation, as documented in the filings, was swift and severe. It culminated in the U.S. Probation Office authoring a fraudulent arrest warrant based on a verifiably false claim that the veteran, Conrad Rockenhaus, was an &ldquo;absconder,&rdquo; despite having written proof he was hospitalized in a VA mental health facility.&nbsp;</p><p>This led to a <a href="https://youtu.be/E4WlPdNhzjM?si=XSdj9PdyurFPyybQ">traumatic raid</a> where the couple was held at gunpoint in their own driveway. </p><p>This public record, supported by official court documents, video evidence, and internal communications, exposes a pattern of fabricated evidence. It also shows a malicious prosecution designed to punish a private citizen for speaking out and to exploit the known medical vulnerabilities of a disabled veteran.</p><ul> <li><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.388083/gov.uscourts.mied.388083.1.0.pdf"><em>See Conrad&rsquo;s Lawsuit: Rockenhaus v. Agapiou (2:25-cv-12716)</em></a></li> <li><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.388138/gov.uscourts.mied.388138.1.0.pdf"><em>See Adrienne&rsquo;s Lawsuit: Rockenhaus v. Agapiou (2:25-cv-12736)</em></a></li> </ul> <figure><img width="1024" height="451" src="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-1024x451.jpeg" alt srcset="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-1024x451.jpeg 1024w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-300x132.jpeg 300w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2-768x338.jpeg 768w, https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/rockenhaus-federal-marshals-2.jpeg 1290w"></figure><p>[WATCH: <a href="https://youtu.be/E4WlPdNhzjM?si=XSdj9PdyurFPyybQ">Feds Hold Up Disabled Couple on False Warrant</a>]</p><p>The complete public record for this case, including the official lawsuits, a detailed timeline, and all supporting evidence, is available in the <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/press-kit/">comprehensive press kit</a>.</p><h3><strong>An Impossible Mandate: The Supervision &lsquo;Catch-22&rsquo;</strong></h3><p>At the heart of the federal case is the &ldquo;Catch-22&rdquo; of Conrad&rsquo;s supervision: a set of impossible and contradictory conditions imposed on a 100% medically retired and disabled combat veteran with a TBI.</p><p>The U.S. Probation Office demands that Conrad &ndash; a man certified as 100% disabled and unable to work by both the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Social Security Administration &ndash; simultaneously maintain a full-time job and pay $800 per month in restitution from his disability income.</p><p>At the same time, the officers have actively sabotaged his ability to even attempt to comply with this mandate. On two separate occasions, they have conducted unannounced visits and illegally seized his authorized work equipment, owned by his wife&rsquo;s company, which were the essential tools he used for his approved employment as a software developer.</p><p>They have then used this manufactured non-compliance as a basis for fraudulent violation petitions, effectively punishing him for failing to achieve a goal they themselves made impossible. This strategy of entrapment is a core feature of the Bivens civil rights complaint.</p><h3><strong>The Foundation of Injustice (Texas, 2019&ndash;2022)</strong></h3><p>The ordeal in the Eastern District of Michigan is the second chapter in a multi-year saga that began in Texas. In early 2019, Conrad Rockenhaus, a supporter of free speech and online privacy, refused to help federal agents decrypt traffic on <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/an-american-invention-for-global-freedom-the-true-story-of-tor/">Tor exit nodes</a> he operated for journalists and activists. Months later, on a pretextual, non-violent computer crime (CFAA) charge, he was arrested.</p><p>His three-year pre-trial detention was triggered by a single, provably false claim. The <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/U.S.-v.-Rockenhaus-2-20-20-2.pdf">official court transcript from a February 20, 2020, hearing</a> provides an irrefutable record of Texas Probation Officer Tiffany Routh testifying under oath that Conrad had installed a &ldquo;Linux operating system&rdquo; that &ldquo;knocked out their monitoring software&rdquo;.</p><p><strong>The Verifiable Lie:</strong> The software was, in reality, a pre-approved SPICE graphics driver for his Ph.D. program &ndash; not an operating system. It did not, nor could it, disable the monitoring software. Routh used this false claim to baselessly suggest Conrad might be accessing &ldquo;dark web sites,&rdquo; an inflammatory accusation she was forced to admit under oath she had no evidence to support.</p><p>This false testimony was fueled by a malicious campaign. We have documented proof that Conrad&rsquo;s then-wife, Ashley Luster, was actively working to keep him incarcerated for her own financial gain. While he was imprisoned, she illegally made herself the representative payee for his Social Security disability benefits, directing the funds to her own account after divorce proceedings had begun. Financial records further document how she systematically drained his bank accounts, maxed out his credit cards, and spent his monthly pension and disability payments. </p><p><strong>The Smoking Gun Confession: </strong>In a letter to her parents, Luster confessed, &ldquo;I had some tricks up my sleeve to keep him in there&rdquo;.</p><p><strong>Documented Collusion: </strong>Emails reveal Luster colluding with Conrad&rsquo;s own attorney, Walter Reaves, to secretly prolong his detention.&nbsp;</p><p>Based on this foundation of false testimony and conspiracy, Conrad was held for three years in horrific county jail conditions, where he was regularly beaten by guards and denied his life-sustaining seizure medication. The grueling ordeal ended only when he felt forced to accept a coerced guilty plea.</p><h3><strong>The Price of Speaking Out (Michigan, 2024&ndash;Present)</strong></h3><p>After his release to Michigan, Conrad&rsquo;s supervision under his first probation officer was stable and compliant. The crisis began in September 2024, when his case was reassigned to Officer Stylianos Agapiou, who immediately created a hostile environment. After months of harassment, illegal property seizures, and threats against Adrienne, she did what any citizen is supposed to do.</p><p><strong>The Trigger: </strong>On February 13, 2025, Adrienne Rockenhaus filed a <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Formal-Complaint-and-Demand-for-Investigation-Regarding-Probation-Officer-Stylianos-Agapiou_Redacted.pdf">detailed, 10-point formal complaint against Officer Agapiou</a> with his supervisors, including Chief Dion Thomas.</p><p>The response was not an investigation. It was retaliation.</p><p><strong>The Retaliation Begins:</strong> Just seven days later, on February 20, 2025, Chief Dion Thomas personally engaged in an act of intimidation by calling Adrienne&rsquo;s ex-husband and <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Dion-Thomas-Voicemail-to-EX-husband.mp3">leaving an unnerving and intimidating voicemail</a>, despite having just been given her contact information in an email.</p><h3><strong>The First Fraudulent Warrant</strong></h3><p><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.3.0.pdf">The April 29, 2025, arrest warrant</a>, signed by Supervisor Jeffry W. Konal, is a fraudulent document built on a foundation of demonstrable lies, malicious omissions, and the deliberate misrepresentation of facts. The petition&rsquo;s central claim, that Conrad was an &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; whose &ldquo;current whereabouts are unknown&rdquo;, is systematically dismantled by the probation office&rsquo;s own communications records.</p><p>The warrant also falsely accused Conrad of opening seven new lines of credit. This allegation was later disproven by an investigation that uncovered identity theft against both Conrad and Adrienne, for which a police report was filed. The petition was not an act of supervision; it was an attempt to punish the victim of a crime.</p><p>The warrant contains a misleading claim of illicit drug use based on a positive marijuana screen, while deliberately omitting the fact that Conrad has a legal prescription for Marinol (dronabinol), a medication known to cause such a result.</p><p>The evidence proves the office was not just aware of Conrad&rsquo;s hospitalization, but was in active, continuous communication about it.</p><p><strong>The Official Notification:</strong> Phone records provide irrefutable proof that on February 20, 2025, Adrienne Rockenhaus placed a six-minute call to Chief Dion Thomas&rsquo;s office at 11:21 AM to formally discuss Conrad&rsquo;s admission to a VA mental health facility.</p><p><strong>The Acknowledged Plan &amp; Continuous Updates: </strong>Text messages show the follow-up communication was with Konal himself. He not only acknowledged the plan for Conrad&rsquo;s doctor to send verification but continued to solicit and receive direct updates from Adrienne from February 24 through at least March 1, 2025. Konal&rsquo;s sworn statement in the warrant that Adrienne &ldquo;failed to&hellip;provide&rdquo; updates is a blatant falsehood, contradicted by his own phone&rsquo;s records.</p><p><strong>The Deceptive Misrepresentation of Privacy Laws: </strong>Konal&rsquo;s claim that the VA hospital told him on March 14 that Conrad was not a patient is a deliberate deception. Due to federal HIPAA laws protecting mental health patients, the VA would provide a standard, privacy-compliant &ldquo;no comment&rdquo; to an unauthorized caller. Konal, a federal officer, would have known this. He weaponized this privacy law, twisting a legally required non-answer into false &ldquo;proof&rdquo; that Conrad was a fugitive when he had already been told to expect a discharge. Conrad&rsquo;s doctor had been in contact with the probation office as well.</p><p>The &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; status was manufactured. Supervisor Konal possessed phone records, text messages, and direct knowledge of Conrad&rsquo;s medical crisis. He chose to ignore all of it, misrepresent the facts, and fabricate a basis for a traumatic arrest.</p><p><strong>The Traumatic Raid:</strong> On May 5, 2025, U.S. Marshals executed the fraudulent warrant in a raid on the family&rsquo;s home. <a href="https://youtu.be/E4WlPdNhzjM?si=XSdj9PdyurFPyybQ">Home security footage</a> provides an irrefutable record of officers holding the complying couple at gunpoint and threatening, &ldquo;If you do anything, I&rsquo;m gonna release the dog, he&rsquo;s gonna bite you&rdquo;. The transporting &ldquo;John Doe&rdquo; U.S. Marshal later showed Conrad a sexually harassing text he wrote about Adrienne while he drove recklessly down the shoulder of the highway.</p><h4><strong>A Suspicious Removal and Punitive Reinstatement</strong></h4><p>The retaliation was not limited to intimidation. Shortly after Adrienne filed her formal complaint on February 13, Officer Agapiou was quietly placed &ldquo;on leave&rdquo; and removed from the case. However, this was not a corrective measure. The timeline suggests a coordinated effort: Agapiou was sidelined while his supervisor, Jeffry Konal, authored the fraudulent &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; warrant that led to Conrad&rsquo;s arrest. Then, just days after the coerced guilty plea was secured on May 13, Agapiou was immediately reinstated to Conrad&rsquo;s case, a move the family alleges was a punitive measure and a continuation of the harassment.</p><h3><strong>The Betrayal by Counsel: The Misconduct of Marc Lakin</strong></h3><p>A central objective of the legal fight is the withdrawal of the guilty plea Conrad entered on May 13, 2025. This plea was not a legitimate admission of the fabricated violations; it was the direct result of a calculated ethical breach and coercion by his own retained attorney, <a href="https://rockenhaus.com/the-role-of-attorney-marc-r-lakin-p41147-in-a-constitutional-crisis/">Marc Lakin</a>.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>The Coerced Plea: </strong>The record shows that Lakin knowingly coerced his client into pleading guilty despite possessing clear evidence of his innocence. On May 7, 2025, six days before the hearing, Lakin was provided with a detailed &ldquo;<a href="https://rockenhaus.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Responses-to-Alleged-Violations-Rockenhaus-Conrad-05-07-2025-2.pdf">Defense Summaries</a>&rdquo; document, which contained point-by-point exculpatory evidence refuting the &ldquo;absconder&rdquo; claim. Despite having this proof, Lakin ambushed his client moments before the hearing on May 13. After separating Conrad from Adrienne at the courthouse to isolate him, Lakin threatened him with more jail time if he refused to plead guilty. This last-minute, high-pressure tactic was a direct and cynical exploitation of Conrad&rsquo;s known combat-related TBI.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Harassment and Refusal to Withdraw: </strong>Lakin&rsquo;s misconduct continued after he was fired in August 2025. He demanded an exorbitant payment after already having received a large sum for a retainer. When Conrad told him he was unable to pay, Lakin refused to withdraw from the case and engaged in a series of harassing text messages. He made manipulative financial demands, pressuring Conrad to &ldquo;borrow the money from your wife&rdquo;. When his withdrawal was formally requested, he issued a direct threat, stating that if forced to file a motion, he &ldquo;would have to state the reasons, which frankly might put you in a bad light&rdquo;. This pattern of coercion, threats, and a refusal to withdraw constitutes a profound violation of Conrad Rockenhaus&rsquo;s Sixth Amendment right to the effective assistance of counsel and is the primary basis for the motion to withdraw the coerced guilty plea.&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Forced Legal Action: </strong>As a result of this misconduct, Conrad was forced to act as his own attorney, filing pro se motions with the court on August 21 and August 27 asking the judge to order Lakin&rsquo;s removal. A comprehensive formal grievance has since been filed against Marc Lakin with the Michigan Attorney Grievance Commission and was confirmed as received on August 27, 2025.</p><p><strong>The Procedural Trap: A Motion Struck from the Record: </strong>The procedural trap Conrad is caught in was perfectly illustrated on August 29, 2025. After his attorney, Marc Lakin, refused to withdraw from the case, Conrad was forced to take the only action available to him and file his own <em>pro se</em> motions asking the judge to intervene. In response, <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.16.0.pdf">Judge Stephen J. Murphy III struck the filings</a>, citing the standard court rule against &ldquo;hybrid representation,&rdquo; which prevents a defendant from acting for themselves while they have an attorney of record. This created a legal Catch-22: Conrad was required to act through a lawyer who refused to act, and was blocked from acting for himself. The judge deferred a final decision, stating that the issue of Conrad&rsquo;s legal representation will now be addressed at the upcoming supervised release hearing on September 30, 2025, transforming it into a crucial showdown over his constitutional right to effective counsel.</p><h3><strong>The Second Fraudulent Warrant</strong></h3><p>After Lakin&rsquo;s coerced plea put Conrad back under his supervision, <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mied.374280/gov.uscourts.mied.374280.12.0.pdf">Officer Agapiou filed a second warrant petition</a> on August 20, 2025, filled with a new set of demonstrably false claims:</p><ul> <li>A fabricated story that Conrad used his vehicle&rsquo;s OnStar service to instruct Adrienne to wipe a seized phone. Official OnStar records prove this call never happened.</li> </ul> <ul> <li>A false claim that his restitution payments had &ldquo;bounced&rdquo;. Verifiable debit card receipts prove the payments were successful.</li> </ul> <ul> <li>A misleading claim of illicit drug use from a positive marijuana screen, while deliberately omitting the fact that Conrad has a legal prescription for Marinol, a medication known to cause such a result.</li> </ul> <h3><strong>A Documented Double Standard: The Case of U.S. v. Jalen Johnson</strong></h3><p>The claim that these punitive actions were standard procedure is verifiably false. <a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/65414945/united-states-v-johnson/">Official court records from the case of U.S. v. Jalen Johnson</a>, supervised by the same officer, Jeffry Konal, reveal a stark double standard. Johnson, on supervision for a firearm charge, committed numerous severe and admitted violations, including repeated positive drug tests for marijuana, codeine, morphine, and alcohol, as well as committing new crimes.</p><p>Instead of a punitive warrant, Konal&rsquo;s office responded with a therapeutic approach, referring him to therapy and using a summons to bring him to court. This documented disparate treatment is hard evidence that the actions against Conrad were not procedural, but personal and retaliatory.</p><h3><strong>The &ldquo;Computer Expert&rdquo; Lie: A Fraudulent Basis of Authority</strong></h3><p>From his first interaction, Officer Agapiou built his authority on a lie, misrepresenting himself to Conrad as the probation office&rsquo;s &ldquo;computer forensic expert&rdquo;. This claim is not only verifiably false, but his actual, verified background consists of a Master&rsquo;s degree in Criminal Justice from an online college, and employment as a state corrections agent. This is completely inconsistent with the specialized qualifications of a computer forensic expert.</p><p>It is also irreconcilable with the documented reality of his personal finances. The profile of a highly compensated federal forensics specialist is fundamentally at odds with the need to work a secondary job as an Amazon Flex driver to make ends meet. This deception about his own professional and financial standing establishes a clear pattern of untrustworthiness, calling into question the veracity of every claim made in his official reports.</p><h3><strong>A Fight for Accountability</strong></h3><p>This is not just a case about one veteran. It is about the right of every American to hold government officials accountable without being terrorized.</p><p>&ldquo;When I witnessed a federal officer engage in what I believed to be serious misconduct, I did what any citizen is supposed to do: I filed a detailed, formal complaint through the proper channels,&rdquo; said Adrienne Rockenhaus. &ldquo;The retaliation from the officer&rsquo;s supervisors was immediate and terrifying. We will not be intimidated into silence&rdquo;.</p><p>&ldquo;As a 100% disabled veteran, I was told that supervised release was a process to help me reintegrate,&rdquo; said Conrad Rockenhaus. &ldquo;Instead, my disabilities, especially my Traumatic Brain Injury, have been used as weapons against me. We are fighting for a system that offers veterans justice&hellip; not one that exploits their vulnerabilities for the sake of punishment&rdquo;.</p><p><br>The evidence is clear, the timeline is documented, and the injustice is irrefutable. The question now is one of accountability. Is this the standard of conduct we expect from our federal officers? Contact the <a href="https://www.miep.uscourts.gov/directory.cfm">U.S. Probation Office for the Eastern District of Michigan</a> and ask them.</p></div></article> </main> </div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Innocent until proven guilty.</p><p>Can’t they only hold for 72 hours?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/nej90or/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A lot of information about this case that&#39;s been omitted has been discussed in the original thread.    </p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/TOR/comments/1ni5drm/comment/neivs35/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">https://www.reddit.com/r/TOR/comments/1ni5drm/comment/neivs35/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button</a>  </p><p>He violated his bail conditions in multiple ways.  He was on bail for doing 500k worth of damages to get back at his employer after being let go- he was even retained by the company to fix the damage he had done himself.  His wife, who created the post, was the one who told his bail officers that he had been using an unsupervised computer when he wasn&#39;t allowed.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/nejkqip/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is COMPLETELY one-sided and they&#39;re extremely cagey on the actual details. There are <strong>two</strong> waves of charges here. He&#39;s also not held for 3 years for refusing, his supervised release was revoked for probation violation.</p><p>Here&#39;s what&#39;s clear so far:</p><ol><li>He was initially convicted under CFAA (federal law) for a computer-related intrusion offense. Details unknown. <strong>Nobody disputes this on either side.</strong></li><li>He received <strong>supervised release</strong> with probation conditions that included restricted/monitored computer and internet use</li><li>Allegedly, he installed Linux to disable/interfere with the <strong>monitoring software he was required to use because of his initial violation.</strong></li><li>This is a clear violation of his probation so his supervised release was <strong>revoked.</strong> Thus, back to original conviction and 3 years.</li><li>He now claims that the revocation of release was because he refused to decrypt Tor traffic.</li></ol><p>His claims don&#39;t make ANY sense to me.</p><ol><li>He committed a computer crime</li><li>was required to have monitoring software as a condition of his release to ensure he doesn&#39;t do another computer crime</li><li>He bypassed the monitoring software and was running a TOR exit node??</li><li><strong>FAFO?</strong></li></ol><p>If you&#39;re convicted for a computer crime, why the F would you decide to jump right into TOR exit nodes and other parts of the dark web?? Then it seems like a media campaign to confuse the public?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nijhk7/man_held_3_years_in_jail_by_fbi_for_refusing_to/nejt9lm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:15:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/09/meet-the-latest-anti-vaccine-voices-on-rfk-jr-s-cdc-advisory-panel/</link><title>RFK Jr. adds more anti-vaccine members to CDC vaccine advisory panel | The panel will meet this week and could limit access to measles, Hep B, COVID vaccines. (arstechnica.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nic3o4/rfk_jr_adds_more_antivaccine_members_to_cdc/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nic3o4/rfk_jr_adds_more_antivaccine_members_to_cdc/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nic3o4/rfk_jr_adds_more_antivaccine_members_to_cdc/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/GettyImages-2221878046-2048x1366.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><strong>Kirk Milhoan, </strong>a pediatric cardiologist who is <a href="https://imahealth.org/about/senior-fellows/">a senior fellow</a> at the Independent Medical Alliance (formerly Front Line COVID-19 Critical Care Alliance), which promotes misinformation about COVID-19 vaccines and touts unproven and dubious COVID-19 treatments. Those include the malaria drug hydroxychloroquine, the de-worming drug ivermectin, and various concoctions of vitamins and other drugs. Milhoan has stated that mRNA COVID-19 vaccines should be removed from the market, <a href="https://kffhealthnews.org/news/article/mrna-vaccines-trump-boast-under-gop-attacks-legislation/">telling KFF in March</a>: "We should stop it and test it more before we move forward."</p><p><strong>Evelyn Griffin</strong>, an obstetrician and gynecologist in Louisiana who reportedly lost her job for refusing to get a COVID-19 vaccine. In a speech at a Louisiana Health Freedom Day in May 2024, Griffin claimed that doctors <a href="https://www.facebook.com/centralcitynews.us/videos/3843797775903484/">"blindly believed"</a> that mRNA COVID-19 vaccines were safe. She has also claimed that the vaccines cause &ldquo;bizarre and rare conditions," according to the Post.</p><p><strong>Hillary Blackburn</strong>, a pharmacist in St. Louis. <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/kennedy-appoints-five-new-members-us-vaccine-panel-2025-09-15/">Reuters reports</a> that she is the daughter-in-law of Sen. Marsha Blackburn (R-Tenn.), who has opposed vaccine mandates.</p><p><strong>Raymond Pollak</strong>, a semi-retired transplant surgeon who filed <a href="https://www.modernhealthcare.com/article/20050818/NEWS/508180311/ill-university-settles-dispute-with-transplant-surgeon/">a whistleblower lawsuit</a> against the University of Illinois Hospital in 1999, alleging the hospital manipulated patient data to increase their chances of receiving livers. The hospital settled the suit, paying $2.5 million, while denying wrongdoing.</p><p>ACIP is scheduled to meet at the end of this week, on September 18 and September 19. According to <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/acip/downloads/agendas/draft-posted-2025-09-12-508.pdf">an agenda recently posted online</a>, the committee will vote on recommendations for a measles, mumps, rubella, and varicella (MMRV) combination vaccine, the Hepatitis B vaccine, and this year's updated COVID-19 vaccines. Vaccine experts <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/09/14/rfk-jr-s-vaccine-panel-to-consider-major-changes-to-childhood-shots-00563165">widely fear</a> that the committee will rescind recommendations and restrict access to those vaccines. Such moves will likely create new, potentially insurmountable barriers for people, including children, to get vaccines.</p><p>ACIP-recommended vaccines are required to be covered by private health insurance plans and the Vaccines for Children program for Medicaid-eligible and under- or uninsured kids, which covers about half of American children. Without ACIP recommendations for a vaccine, insurance coverage would be an open question, and vulnerable children would simply lose access entirely.</p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Plague ship country</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nic3o4/rfk_jr_adds_more_antivaccine_members_to_cdc/nehr35f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Cant wait for the day when the rest of the world starts cancelling plane routes to and from USA due to rampant [name] disease</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nic3o4/rfk_jr_adds_more_antivaccine_members_to_cdc/nehvyb0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A generation of kids will die with this man in charge of the CDC.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nic3o4/rfk_jr_adds_more_antivaccine_members_to_cdc/nei1e1x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 14:17:09 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.fox2detroit.com/news/total-porn-ban-proposed-michigan-lawmakers</link><title>Total porn ban proposed by Michigan lawmakers. The bill also includes a section that takes aim at transgender individuals by prohibiting material "that includes...an individual of 1 biological sex imitating, depicting, or representing himself or herself to be of the other biological sex." (fox2detroit.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxsrs/total_porn_ban_proposed_by_michigan_lawmakers_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxsrs/total_porn_ban_proposed_by_michigan_lawmakers_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxsrs/total_porn_ban_proposed_by_michigan_lawmakers_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><strong>Published</strong>&nbsp; September 15, 2025 12:35pm EDT </p></div><div><div><p><img src="https://images.foxtv.com/static.fox2detroit.com/www.fox2detroit.com/content/uploads/2025/09/764/432/gettyimages-1236525221.jpg?ve=1&amp;tl=1" alt> <span>article</span></p><div><p><span>In this photo illustration a PornHub logo seen displayed on a smartphone screen with a computer wallpaper in the background in Athens, Greece on November 12, 2021. (Photo by Nikolas Kokovlis/NurPhoto via Getty Images)</span> </p></div></div><p><span><strong>LANSING, Mich. (FOX 2)</strong> - </span><a href="https://www.fox2detroit.com/tag/us/mi">Michigan</a> lawmakers proposed a bill last week banning porn.</p><p>This comes after the bill's primary sponsor, Rep. Josh Schriver (R-Oxford), said earlier this year that he was working to draft legislation banning all porn online.</p><p>Dig deeper:</p><p>House Bill 4938, called the "Anticorruption of Public Morals Act," would prohibit the distribution of "real, animated, digitally generated, written, or auditory" depictions of sexual acts. The bill breaks down the types of acts covered, including intercourse and masturbation.</p><p>The bill also includes a section that takes aim at transgender individuals by prohibiting material "that includes a disconnection between biology and gender by an individual of 1 biological sex imitating, depicting, or representing himself or herself to be of the other biological sex."</p><div><p>Related </p><div><h3><a href="https://fox2detroit.com/news/new-michigan-laws-ban-ai-generated-porn-real-people">New Michigan laws ban AI-generated porn</a></h3><p>Using artificial intelligence to create pornographic deepfakes of real people is now prohibited in Michigan, thanks to bills signed by Gov. Gretchen Whitmer this week.</p></div></div><p>The bill would require internet service providers in Michigan to use filters to prevent people from seeing the prohibited material.&nbsp;</p><p>If the bill were to become law, violators could be looking at prison time or hefty fines. Distributing the prohibited material or making it available online would carry a maximum prison sentence of 20 years and/or a $100,000 fine. If more than 100 pieces of prohibited material are involved, that penalty jumps to 25 years in prison and/or a fine up to $125,000.</p><p>Additionally, an internet service provider or commercial entity could face fines for knowingly allowing people to access sexually explicit material online.&nbsp;</p><p>The bill's sponsors are also pushing for violators of the Anticorruption of Public Morals Act to register as sex offenders.&nbsp;</p><p>Others behind the bill include Reps. Joseph Pavlov (R-Smiths Creek), Matthew Maddock (R-Milford), James DeSana (R-Carleton), and Jennifer Wortz (R-Quincy).</p><p>What they're saying:</p><p>According to Schriver, the ban, which would apply to adults and minors alike if it were to become law, is designed to protect children.</p><p>"These measures defend children, safeguard our communities, and put families first," he wrote on X. "Obscene and harmful content online threatens Michigan families, especially children."</p><p>Schriver has been outspoken about his objections to porn and his desire to ban it completely in Michigan. Earlier this year, he said porn and human trafficking were linked, adding that "shutting down the porn industry would be a crushing blow to the human trafficking industry."</p><p>Big picture view:</p><p>If the bill were to become law, Michigan would be the first state to enact a total porn ban.&nbsp;</p><p>Some states have moved to require age verification to ensure only adults are watching porn, but no states have outright banned the viewing of pornographic material.</p><p>For instance, earlier this summer, the United States Supreme Court <a href="https://www.fox2detroit.com/news/supreme-court-texas-pornhub-sites-age-verification">upheld a Texas law requiring age verification</a> for users visiting porn websites. Several other states, <a href="https://www.fox2detroit.com/news/pornhub-threatens-pull-out-florida-over-hb-3-law-online-age-verification-privacy-fight">such as Florida</a>, have passed similar laws.&nbsp;</p><p>What's next:</p><p>The bill was referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</p><p>No meetings have been scheduled for the committee to review the proposed law.</p><p><b>The Source:</b> A copy of HB 4938, Rep. Schriver's X account, and previous reporting were used in this story.</p><h2><a href="https://www.fox2detroit.com/live">Watch FOX 2 News Live</a></h2> <section><a href="https://www.fox2detroit.com/tag/crime-publicsafety">Crime and Public Safety</a><a href="https://www.fox2detroit.com/tag/politics">Politics</a></section> </div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Michigan lawmakers should have their hard drives checked before they&#39;re allowed to vote on this bill.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxsrs/total_porn_ban_proposed_by_michigan_lawmakers_the/neexrtl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Inb4 Mrs. Doubtfire is banned by conservative asshats.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxsrs/total_porn_ban_proposed_by_michigan_lawmakers_the/neexubx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>1A violation, at the very least, but since there are no Constitutional rights or protections that SCOTUS wouldn&#39;t abridge for the regime&#39;s benefit, it&#39;s anybody&#39;s guess.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxsrs/total_porn_ban_proposed_by_michigan_lawmakers_the/neezy3r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 02:21:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/2025/09/15/zoom-ceo-eric-yuan-three-day-workweek-ai-automation-human-jobs-replaced-future-of-work/</link><title>Zoom’s CEO agrees with Bill Gates, Jensen Huang, and Jamie Dimon: A 3-day workweek is coming soon thanks to AI | Fortune (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://fortune.com/img-assets/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GettyImages-2175654021-e1757947434614.jpg?resize=1200,600' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>However, as more chatbots and automated assistants <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/09/06/godfather-of-ai-geoffrey-hinton-massive-unemployment-soaring-profits-capitalist-system/">take over the</a> duties of human roles, there&rsquo;s a growing cohort of executives who see shorter workweeks on the horizon&mdash;and <a href="https://fortune.com/company/zoom/">Zoom</a> CEO <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/10/09/zoom-ceo-eric-yuan-interview-says-ai-workplace-future-challenge-microsoft-google/">Eric Yuan</a> can even see staffers only clocking in a few days a week.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;I feel like if A.I. can make all of our lives better, why do we need to work for five days a week?&rdquo; Yuan told <em>The New York Times </em>in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/14/business/zoom-meetings-eric-yuan.html">a recent interview</a>. &ldquo;Every company will support three days, four days a week. I think this ultimately frees up everyone&rsquo;s time.&rdquo; </p><p>It&rsquo;s music to the ears of Americans stuck in corporate <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/09/11/what-is-the-great-lock-in-gen-z-millennial-hustle-culture-burnout/">hustle culture</a>, enviously watching their <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/08/28/netherlands-four-day-workweek-europe-us-staffers-grindset-working-women-flexible-schedules-rto-wfh/">European peers</a> trial four-day workweeks <a href="https://fortune.com/europe/2024/11/05/german-workers-4-day-workweek-trial-sleep-exercise-stress/">with major success</a>. And when U.S. performance coaching company Exos <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/04/16/4-day-workweek-success-lower-turnover-more-productivity/">experimented with</a> schedules one workday shorter, it proved to be good for business; employee burnout was cut in half, and productivity soared by 24%. And CEOs agree shorter workweeks born from these automation gains will be terrific for human workers&mdash;even if it means fewer of them have jobs in general.&nbsp; </p><p><em>Fortune </em>reached out to Zoom for comment. </p><h2>Other CEOs including Gates, Huang, and Dimon see a shorter workweek ahead</h2><p>AI tools can be immensely useful for staffers, cutting out everything from menial tasks like emailing to more tedious <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/07/14/goldman-sachs-ai-powered-software-engineer-devin-new-employee-increase-productivity-fears-of-job-replacement/">jobs like coding</a>. Tech leaders are seeing the gains from AI firsthand, and they&rsquo;re promoting the possibility that employees will no longer have to clock in five days a week.&nbsp; </p><p><a href="https://fortune.com/company/microsoft/">Microsoft</a> cofounder Gates first pioneered technology back in the 1970s and 1980s; and now, the billionaire <a href="https://fortune.com/2023/11/23/bill-gates-microsoft-3-day-work-week-machines-make-food/">predicted that</a> AI&rsquo;s current pace of innovation <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/03/27/billionaire-bill-gates-two-day-workweek-ai-replacing-humans/">will remove the need</a> for humans for &ldquo;most things&rdquo; in the next 10 years. When people are no longer needed, those who are left on staff won&rsquo;t have to swipe in daily.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;What will jobs be like? Should we just work like 2 or 3 days a week?&rdquo; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uHY5i9-0tJM">Gates told</a> Jimmy Fallon on <em>The Tonight Show</em> in February. &ldquo;If you zoom out, the purpose of life is not just to do jobs.&rdquo; </p><p><a href="https://fortune.com/company/nvidia/">Nvidia</a> CEO Huang is also on board with the idea of fewer workdays&mdash;but has a catch. The leader of the $4 trillion GPU company <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/08/29/nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-4-day-work-week-productivity/">said that</a> we&rsquo;re just &ldquo;at the beginning of the AI revolution,&rdquo; and if industries continue to adopt artificial intelligence at the current rapid rate, it could &ldquo;probably&rdquo; bring about a four-day workweek. However, that work may only be crammed into a condensed schedule, as Huang predicts that we&rsquo;re going to be &ldquo;busier in the future than now.&rdquo; </p><p>Even the financial industry&mdash;known for putting its workers <a href="https://fortune.com/2024/09/12/jpmorgan-cap-junior-bankers-hours/">through 80-hour workweeks</a>&mdash;may finally get some relief from AI automation. <a href="https://fortune.com/company/jpmorgan-chase/">JPMorgan Chase</a> CEO Dimon predicted years ago that the technology may bring about better work-life balance, although it would &ldquo;of course&rdquo; replace some jobs.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;Your children are going to live to 100 and not have cancer because of technology,&rdquo; Dimon said <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2023-10-02/dimon-sees-ai-giving-a-3-1-2-day-workweek-to-the-next-generation?sref=2jPYL79S">in an interview</a> with <em>Bloomberg</em> TV back in 2023. &ldquo;And literally they&rsquo;ll probably be working 3 and a half days a week.&rdquo; </p><h2>Zoom CEO admits that some jobs will be erased</h2><p>While workers globally will finally have the opportunity to clock in fewer days per week, not everyone will be enjoying the shortened schedules. Leaders are open to the fact that there will be a massive upheaval in the jobs market, with some roles inevitably automated in the shift. Zoom&rsquo;s CEO doesn&rsquo;t shy away from the reality that some humans will be fired&mdash;but it&rsquo;s just another adjustment, just like the industrial revolution and birth of the internet.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;Whenever there&rsquo;s a technology paradigm shift, some job opportunities are gone, but it will create some new opportunities,&rdquo; Yuan admitted in the interview. &ldquo;For some jobs, like entry-level engineers, we can use A.I. to write code. However, you still need to manage that code. You also create a lot of digital agents, and you need someone to manage those agents.&rdquo; </p><p>Other chief executives like Ford <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/07/05/ford-ceo-jim-farley-ai-white-collar-jobs-essential-economy-skilled-trade-jobs-shortage/">CEO Jim Farley</a> and Klarna leader <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/02/03/klarna-ceo-ai-replacing-human-workers/">Sebastian Siemiatkowski</a> agree that some roles will be erased in the change&mdash;but some, like Huang, think it <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/07/15/jensen-huang-nvidia-ai-layoffs-jobs/">could actually bolster</a> employment. Instead of humans being replaced by AI, the chip leader <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/05/29/billionaire-nvidia-ceo-jensen-huang-ai-replace-jobs-if-technology-not-embraced/">claimed that</a> people&rsquo;s roles will be taken over by others who can actually use the advanced tech.&nbsp; </p><p>&ldquo;Over the course of the last 300 years, 100 years, 60 years, even, in the era of computers, not only did productivity go up, employment also went up,&rdquo; Huang <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/07/13/business/video/gps0713-ai-workforce-nvidia-productivity">told <em>CNN</em></a><em> </em>this year. &ldquo;Now the reason for that is if we have an abundance of ideas, ways that we could build a better future, if we were more productive, we could realize that better.&rdquo;</p></div><p><strong>Fortune Global Forum</strong> returns Oct. 26&ndash;27, 2025 in Riyadh. CEOs and global leaders will gather for a dynamic, invitation-only event shaping the future of business. <a href="https://conferences.fortune.com/event/global-forum-2025/summary?utm_source=fortunecom&amp;utm_medium=plealink">Apply for an invitation.</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>And they&#39;re leaving out that means your paycheck will get adjusted accordingly.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/neestud/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Allowing CEOs to have a 3 day work week has been a dream of mine since I was a child.  This is loooong overdue.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/neeri79/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The benefits of productivity haven’t been going in labor’s pocket for 50 years, and that’s not changing anytime soon without a huge fight.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nhxa4p/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/neety6i/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 02:02:23 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
