<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=science&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/science</title><description>Hot posts in /r/science (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 11:42:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_mouw-styles-communityIcon_xtjipkhhefi41-144x400.png</url><title>/r/science</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.helsinki.fi/en/news/food-and-nutrition/consuming-more-legumes-and-less-red-and-processed-meat-may-have-surprisingly-positive-impact-mens-health</link><title>Consuming more legumes and less red and processed meat may have a surprisingly positive impact on men's health. Replacing red and processed meat with pea- and faba bean-based foods resulted in reduced total and 'bad' LDL cholesterol levels in men, along with weight loss. (helsinki.fi)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>What is surprising about that?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5n0gl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The benefits of eating more beans and peas instead of red meat is you are getting a ton of more fiber which helps your colon out and prevents colon cancer. Keeps your regular. Also fiber pulls out bad cholesterol LDL from your blood into your poop, and you poop out the bad cholesterol. Also fiber in beans are very filling. I challenge anyone to try to over eat beans. It is almost impossible because it is fills you up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5uljr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I swapped out beef for bean burritos and love it just the same. My LDL cholesterol is down to 62mg/dL, which is probably also from other dietary swaps toward whole plants / more fiber / less saturated fat.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5lwzr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn’t replacing red meat with a lot of things including white meat also lead to better health? Like I get red meat is good but it’s one of those foods that gets consumed way too much.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5uzan/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I thought the ideal male body was supposed to be raised purely on a diet of raw beef and eggs?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf6dl1j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the press release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article: </p><p><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00394-025-03783-x">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00394-025-03783-x</a></p><p>From the linked article: </p><p>Consuming more legumes and less red and processed meat may have a surprisingly positive impact on men’s health</p><p>A University of Helsinki study found that partially replacing red and processed meat with pea- and faba bean–based foods resulted in reduced total and ‘bad’ LDL cholesterol levels in men, along with weight loss.</p><p>On average, men consume significantly more red and processed meat than is recommended, and more than women do. The high nutritional value of legumes makes them well suited to replacing meat. However, they do not naturally contain vitamin B12, which is found in animal-derived foods. The BeanMan study investigated how partially replacing red and processed meat with legumes thriving in Finnish conditions affected men’s health and levels of critical micronutrients in the blood.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf5gskk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The thing all these studies ignore is that the diets don&#39;t replace only red meat, they mostly replace highly-processed meats like fast food burgers, chicken sammies, sausages, bacon and ham among others.  IMHO, it&#39;s there where the devil lives and not in fresh, cleanly prepared, minimally processed meats.</p><p>Call me out but my Gleason score went down after removing processed meats,alcohol and wheat flour from my diet.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlhfp2/consuming_more_legumes_and_less_red_and_processed/nf6ynay/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 03:59:20 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/keto-diet-health-risk-glucose-high-fat</link><title>Mice fed on the keto diet had trouble processing sugar, showed signs of liver and cardiovascular disease | Long-term adherence to the low-carb, high-fat diet caused buildups of fat in the bloodstream (sciencenews.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m pretty open to the evidence that a ketogenic diet has health benefits for a number of use cases. But I&#39;d never go for it myself because I know I have a genetic predisposition for high cholesterol (that makes dietary cholesterol affect my levels), non-alcoholic fatty liver disease, cardiovascular risk, and kidney insufficiency. I don&#39;t need evidence that it&#39;s bad for other people before I know it&#39;s bad for me personally.</p><p>There is a study showing that a ketogenic diet <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC5609489/">extended longevity and healthspan in male mice</a>. Scientific inquiry generates plenty of conflicting evidence. I hope we can look at this as a sign that, especially when it comes to medical science, your mileage is still highly individualised, and overall risk to health and longevity is a composite of the accumulated risks of many interconnected systems. I think it&#39;s worth the investment to learn about your own biological composition to anchor your decisionmaking instead of looking for an &quot;objective&quot; direction.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf5429j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve always said keto is a great weight loss “tool” but never thought of it as a long term method of sustaining weight loss.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf54xbz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah. I am newly diabetic and switching to super low carb is the only thing that is keeping my blood sugar below 160 on metformin. On keto, your main energy source is fats, so them being in the bloodstream makes sense, but not sure if it&#39;s supposed to turn to sugar through the liver first or something.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf5fc1q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&gt; Adult C57Bl/6J male and female mice were placed on one of four long-term diet regimens<br/><a href="https://www.jax.org/strain/000664">C57BL/6J is the most widely used inbred strain[...]They are also susceptible to diet-induced obesity, type 2 diabetes, and atherosclerosis.</a></p><p>It&#39;s good to know that feeding mice that have genetic predispositions to conditions, which naturally mostly eat seeds, grains and some insects, with extremely species inappropriate diets, leads to them having metabolic problems.</p><p>So their conclusion of:</p><p>&gt; In summary, while a KD can prevent and treat obesity, it causes hyperlipidemia, hepatic steatosis, and glucose intolerance.</p><p>Should come with a big, red, bold</p><h1>IN MICE.</h1></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf546k6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How incredibly predictable. It’s like we had years of research that pointed to this already.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf51714/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A 90% fat diet is not a modern keto diet. Generally 70% 25% 5% (fat, protein, carbs) is the most common. Also, different strains of mice have been known to respond dramatically different to keto diets. Also, they&#39;re mice.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf55ojd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>is it even a high fat diet?  It CAN be, but it doesn&#39;t have to be...like...what?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlfcyf/mice_fed_on_the_keto_diet_had_trouble_processing/nf632gb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 02:31:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://news.uga.edu/role-of-parents-in-social-anxiety/</link><title>Both mothers and fathers significantly shape their children's social anxiety: warmth, affection and acceptance from either parent reduce anxiety, while rejection, coldness, and controlling behaviors heighten it (news.uga.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>More warmth and affection from both mothers and fathers were linked to fewer social anxiety symptoms. However, rejection and coldness were tied to higher levels of social anxiety.</p><p> “We’re finding these effects across cultures and age groups,” Howard said. “Giving more acceptance can be a way for parents to meaningfully help and support their children.”</p><p><strong>A controlling mom may have a stronger impact than a strict dad</strong></p><p>While it’s common for parents to set limits, tactics like guilt-tripping, holding their children to unrealistic expectations and overprotecting them can be damaging, the researchers said.</p><p>The study found children with overly controlling parents were more likely to exhibit social anxiety symptoms. And controlling mothers appeared to have a larger effect than overbearing fathers</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40894-025-00268-0">Perceived Mother and Father Parenting and Adolescent Social Anxiety Symptoms: A Meta-Analysis | Adolescent Research Review</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf4buzt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yes, the neglect and abuse did cause me all kinds of issues.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf5crqc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I guess the guilt-tripping and unrealistic expectations from my dad worked.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf5ugzw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Learn what love is and love your children.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf5ahp4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Our primary caregivers model emotional capacity and (co)regulation skills. If kids are treated in a way that certain emotions aren&#39;t safe things to feel, labelled as a &#39;tantrums&#39;, leaving them to cry it out, punishing with physical punishments, the list goes on... This undermines their safety not just with the caregiver but also their own relationship to emotions. The healthy role of emotions is to inform us about our experience and environment as well as process our experiences in life.<br/>If they learn inner conflicts toward their own emotional states, this is when anxiety and other issues (including unhealthy coping mechanisms) start to enter the picture. It creates a predisposition to trauma and by extension vulnerability to abuse due to the lack of ability to process and integrate experiences due to these conflicts and inner aversions, lack of emotional safety and regulation skills.<br/>Would-be parents: Don&#39;t neglect your kids&#39; emotions. Take time to understand how it works and its importance. The world is harsh out there and they need a foundation of implicit <em>and</em> explicit safety (physical, emotional, social) which they can bring with themselves into the world.<br/>Emotional neglect is one of the most common and yet most covert and detrimental forms of abuse, and many parents themselves were raised that way and have no differentiating experience to understand what they&#39;re actually doing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf6bhfi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thanks dad, ya fuckin mook.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf6klol/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Just call me Exhibit A.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nlc5i2/both_mothers_and_fathers_significantly_shape/nf6tv5v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:25:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/cancer/vitamin-b3-skin-cancer-risk/</link><title>Daily vitamin B3 dose cuts skin cancer risk by up to 54%: A common, over-the-counter form of vitamin B3 has emerged as an inexpensive ally in protecting us from skin cancer, lowering the risk by an average of 14% and increasing to a massive 54% for anyone who has previously had a positive diagnosis. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>My dad has Gorlin syndrome. Approximately 10years ago he commenced treatment with larger doses of B3. Instead of having 20-30 BCCs removed every ~6 months, the number has reduced to 8-12 removed every  12months.</p><p>When growing up it always confused me why he wore his hat in buildings with skylights etc. - he has always been extremely careful.</p><p>B3 has been a game changer for him.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf1qva2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The study used 500 mg of nicotinamide twice daily, for those curious.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf3239b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sounds like Australia should maybe introduce it into their food supply like iodine</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf27b4z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve linked to the news release in the post above. In this comment, for those interested, here’s the link to the peer reviewed journal article: </p><p><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2838591">https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamadermatology/article-abstract/2838591</a></p><p>From the linked article: </p><p><strong>Daily vitamin B3 dose cuts skin cancer risk by up to 54%</strong></p><p><strong>A common, over-the-counter form of vitamin B3 has emerged as an inexpensive ally in protecting us from skin cancer, lowering the risk by an average of 14% and increasing to a massive 54% for anyone who has previously had a positive diagnosis</strong>. This latest study of more than 33,000 patients supports earlier evidence that emerged in a 2015 Australian trial.</p><p>Researchers from Vanderbilt University Medical Center conducted a large real-world analysis of US veterans, which looked at the health records of 33,822 individuals, comparing those prescribed niacinamide (typically 500 mg twice daily for more than 30 days) with matched patients who didn’t take it.</p><p>Overall, niacinamide – also known as nicotinamide, a vitamin B3 form found in food and supplements that supports cellular energy, DNA repair and healthy skin – was associated with a 14% lower risk of developing skin cancer. When people began nicotinamide after having earlier received a positive skin cancer diagnosis, the reduction in risk was 54%. What&#39;s more, the effect was seen in both basal cell carcinoma and cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, with the largest drop in squamous cell cancers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf1p5i8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Time to add a B vitamin complex back into my supplements.</p><p>Fluorescent pee here we come!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf2ur1w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Niacinimide is a popular skin care ingredient.  I wonder if topical use provides any cancer protection?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf2xt03/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Wonder if this applies to other forms like NMN?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkzwk7/daily_vitamin_b3_dose_cuts_skin_cancer_risk_by_up/nf2s6bi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:58:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://now.tufts.edu/2025/09/18/one-three-young-adults-skip-dentist-and-thats-problem</link><title>1 in 3 young adults skip the dentist, putting young adults at greater risk for future health problems. Dental care in the United States is still excluded from medical health insurance coverage and usually not integrated with public health initiatives that promote preventative care. (now.tufts.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn’t help that in the U.S., dental insurance is basically a coupon. If you have anything major, you’ll hit your limit and be paying out of pocket for most of the procedure.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez0i39/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s insane really. That somehow the government was convinced that eyes and mouth just don’t count as part of your body and you need a separate plan. And all we’re doing it finding out how the more we neglect the more harm we do to other parts of our body.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez11cr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I hate to break it to the researchers, but ALL ages are skipping dental visits or self limiting care. The cost of dental work to a fixed income senor means you &quot;might&quot; get one problem fixed per year and as your older, you have lots more problems than one per year and they only get worse.</p><p>I get $400 a quarter from my Advantage Medicare+ insurance. To cover <em>any</em> dental needs. I have two painful, abscessed, fractured teeth and I&#39;m struggling to figure out what necessity I can give up this next year to afford to have them pulled. Not fixed, not implanted, not even bridged. Just yank them out and give up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez63wd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Skip is a strong word for &quot;cannot afford&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez54nm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I JUST had a dentist appointment two weeks ago... after 20+ years.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez7rjb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We quite literally put $450 in our HSA every month, with the anticipation that we’ll be paying $2000/year out of pocket for dental stuff. Last 4 years: biteguard ($900); crown ($1500); gum grafting surgery ($2700); another biteguard ($800)</p><p>(Yes I’ve tried to find a cheaper option for my biteguards… every other option sucks and ends up needing to be replaced so quickly, I’d rather pay for a legit biteguard. I have very expensive post-orthodontic teeth, so it’s not worth cheaping out on this)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nez6qsb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is also happening in the UK as, despite the NHS, nobody can actually get a dentist appointment without going private.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkmcc9/1_in_3_young_adults_skip_the_dentist_putting/nezm9dr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:55:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/women-tend-to-feel-more-fearful-in-nature-especially-when-social-threats-are-present/</link><title>Women tend to feel more fearful in nature, especially when social threats are present | Study found women consistently expressed more fear, perceived higher risk, and were less inclined to explore wooded environments when potential dangers were present. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>As a woman who loves being in nature, I don’t feel secure if there’re no people around and I would be an easy target for a potential attacker.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nex701x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They buried the important bit in the article.</p><p>&#39;Across the board, women again reported higher levels of fear and lower willingness to explore the environments. This was especially true when the danger was social in nature. In fact, the presence of a social threat produced the strongest gender differences. Women’s fear scores spiked significantly in these conditions, while men’s responses remained largely unaffected. This pattern was not seen when the danger was physical or animal-related.&quot;</p><p>So it appears its all social threat  though the wording of the article is not that clear and im not going to examine the paper. The women were not more fearful or deterred by other threats. Which is interesting.</p><p>Though I wouldn&#39;t overly trust the results given the methodology.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nexjxqx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That&#39;s because of the implications...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/newwkdd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: Women are more likely than men to feel unsafe in nature, particularly in areas with dense vegetation or when social threats are implied, according to a new study <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0272494425002051?via%3Dihub">published</a> in the Journal of Environmental Psychology. Across three experiments involving hundreds of adults in the United Kingdom, women consistently expressed more fear, perceived higher risk, and were less inclined to explore wooded environments when potential dangers were present.</p><p>The study was partially inspired by a viral social media trend that captured public attention in 2024. The “Man or bear” debate asked users whether they would rather encounter a man or a bear while alone in the woods. Many women chose the bear, suggesting that they perceived a greater threat from an unknown man than from a wild animal. This phenomenon sparked a broader discussion about women’s experiences of safety in natural environments and highlighted how social fears can shape engagement with nature.</p><p>Although earlier studies have shown that environmental features like vegetation density can influence feelings of safety, relatively few had examined how those effects may vary by gender, especially when different types of threats — such as social, animal, or physical dangers — are involved. The researchers sought to fill this gap using experimental methods that allowed them to systematically vary environmental cues and measure psychological responses.</p><p>“I became interested in women’s experiences in forests and greenspaces because I had a few experiences in nature myself when I didn’t feel entirely safe, and as a consequence the visit was not as enjoyable as I hoped,” explained study author Anna Bornioli, a Marie Skłodowska-Curie Postdoctoral Fellow at the Barcelona Institute for Global Health and an associate researcher at the Environmental Psychology Research Group at the University of Surrey, where this study was conducted.</p><p>“When chatting with my friends about this, I realised that many female friends empathized, having had similarly bad experiences. On the other hand, many male friends had no idea of what we were talking about. So I started to wonder if gender has anything to do with how we experience nature, and reflected on how gender stereotypes, the way we are brought up, and safety concerns can affect nature experiences. This specific study focuses on safety perceptions.”</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/newqb4z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I love that no one reads in <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science">r/science</a>. The study is clearly suggesting women are more afraid of being attacked by &quot;social threats&quot;, in other words, people.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nexqa9k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Women also live longer</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nex7dvk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I feel like this is probably true in any setting? Women have more to be fearful of than men, generally… even walking a city street, I think women are just going to have more anxiety about people looking at them, following, etc.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nkcb9q/women_tend_to_feel_more_fearful_in_nature/nexp0zo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:32:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newscientist.com/article/2496879-vitamin-d-supplements-may-lower-your-level-of-one-type-of-vitamin-d/</link><title>Vitamin D supplements may lower your level of one type of vitamin D (newscientist.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;They found taking vitamin D2 supplements can lead to a drop in the body’s concentration of vitamin D3. Why this happens, or if vitamin D3 supplements reduce vitamin D2 levels, isn’t entirely clear.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/new609t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The headline is misleading, the study actually shows that D2 suplements lower your levels of D3, but there isn&#39;t evidence that supplementing with D3 affects your D2 levels. It doesn&#39;t recommend stopping supplementing with either, just suggests that D3 is probably more effective.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/new6y7k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While you should always double-check, I don&#39;t think I&#39;ve ever come across a supplement which wasn&#39;t D3.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/newadju/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>mods, why has this clickbaity title been allowed here?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/nexis7i/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tldr, just take D3</p><p>Bonus point, add K2</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/newaum4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This may be relevant to some parents of newborns and young infants, as formula is fortified with vitamin D, and infants exclusively on breast milk are recommended to have Vitamin D supplements. I just checked the vitamin D drops that I have, and it is cholecalciferol, which is D3. The formula I have on hand also specifies D3, but the drops and formula are both Enfamil. It wouldn&#39;t be a bad idea to double check any baby products to see if they specify D2 or ergocalciferol.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/nexpx4d/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>D3 K2 tablets here. I have MDS ( it&#39;s called a &quot; Cinderella condition &quot; because it&#39;s a bit off the radar, and the only famous people to pop their clogs from it are my hero the scientist Carl Sagan, and Larry Hagman the actor ) The D3 K2 supplements are veggie / vegan and cheap as chips.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk9ps1/vitamin_d_supplements_may_lower_your_level_of_one/nex8npl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:54:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/au/blog/the-asymmetric-brain/202509/is-this-the-end-of-the-growth-mindset-theory</link><title>Growth mindset interventions are often used to improve academic performance of students. But a new study found that growth mindset interventions do not improve academic achievements of students. Just by telling somebody that their intelligence can grow if they work hard, it does not actually grow. (psychologytoday.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This may suggest that you can&#39;t give them growth mindset training alone. If you&#39;re giving them that training but not also giving them the training how to study well, I could see this failing--you&#39;re telling them that they can do better without telling them how.</p><p>Moreover, what if you give them the training and they just don&#39;t care anyway?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev4on6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Telling someone about growth mindsets doesn&#39;t give them a growth mindset. And that&#39;s all these &#39;interventions&#39; ever are.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev64y8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you tell people to get over their depression, you&#39;ll probably get the same results.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev669x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But that isn’t what it was for? They were never primarily academic, and certainly not about quick results</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nevjqf7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Isn&#39;t growth mindset just about taking risks and being ok with failure and mistakes?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev42dp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What an awful headline. First is start talking about students academic performance then ends with intelligence. I am not certain the two are always synonymous nor do I believe intelligence can truly be measured in any useful capacity.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nevkb8y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Not to be facetious, but did anyone think this actually worked? Were there real studies that led people down this path?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nk4nd6/growth_mindset_interventions_are_often_used_to/nev3ohh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:00:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/17/climate/national-academies-climate-trump.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mk8.H9nY.DT8PLhUIEux5</link><title>Top Scientists Find Growing Evidence That Greenhouse Gases Are, in Fact, a Danger (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.zinnedproject.org/news/tdih/coal-burning-co2-emissions-and-global-temperatures/">https://www.zinnedproject.org/news/tdih/coal-burning-co2-emissions-and-global-temperatures/</a></p><p>Evidence growing for 113 years and counting.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netmlom/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hasn&#39;t this been known for a while?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/net4jkv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Posting this salient paragraph cause zero people commenting  clicked on the link </p><p>&gt;The report, published by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, is significant because it could complicate the Trump administration’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/07/29/climate/epa-endangerment-finding-repeal-proposal.html">efforts to revoke a landmark scientific determination</a>, known as the endangerment finding, that underpins the federal government’s legal authority to control the pollution that is driving climate change.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/nettart/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Shocker!! What’s amazing is how oil &amp; gas companies have suckered the world to cling to their ugly , toxic, inefficient, outdated fuel that ruins our planet and future!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netv2ec/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>yeah but the new nasa admin is announcing that the suns activity is increasing. that will be used to stop all green initiatives because &quot;it&#39;s not human caused&quot; climate change anymore. lots of conspiracy theories about the sun causing the issues just got validated</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netje4y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I feel like 99% if posts here are just &quot;study finds that water makes stuff wet.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/netanrl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is the crux of why Trump and his administration is so anti-science, it&#39;s difficult to find any of his policies supported by the science. Trump is the mumbo-jumbo President.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njuqmb/top_scientists_find_growing_evidence_that/neu3sob/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:33:02 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.upi.com/Health_News/2025/09/17/circumcision-rates-decline-United-States-mistrust-doctors/5851758118319/</link><title>Study notes decrease in popularity of circumcision in United States (upi.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This article is misleading in how they represent the WHO. The WHO and UNAIDS only recommend male circumcision in their HIV prevention package which was geared towards areas with a high risk of HIV (namely Eastern and Southern Africa). This is <em>not</em> a universal recommendation.</p><p>I could not find any major medical bodies that recommend routine circumcisions in the West, and several bodies such as the AAP and Canadian Paediatric Society explicitly say that they do not recommend it. Some European bodies explicitly advise against routine circumcision for males unless medically necessary.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesskrx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>&quot;Based on our findings, we believe that multiple factors may contribute to the decline in the number of neonates circumcised,&quot; co-senior researcher Dr. Aaron Tobian, a professor of pathology at Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine in Baltimore, said in a news release.</p><p>The sort of distrust that&#39;s led to vaccine skepticism and hesitancy is likely one of those factors, researchers said.</p><p>&quot;Despite overwhelming evidence that neonatal male circumcisions provide health benefits, increasing public skepticism in the United States toward medical recommendations may be driving more parents to choose not to have their sons get circumcised,&quot; Tobian said.</p></blockquote><p>I really dislike this framing. I feel our decision to not circumcise was based on medical advice and recommendations from reputable, credible international and national organizations. Just not exclusively and entirely based on what a couple specific US based orgs and agencies may have recommended.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesqrak/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Disregarding the usual Reddit tilting about circumcision, it simply isn&#39;t medically necessary for most men, the history of circumcision in the US generally stems from religious purity culture, and decisions for elective surgeries should be left to the individual for when they&#39;re adults.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nessr46/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You know what else prevents HIV? Condoms. And not only are they several times more effective, they also don&#39;t involve violating an infant&#39;s bodily autonomy and disfiguring their genitals.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesuqx1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I am glad it&#39;s decreasing. I won&#39;t circumcise my son if I ever have one. Millions upon millions of European men are doing just fine, rarely if ever have issues being uncircumcised, and are somehow managing the <em>really simple</em> task of keeping themselves clean.  </p><p>There is no good reason to <em>proactively</em> do it. If a need arises, do it then. But issues are so rare it doesn&#39;t justify routinely doing it to everyone.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesvphl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yea I am not an antivax, distrust in healthcare kind of guy. I personally just think chopping of a piece of a baby&#39;s bits as soon they are born is simply weird, and wish someone had given me a say in the matter. Simply teaching your child to wash properly eliminates any and all issues related to infections. Shocking I know.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/nesvs3q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It should have been made illegal 100 years ago.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njsv2l/study_notes_decrease_in_popularity_of/netdbmt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 05:05:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.unsw.edu.au/newsroom/news/2025/09/ai-reveals-gender-bias-in-family-courts?&amp;</link><title>The language chosen by judges in family courts reinforces gender biases, with mothers seen mainly as caregivers and fathers judged on their ability to provide financially. Fathers were also praised for even a limited involvement in childcare, whereas mothers' efforts were expected (unsw.edu.au)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Another example – again, consistent with previous work – was when judges looked at whether a father has capacity to care for his child, he often received the benefit of his new partner’s capacity. Where the court was satisfied the father could provide care for his children ‘with the assistance of his present wife&#39;.”</p><p>This would really piss me off as a mother.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/neu6g0j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This title kind of buries the lede here. Language that the judges use always matters, and fathers are often rewarded for limited involvement while mothers’ efforts are expected, but those are both fairly surface level observations that society has regardless. The precise language you use always matters, especially in court. Mothers are always expected to give everything while fathers are generally praised for giving anything at all. Genuine sociological norms in the American 21st century that I’d expect a high schooler to know. </p><p>What I find interesting is that there’s apparent gender differences with 2/3 of all judges being men, but this article doesn’t go into how that imbalance really affects court orders. The article says female judges prioritize the kids while male judges prioritize “court procedures and processes”? But it doesn’t go into what that means or how it affects the children. </p><p>I think it’s <em>really</em> interesting that the article points out that these were known, voiced, and discussed issues already. But it’s interesting that the conversation was only given weight once ai confirmed its (known) existence. </p><p>They discuss how male &amp; female lecturers were evaluated differently. Men were authoritative, women were approachable. That’s interesting.</p><p>They didn’t even factor in minorities! They had ai run this study on gender but supposedly weren’t able to have ai run racial studies. Odd. Interesting, even. I don’t know yall. Basically, ai confirmed known biases that we knew exist. It only ran gender biases. It only confirmed known &amp; proven stereotypes that exist in family court. It’s just another straw in the hay bale of proof that discrimination exists in our society. <strong>It’s not new. It’s been known for decades.</strong></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nespk9t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hi <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/science">r/science</a> - sharing this study led by our researcher Associate Professor Mehera San Roque.</p><p>The team analysed more than 2500 custody and parenting judgments across 4330 documents, handed down in Australian family courts between 2001 and 2021. They looked at the way male and female judges spoke to, and about, male and female parties in relation to their capacity to care for their children and found that judgments reflected gender stereotypes.</p><p>Here&#39;s a link to the full study if you&#39;d like to check it out: <a href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0331841#sec012">https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371/journal.pone.0331841#sec012</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesam5w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yea. This sucks. I was the stay at home dad, took care and nurtured my kids. Effing judge still gave them to my ex.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesfe6b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Do judges anywhere get anti-bias trainings? </p><p>And I mean real training, tested, evaluated, and then repeated after some years?</p><p>Or, because judges ARE justice, there is no such mechanism?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nevhtpp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Glad to have hard evidence on what has always seemed like reality.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesbbsw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&#39;“We used AI to uncover the biases we knew existed in the legal system but remained ‘hidden’,” says the study’s lead author Associate Professor Mehera San Roque&#39;</p><p>That&#39;s not how we do science.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njr0sv/the_language_chosen_by_judges_in_family_courts/nesh681/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 03:46:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/chimpanzees-alcohol-cocktails-fruit-research/</link><title>Wild chimpanzees consume the equivalent of 2 cocktails a day in the form of boozy fruit, research finds (cbsnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I knew of a place in Portland (OR) that had cherry trees in the back yard. Starlings would party like crazy on the cherries fermenting on the ground. Drunk, flopping birds on the ground, birds in the trees keeping watch and making loud bird laughing noises. Crazy scene would go on for days. Outrageous amounts of noise.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/ner3qt0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Am ape<br/>I too like being buzzed, chillen among the trees</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/neqysmw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And humans think they are so different…</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/neqxdz0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Wow how responsible of them, so no heavy boozy fruit consumption. I wonder if they would get any of the long term diseases associated with alcohol.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/nere85u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sure ok but what about the more responsible chimps?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/ner5ols/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While in this case (Ugandan fig) it doesn&#39;t match the alcohol level of a more *impaired* primate, as far as tolerance &amp; abv level (fruit @ .3% by weight / kombucha-level ), other cases of primates included what appeared to be abv% seeking behaviour in other groups of wild chimps &amp; other primates.</p><p><strong><em>Caribbean monkeys</em></strong>, for example, with a penchant for pilfering tourist cocktails. Repeatedly in large amounts, resulting in a dramatic effect/impairment, apparently seeking intoxication.</p><p><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/277985406_Tools_to_tipple_Ethanol_ingestion_by_wild_chimpanzees_using_leaf-sponges/link/62a32160a3fe3e3df86c5ffd/download"><strong><em>The Palm Wine-drinking Chimpanzees of Bossou</em></strong></a></p><p>A community of wild chimpanzees in Guinea that have been observed for ~20 years consuming fermented raffia palm sap, a potent alcoholic beverage with up to 6.9% ABV. <strong><em>Using tools</em></strong> (leaf-sponges) they fashion by chewing leaves—to intentionally access the sap from containers left by villagers &amp; resulting in observed effective behaviour. This deliberate tool use indicates that their consumption of the alcoholic beverage isn&#39;t accidental.</p><p>On a humorous note:</p><blockquote><p>Wild chimpanzees consume the equivalent of 2 cocktails a day</p></blockquote><p><strong><em>Wild chimpanzees</em></strong>?... Wait until they learn:</p><p><strong><em>Really Wild Chimps</em></strong> are hammered by noon, hungover &amp; then breaking their fast by binging!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/net60t0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hey, after a long day of swinging through trees and avoiding hungry cheetahs who wouldn&#39;t enjoy a nice cocktail to wind down.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njkr29/wild_chimpanzees_consume_the_equivalent_of_2/nero2kf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:41:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/autistic-individuals-and-those-with-social-anxiety-differ-in-how-they-experience-empathy-new-study-suggests/</link><title>Empathy may operate quite differently in individuals with autism spectrum condition compared to those with social anxiety. Both groups tended to report elevated levels of emotional distress in social situations, but only individuals with autism showed lower levels of emotional concern for others. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>The findings support a growing view that empathy is not a single, unified trait but a multidimensional construct, with different profiles emerging across psychological conditions. In the case of autism, the study suggests a combination of reduced perspective taking and empathic concern, coupled with heightened personal distress. For those with social anxiety, the pattern includes elevated distress without a corresponding drop in empathic concern. These distinctions have important implications for how we assess and support individuals facing social challenges.</p><p>The study also aligns with existing theories about emotional regulation in autism. One model suggests that autistic individuals may experience high levels of emotional arousal in social situations but lack the cognitive tools to manage those emotions effectively. This imbalance may lead to withdrawal or self-focused responses, which can be misinterpreted as a lack of empathy. The current findings add nuance to this picture by showing that lower levels of empathic concern are not necessarily universal but may interact with how individuals experience and regulate emotional distress.</p></blockquote><p>(Because people were asking about how this ties to other literature on autism &amp; empathy in the previous version of this post).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/neozs9u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>People use the word &quot;empathy&quot; for different concepts. Like reading/interpreting the emotional state of others but also for actually <em>caring about</em> the wellbeing of others when you do know.</p><p>As if not knowing and not caring are the same thing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nep2xuz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Neurotypicals have a specific way they measure empathy and it doesn’t track with how many neurodivergent people demonstrate  empathy.</p><p>If you’re looking for clear outward signs that are kind of performative, then you will miss a lot of it.</p><p>I’m autistic and unless I make the faces and use the tone of voice they’re looking for, it won’t be acknowledged. Even if I jump in to help a stranger or verbally acknowledge I can relate to the feelings of another, the tone and facial expressions have to be ‘right’.</p><p>I have witnessed people do this (‘oh no, I’m so sorry!’) and then walk away with no genuine offers of assistance and that is seen as more empathetic.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nepism1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Neurotype and empathy&#39;s a whole can of worms.</p><p>There&#39;s cognitive, emotional, and compassionate empathy.  While they&#39;re somewhat intertwined, it&#39;s quite possible to be more empathetic in some of these respects than others.</p><p>With autism, each of your senses is just as likely to be too strong or too weak as it is spot on.  That includes interoception, the ability to feel your own internal organs telling you how they&#39;re doing (such as whether you&#39;re hungry, thirsty, or tired).  The ability to feel your own emotions is built on top of interoception (interoceptive hyposensitivity or hypersensitivity -- being too &quot;robotic&quot; or conversely too &quot;childish&quot;), and in turn the ability to feel your emotions reflecting other people&#39;s is built on top of that.</p><p>And on top of all that, how you <em>express</em> empathy and sympathy can be different for many autistic people compared to allistic people.  For example, if someone talks about something bad that happened to them, for many autistic people, sharing a story of something similar that happened to you is a way of showing you understand what they&#39;re going through, whereas for many allistic people, that&#39;s misinterpreted as a selfish attempt to one-up them.</p><p>Not to mention how you express even your own emotions -- such as forgetting to inflect your voice with the right tone, for those of us it doesn&#39;t come naturally to, or not visibly reacting to something even if inside you&#39;re having empathetic thoughts.</p><p>And on top of <em>that</em>, there&#39;s trauma responses causing even more issues.  For example, if you&#39;ve spent your whole life having people think you&#39;re exaggerating your discomfort and pain when you were actually correct, it can make you learn to discount your own needs.  And if every conversation you have with almost everyone backfires, you learn to clam up in public, at work, etc (essentially, justified social anxiety based on a lifetime of experience).</p><p>It&#39;s messy.  There&#39;s a lot of factors at play.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nepch2q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>My son was just diagnosed with autism and he&#39;s extremely empathetic.  He has an incredible amount of concern for others, much more than I did at his age.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nepzkcn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>this is another study failing to address how Autistic people process empathy, described by the double empathy problem.</p><p>I and most Autistic women I know contend with too much empathy and conscientiousness, to the point where it can be anxiety inducing. So an adaptive mechanism is to cognitively interrupt the processing, to parse it at a less demanding time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nepu6ov/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Did they control for ptsd in this study or are we going to continue to pretend that autistic people aren’t collecting all kinds of emotionally screwed up experiences?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1njbegx/empathy_may_operate_quite_differently_in/nepu36l/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 17:41:43 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
