<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=homelab&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/homelab</title><description>Hot posts in /r/homelab (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 11:44:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-Flac-ySmslzY0SE583PNA42rFbcYxLt7hqgCeUrC11s-144x400.png</url><title>/r/homelab</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://i.redd.it/45mv8wv2s4qf1.jpeg</link><title>Finally put some money into a proper rack. (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Now I just need a 3d printer to get some proper mounts for the HP 1L systems.</p><p>Still lots of room for expansion. Would like to get a rack mounted UPS and possibly build a NAS soon enough.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/45mv8wv2s4qf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>what do you use those HPs for?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/nf2sflk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Every time I see one of these racks on here there are a bunch of cables going from what looks like switch to switch. Multiple links from the same device to the same device. What&#39;s going on here? VLAN? QoS? LAG?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/nf2vgje/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Cool, you also use mini PCs. I have 6 HP EliteDesk 800 G5 DM 35W. What do you run on your EliteDesks?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/nf3p763/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Very nice setup</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/nf40o8y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>i&#39;m planning to get one very soon</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/nf41zrw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I really need one also.  its going to have to wait a few weeks.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/nf44dje/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That’s a clean setup!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl4xhk/finally_put_some_money_into_a_proper_rack/nf4brgu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:52:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/rtq1l67oa4qf1.jpeg</link><title>Going to need a bigger rack and a bigger wallet (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Feeling pretty happy with the state of my lab now! No fancy LED lighting, but trying to make up for it with etherlighting.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/rtq1l67oa4qf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>you got my vote. No HP printer (:</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/nf2fao6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There is no end to this hobby my friend. Once you get in there&#39;s no exit 💀💀</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/nf2knu5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>i&#39;m struggling with a 15U rack honestly, UPS, and workstation are eating my rack space like motherfuckers</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/nf2iqsr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Deffo bigger wallet mate :)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/nf2gjw7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>oh brother!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/nf6f16o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>No need for a larger wallet if the money is always gone :D</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/nf46c3c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;d say etherlighting is fancy!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nl2o3v/going_to_need_a_bigger_rack_and_a_bigger_wallet/nf4cfsa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 18:19:27 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/</link><title>Yes, Your ISP can Detect/Block VPN Connections</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I make this post because there seems to be a mass misconception that your ISP can&#39;t detect or block  VPN connections. I&#39;m not sure why so many people think this, but I thought it needed addressed. Especially given posts about Michigan HOUSE BILL NO. 4938, and one of the most up-voted comments there being &quot;Banning VPNs and the other items they listed is literally impossible right now&quot;</p><p>It&#39;s a strange comment, because it is obviously a thought from someone who has never worked in an industry where the subject is important, yet is extremely confident. Your VPN traffic is easily detectable, and blockable at any network device between yourself, and the VPN server itself. There is actually  literally nothing stopping your ISP from doing it except a policy, a protocol analyzer and a firewall (and they already have the last two). </p><p>I work in the cyber security industry (incident response), as well as a network assessment/penetration tester/consultant (several hats).</p><p>Part of what I do in the incident response/security assessments role is detect the use of VPNs, or other tunnels on a network. </p><p>We do this to detect bad actors who may have a back door connection, or system administrators who may be doing Shadow IT to access the network from out of office using unapproved tools.  It&#39;s fairly trivial to detect when connections are using OpenVPN/Wireuard/Cloudflare Tunnels with a little protocol analysis. Most modern packet analyzers make this pretty easy. Of course, it&#39;s extremely obvious when default VPN ports are used, but either way, detectable due to how the packets are structured, as well as those initial handshakes. </p><p>Part of what I do on the penetration testing side is attempt to circumvent VPN filters. There are tools out there that can mask VPN traffic as Websocket/https, and several other technologies. There&#39;s not many open source tooling out there for this, and its fairly obvious to someone (or an AI) looking at the network traffic to tell something isn&#39;t quite right. </p><p>Considering lots of people can&#39;t seem to configure wireguard for example, imagine asking them to setup a Wireguard VPN proxy between their wireguard servers/client that translates the protocol to something else before sending it to it&#39;s destination. Imagine asking everyone to ditch all of the fancy cloud-flare tunnels, Taislcale, etc and instead opt in for implementing complicated protocol masking VPN proxies, and also expecting the ISP to not have some basic packet analysis to detect anomalous packets. Imagine how easy it is for a system to auto-lookup these VPN server IP addresses when suspicious behaviors are detected, and have open source intelligent tools API reply back with a service(VPNServer) version from an automated bot scan. </p><p>The other big argument was the fact so many people use them for work. Most businesses have IP ranges outside of data-center/residential IP blocks. To allow users to still conduct remote work with VPNs, they could just allow VPN connections to those IP ranges. The few exceptions can be told to get over it, or have their company submit their IP range for whitelisting. They could just as easily block VPN connections to your home itself without issue if your servers there. (It&#39;s probably in your TOS) if you aren&#39;t a business.</p><p>My point here is yes, your ISP CAN block your VPN connections. Yes, if you didn&#39;t know, your VPN traffic can easily be identified as VPN traffic, dispite the protocol. There are too many common giveaways. If you&#39;re curious, deploy something like Netflow/SecurityOnion on your network, and watch the alerts/protocols being used/detected. The data itself will stay encrypted, but your ISP knows what you are connecting to, and how. This also extends to generic tunnels. </p><p>This is something that is very real, and should be taken seriously. This isn&#39;t the time for &quot;they can&#39;t or won&#39;t do it&quot;. One day you will simply try to connect, and it will fail. There will be no large network change, and they don&#39;t need to come to your house. They flipped a switch, and now a rule is enabled.</p><p>It is happening right now. You can choose to stick your fingers in your ears, but that won&#39;t stop it.  </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I think majority of us homelabbers know this.  But kudos on writing this post. It’s well explained and worth saving for those who thinks otherwise.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/neyjdsx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>that your ISP can&#39;t detect or block VPN connections.</p></blockquote><p>As other locations that do/try this, it is a whack-a-mole situation.  </p><p>One side finds a work around for a block, the other side adjusts and blocks the new method.</p><p>I&#39;ve also seen a Tier1 ISPs accidentally block VPNs with a misconfiguration in DDoS mitigation tools..  Those are very difficult to get fixed because the group that did it never interacts with end-users who have the issue.  Customer service don&#39;t know anything has changed so it is the customer&#39;s fault..</p><p>Been there done that..</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/neymh8x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Honestly, i do similar job for 5 years. Using solution like darktrace and others stuff. Most common vpn got catched. But obfuscate TCP vpn inside HTTPS with a custom layer in between definitively don&#39;t raise any alarm in 5 years. What i mean is more they want to block, more intrusive they have to be (HTTPS decryption, xdr ,... ). Rely only on network detection have limit and i&#39;m sûre some vpn provider or nerds create à good obfuscation layer to go over gov protection. China cityzen bypass gfw in similar way ;)</p><p>So like everything in security, cat and mouse game. Not a permanent fact.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/neyoieu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>The other big argument was the fact so many people use them for work. Most businesses have IP ranges outside of data-center/residential IP blocks. To allow users to still conduct remote work with VPNs, they could just allow VPN connections to those IP ranges</p></blockquote><p>We are aware of this, but if the bill is banning VPNs since it claims the tech is designed for circumvention then how would corporate VPNs not fit under that same category. The bill I read does not distinguish between the two</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/neym8pc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m not saying you can&#39;t, but I&#39;ve been curious - how can you tell my HTTPS traffic on 443 to some random AWS box is a tunnel among all the noise?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/neykqz1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Blocking VPN’s is definitely but would raise issues. VPN’s used for businesses (mobile or bovpn) for example. </p><p>There’s then just tunneling the traffic over other commonly used ports/protocols that generally aren’t blocked. Attackers have been abusing NTP/DNS/HTTPS ports for eons to exfiltrate data and obfuscating it. </p><p>There’s amount of wasted resources on packet analyzing/inspection and setting it up so it doesn’t impact legitimate use would be a nightmare and massive waste. </p><p>Then people would just find a new way to bypass it. SSH tunnels, proxies, etc. someone could even design a vpn designed to roam between gateways/ports/etc like a laptop between wifi access points.</p><p>If my ISP wants to start a weird war with me using a VPN I’m up to the challenge. For years I used a free Google micro server running strongswan and spamassin to host an on prem Exchange server in my lab (ISP blocks port 25).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/neyszro/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Edit for auto-correct corrections:  </p><p>You are correct. There is no technical reason that vpn traffic can’t be detected and blocked. The bigger problem is all the lawsuits that will quickly follow when remote employees cannot work all the sudden. Yes I know they can just leave the commercial ip ranges alone. But then, you’ll have ppl spinning up businesses just to get around the issue. In fact, country wide, homelabbers, criminals, hobbyists etc will find the cracks and get through them. Then they too will get shut down. It will become a long and nasty game of whack-o-mole on all sides. But the whole time this is going on, there will be lawsuits all over the place, and lawmakers will fold under all the complaints and crazy stuff happening like being constantly hacked by pissed off citizens. Then they will get voted out and replaced. All because they got the grand idea to tinker with a system that they are 100% clueless about.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkkf2y/yes_your_isp_can_detectblock_vpn_connections/neyougk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:37:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/dntn3hfy3zpf1.jpeg</link><title>Finally 3-phase 400V 16A for the Homelab (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>In order to balance the load on the houses electric connection, I finally got 3 phase with 3 individual single phase outlets contracted and installed 😍</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/dntn3hfy3zpf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://giphy.com/gifs/3owzWgnMr5vS37fBsc" target="_blank"><img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/fEBPMsYjjHbqLDUJjC7uPVNb8v3Ab3HhyOeO3Q3AV5E.gif?width=464&height=200&s=627fc35f4baaa18755cf8bb67b9facac828126ec" width="464" height="200"></a></p><p>😍Sick outlets. What do they power? 😍</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/ney0jub/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That is NOT a home lab. You need a new sub - say mansionlab? palacelab? monsterlab?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/ney0mde/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>For me as a german electrician, this is a weird outlet box, especially with the one outlet to the side</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/nexwjpm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Now I wonder how cheap power is where you live. I think my rack uses about 700 W (which I consider somewhat sizable or at least somewhat expensive :) ). And of course I can easily pull this from one phase.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/nexxiqe/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I got the old style giant flat 32A plug in my basement, from old owners having a ceramic oven.</p><p>&quot;Downgrading&quot; to 4 regular 16A circuits.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/ney1y0f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Would that be enough?<br/>I&#39;m eyeing some portable nuclear reactors...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/ney8f8n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Connect directly to the Warp Core&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkhk14/finally_3phase_400v_16a_for_the_homelab/ney5dda/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:48:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1nkez9d</link><title>My current HomeLab setup/TrueNAS (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkez9d/my_current_homelab_setuptruenas/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkez9d/my_current_homelab_setuptruenas/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkez9d/my_current_homelab_setuptruenas/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Mainly running JellyFin &amp; arr’s + Nextcloud with some other self hosted apps on a TerraMaster F4-423 running TrueNAS. OPNsense running on a GMKtec G9 mini NAS which was my main NAS before I upgraded to the TerraMaster. This whole setup has gone through so many phases over the last couple years. Originally started with just a Raspberry Pi5 8GB, which now I have 3. 1 of them is mainly used for NGINX/remote access proxy server and another is mirrored as a back up in case that goes down. Still trying to figure out what to do with the other one. Any recommendations, comments, critique or suggestions welcome. I work in IT now for the past year as a IT support specialist after switching careers from a Commercial HVAC technician for almost 17 years. Hope everyone has a blessed day! </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/26ca5aqpmypf1.jpg?width=4284&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=8c4d25c52ecf88b0c4ee6f8a8ac932765395eed4" height="5712" width="4284" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/bmx49oqpmypf1.jpg?width=5712&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=6cb1e96c600e3577884697f74ae54cf19d340c60" height="4284" width="5712" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/ujc4qnqpmypf1.jpg?width=5712&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=eafd89f1e63b29690f1341d2a42fac6465a82dfe" height="4284" width="5712" /></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The third pi you could run pi hole for a network dns and ad blocker</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkez9d/my_current_homelab_setuptruenas/ney3ute/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Like your cabinet setup! Been thinking of converting my ikea desk drawers to something like that.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkez9d/my_current_homelab_setuptruenas/ney5m1v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Are the racks printed, or RackMate?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkez9d/my_current_homelab_setuptruenas/ney6v4o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Very nice</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkez9d/my_current_homelab_setuptruenas/nf3i2qs/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:11:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/5nq1ja59yxpf1.jpeg</link><title>Server on the wall (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I have no room for a rack the size to fit my server. So i just hung it on the wall behind a door as the door is always open anyway.</p><p>The server is rather quiet so it wont bother.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/5nq1ja59yxpf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Server server on the wall, who has the highest power bill of them all?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/news56q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Edge computing ?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/nex2a7r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/aaz7driskypf1.jpeg?width=2268&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=54b0a1c32ad538acc160ecce2c0f3861dd41b086">https://preview.redd.it/aaz7driskypf1.jpeg?width=2268&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=54b0a1c32ad538acc160ecce2c0f3861dd41b086</a></p><p>So do I</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/nex8sol/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;ve seen people do it like that, but backside upwards to ensure heat escapes upwards. Your method seems less prone to dust accumulation though, as long as there&#39;s enough air flow coming from the front there.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/newitow/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Oops, you might have not left enough space to pop the drives out.</p><p>I recognize that baby, It&#39;s a R730 !!! You&#39;re going to love it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/nex2fre/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I run two 2HE machines in my basement. Clearly we have a different understanding of the word &quot;quiet&quot;...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/newvy98/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I probably would have mounted it vertically so the stress on the mounting rails is more evenly distributed, but all good. :)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkbagz/server_on_the_wall/newjl2p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 20:54:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/</link><title>Michigan HOUSE BILL NO. 4938</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>(a) &quot;Circumvention tools&quot; means any software, hardware, or service designed to bypass internet filtering mechanisms or content restrictions including virtual private networks, proxy servers, and encrypted tunneling methods to evade content restrictions.</p><p><a href="https://www.legislature.mi.gov/documents/2025-2026/billintroduced/House/htm/2025-HIB-4938.htm">https://www.legislature.mi.gov/documents/2025-2026/billintroduced/House/htm/2025-HIB-4938.htm</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Trying to ban VPNs? What&#39;s next? Ad-blockers are illegal? Fuck these people.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/newhy1l/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m not from Michigan, but they could have my &quot;circumvention tools&quot; when they pry them from my cold, dead hands.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/newkwi9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What the fuck is going on. Legislators won’t pass a single law for people’s privacy and refuse to prosecute tech companies with existing antitrust laws but they are turning their focus towards individuals way of accessing networks on their own terms. I’m really getting fed up with this dystopian shit hole future we are headed towards. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/nex074h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>See Also: The First Amendment to the Constitution.</p><p>What they want to restrict is already covered by fraud. (eg. using a VPN to appear to be somewhere else that can access a geolocked stream.)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/newud6x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sponsors are all Republicans in case you had any question about which party is doing this.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/newwinz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Banning VPNs and the other items they listed is literally impossible right now.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/newk7eh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Big Intellectual Property (rights holders)&quot; going after Michiganders&#39; rights.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1nkarm0/michigan_house_bill_no_4938/nex15tc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 20:35:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/uyq5uholltpf1.jpeg</link><title>This is your fault! (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I had no real need for any of this. But I’ve followed this page for a long time and felt like I was missing out. </p><p>TecMojo rack, Tp Link smart switch, old HP laptop with USB external WiFi shared to Ethernet for my wired devices and stand alone network (not ideal I know but the only option for me right now), Synology 220+ for backups of PCs and file sharing, Ubiquiti gateway, U7 WiFi AP for my personal network, Lenovo Tiny for Plex. </p><p>Still trying to figure out how to explain the need to spend the money. </p><p>More to come I’m sure. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/uyq5uholltpf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;When you don&#39;t have me, you don&#39;t need me. When you get me, you can&#39;t be without me.&quot;</p><p>&quot;Love?&quot;</p><p>&quot;Homelab.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/net32ta/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you make it messier, it won’t look expensive and you don’t have to explain anything. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/net7du1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://giphy.com/gifs/Ae7SI3LoPYj8Q" target="_blank"><img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/hFDZK65lXJ6jhWdAq1E8Q8cmWU5TcVBFFFXIvzKUfRw.gif?width=331&height=200&s=a75fdac39bc5eea4a30d83bc7f1f4ae4f0538a9c" width="331" height="200"></a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/netwi93/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>All we did was mention water. We neither led you to it, or forced you to drink.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/netky3f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://giphy.com/gifs/B6Jr28VwfxUFa" target="_blank"><img src="https://external-preview.redd.it/joylmjUx0xOTKKc9NASS5vyvidPHO5Yrz2c09KGvocQ.gif?width=306&height=200&s=de252dd7501d4bc49fe76da33ee27b861ccce696" width="306" height="200"></a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/neu3yd0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Very nice OP!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/net63mp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I see 8 cables and 4 devices. Does that mean they are bridged 2 to a device for bandwidth? </p><p>I&#39;m learning and therefore I&#39;m curious.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/homelab/comments/1njue0k/this_is_your_fault/netn2og/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:16:27 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
