<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:22:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://theintercept.com/2025/09/10/trump-venezuela-boat-attack-drone</link><title>Rand Paul Reveals Venezuela Boat Attack Was a Drone Strike. The senator told The Intercept the attack defied rules of engagement and came from a drone. (theintercept.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ndjq1c/rand_paul_reveals_venezuela_boat_attack_was_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ndjq1c/rand_paul_reveals_venezuela_boat_attack_was_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 11 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ndjq1c/rand_paul_reveals_venezuela_boat_attack_was_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://theintercept.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Screenshot-2025-09-10-at-3.40.44-PM-e1757533798317.png?fit=2580%2C1290&w=1200&h=800' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>The attack on</span> a boat in the Caribbean last Tuesday was carried out by a drone, according to a Republican senator.</p><p>Sen. Rand Paul, R-Ky., took aim at the Trump administration for glorifying the killing of people without trial, saying that the &ldquo;lethal strike&rdquo; was a breach of long-accepted rules of engagement. He also disclosed that it was a drone strike, a fact that the Pentagon and Secretary of War Pete Hegseth have <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/media/hegseth-issues-stark-warning-drug-traffickers-following-us-military-strike-venezuelan-vessel">refused to reveal</a>.</p><p>Paul first criticized the attack in a back-and-forth with Vice President JD Vance on social media. Vance responded to the suggestion that the strike was a war crime by <a href="https://x.com/JDVance/status/1964341436096057502">writing on X</a>, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t give a shit what you call it.&rdquo;&nbsp;Paul <a href="https://x.com/RandPaul/status/1964494191783714933?t=-tk9U3eTwYly_yEh8widFQ&amp;s=19">responded</a> on Saturday calling Vance&rsquo;s comments about killing people without a trial &ldquo;despicable and thoughtless.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>Paul told The Intercept he didn&rsquo;t oppose the use of drones in war but objected to summarily killing people without due process.</p><p>&ldquo;During my time in the Senate, I have been the foremost critic of drones being used on civilians, especially Americans,&rdquo; said Paul, a member of the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations. &ldquo;The recent drone attack on a small speedboat over 2,000 miles from our shore without identification of the occupants or the content of the boat is in no way part of a declared war and defies our longstanding Coast Guard rules of engagement which include: warnings to halt, non-lethal force to capture, and ultimately lethal force in self-defense or in cases of resistance.&rdquo;</p><p>Rep. Gregory Meeks, D-N.Y., and the ranking member of the House Foreign Affairs Committee, was also alarmed about the attack. &ldquo;It is unacceptable that, a week after the strike, Members of the Foreign Affairs Committee have yet to be briefed by the administration on this use of force despite the Committee&rsquo;s clear jurisdiction,&rdquo; he said in a statement on Tuesday. &ldquo;We are a nation of laws, not of one man&rsquo;s whims. Donald Trump does not have the authority to order strikes in international waters.&rdquo;</p><p>President Trump&nbsp;<a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115136798909755892">posted a video</a>&nbsp;to social media last week showing a four-engine speedboat cutting through the water with numerous people on board. An explosion then destroys the boat. Trump said the strike killed 11 people whom he characterized as &ldquo;narcoterrorists.&rdquo; The administration has offered no evidence to bolster these assertions.</p><p><span>Experts say that</span> whoever was on board, the attack was an extrajudicial killing by the Trump administration &mdash; or flat-out murder.</p><p>&ldquo;All people, no matter where they live or what crime they have been accused of, have fundamental human rights, including the rights to life and due process,&rdquo; said Annie Shiel, the U.S. advocacy director of the Center for Civilians in Conflict. &ldquo;Using lethal force in this way, outside of any recognizable armed conflict and without due process, is an extrajudicial execution, not an act of war.&rdquo;</p><p>Brian Finucane, a former State Department lawyer who is a specialist in counterterrorism issues and the laws of war, said that given the evidence that has emerged, the government&rsquo;s statements, and after discussions with other national security lawyers in the week since the strike, he has formed stronger conclusions about the legality of the attack.</p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m much more inclined to think this was just flat-out murder. And I&rsquo;ve bent over backwards to be generous to the government in my interpretations,&rdquo; he told The Intercept. &ldquo;There are circumstances in which the U.S. can use lethal force but that is in the context of an armed conflict, against a lawful target &mdash; an enemy combatant. The Trump administration has not even bothered to make that argument. They have not argued that the United States is in an armed conflict governed by the law of war. They have not argued, much less substantiated, that the target of this attack was a lawful target.&rdquo;</p><figure> <blockquote><p>&ldquo;Outside of armed conflict, we have a word for the premeditated killing of people. That word is murder.&rdquo;</p></blockquote> </figure><p>Finucane accused the government of using legalistic sleight of hand to confuse the various organized armed groups the U.S. has fought during the war on terror and the criminal entities it&rsquo;s now targeting in Latin America. He also took a dim view of Trump&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.lawfaremedia.org/article/trump-offers-first-legal-justification-for-venezuela-boat-strike">War Powers report to Congress</a>,&nbsp;in which the president justified the attack under his Article II constitutional authority as commander in chief of the U.S. military and claimed to be acting pursuant to the United States&rsquo; inherent right of self-defense as a matter of international law.</p><p>&ldquo;The war powers certification doesn&rsquo;t even identify the supposed designated terrorist organization. It uses a lot of legal terms but does not make any sort of coherent legal argument,&rdquo; Finucane said. &ldquo;What is conspicuously absent is any attempt at a legal justification for the premeditated killing of people. And outside of armed conflict, we have a word for the premeditated killing of people. That word is murder.&rdquo;</p><p>Last week, a high-ranking Pentagon official who spoke to the Intercept on the condition of anonymity said that the strike in the Caribbean a <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/09/05/pentagon-official-trump-boat-strike-was-a-criminal-attack-on-civilians/?utm_content=bufferceea8&amp;utm_medium=buffer&amp;utm_source=bsky&amp;utm_campaign=theintercept">criminal attack on civilians</a> and said that the Trump administration paved the way for it by firing the top legal authorities of the Army and the Air Force earlier this year. &ldquo;The U.S. is now directly targeting civilians. Drug traffickers may be criminals but they aren&rsquo;t combatants,&rdquo; the War Department official said. &ldquo;When Trump fired the military&rsquo;s top lawyers the rest saw the writing on the wall, and instead of being a critical firebreak they are now a rubber stamp complicit in this crime.&rdquo;</p><p>The Pentagon refused to comment on the official&rsquo;s characterization of the strike. &ldquo;We have nothing additional to provide,&rdquo; press secretary Kingsley Wilson wrote in an email after providing nothing.</p><p>Asked about Paul&rsquo;s disclosure that the strike last Tuesday was carried out by a drone, Wilson replied: &ldquo;Nothing for you on that.&rdquo;</p><p>Secretary of State Marco Rubio made clear that the U.S. could have halted the ship and arrested the crew but chose to summarily execute them instead. &ldquo;Instead of interdicting it, on the president&rsquo;s orders, we blew it up &mdash; and it&rsquo;ll happen again,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/trump-weighs-strikes-targeting-cartels-inside-venezuela">he boasted</a>.</p><p>Finucane called the admission &ldquo;horrifying&rdquo; and pointed to the legal ramifications. The assertion that the president opted to blow the vessel up to send a message &ldquo; undercuts any sort of claim that the U S was acting in self-defense, either for purposes of international law or self-defense as an affirmative defense to charges of murder by the president,&rdquo; Finucane said.</p><p><a href="https://www.law.georgetown.edu/faculty/todd-c-huntley/">Todd Huntley</a>, a former Staff Judge Advocate who served as a legal adviser on Joint Special Operations task forces conducting drone strikes in Afghanistan and elsewhere and now directs the national security law program at Georgetown University Law Center, said that the strike risked opening the door to attacks against Americans &mdash; and even U.S. citizens &mdash; within the United States.</p><p>&ldquo;With Afghanistan, Iraq, and the war on terror, we framed everything as counterterrorism. And we&rsquo;ve seen counterterrorism and counter-insurgency tactics flowing back into the United States with militarized policing,&rdquo; Huntley told The Intercept. &ldquo;Now, if the president is willing to strike a boat in international waters, is he willing to use force against a vehicle with members of a cartel in it? What if there is a civilian, like a wife or a girlfriend &mdash; an American citizen &mdash; in the vehicle? It&rsquo;s a slippery slope.&rdquo;</p><p><span>Venezuela&rsquo;s government pushed</span> back on claims that the country is a key player in the global drug trade on Monday. Vice President Delcy Rodr&iacute;guez <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A4cX5VNk9EU">offered</a> a detailed <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2c7OJlf7JDY">rebuttal</a>, citing reports from the United Nations and the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration, insisting that Venezuela &ldquo;has absolutely nothing to do with the deaths of [U.S.] citizens from drug overdoses.&rdquo; Rodr&iacute;guez added that her country &ldquo;is not relevant&rdquo; in global drug production and said that the U.S. government should redirect its recently deployed maritime forces in the Caribbean to the Pacific, where speedboats and container ships have, she said, long carried Colombian cocaine.</p><p>Venezuelan officials believe Trump may be renewing&nbsp;<a href="https://theintercept.com/2019/01/30/donald-trump-and-the-yankee-plot-to-overthrow-the-venezuelan-government/">long-running efforts</a>, which failed during his <a href="https://theintercept.com/2019/02/13/neoliberalism-or-death-the-u-s-economic-war-against-venezuela/">first term</a>, to topple President Nicol&aacute;s Maduro&rsquo;s government. Maduro and several close allies <a href="https://theintercept.com/2020/05/09/venezuela-coup-regime-change/">were indicted</a> in a New York federal court in 2020 on federal charges of narco-terrorism and conspiracy to import cocaine. Last month, the U.S. doubled its reward for information leading to Maduro&rsquo;s arrest to $50 million.</p><p>The Trump administration added the Venezuelan Cartel de los Soles, or Cartel of the Suns, to a list of specially designated global terrorist groups, alleging that it is headed by Maduro and high-ranking officials in his administration. In July, Trump&nbsp;also&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/08/us/trump-military-drug-cartels.html">signed a secret directive </a>ordering the Pentagon to use military force against some Latin American drug cartels he<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/02/us/politics/trump-venezuela-boat-drugs-attack.html">&nbsp;</a>has<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/02/us/politics/trump-venezuela-boat-drugs-attack.html"> labeled terrorist organizations</a>.</p><p>Speaking on Fox News, Hegseth did not rule out regime change by the U.S. in Venezuela. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s a presidential-level decision and we&rsquo;re prepared with every asset that the American military has,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Hegseth and Chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Dan Caine made an unannounced trip to Puerto Rico on Monday. Their visit followed reports that the Pentagon had repositioned 10 F-35 fighter jets to the island amid escalating tensions with Maduro.&nbsp;The aircraft will join around 4,500 U.S. personnel,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-builds-up-forces-caribbean-officials-experts-ask-why-2025-08-29/">seven U.S. warships</a>&nbsp;and one nuclear-powered attack submarine which are either currently in the Caribbean or are expected to arrive there soon.</p><p>Two armed Venezuelan F-16 fighter jets flew over the U.S. Navy guided-missile destroyer USS Jason Dunham in the southern Caribbean Sea in a show of force last week. The Pentagon called it a &ldquo;highly provocative move&rdquo; that was &ldquo;designed to interfere with our counter-narco-terror operations&rdquo; and issued a threat. &ldquo;The cartel running Venezuela is strongly advised not to pursue any further effort to obstruct, deter or interfere with counternarcotics and counterterrorism operations carried out by the U.S. military,&rdquo; read the&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/DeptofDefense/status/1963775938233299235">statement</a>&nbsp;released on X last Thursday night.</p><p>Maduro&rsquo;s government recently made a <a href="https://presidencia.gob.ve/Site/Web/Principal/paginas/classMostrarEvento3.php?id_evento=30637">formal complaint</a> about &ldquo;systematic and illegal harassment&rdquo; by the U.S. to the United Nations.&nbsp;On Sunday, Maduro <a href="https://presidencia.gob.ve/Site/Web/Principal/paginas/classMostrarEvento3.php?id_evento=30627">ordered</a> the deployment of 25,000 soldiers to reinforce rapid reaction forces, including along the country&rsquo;s Caribbean coast. This followed the <a href="https://presidencia.gob.ve/Site/Web/Principal/paginas/classMostrarEvento3.php?id_evento=30626">activation</a> of militia and popular forces.</p><p>Before the Trump administration ramped up tensions with Venezuela in recent weeks, the Pentagon had already been carrying out numerous <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/09/02/trump-military-venezuela-drug-boat/">training missions, exercises, and conferences</a> &mdash; that have mostly been ignored by the press &mdash; with military personnel from across Latin America and the Caribbean. U.S. Southern Command has been busy of late, conducting a series of military exercises and training operations. One Marine Corps operation in Puerto Rico includes the amphibious landing of troops on a beachhead in southern Puerto Rico &mdash; precisely the forces necessary for the invasion of a coastal nation.</p><p>On Monday, Hegseth visited the amphibious assault ship USS Iwo Jima off the coast of Puerto Rico, which he called &ldquo;a floating island of American power,&rdquo; according to a video <a href="https://x.com/DOWResponse/status/1965152057196957935">posted by the Pentagon</a> on X.&nbsp;&ldquo;What you&rsquo;re doing right now, it&rsquo;s not training,&rdquo; he told troops on board. &ldquo;This is the real-world exercise on behalf of the vital national interests of the United States of America to end the poisoning of the American people.&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 22:24:56 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theverge.com/news/775524/reddit-subreddit-member-count-vistors-contributions</link><title>Reddit is dropping subscriber counts on subreddits. ﻿Users will now see seven-day metrics that track active visitors and contributions instead. (theverge.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nddbx0/reddit_is_dropping_subscriber_counts_on/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nddbx0/reddit_is_dropping_subscriber_counts_on/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nddbx0/reddit_is_dropping_subscriber_counts_on/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/02/STK115_Reddit_04.jpg?quality=90&strip=all&crop=0%2C10.732984293194%2C100%2C78.534031413613&w=1200' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><div><p><span><span><span>Jess Weatherbed</span></span></span></p><p><span>is a news writer focused on creative industries, computing, and internet culture. Jess started her career at TechRadar, covering news and hardware reviews.</span></p></div></div><div><p>Reddit users can no longer see how many people are subscribed to their favorite subreddit communities. The platform has announced that it&rsquo;s removing the member count metric that appears on subreddit pages &mdash; located under the page bio on the right for desktop users, or at the top under the subreddit name on mobile &mdash; to better focus on real-time engagement.</p><p>The member count is being replaced by two metrics. One shows how many users have visited a subreddit in the past seven days, &ldquo;based on a rolling 28-day average,&rdquo; <a href="https://redditinc.com/blog/new-ways-to-see-community-activity-on-reddit">according to Reddit</a>, and the other displays how many contributions have been made in the past seven days, excluding any posts or comments that have been removed. The change aims to provide a better glimpse at how active a subreddit actually is, as Redditors may simply be &ldquo;lurking&rdquo; in these communities without adding content or engaging in conversations.</p><p>&ldquo;Member counts don&rsquo;t tell the whole story. In most cases, Redditors don&rsquo;t need to be a member of a community to post or comment, which means member totals have never fully reflected true engagement,&rdquo; <a href="https://redditinc.com/blog/new-ways-to-see-community-activity-on-reddit">Reddit said in its announcement</a>. &ldquo;By emphasizing active participation over passive membership, we&rsquo;re continuing to highlight what makes Reddit unique: real people engaging in real conversations.&rdquo;</p><p>This update is part of Reddit&rsquo;s goal to improve moderation on the platform, because allowing individuals to moderate an unlimited number of large communities isn&rsquo;t &ldquo;sustainable,&rdquo; according to Reddit. The new visitor counts will be used to limit how many busy subreddits each moderator can oversee, restricting them to a maximum of five communities with over 100k visitors. Reddit says that communities with fewer than 100k visitors &ldquo;won&rsquo;t count toward this limit,&rdquo; and that the change will only impact 0.1 percent of active mods.</p><p>Moderators can still view the total number of subscribers by looking at the subreddit insights, but this isn&rsquo;t something that regular Reddit users will be able to see. The changes haven&rsquo;t gone down well, judging by the comments on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/modnews/comments/1ncn0go/evolving_moderation_on_reddit_reshaping_boundaries/?share_id=Om3p8CUFtZO3bYBy5pdCN&amp;utm_content=2&amp;utm_medium=android_app&amp;utm_name=androidcss&amp;utm_source=share&amp;utm_term=1">Reddit&rsquo;s post on r/modnews</a>, but the new metrics do seem useful for users who want a more accurate look at how active a subreddit actually is.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/775524/reddit-subreddit-member-count-vistors-contributions#comments"><span>0 Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Jess Weatherbed</span></span></span></li><li><li><li></ul></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/chorus/author_profile_images/195820/JESSICA_WEATHERBED.0.jpg?quality=90&amp;strip=all&amp;crop=0%2C0%2C100%2C100&amp;w=96"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 18:20:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/09/pfizer-reports-positive-covid-shot-results-despite-government-fueled-chaos/</link><title>Pfizer says this season’s COVID shot boosts immune responses fourfold (arstechnica.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ndbdf1/pfizer_says_this_seasons_covid_shot_boosts_immune/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ndbdf1/pfizer_says_this_seasons_covid_shot_boosts_immune/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ndbdf1/pfizer_says_this_seasons_covid_shot_boosts_immune/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/GettyImages-1231396408-1152x648.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Pfizer and BioNTech report that their <a href="https://www.pfizer.com/news/press-release/press-release-detail/pfizer-and-biontech-announce-topline-data-demonstrating">updated mRNA COVID-19 vaccine for the 2025&ndash;2026 season</a> produced strong immune responses, boosting neutralizing antibody levels by at least fourfold in older people and those with underlying medical conditions.</p><p>The positive results come as <a href="https://arstechnica.com/health/2025/09/who-can-get-a-covid-vaccine-and-how-its-complicated/">Americans face a confusing, state-by-state patchwork of access to the shots</a> under health secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr., an ardent anti-vaccine activist who has unilaterally restricted access. Prior to the second Trump administration, all Americans ages 6 months and older had access to the vaccines. But under Kennedy, the Food and Drug Administration limited COVID-19 vaccine approvals to people 65 and older, and people under 64 years only if they have an underlying medical condition.</p><p>In Pfizer and BioNTech's latest trial, the companies limited enrollment to these groups. The phase 3 trial included 100 people total, 50 people age 65 or older and 50 people age 18 to 64 with an underlying condition. <a href="https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT07069309">Those conditions</a> included asthma, diabetes, heart conditions, HIV, mental health conditions, Parkinson's disease, obesity, or smoking. All participants had gotten last season's COVID shot at least six months prior to the trial and had not gotten any other COVID-19 vaccines or a COVID-19 infection since then.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:46:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thedailybeast.com/rfk-jr-comes-up-with-new-possible-cause-for-mass-shootings-video-games/</link><title>RFK Jr. Comes Up With New Possible Cause for Mass Shootings: Video Games (thedailybeast.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nd53ee/rfk_jr_comes_up_with_new_possible_cause_for_mass/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nd53ee/rfk_jr_comes_up_with_new_possible_cause_for_mass/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 12 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nd53ee/rfk_jr_comes_up_with_new_possible_cause_for_mass/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article><p>Robert F. Kennedy Jr. has vowed to get to the bottom of whether there is a connection between video games and mass shootings in America. </p><p>On Tuesday, amid <a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/rfk-jrs-family-joins-chorus-calling-for-his-resignation-amid-chaos-at-hhs/" title="https://www.thedailybeast.com/rfk-jrs-family-joins-chorus-calling-for-his-resignation-amid-chaos-at-hhs/">calls for his resignation</a>, Kennedy and the Make America Healthy Again Commission held an <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o9Ya5X7bxMg" title="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o9Ya5X7bxMg">hour-long event</a> to discuss the committee&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/MAHA-Report-The-White-House.pdf" title="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/MAHA-Report-The-White-House.pdf">report on children&rsquo;s health</a>. During the proceedings, Kennedy discussed the topic of mass shootings. </p><p>&ldquo;Switzerland has a comparable number of guns as we do, and the last mass shooting they had was 23 years ago,&rdquo; said Kennedy, 71. &ldquo;We have a mass shooting every 23 hours.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;There are many things that happened in the 1990&rsquo;s that could explain these,&rdquo; he added. &ldquo;One is the dependence on psychiatric drugs... there could be connections with video games and social media.&rdquo;</p><p>Kennedy concluded by noting the NIH is &ldquo;initiating studies&rdquo; that &ldquo;look at the correlation and connection between overmedicating our kids and this violence, and these other possible co-founders.&rdquo;</p><figure><img alt="Robert F. Kennedy Jr. testifies before the House Energy and Commerce Committee Health Subcommittee in the Rayburn House Office Building on June 24, 2025 in Washington, DC" src="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/FE3B2SEVI5AQ5K5BAMKQI3RMAY.jpg?auth=0e780c2bf55bd2d732ba8cc268520c90bc013102179bad327f920094eec8825b&amp;width=800&amp;height=533" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/FE3B2SEVI5AQ5K5BAMKQI3RMAY.jpg?auth=0e780c2bf55bd2d732ba8cc268520c90bc013102179bad327f920094eec8825b&amp;width=274&amp;height=182 274w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/FE3B2SEVI5AQ5K5BAMKQI3RMAY.jpg?auth=0e780c2bf55bd2d732ba8cc268520c90bc013102179bad327f920094eec8825b&amp;width=400&amp;height=266 400w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/FE3B2SEVI5AQ5K5BAMKQI3RMAY.jpg?auth=0e780c2bf55bd2d732ba8cc268520c90bc013102179bad327f920094eec8825b&amp;width=768&amp;height=511 768w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/FE3B2SEVI5AQ5K5BAMKQI3RMAY.jpg?auth=0e780c2bf55bd2d732ba8cc268520c90bc013102179bad327f920094eec8825b&amp;width=1024&amp;height=682 1024w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/FE3B2SEVI5AQ5K5BAMKQI3RMAY.jpg?auth=0e780c2bf55bd2d732ba8cc268520c90bc013102179bad327f920094eec8825b&amp;width=1440&amp;height=959 1440w" width="800" height="533"><figcaption><span>The HHS declined to comment on Kennedy's statement connecting video games to mass shootings. </span><span>Kayla Bartkowski/Getty Images </span></figcaption></figure><p>American politicians and anti-video game activists have attempted to paint video games as a cause for gun violence for decades, but experts have asserted there is no correlation between video games and mass shootings. </p><p>In 2019, the <a href="https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2019/09/video-games-school-shootings" title="https://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2019/09/video-games-school-shootings">American Psychological Association</a> published a report from psychology professor Patrick Markey, PhD, that described video games as a &ldquo;red herring&rdquo; to distract from other potential causes of mass shootings. Markey&rsquo;s study also discovered that &ldquo;video games&rdquo; are talked about as a potential cause for shootings more often when the perpetrator behind a recent mass shooting is white. </p><div><a href="https://www.thedailybeast.com/rfk-jrs-family-joins-chorus-calling-for-his-resignation-amid-chaos-at-hhs/"><picture><source alt="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 04: Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC. The committee met to hear testimony on President Trump's 2026 health care agenda. (Photo by Andrew Harnik/Getty Images)" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/BMT4B25CHVAQ5CIRW6QT5EH57U.jpg?auth=175fbedbc7196497b414f195a0f30a8421b77c361b9f4524b5d019cf1e0cb9c3&amp;smart=true&amp;width=400" width="400"><source alt="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 04: Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC. The committee met to hear testimony on President Trump's 2026 health care agenda. (Photo by Andrew Harnik/Getty Images)" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/BMT4B25CHVAQ5CIRW6QT5EH57U.jpg?auth=175fbedbc7196497b414f195a0f30a8421b77c361b9f4524b5d019cf1e0cb9c3&amp;smart=true&amp;width=600" width="600"><source alt="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 04: Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC. The committee met to hear testimony on President Trump's 2026 health care agenda. (Photo by Andrew Harnik/Getty Images)" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/BMT4B25CHVAQ5CIRW6QT5EH57U.jpg?auth=175fbedbc7196497b414f195a0f30a8421b77c361b9f4524b5d019cf1e0cb9c3&amp;smart=true&amp;width=800" width="800"><source alt="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 04: Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC. The committee met to hear testimony on President Trump's 2026 health care agenda. (Photo by Andrew Harnik/Getty Images)" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/BMT4B25CHVAQ5CIRW6QT5EH57U.jpg?auth=175fbedbc7196497b414f195a0f30a8421b77c361b9f4524b5d019cf1e0cb9c3&amp;smart=true&amp;width=1000" width="1000"><source alt="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 04: Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC. The committee met to hear testimony on President Trump's 2026 health care agenda. (Photo by Andrew Harnik/Getty Images)" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/BMT4B25CHVAQ5CIRW6QT5EH57U.jpg?auth=175fbedbc7196497b414f195a0f30a8421b77c361b9f4524b5d019cf1e0cb9c3&amp;smart=true&amp;width=1200" width="1200"><source alt="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 04: Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC. The committee met to hear testimony on President Trump's 2026 health care agenda. (Photo by Andrew Harnik/Getty Images)" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/BMT4B25CHVAQ5CIRW6QT5EH57U.jpg?auth=175fbedbc7196497b414f195a0f30a8421b77c361b9f4524b5d019cf1e0cb9c3&amp;smart=true&amp;width=1400" width="1400"><img alt="WASHINGTON, DC - SEPTEMBER 04: Health and Human Services Secretary Robert Kennedy Jr. testifies before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC. The committee met to hear testimony on President Trump's 2026 health care agenda. (Photo by Andrew Harnik/Getty Images)" src="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/BMT4B25CHVAQ5CIRW6QT5EH57U.jpg?auth=175fbedbc7196497b414f195a0f30a8421b77c361b9f4524b5d019cf1e0cb9c3&amp;smart=true&amp;width=300" width="300"></source></source></source></source></source></source></picture></a></div><p>Kennedy&rsquo;s comparison between Switzerland&rsquo;s gun rates and the United States&rsquo; is a familiar talking point for pro-gun activists like the NRA. Roughly 3-in-10 citizens in both Switzerland and the United States own guns, and Switzerland has a much lower rate of gun-related crime. As a result, pro-gun activists have long pointed to Switzerland as a way to refute the idea that the proliferation of guns leads to mass violence. </p><p>The claims have led to significant research investigating why Switzerland&rsquo;s gun-related crime rate is so much lower than the United States. A <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178924000776" title="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1359178924000776">study</a> published by Science Direct in August of 2024 suggested a myriad of factors could explain the discrepancy in the two nations&rsquo; crime rates. <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0020138324004406#:~:text=In%20comparison%2C%20Austria%20and%20Germany,in%20Germany%2C%20Austria%20and%20Switzerland." title="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0020138324004406#:~:text=In%20comparison%2C%20Austria%20and%20Germany,in%20Germany%2C%20Austria%20and%20Switzerland.">For example</a>, Switzerland has significantly stricter barriers to gun ownership than the United States, and only ex-military personnel in Switzerland are allowed to keep their gun in the house. </p><p>Switzerland also has access to psychiatric medicine, video games, and social media. </p><figure><img alt="Robert Kennedy Jr. appears before the Senate Finance Committee at the Dirksen Senate Office Building on September 04, 2025 in Washington, DC" src="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/3HG2PD2VJVAXFGN4XLIN4MP5YY.jpg?auth=593e244e934d157ade16c1a074a04ccdb559285e7d0f1a7bd4b2de4577ae89fd&amp;width=800&amp;height=533" srcset="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/3HG2PD2VJVAXFGN4XLIN4MP5YY.jpg?auth=593e244e934d157ade16c1a074a04ccdb559285e7d0f1a7bd4b2de4577ae89fd&amp;width=274&amp;height=182 274w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/3HG2PD2VJVAXFGN4XLIN4MP5YY.jpg?auth=593e244e934d157ade16c1a074a04ccdb559285e7d0f1a7bd4b2de4577ae89fd&amp;width=400&amp;height=266 400w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/3HG2PD2VJVAXFGN4XLIN4MP5YY.jpg?auth=593e244e934d157ade16c1a074a04ccdb559285e7d0f1a7bd4b2de4577ae89fd&amp;width=768&amp;height=511 768w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/3HG2PD2VJVAXFGN4XLIN4MP5YY.jpg?auth=593e244e934d157ade16c1a074a04ccdb559285e7d0f1a7bd4b2de4577ae89fd&amp;width=1024&amp;height=682 1024w, https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/3HG2PD2VJVAXFGN4XLIN4MP5YY.jpg?auth=593e244e934d157ade16c1a074a04ccdb559285e7d0f1a7bd4b2de4577ae89fd&amp;width=1440&amp;height=959 1440w" width="800" height="533"><figcaption><span>Kennedy's comments come days after a calamitous Senate hearing led to loud calls for his resignation. </span><span>Andrew Harnik/Getty Images </span></figcaption></figure><p>The HHS declined to expand on Secretary Kennedy&rsquo;s comments.</p></article></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thedailybeast.com/resizer/v2/IGFDZ4PSNNEU3ESTL6XUM3JE74.jpg?auth=3afbee22500f5762a7a445966c23d0633c63e08e28f9f81e2708b531089a6836&amp;smart=true&amp;width=300"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 10:16:02 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wired.com/story/moderna-ceo-responds-to-rfk-jrs-crusade-against-the-covid-19-vaccine/</link><title>Moderna CEO Responds to RFK Jr.’s Crusade Against the Covid-19 Vaccine (wired.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncxcfg/moderna_ceo_responds_to_rfk_jrs_crusade_against/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncxcfg/moderna_ceo_responds_to_rfk_jrs_crusade_against/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncxcfg/moderna_ceo_responds_to_rfk_jrs_crusade_against/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.wired.com/photos/68c086b8a090cc6a539ba25d/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/GettyImages-1475304113.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>At the WIRED</span> Health summit on Tuesday, <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/rewired-2021-stephane-bancel-nahid-bhadelia/">Moderna CEO St&eacute;phane Bancel</a> said the recent changes to <a href="https://www.wired.com/tag/covid-19">Covid-19</a> vaccine policy made by Health and Human Services secretary <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/rfk-jr-is-supporting-mrna-research-just-not-for-vaccines/">Robert F. Kennedy, Jr. are a &ldquo;step backward.&rdquo;</a></p><p>Moderna is one of the manufacturers of mRNA-based Covid-19 vaccines, and last month the company received approval from the Food and Drug Administration for an <a href="https://feeds.issuerdirect.com/news-release.html?newsid=8068604919603497&amp;symbol=MRNA">updated version of the shot</a>. But as part of that approval, the FDA imposed new restrictions on who can receive the vaccine. Previously, Covid vaccines were recommended for anyone 6 months or older. Now, the FDA says they should only be given to individuals at high risk of serious disease, either because they are 65 and older or have other health problems.</p><p>&ldquo;I think it complicates things for people,&rdquo; Bancel said. &ldquo;You might have somebody in your household&mdash;a parent, a spouse, a kid&mdash;who is at high risk&rdquo; that you want to protect, he said. Before, healthy individuals could just go to a pharmacy to receive a Covid shot. Now, several states require a prescription to get a Covid shot because of the FDA&rsquo;s changes.</p><p>Kennedy has been on a <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/rfk-jr-is-supporting-mrna-research-just-not-for-vaccines/">crusade against vaccines</a> since he stepped into the role of HHS secretary in February; earlier this week, the Senate Finance Committee grilled him about his actions in office so far.</p><p>In May, Kennedy terminated a $590 million contract with Moderna for the development of an mRNA-based <a href="https://www.wired.com/tag/bird-flu/">bird flu</a> vaccine candidate. The contract was awarded during the final days of the Biden administration in January, just before President Donald Trump&rsquo;s second term began. Bird flu is widespread in wild birds and has been causing outbreaks in poultry and US dairy cows since March 2024. It has caused sporadic cases in people, most of them farm workers, but poses a pandemic potential if it develops the ability to spread from person to person.</p><p>That same month, Kennedy announced that HHS would no longer recommend mRNA Covid-19 vaccines for healthy children and pregnant women. In June, the FDA said it would require new labels on mRNA vaccines to include safety information about the risks of myocarditis and pericarditis, rare side effects observed mostly in young men following administration of the shots.</p><p>In August, as a part of a &ldquo;coordinated wind-down&rdquo; of mRNA vaccine research, HHS canceled 22 related contracts and investments worth nearly $500 million. Kennedy incorrectly said in a statement these vaccines &ldquo;fail to protect effectively against upper respiratory infections like Covid and flu.&rdquo; HHS is instead shifting funding to an older vaccine platform known as &ldquo;whole-virus&rdquo; vaccines.</p><p>Despite the administration&rsquo;s backlash against mRNA vaccines, Bancel said he is &ldquo;encouraged by the dialog&rdquo; that the company has had with the FDA. In addition to getting updated Covid shots, albeit with limitations, Moderna also received expanded approval this year for its respiratory syncytial virus, or RSV, vaccine to include adults ages 18 to 59 who are at increased risk of disease. The vaccine was initially approved in May 2024 for adults aged 60 years and older.</p><p>&ldquo;I think a lot of people back in January, including my own team, were quite worried that we might not get those approvals,&rdquo; Bancel said.</p><p>The administration&rsquo;s crackdown on mRNA research so far has not extended to the cancer space, and Moderna is developing several mRNA therapies against cancer, including personalized cancer vaccines. The company has 45 programs in the pipeline&mdash;across cancer, rare diseases, and more&mdash;and has said it expects 10 FDA approvals in the next three years. &ldquo;We are using exactly the same technology to go from infectious disease to cancer,&rdquo; Bancel said.</p><p>He also addressed accusations that the Covid vaccines have not been well tested. &ldquo;I don't think there's been a vaccine more studied for efficacy and safety in the history of vaccines,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;In terms of vaccine efficacy and safety, there's been studies done in literally millions of people in the real world.&rdquo;</p><p><em>Update 9/10/25 10:25am ET: This story has been updated to reflect that Moderna's 45 pipeline programs address a range of disease, including but not limited to cancer.</em></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 04:05:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/jobs-manufacturing-trump-tariffs-economy/</link><title>The U.S. is losing thousands of manufacturing jobs, analysis finds (cbsnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncnvoa/the_us_is_losing_thousands_of_manufacturing_jobs/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncnvoa/the_us_is_losing_thousands_of_manufacturing_jobs/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncnvoa/the_us_is_losing_thousands_of_manufacturing_jobs/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets3.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2025/09/09/b2537a60-15f7-4ea3-9809-5b299125d3fd/thumbnail/1200x630/afbc01384dccc2cc8798fd8e0db5aee2/gettyimages-2157173718.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"> <article><div><header><div><div><p>By </p><div><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/team/megan-cerullo/"><div><p>Megan Cerullo</p><p>Reporter, MoneyWatch</p></div></a><p>Megan Cerullo is a New York-based reporter for CBS MoneyWatch covering small business, workplace, health care, consumer spending and personal finance topics. She regularly appears on CBS News 24/7 to discuss her reporting. </p><p><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/team/megan-cerullo/">Read Full Bio</a> </p></div></div><p><time>Updated on: September 9, 2025 / 1:49 PM EDT</time> / CBS News </p></div></header> </div><figure><div><div><div><svg> <use></use> </svg><p><span>White House reacts to lousy jobs report </span> </p></div></div></div><figcaption> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/video/white-house-reacts-to-lousy-jobs-report/"> <span>White House reacts to lousy jobs report</span> <span>05:29</span> </a> </figcaption> </figure> <section><p>Manufacturers in the U.S. are cutting thousands of jobs even as President Trump pushes economic policies that he says will revitalize the industry.&nbsp;</p><p>Employers <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/jobs-report-august-2025-economy-trump-hiring-bls/">shed 12,000 manufacturing jobs</a></span>&nbsp;in August, while payrolls in the sector have shrunk by 42,000 since April, according to a new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/article/trumps-trade-war-squeezes-middle-class-manufacturing-employment/">analysis</a>&nbsp;from the Center for American Progress (CAP) that draws on government labor data.&nbsp;</p><p>The nonpartisan policy institute attributes that decline to the Trump administration's steep new tariffs; hardline stance on immigration; and the Republican-backed "big, beautiful bill," a tax and spending package <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-to-sign-one-big-beautiful-bill-ceremony-today-watch-live-2025-07-04/">enacted by Mr. Trump</a></span> in July that CAP says hurts renewable energy companies by phasing out certain tax credits.</p><p>For all of 2025, manufacturing employment in the U.S. has sunk by a total of 33,000 jobs, according to Labor Department&nbsp;<a href="https://data.bls.gov/dataViewer/view/timeseries/CES3000000001">figures</a>. Most of those job losses have been among companies that make durable goods, such as cars, household appliances and electronics. The drop comes as hiring overall has slowed sharply in recent months, with employers adding only <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/jobs-report-august-2025-economy-trump-hiring-bls/">22,000 jobs in August</a></span>, well below forecasts.&nbsp;</p><p>The number of manufacturing jobs in the U.S. has declined for the past six decades, according to&nbsp;<a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/MANEMP#:~:text=Observations,Release%20Date:%20Oct%203,%202025">data</a>&nbsp;from the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis. In 1960, manufacturing represented about 34% of total employment, while the number of jobs in the sector peaked in 1970 at 19.5 million. As of August this year, 12.7 million Americans were employed in manufacturing, while the industry lost 87,000 jobs in 2024,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bls.gov/ces/publications/highlights/2024/current-employment-statistics-highlights-12-2024.pdf">data</a> shows.&nbsp;</p><h2>Uncertainty hurting businesses</h2><p>When Mr. Trump in April announced a <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-liberation-day-new-tariffs-us/">range of levies</a></span> on dozens of other countries, the White House said tariffs would protect American workers by reducing the U.S. trade deficit with its economic partners and spurring employers to move manufacturing jobs to the U.S.</p><p>For now, however, confusion over the scale and scope of U.S. tariffs has put manufacturers on the defensive, increasing their costs and discouraging them from hiring, economist Sara Estrep, one of the authors of the CAP report, told CBS MoneyWatch.</p><p>"Companies are uncertain about what's happening," she said. "Everything has been changing on a day-to-day basis, so it's not clear what production should look like. That's why they aren't hiring."</p><p>In August, for example, farm equipment giant John Deere <a href="https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/315189/000155837025011453/de-20250814xex99d1.htm">cited</a> tariffs in announcing that its sales and operating profits had dipped from a year ago. In an earnings call, an executive with the company noted that it had racked up roughly $300 million in tariff-related costs, including on steel and aluminum imports. John Deere also announced it was laying off more than 200 workers at plants in Illinois and Iowa, according to <a href="https://www.agweb.com/news/breaking-john-deere-confirms-238-layoffs-across-3-plants">AgWeb</a>, a trade publication.&nbsp;</p><p>Automakers pointed partly to tariffs in announcing nearly 5,000 job cuts in July, according to outplacement firm Challenger, Gray &amp; Christmas, while it noted that the retail sector has also stepped up layoffs and store closures because of economic uncertainty.</p><p>Another factor fueling uncertainty for manufacturers are the ongoing legal challenges to the Trump tariffs, making it hard to plan and invest for the future, according to experts.&nbsp;</p><p>A federal appeals court in August ruled that Mr. Trump <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/appeals-court-trump-tariffs-illegal/">unlawfully invoked</a></span> the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, or IEEPA, to impose sweeping tariffs on U.S. trade partners. Mr. Trump on September 3&nbsp;<span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-appeals-tariffs-supreme-court/">asked the Supreme Court</a></span>&nbsp;to review the lower court's decision before it takes effect in October.&nbsp;</p><p>The outcome of the case leaves many manufacturers in doubt about how to proceed, making them reluctant to expand their workforce as they seek to control costs, Daco told CBS MoneyWatch.&nbsp;</p><p>"The slowdown is symptomatic of an environment where purchasing managers are all under stress, and they are being squeezed by higher costs of goods and reduced demand," said EY-Parthenon chief economist Gregory Daco. "And so in that squeeze, they are having to find ways to offset the higher costs, and one of the avenues to do that is to streamline their operations and make sure that they only have the essential talent on hand."<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p><p>The White House did not respond to several requests for comment on CAP's findings. The Office of the United States Trade Representative and National Association of Manufacturers, a trade group, didn't immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;</p><h2>Immigration effect</h2><p>The Trump administration's crackdown on U.S. immigrants is also weighing on hiring in manufacturing, said Daniel Altman, an economist and author of the High Yield Economics newsletter.&nbsp;</p><p>"Immigration has been an important source of employment in manufacturing for some industries, and if you take away some of their labor supply, that's just gives them more incentive to pursue automation and other forms of capital intensive manufacturing," he told CBS MoneyWatch.</p><p>The government stepped up its campaign last week when Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents&nbsp;<span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/hyundai-georigia-ice-raid-450-detained-electric-vehicles-batteries/">detained 475 immigrants</a></span>, most of them Korean, at a Hyundai plant in Georgia because they were suspected of living and working in the U.S. illegally.&nbsp;</p><p>Border patrol agents have also&nbsp;<span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/losangeles/news/home-depot-westlake-district-immigration-operation-border-patrol/">conducted raids</a></span> targeting immigrants working in retail, <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/philadelphia/news/ice-raid-norristown-montgomery-county/">according to CBS News</a></span>. In sectors like farming, food processing and construction, undocumented immigrants make up to 20% of the workforce, according to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.goldmansachs.com/insights/articles/how-will-declining-immigration-impact-the-us-economy">Goldman Sachs</a>.&nbsp;</p><p>White House "border czar" Tom Homan on Sunday said the White House will expand such efforts.</p><p>"We're going to do more worksite enforcement operations," Homan told <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/07/politics/video/border-czar-homan-trump-administration-will-take-action-in-sanctuary-cities-this-week">CNN</a>. "No one hires an illegal alien out of the goodness of their heart. They hire them because they can work them harder, pay them less, undercut the competition that hires U.S. citizen employees."&nbsp;</p><p>Other long-term factors that go beyond the Trump administration's policies are also contributing to the ongoing contraction in manufacturing jobs. During the pandemic, manufacturers invested heavily in technologies to automate their operations, Altman noted.</p><p>"We've seen a lot of automation, which means companies do not need as many workers to provide the same output," he told CBS MoneyWatch. "Output per worker has been increasing, and when we see that kind of increase in labor productivity, it usually means workers have access to more capital, or better technology or both, and that's what you'd expect with automation."</p><ul> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/employment/">Employment</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/economy/">Economy</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/consumer-news/">Consumer News</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/tariffs/">Tariffs</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/unemployment/">Unemployment</a></li> </ul><div><p><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/team/megan-cerullo/">Megan Cerullo</a></p><div><p>Megan Cerullo is a New York-based reporter for CBS MoneyWatch covering small business, workplace, health care, consumer spending and personal finance topics. She regularly appears on CBS News 24/7 to discuss her reporting.</p></div></div></section> </article> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets1.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/2025/09/09/b2537a60-15f7-4ea3-9809-5b299125d3fd/gettyimages-2157173718.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 22:08:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-send-employees-back-to-office-rto-remote-work-2025-9</link><title>Microsoft Is Officially Sending Employees Back to the Office (businessinsider.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nclz5f/microsoft_is_officially_sending_employees_back_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nclz5f/microsoft_is_officially_sending_employees_back_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 12 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nclz5f/microsoft_is_officially_sending_employees_back_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.insider.com/68af7d86a17a8c5b40539f07?width=1200&format=jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><div><figure> <span> <span> <label> </label> <figcaption> <span>Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella</span> <span> <span> Max Cherney/REUTERS </span> </span> </figcaption> </span> </span></figure> </div><div><ul> <li>Microsoft is sending employees back to the office at least three days a week.</li> <li>The first phase will be for employees who live near its Seattle-area headquarters in February.</li> <li>Business Insider <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-considering-stricter-rto-policy-2025-8">reported last month</a> that Microsoft's was considering a stricter RTO policy.</li> </ul> </div><section><p>One of Big Tech's last remaining <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/rto-mandates-driving-workers-quit-helping-employers-avoid-layoffs-2025-9">RTO</a> holdouts is officially sending employees back to the office.</p><p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-pay-data-engineers-share-compensation-2025-8">Microsoft</a> is mandating employees work from offices at least three days a week, according to an internal email the company sent to staff on Tuesday.</p><p>The mandate will happen in three phases, beginning at the end of February 2026, with Seattle-area employees who live within 50 miles of a Microsoft office. It will then expand to other US offices and eventually internationally, according to the email from Microsoft HR chief Amy Coleman. February 23 was one of the start dates Microsoft considered, but it hasn't been decided yet.</p><p>Employees can request an exception by September 19. Coleman's email didn't include details about how such exceptions may work.</p><p>Business Insider reported in August that Microsoft was considering a <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-considering-stricter-rto-policy-2025-8">stricter RTO policy</a> mandating three days a week in the office.</p><p>Microsoft sells software that enables remote work, such as its popular Teams workplace chat and meeting app. It remained relatively lax compared to some other Big Tech companies when it comes to RTO, especially cross-town rival Amazon. Even Zoom <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/zoom-tells-employees-return-to-office-remote-work-video-conferencing-2023-8">sent its employees back</a> to the office part-time in 2023.</p><p>Microsoft first introduced a <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-flexible-work-policy-how-it-works-2020-10">flexible work policy</a> when it brought employees back to the office in late 2020 after pandemic-forced closures. That policy officially allowed employees to work from home at least half of the time without approval, but in practice it was even more flexible and most employees worked remotely most of the time.</p><p>Now its policy is evolving to be similar to guidelines at Meta and Google, which generally require most employees to work in offices three days a week.</p><p>Microsoft's new approach is the latest sign of the company <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-performance-management-low-performers-country-club-2025-2">increasing performance pressure</a> on employees. It has <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-performance-management-low-performers-country-club-2025-2">fired thousands of employees</a> deemed low performers this year and <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/microsoft-pivot-amazon-low-performers-paying-employees-to-leave-2025-4">introduced a new performance improvement plan</a> meant to exit low performers more quickly.</p><p>While working on the new RTO policy, Microsoft appears to have scrubbed a blog post that once heralded the benefits of remote work for retaining employees and boosting their productivity.</p><p>"Hybrid work is more than a change in technology&mdash;it's a change in mindset, a change in culture, and a change in the way you think about physical and virtual spaces to enable an inclusive and productive environment for all," Microsoft wrote, according to a <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230105140339/https://www.microsoft.com/insidetrack/blog/reinventing-microsofts-employee-experience-for-a-hybrid-world/">snapshot of the blog</a> retained by the Internet Archive. "The change isn't easy, but it's worth it. If you make the time to do it right, your employees will be more engaged, more productive, and more connected, even when they're miles away. And they'll be far less likely to leave for a competitor who has a more sophisticated and flexible model than you do."</p><p>The <a href="https://affiliate.insider.com/?h=d5cba10071ca542a3d19f9f5702b81e2eeacd089d2ce0c055c2b35b52f88ab1f&amp;platform=browser&amp;postID=68af7c9fbdd07b99f0c4cfbe&amp;postSlug=microsoft-send-employees-back-to-office-rto-remote-work-2025-9&amp;site=bi&amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.microsoft.com%2Finsidetrack%2Fblog%2Freinventing-microsofts-employee-experience-for-a-hybrid-world%2F">link to that blog post</a> now redirects to one published on July 31 calling out how "hybrid work created new challenges for employee engagement" and how AI can solve them.</p><h2>Read the full memo:</h2><p><em>"How we work has forever changed. I remember starting at Microsoft in the late '90s, always in the office, no laptops, and primarily working with the people right down the hall. As technology evolved and our business expanded, we became more open, more global, and able to scale in ways we couldn't have imagined. Then the pandemic reshaped everything. It pushed us to think differently about work, to connect like never before (thank you Teams!), reminded us of how much we value being together, and gave us focus and autonomy in the traditional workday. We're not going back, and we shouldn't. Instead, we should take the best of what we've learned and move forward.</em></p><p><em>In the AI era, we are moving faster than ever, building world class technology that changes how people live and work, and how organizations everywhere operate. If you reflect on our history, the most meaningful breakthroughs happen when we build on each other's ideas together, in real time.</em></p><p><em>We've looked at how our teams work best, and the data is clear: when people work together in person more often, they thrive&mdash;they are more energized, empowered, and they deliver stronger results. As we build the AI products that will define this era, we need the kind of energy and momentum that comes from smart people working side by side, solving challenging problems together.</em></p><p><em>With that in mind, we're updating our flexible work expectations to three days a week in the office.</em></p><p><em>We'll roll this out in three phases: 1) starting in Puget Sound at the end of February; 2) expanding to other US locations; 3) and then launching outside the US.</em></p><p><em>Our goal with this change is to provide more clarity and consistency in how we come together, while maintaining the flexibility we know you value. We want you to continue to shape your schedule in ways that work best for you, making in-person time intentional and impactful. Importantly, this update is not about reducing headcount. It's about working together in a way that enables us to meet our customers' needs.</em></p><p><em>For some of you, this is not a change. For others this may be a bigger adjustment, which is exactly why we're providing time to plan thoughtfully. As part of these updates, we're also enhancing our workplace safety and security measures so we can continue to provide a workplace where every employee can do their best work.</em></p><p><em>What you need to know:</em></p><p><em>Puget Sound-area employees: If you live within 50 miles of a Microsoft office, you'll be expected to work onsite three days a week by the end of February. You'll receive a personalized email today with more details. Please connect with your manager and team to understand your organization's plans. If needed, you can request an exception by Friday, September 19.</em></p><p><em>Managers: You'll find actions to take, and the resources to support both you and your team on the Managers@Microsoft SharePoint.</em></p><p><em>All employees: You'll hear from your EVP or organizational leadership today with specific guidance. Each business will do what is best for their team, which means some groups will deviate from our company-wide expectations. If you are outside of the Puget Sound area, you do not need to take any action at this time unless your EVP communicates otherwise.</em></p><p><em>Timelines and details for additional US office locations will be announced soon. For employees outside the United States, we will begin planning in 2026. More information is available on the Flexible Work at Microsoft SharePoint.</em></p><p><em>As always, we'll keep learning together to ensure Microsoft is the best place for you to grow and have a great career. Let's keep moving forward together.</em></p><p><em>Thank you,</em></p><p><em>Amy"</em></p><p><strong><em>Have a tip? Contact this reporter via email at </em></strong><a href="https://www.businessinsider.commailto:astewart@businessinsider.com"><strong><em><u>astewart@businessinsider.com</u></em></strong></a><strong><em> or Signal at +1-425-344-8242. Use a personal email address and a nonwork device; </em></strong><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/insider-guide-to-securely-sharing-whistleblower-information-about-powerful-institutions-2021-10"><strong><em><u>here's our guide to sharing information securely</u></em></strong></a><strong><em>.</em></strong></p></section> </section><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://i.insider.com/681924e3a466d2b74ab5149f?width=700"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 20:57:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/09/09/with-looming-cbs-hire-of-bari-weiss-two-of-the-four-major-u-s-networks-will-now-be-right-wing-propaganda-mills/</link><title>With Looming CBS Hire Of Bari Weiss, Two Of The Four Major U.S. Networks Will Now Be Right Wing Propaganda Mills (techdirt.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nchnf7/with_looming_cbs_hire_of_bari_weiss_two_of_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nchnf7/with_looming_cbs_hire_of_bari_weiss_two_of_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nchnf7/with_looming_cbs_hire_of_bari_weiss_two_of_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:03:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/bill-gates-trump-ice-signature-aviation_n_68acd96fe4b0d17ae21e7ec4</link><title>Donald Trump's Mass Deportation Agenda Has A Surprising Stakeholder: Bill Gates (huffpost.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncg8xr/donald_trumps_mass_deportation_agenda_has_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncg8xr/donald_trumps_mass_deportation_agenda_has_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 54 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncg8xr/donald_trumps_mass_deportation_agenda_has_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bf094a1800004c3f8c75c3.jpg?ops=1200_630' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><section><p>President <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/news/topic/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a>&rsquo;s mass deportation agenda has a surprising stakeholder: Bill Gates. </p><p>The multibillionaire tech mogul and philanthropist owns a large portion of a key service provider for immigration flights. </p><p>And now, with new funding from Congress and an aggressive push from the White House, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/13/politics/ice-flights-locations-tracking-maps">more </a>and <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5e221cacff87ba2d2833cf54/t/6890c72c36915023d86b61a2/1754318642276/ICE+Air+JulTHCPDF.pdf">more</a> immigration flights are taking off, transporting immigration detainees both within the United States and to their home countries &mdash; or, in some cases, to places <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/us-trump-administration-third-country-deportations_n_6877b467e4b0cc43a0bf1473">they&rsquo;ve never been before</a>.</p><p>Gates&rsquo; connection to the U.S. detention and deportation machine is a company called Signature Aviation. Signature <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/">calls</a> <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/news/signature-aviation-celebrates-modernized-terminal-in-winston-salem/">itself</a> &ldquo;the world&rsquo;s largest network of private aviation terminals,&rdquo; and it&rsquo;s a linchpin in the day-to-day machinery of Trump&rsquo;s immigration enforcement apparatus. </p><div><blockquote><p><em><strong>For two decades, HuffPost has been fearless, unflinching, and relentless in pursuit of the truth. <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/support?utm_campaign=in-text-support-member">Support our mission</a> to keep us around for the next 20 &mdash; we can&rsquo;t do this without you.</strong></em></p></blockquote></div><p>Private <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/airlines/avelo-airlines-ice-deportation-flights-f5f150db?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAj1SzI2kI1CRzURQ_WyA4mcDpyIzkB4u6f82FXR4SWdhHu5IyqQtLihhYn_1jc%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68ac9721&amp;gaa_sig=HtxI3-vjIq5Ad6GG3oLKbC4fg0EZyid4wTeVtZxLSo1IqolawfD1fu5Zz6aeA-I46yNp0JOF_c6YVBo2yUplAA%3D%3D">charter</a> <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/inside-ice-air-deportation-flights">carriers</a> subcontracted for Immigration and Customs Enforcement to transport immigration detainees &mdash; part of a network known as &ldquo;ICE Air,&rdquo; a reference to the Department of Homeland Security&rsquo;s ICE Air Operations &mdash; use Signature&rsquo;s services daily. As a fixed-base operator, or FBO, Signature supplies ground crews, aviation fuel, boarding stairs, and airplane hangar space at hundreds of airports around the world, mostly in the United States. </p><p>The private firm that holds Gates&rsquo; and the Gates Foundation Trust&rsquo;s assets, Cascade Investment, increased its stake in the company to 30% in 2021, when it and two partners bought Signature outright for $4.7 billion. Human rights advocates &mdash; plane trackers and activists who <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/seattle-boeing-field-ice-deportation-flights">keep tabs on deportation flights</a>, as well as the aviation and logistics companies profiting from them &mdash; say Gates&rsquo; stake in Signature is at odds with his humanitarian work, including the Gates Foundation&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/about/committed-grants?q=immigration">support</a> of a plethora of immigration-focused nonprofits. Without FBOs like Signature, they say, Trump&rsquo;s mass deportation agenda would be stuck on the ground.</p><p>Gates himself has not publicly commented on Signature Aviation&rsquo;s crucial role in servicing ICE Air flights. Neither the Gates Foundation nor Cascade Asset Management Company, which oversees Cascade Investment, responded to multiple requests for comment. </p><p>At one airport, Signature appears to have worked to make its branding less visibly associated with immigration flights. Last month, a set of Signature boarding stairs in Seattle &mdash; where the county government set up cameras in 2023 to keep an eye on immigration flights &mdash; got a <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/jjindc.bsky.social/post/3lwrlthymck2w">new accessory</a>: two sheets of cardboard, taped over the company&rsquo;s logos. </p><figure><picture><source srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale&amp;format=webp 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560&amp;format=webp 2x"><img alt="A worker in a mask walks off a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement flight departing from King County International Airport-Boeing Field in Seattle on Aug. 23." src="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale" srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bb416318000010548c7344.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560 2x"></source></picture><div><figcaption>A worker in a mask walks off a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement flight departing from King County International Airport-Boeing Field in Seattle on Aug. 23.</figcaption><div><p><span>Lindsey Wasson/Associated Press</span></p></div></div></figure><p><span>FBOs &ldquo;are critical, obviously, because they provide fuel and other services while the plane makes its stops,&rdquo; said Tom Cartwright, a retired financial executive who has tracked ICE flights for nearly six years. </span></p><p><span>Cartwright estimated that through the end of June, 95% of the ICE Air flights he&rsquo;d tracked were operated by charter companies, with military and Coast Guard planes being used for the remainder. That doesn&rsquo;t include a tally of commercial flights used to deport people, he said &mdash; but in fiscal year 2017, ICE Air used charter flights to remove or transfer 181,317 people, compared with just 8,288 who were removed on commercial flights, </span><a href="https://www.oig.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/assets/2019-03/OIG-19-28-Mar19.pdf"><span>according to a 2019 DHS inspector general report</span></a><span>. </span></p><p><span>&ldquo;In this case, when they&rsquo;re doing 1,100 flights a month, that&rsquo;s a pretty significant piece of the operation &mdash; so they&rsquo;re absolutely critical,&rdquo; he said of the planes carrying immigration detainees. &ldquo;Without a fixed-base operator, I&rsquo;m not sure this system really operates.&rdquo; </span></p><p><span>In a </span><a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2025/08/21/gross-human-rights-violations-in-washington-state-enforced-disappearance-and-refoulement/"><span>recent report</span></a><span> covering local connections to alleged human rights violations stemming from the Trump administration&rsquo;s immigration enforcement agenda, the University of Washington Center for Human Rights (UWCHR), which has studied ICE Air flights </span><a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air/"><span>for years</span></a><span>, called out Gates&rsquo; Signature Aviation investment specifically. </span><em></em></p><p><span>&ldquo;In Washington, our most famous philanthropist grows his investments in part by supporting a company complicit in gross human rights abuses, potentially ascending to the level of crimes against humanity,&rdquo; the report alleged.</span></p><h2><strong>Signature At Work</strong></h2><p><span>To report this story, HuffPost scoured government records and plane location data, collected plane-spotting reports from activists on the ground, and matched aviation photographs to planes known to ferry ICE detainees. Still, ICE Air operates largely in the shadows, and many key players, including Signature Aviation, did not answer detailed questions about their operations. </span></p><p><span>So we wanted to see the process for ourselves. On Aug. 31, HuffPost witnessed Signature Aviation in action. On the tarmac of Newark Liberty International Airport, a couple hundred yards from Signature&rsquo;s private terminal, a Signature-branded set of boarding stairs and fuel tanker met a Boeing 737 belonging to Avelo Airlines, the low-cost carrier that has faced </span><a href="https://www.wbaltv.com/article/avelo-airlines-protest-bwi-marshall-ice-deportation-flights/65943086"><span>protests</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://www.change.org/p/we-won-t-fly-avelo-until-they-stop-ice-flights-no-volaremos-con-avelo"><span>a boycott</span></a><span> from potential passengers over </span><a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/airlines/avelo-airlines-ice-deportation-flights-f5f150db?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAj1SzI2kI1CRzURQ_WyA4mcDpyIzkB4u6f82FXR4SWdhHu5IyqQtLihhYn_1jc%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68ac9721&amp;gaa_sig=HtxI3-vjIq5Ad6GG3oLKbC4fg0EZyid4wTeVtZxLSo1IqolawfD1fu5Zz6aeA-I46yNp0JOF_c6YVBo2yUplAA%3D%3D"><span>its work with ICE Air</span></a><span>. Like other </span><a href="https://www.jetphotos.com/photo/keyword/N804VL"><span>Avelo</span></a> <a href="https://www.jetphotos.com/photo/keyword/N805VL"><span>planes</span></a><span> working ICE Air flights, this plane, with the tail number N801XT, was recently painted completely white, erasing any </span><a href="https://www.jetphotos.com/showphotos.php?aircraft=all&amp;airline=all&amp;country-location=all&amp;photographer-group=all&amp;category=all&amp;keywords-type=all&amp;keywords-contain=1&amp;keywords=n801xt&amp;photo-year=all&amp;genre=all&amp;search-type=Advanced&amp;sort-order=2"><span>prominent Avelo branding</span></a><span>. </span></p><p><span>One by one, 16 people dressed in white and gray, and shackled at the wrists, waist and ankles, hobbled off the plane and onto Signature Aviation&rsquo;s boarding stairs, unable to reach the handrail on the stairs. On the tarmac, the second man in line shuffled his feet slightly, taking uneven steps as his head drooped, making him look older than the rest. The plane had just finished a </span><a href="https://www.flightaware.com/live/flight/VXP55/history/20250831/1530Z/KAEX/KEWR"><span>two-and-a-half-hour flight</span></a><span> from Alexandria, Louisiana, a </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/07/31/us/ice-deportation-hub-alexandria-louisiana.html"><span>central hub</span></a><span> for ICE Air flights, meaning the men had </span><a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/inside-ice-air-deportation-flights"><span>likely</span></a><span> been shackled for several hours straight. The detainees waited on the tarmac as they were processed into sprinter vans with flashing police lights. A Signature-branded fuel tanker sidled up to the plane, and personnel on the ground hauled plastic mesh bags </span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/north-america-us-news-ap-top-news-az-state-wire-immigration-a1d44854cd134333b2cb85de853056c9"><span>known</span></a><span> to be used for detainees&rsquo; personal belongings. Eventually, accompanied by Port Authority police vehicles, the caravan left the tarmac, likely heading to nearby ICE detention facilities. </span></p><p><span>Two weeks prior, HuffPost saw a similar scene play out, when a plane operated by Eastern Air Express &mdash; the same aircraft CNN recently </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AlRypvEB76Q"><span>spotted</span></a><span> ferrying people in ICE custody &mdash; was met with similar fanfare at Newark. Law enforcement vehicles with flashing lights approached that plane as well, including one that looked similar to a shuttle bus previously </span><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wSIL0wpxUyc"><span>filmed</span></a><span> transporting detainees out of Delaney Hall, the </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/14/nyregion/newark-ice-detainees-escape.html"><span>infamous</span></a><span> immigration jail. </span></p><p><span>In both cases, after about an hour on the ground, the planes continued on their way around the country, ferrying people in ICE custody to other detention facilities, and for some, onto their ultimate deportation, according to one activist plane spotter who goes by the moniker &ldquo;JJ in DC&rdquo; on Bluesky and who helped HuffPost track the aircraft.</span></p><blockquote><div><p>&ldquo;In Washington, our most famous philanthropist grows his investments in part by supporting a company complicit in gross human rights abuses, potentially ascending to the level of crimes against humanity.&rdquo;</p><p>- Recent report from the University of Washington Center for Human Rights</p></div></blockquote><p>Such scenes are now commonplace throughout the country. But they are not new. For over a decade, private aviation contractors have handled tens of thousands of ICE Air flights, according to Cartwright&rsquo;s count, which can collectively <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air/">transfer or remove</a> hundreds of thousands of people <a href="https://www.oig.dhs.gov/sites/default/files/assets/2019-03/OIG-19-28-Mar19.pdf">annually</a>.</p><p>Recent video from King County&rsquo;s cameras at Boeing Field-King County International Airport in Seattle shows a grim parade of detainees. One climbs a set of boarding stairs while <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DKc3-uPhNVD/">shackled and holding a cane</a>. Another, also shackled &mdash; detainees generally are, including during flights &mdash; is <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/lalabote.bsky.social/post/3ltun6dwqos2e">manhandled by several guards</a> who run him onto the plane; a few feet before Signature&rsquo;s staircase, the group stumbles and the man falls onto the tarmac.</p><p>&ldquo;The use of restraints on detainees during deportation flights is a standard ICE protocol and an essential measure to ensure the safety and well-being of both detainees and the officers/agents accompanying them,&rdquo; an unidentified DHS spokesperson told HuffPost in a statement. &ldquo;Our practices align with those followed by other relevant authorities and is fully in line with established legal standards.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;ICE takes its commitment to promoting safe, secure, humane environments for those in our custody very seriously,&rdquo; the statement added. &ldquo;ICE Air Operations flights are law enforcement sensitive. ICE conducts flights throughout the U.S. on a daily basis. For operational security purposes, ICE does not discuss ongoing or future operations.&rdquo; </p><figure><picture><source srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale&amp;format=webp 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560&amp;format=webp 2x"><img alt="U.S. and Signature Aviation flags fly outside Signature Aviation's Newark Liberty International Airport terminal." src="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale" srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68add1d118000043e38c65e2.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560 2x"></source></picture><div><figcaption>U.S. and Signature Aviation flags fly outside Signature Aviation's Newark Liberty International Airport terminal.</figcaption><div><p><span>Illustration: HuffPost; Photo: Will Tooke/HuffPost</span></p></div></div></figure><p>Activists working to end ICE Air&rsquo;s presence in Seattle have zeroed in on Signature&rsquo;s work as a service provider for charter flights. </p><p>&ldquo;The presence of Signature is essential for ICE to be within the airport, because without having a fixed-base operator to service the planes, they can&rsquo;t land there, and no one else is doing this type of work,&rdquo; said Guadalupe Gonzalez, flight monitoring coordinator for La Resistencia, an immigrant-led activist group in Washington state that seeks to end immigrant detention and deportation. &ldquo;Signature Aviation specifically are the ones responsible for servicing ICE at Boeing Field.&rdquo; </p><p>Gonzalez said La Resistencia volunteers, who observe ICE Air transfers in person at Boeing Field, have in recent years reported seeing detainees bound in the &ldquo;WRAP&rdquo; restraint system, a type of full-body restraint device that has come <a href="https://capitalandmain.com/police-restraint-system-adopted-nationwide-despite-lawsuits-allegations">under</a> scrutiny in the past. More commonly, Gonzalez said, people with mobility issues were made to walk up Signature&rsquo;s stairs to a waiting ICE Air flight. </p><p>Not having a presence at Boeing Field, Gonzalez said, &ldquo;would impair [ICE&rsquo;s] efforts to deport as many people as possible &mdash; or, at the very minimum, make it more costly.&rdquo; </p><p>Signature Aviation did not answer a lengthy list of questions about its practices, including its involvement with ICE Air. Instead, the company sent a one-sentence statement.</p><p>&ldquo;Our FBOs must accept flight operations that comply with the law, FAA regulations and contract requirements at federally funded airports,&rdquo; said Rosanna Fiske, the company&rsquo;s global head of corporate affairs.</p><p>Fiske did not respond to follow-up questions about the nature of Signature&rsquo;s obligations, including the terms of contracts it may have signed with ICE Air charter operators.</p><h2><strong>&lsquo;Don&rsquo;t Want Bill&rsquo;s Name In The Headlines&rsquo;</strong></h2><p>Gates is a significant shareholder in Signature Aviation. Cascade Investment LLC, the holding company for Gates&rsquo; and the Gates Foundation&rsquo;s assets, first bought a piece of the company&rsquo;s predecessor, <a href="https://www.ainonline.com/aviation-news/business-aviation/2020-02-07/bba-aviation-rebrands-signature-aviation">BBA Aviation</a>, <a href="https://www.wsj.com/business/airlines/bill-gates-joins-private-equity-firms-in-4-7-billion-deal-for-private-jet-company-11612534767">in 2009</a>. In 2021, a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jan/09/bill-gates-joins-blackstone-in-bid-to-buy-british-private-jet-firm">bidding war</a> broke out over the company, and Gates&rsquo; Cascade &mdash; then Signature&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/blackstone-gates-team-up-signature-aviation-bid-carlyle-circles-2021-01-08/">largest</a> individual shareholder, with a 19% stake &mdash; joined forces with Blackstone Group and Global Infrastructure Partners to <a href="https://www.ainonline.com/aviation-news/business-aviation/2021-06-08/signature-aviation-now-under-new-ownership">buy it outright</a>. (Global Infrastructure Partners was <a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/finance/blackrock-quarterly-profit-rises-strong-assets-under-management-2024-01-12/">acquired</a> by BlackRock in 2024.)</p><p>Working together, the three firms bought Signature for $4.7 billion, with Cascade winding up with 30% of the company. </p><p>Cascade Investment LLC is <a href="https://cascadeassetmanagement.com/faqs/">overseen</a> by Cascade Asset Management Company. That firm&rsquo;s chief investment officer is Michael Larson, who has Gates&rsquo; &ldquo;complete trust and faith,&rdquo; Gates said in 2014, at a party he threw celebrating the 20th anniversary of Larson managing his assets. <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/this-mans-job-make-bill-gates-richer-1411093811">The Wall Street Journal reported</a> at the time that their arrangement was &ldquo;simple: Mr. Larson makes money, and Mr. Gates gives it away.&rdquo; Cascade Investment is located in the same Kirkland, Washington, office park as Gates&rsquo; personal office, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/05/26/business/bill-gates-cascade-michael-larson.html">The New York Times noted</a> in a 2021 story. Cascade&rsquo;s mandate, one unnamed former employee told the Times for the same story, was: &ldquo;We don&rsquo;t want Bill&rsquo;s name in the headlines.&rdquo; </p><p>Cascade&rsquo;s work on Gates&rsquo; behalf has come up in the news before. </p><p>For example, when <a href="https://landreport.com/farmer-bill-gates">The Land Report revealed</a> in 2021 that Gates was &ldquo;America&rsquo;s largest private farmland owner,&rdquo; what they were really talking about, as <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/mcdonald-s-french-fries-carrots-onions-all-foods-come-bill-n1270033">NBC News later described it</a>, was farmland &ldquo;purchased through a constellation of companies that all link back to [Bill and Melinda Gates&rsquo;] investment group, Cascade Investments, based in Kirkland, Washington.&rdquo; When Gates was asked about his farmland purchases, which made national news, he <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/m8n4vt/comment/grid8pt/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">said</a>, &ldquo;My investment group chose to do this&rdquo; <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/IAmA/comments/109eze3/comment/j3xyx6r/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button">and</a> &ldquo;all these decisions are made by a professional investment team.&rdquo; </p><p>The same might apply to Signature Aviation. It&rsquo;s unclear how much Gates knows about his stake in the company, or whether he knows that Signature plays such a crucial role in Trump&rsquo;s mass deportation operation. </p><p>Still, &ldquo;it would be surprising if Gates couldn&rsquo;t influence a decision to disinvest of this particular investment,&rdquo; said Cartwright, who before his retirement <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/03/ice-flight-tracker-deportations/682226/">spent decades at J.P. Morgan</a>, including as chief financial officer of one division that covered 5,000 bank branches. </p><p>The foundation has previously addressed concerns about its money being invested in Signature Aviation. One complaint recently filed through EthicsPoint, a public-facing portal to submit ethical concerns to the foundation, and later shared with HuffPost, accused the foundation of &ldquo;providing material support for U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement&rdquo; through its investment in Signature.</p><p>In response, the foundation said it did not &ldquo;control or participate in the activities of the Gates Foundation Trust.&rdquo; Instead, the foundation said, the trust&rsquo;s assets were &ldquo;independently managed by Cascade Asset Management Company.&rdquo; </p><h2><strong>Signature&rsquo;s Footprint</strong></h2><p>Look closely and you&rsquo;ll see Signature Aviation popping up across Trump&rsquo;s mass deportation pipeline. </p><p>In fact, the company is part of perhaps the most infamous footage of Trump&rsquo;s second term so far: an <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/white-house-deportation-asmr_n_67b59e2ce4b04083cc996831">&ldquo;ASMR&rdquo;</a> <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/white-house-asmr-deportation-video_l_67b7a45ce4b05145b9c4f94f">video</a> that glorifies shackling and transporting immigration detainees. The video was <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/white-houses-gleeful-video-shows-chained-deportees-at-boeing-field/">filmed at Boeing Field</a>, where the number of contracted ICE flights, all serviced by Signature Aviation, has <a href="https://washingtonstatestandard.com/2025/07/15/deportation-flights-at-wa-airport-up-dramatically-this-year-advocates-say/">shot up</a> this year. It also happens to be a 20-minute drive from the Gates Foundation&rsquo;s offices. </p><p>Signature&rsquo;s <a href="https://brandfetch.com/signatureaviation.com">distinct logo</a> is visible at the top of a set of boarding stairs about five seconds into the clip: </p><p>Signature did not answer HuffPost&rsquo;s inquiry about where it serviced ICE Air flights, but the company has had a significant footprint in servicing aviation contractors hired by ICE. In 2019, one <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/wp-content/uploads/sites/22/2025/08/IAO-AEX2-Schedule-20190711.pdf">internal ICE document</a> listed Signature as the designated FBO for contracted ICE flights at 12 major domestic airports: Atlanta, Dallas, Newark, Houston, Laredo, Kansas City, Memphis, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/minnesota/comments/1k69i6t/weekly_ice_flight_at_msp_this_morning/">Minneapolis-Saint Paul</a>, Chicago, San Diego, San Antonio, and Denver, where HuffPost recently spotted a set of Signature boarding stairs pulled up to another <a href="https://www.planespotters.net/airframe/boeing-737-800-n804vl-avelo-air/eg9gq1">all-white Avelo Air plane</a>.</p><p>And while it&rsquo;s not clear whether ICE Air still uses every airport on the 2019 list, the list also doesn&rsquo;t include airports where Signature has recently been spotted servicing ICE Air flights. For example, the 2019 document doesn&rsquo;t include Seattle&rsquo;s Boeing Field. Signature now <a href="https://kingcounty.gov/en/dept/executive-services/transit-transportation-roads/airport/about/ice-flights">frequently</a> services ICE flights there, and detainees picked up at the airport have ended up in El Salvador&rsquo;s CECOT prison, Guant&aacute;namo Bay, and South Sudan, according to the <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2025/08/21/gross-human-rights-violations-in-washington-state-enforced-disappearance-and-refoulement/">recent report</a> from UWCHR. The human rights center previously obtained the 2019 list of airports that listed FBOs servicing the ICE flights pursuant to a public records request to ICE. </p><p>Signature also appears to be servicing immigration flights out of Jacksonville, Florida. One March email with the subject line &ldquo;ICE Schedule This Week&rdquo; notes several charter flights landing at Jacksonville International Airport. The activist group Ground ICE &mdash; which <a href="https://groundice.org/our-mission">aims</a> to &ldquo;limit the rate at which I.C.E. can transport and remove its detainees&rdquo; &mdash; obtained the document through a public records request and shared it with HuffPost. Recipients of the email included Signature Aviation&rsquo;s Jacksonville manager as well as several email accounts associated with GEO Group, a private prison contractor.</p><p>In July, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kPg8Z8hx2OQ">Fox 13 News Utah captured video</a> of apparent immigration detainees climbing a set of Signature boarding stairs at Salt Lake City International Airport. </p><p>And <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-features/trump-ice-coast-guard-planes-immigrants-detention-1235414267/">Rolling Stone recently spotted</a> a Coast Guard plane refueling and boarding ICE detainees at Baltimore/Washington International Airport. Independent journalist Gillian Brockell, who wrote the Rolling Stone story, told HuffPost that Signature Aviation refueled the plane.</p><p>Signature is also the <a href="https://www.buffaloairport.com/flight-info/air-carriers/fixed-base-operator">only FBO</a> at Buffalo Niagara International Airport, Ground ICE has noted. Planes carrying immigration detainees pass through that airport once or twice a week, according to Cartwright, who is currently transitioning <a href="https://humanrightsfirst.org/ice-flight-monitor/">his work</a> over to the group <a href="https://humanrightsfirst.org/library/ice-flight-tracking-project-now-officially-housed-at-human-rights-first/">Human Rights First</a>.</p><h2><strong>&lsquo;Dehumanizing To A Lot Of Degrees&rsquo;</strong></h2><p>Various entities involved with Gates&rsquo; ICE Air investment proclaim their commitment to human rights. </p><p>Signature Aviation itself <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/about/policies-terms-and-conditions/signature-aviation-bba-aviation-disclosures/signature-aviation-ethics/">says</a> it is committed to &ldquo;refraining from coercion and never deliberately causing harm to anyone&rdquo; and that it takes steps &ldquo;to confirm that our businesses and supply chains are free from modern slavery and human trafficking.&rdquo; Another company policy requires that suppliers &ldquo;never use, support, or engage in forced or indentured labor, or practices involving coercion, deception, or abuse of power &mdash; including human trafficking, slavery and child labor.&rdquo; As part of its efforts to combat human trafficking, it says it <a href="https://www.signatureaviation.com/news/signature-aviation-taking-steps-to-end-human-trafficking/">works with</a> the Department of Homeland Security. (ICE falls under the purview of DHS.) </p><p>Cascade <a href="https://cascadeassetmanagement.com/investment-approaches/">says</a> it takes &ldquo;a value-oriented approach&rdquo; to investing money for Gates and the Gates Foundation Trust, and that one of its objectives is to &ldquo;protect Bill and the Trust by acting lawfully, honestly, ethically, and with integrity, safeguarding their assets and information.&rdquo; It <a href="https://cascadeassetmanagement.com/">notes</a> that &ldquo;neither Cascade nor the Trust play a role in the grantmaking or operations of the foundation&rdquo; and that the foundation &ldquo;does not control or participate in the Trust&rsquo;s investment activities.&rdquo;</p><p>The Gates Foundation <a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/about">says</a> its mission is to &ldquo;create a world where every person has the opportunity to live a healthy, productive life,&rdquo; and the foundation has <a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/about/committed-grants?q=immigration">awarded grants</a> to multiple prominent immigration-focused nonprofits. </p><figure><picture><source srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale&amp;format=webp 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560&amp;format=webp 2x"><img alt="Immigration and Customs Enforcement detainees disembark from an " src="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale" srcset="https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_1280_noupscale 1x, https://img.huffingtonpost.com/asset/68bee42419000042eb34c651.jpg?ops=scalefit_2560 2x"></source></picture><div><figcaption>Immigration and Customs Enforcement detainees disembark from an "ICE Air" flight at Newark Liberty International Airport using a set of Signature Aviation boarding stairs.</figcaption><div><p><span>Photo: Matt Shuham/HuffPost</span></p></div></div></figure><p>The experiences of immigration detainees traveling on ICE Air &mdash; particularly ICE&rsquo;s use of shackles, which bind their wrists and ankles &mdash; seemingly stand in contrast to those commitments. </p><p>The shackles &ldquo;felt very disrespectful, dehumanizing to a lot of degrees,&rdquo; Mahmoud Khalil, the Palestinian activist jailed and threatened with deportation for his beliefs, <a href="https://zeteo.com/p/exclusive-mahmoud-khalil-talks-to">recalled to Zeteo</a> after his release from ICE custody in June. </p><p>After more than a day of travel, &ldquo;by the time I arrived in Jena, [Louisiana, home to an infamous ICE jail,] I couldn&rsquo;t walk because my leg was swollen from the shackles,&rdquo; Khalil added.</p><p>Deportation flight passengers have alleged &ldquo;the use of racist epithets and insults, and rough physical treatment upon boarding,&rdquo; as well as, in more isolated cases, &ldquo;beatings, the use of straitjackets, verbal abuse and threats, and the denial of access to restrooms,&rdquo; according to a UWCHR <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air/">summary</a> of <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/08/16/ice-air-deportation-flight-complaints/">public records</a> it received detailing the complaints. </p><p>In one case, a Somalia-bound deportation flight sat on a tarmac in Senegal for a full day due to technical issues, while detainees remained shackled inside and the plane&rsquo;s toilets &ldquo;overfilled with human waste,&rdquo; according to a <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/meet-the-ice-contractor-running-deportation-flights">subsequent lawsuit</a>. The plane eventually returned all of the detainees to the United States. (The suit was ultimately <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.flsd.518509/gov.uscourts.flsd.518509.215.0.pdf">dismissed</a> for jurisdictional reasons, and many of the people on the ill-fated flight <a href="https://theintercept.com/2019/04/09/somalis-ice-deportation-flights/">continued to face deportation proceedings</a>.)</p><h2><strong>Seattle Shows Vulnerabilities Of Private System</strong></h2><p>Relying on private contractors at every stage of the deportation process creates major vulnerabilities for ICE &mdash; which may be why the Trump administration is <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/immigration/kristi-noem-pushing-ice-buy-operate-fleet-deportation-planes-sources-s-rcna217149?link_source=ta_bluesky_link&amp;taid=68a633abd3e93400010d65da&amp;utm_campaign=trueanthem&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=bluesky">reportedly</a> considering purchasing its own fleet of deportation planes. </p><p>While giant private prison companies like CoreCivic and GEO Group are dependent on federal contracts to survive, FBOs work in different economic conditions. Most rely on business from corporate and private jet travel, and they&rsquo;re often subject to local political pressure. For example, Ground ICE has <a href="https://groundice.org/the-pilots-boycott">encouraged pilots</a> to write to Signature Aviation and &ldquo;let them know you will not be buying fuel from them&rdquo; due to their work for ICE. </p><p>More than anywhere else, Seattle&rsquo;s Boeing Field represents how local anti-deportation sentiment can affect FBOs and seriously slow down ICE&rsquo;s work. </p><p>In 2019, amid <a href="https://inthesetimes.com/article/ice-deportation-boeing-field-airport-washington-immigrant-rights">pressure</a> from local activist groups and an <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2019/04/23/ice-air-king-county/">impactful</a> report from UWCHR concerning &ldquo;King County Collaboration with ICE Air Deportation Flights at Boeing Field,&rdquo; then-King County executive Dow Constantine <a href="https://kingcounty.gov/about/policies/executive/PFCeo/~/media/0B00DFDD9114472BB8C596234A2C631D.ashx?la=en#:~:text=King%20County%20International%20Airport%20shall,United%20States%20or%20its%20territories.">ordered</a>, among other things, that future leases at Boeing Field contain a prohibition against the private transport of immigration detainees. The FBO for those flights at the time, Modern Aviation, stopped servicing them soon after that executive order, even though the order was ultimately blocked in court. Two other FBOs at the airport, including Signature, also said they &ldquo;will not take over from Modern in servicing ICE flights,&rdquo; <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/ice-flights-will-no-longer-use-boeing-field/">The Seattle Times reported at the time</a>, citing the airport&rsquo;s director. (Matt Dill, general manager at Modern Aviation&rsquo;s location at Boeing Field, declined to comment.)</p><p>&ldquo;Without the help of such companies,&rdquo; the paper reported, &ldquo;flights cannot operate at the airport. Though they can technically take off and land, [airport director John] Parrott said, flights need a company to open gates, to provide stairs to get passengers on and off planes, and to offer fuel.&rdquo; </p><p>Without an FBO in Seattle, ICE was forced to <a href="https://www.nwpb.org/2019/05/20/yakima-and-king-county-airports-risk-funding-loss-if-they-dont-cooperate-with-ice/">route planes through Yakima</a> &mdash; where the airport was smaller, more remote, and hours inland. <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.wawd.283169/gov.uscourts.wawd.283169.62.1_2.pdf">In a court filing</a>, the Trump administration said it only landed on the remote airport after approaching three others &ldquo;without success.&rdquo; </p><p>The Trump administration also acknowledged at the time that this shift jammed the gears of its deportation machinery, particularly when it came to people detained at the Northwest Detention Center in Tacoma. </p><p>&ldquo;Transporting detainees from Tacoma to Yakima, as compared to Tacoma to Boeing Field, adds, at a minimum, six hours of travel time to the process of executing an ICE Air flight,&rdquo; the filing read.</p><p>&ldquo;Additionally,&rdquo; it continued, &ldquo;the transport to Yakima and back frequently requires the use of an additional bus and two additional officers, as well as additional meal and fuel costs. This takes resources away from federal law enforcement tasks that would otherwise be performed if the ICE Air flights were flying out of Boeing Field. Relocation of the ICE Air flights to Yakima also impacts ICE operations in Yakima, requiring ICE to utilize staffing of at least two officers from its Yakima sub-office to facilitate the flight processing in Yakima. Additionally, travel over the mountain passes in winter is hazardous, and frequently either slowed significantly by road conditions or suspended altogether, as was the case on January 14, 2020, when an ICE Air flight had to be cancelled due to road conditions prohibiting transport.&rdquo; </p><p>On March 30, 2023, a federal judge <a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/politics/federal-judge-allows-deportation-flights-to-resume-at-boeing-field/">ruled against</a> the county&rsquo;s executive order requiring future FBO leases to prohibit work on deportation flights. </p><p>&ldquo;At that time, Signature Aviation said, &lsquo;OK, we&rsquo;ll do that business,&rsquo;&rdquo; recalled Angelina Snodgrass Godoy, the director of UWCHR. &ldquo;Ever since then, the ICE flights have resumed at Boeing Field, and they&rsquo;re being served by Signature Aviation.&rdquo; </p><p>Local public radio station KNKX <a href="https://www.knkx.org/social-justice/2023-05-10/ice-deportation-flights-resume-at-king-countys-boeing-field">described Signature</a> at the time as &ldquo;the fixed-base operator that agreed to service ICE flights at Boeing Field.&rdquo; </p><p>By May 2, four years after ICE Air flights stopped at Boeing Field, they resumed again, according to <a href="https://kingcounty.gov/en/dept/executive-services/transit-transportation-roads/airport/about/ice-flights">records of the flights</a> kept by the county. Signature has been their sole service provider ever since, according to the same records. </p><blockquote><div><p>&ldquo;Without a fixed-base operator, I&rsquo;m not sure this system really operates.&rdquo;</p><p>- Tom Cartwright, a retired financial executive who has tracked ICE flights for nearly six years</p></div></blockquote><p>For Godoy, the years-long absence of deportation flights running through Seattle shows just how important FBOs like Signature Aviation are.</p><p>&ldquo;Here in Seattle, what we saw in 2019 and to this date, was that when there was enough local concern, and people expressing local outrage about it, that the other FBOs also didn&rsquo;t want to do it,&rdquo; she said. </p><p>&ldquo;There are businesses who will say, &lsquo;No, we don&rsquo;t want this, we don&rsquo;t want to be associated with this.&rsquo;&rdquo; </p><p>Local pressure also may have recently disrupted ICE Air operations on the other side of the country. Last month, after <a href="https://www.wbur.org/news/2025/06/17/plymouth-county-sheriff-ice-immigration-detentions-flights">media attention</a> and local protest over the spike in immigration flights from Hanscom Field in Bedford, Massachusetts &mdash; including specific attention <a href="https://lexobserver.org/2025/07/22/ice-flights-move-from-hanscom-to-portsmouth/">on Signature Aviation</a> for servicing the flights &mdash; the ICE Air flights to that airport <a href="https://concordbridge.org/index.php/2025/07/18/breaking-ice-no-longer-using-hanscom-field-spokesperson/">stopped</a>, <a href="https://www.wbur.org/news/2025/07/31/immigration-hanscom-portsmouth-flights-airport">instead going through</a> Portsmouth International Airport at Pease in Portsmouth, New Hampshire, where Signature does not have a presence.</p><p>&ldquo;It was because the activists were so annoying, basically, to that airfield, and they were so focused on Signature, that they decided to shift to [Portsmouth International Airport] as the hub for New England,&rdquo; JJ in DC posited to HuffPost, referring to the shift from Massachusetts to New Hampshire.</p><p>Godoy also speculated that the shift came in response to protest. </p><p>&ldquo;My impression is that, for Signature, the ICE flights are only a portion of their business, and not the majority of their business &mdash; and when the ICE flights become sufficiently notorious, that threatens Signature&rsquo;s overall business, and then they say &lsquo;no thanks,&rsquo;&rdquo; she said.</p><p>&ldquo;And it looks to me &mdash; this is speculation, because I&rsquo;m not privy to the discussions between ICE and Signature &mdash; like that&rsquo;s what happened at Hanscom Field,&rdquo; Godoy added. &ldquo;So now, ICE is going to be using a more far-away airport, which is more inconvenient for them. And they haven&rsquo;t said why.&rdquo; </p><p>Still, even apparent route changes may not last: Two flights from Avelo Airlines planes landed at Hanscom Field on Friday and Saturday, flight records show. The airline, ICE, and Signature Aviation did not respond to questions about the purpose of the flights.</p><h2><strong>It&rsquo;s Not Just Bill</strong></h2><p>The financial backing behind Signature Aviation doesn&rsquo;t stop with Bill Gates and the Gates Foundation. </p><p>Annual financial reports reviewed by HuffPost show several large public pension funds are also stakeholders in Signature.</p><p>Institutional investors Blackstone and BlackRock (via Global Infrastructure Partners) own the remainder of the company that Gates does not. And those massive asset management firms often invest money in various funds on behalf of public pensions, nonprofits and university endowments.</p><p>One such fund, a BlackRock product called Global Infrastructure Partners Fund IV, has 68 such limited partners, according to data from PitchBook, a private-equity market database.</p><p>That includes the California Public Employees&rsquo; Retirement System, a public pension that in 2023 held more than $350 million of the fund; the New York State Common Retirement Fund; the Utah State University endowment; the Oregon Public Employees Retirement System; the Washington State Investment Board; <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1HfRYzWYIZ7kBAnyRsDMT5ixTNpDWqaAefiF4LeM-OdE/edit?usp=sharing">and more than 60 others</a>.</p><p>BlackRock and the California Public Employees&rsquo; Retirement System declined to comment. The New York State Common Retirement Fund, Oregon Investment Council (which manages OPERS&rsquo; investments) and the Utah State University endowment didn&rsquo;t respond. A spokesperson for WSIB told HuffPost that, as a policy, it does not comment on individual holdings.</p><p>Washington&rsquo;s stake was flagged by UWCHR, which <a href="https://jsis.washington.edu/humanrights/2025/08/21/gross-human-rights-violations-in-washington-state-enforced-disappearance-and-refoulement/#_ftn155">warned in its recent report</a> that &ldquo;public workers&rsquo; retirements are being financed in part through investments in organizations that profit from the detention and deportation of our neighbors.&rdquo;</p><p>A handful of public pension funds are also invested in a similar offering from Blackstone, called Blackstone Infrastructure Partners. They include the New Mexico State Investment Council, the Orange County Employees&rsquo; Retirement System, Pennsylvania Public School Employees&rsquo; Retirement System, and the Teacher Retirement System of Texas, according to the PitchBook data.</p><p>Blackstone didn&rsquo;t respond to a request for comment, nor did the New Mexico State Investment Council. A spokesperson for the Teacher Retirement System of Texas declined to comment, citing a Texas law that prohibits discussing specific investments. The Orange County Employees&rsquo; Retirement System and Pennsylvania Public School Employees Retirement System similarly declined to comment.</p><p>Azani Creeks, a senior campaign and research coordinator at PESP, a nonprofit watchdog organization focused on the private equity industry, told HuffPost that people whose pensions rely on these investments are entitled to have a say in their composition.</p><p>&ldquo;You can contact pension fund staff and trustees by email to schedule a meeting, and often, pension funds have regular meetings with public comment periods in which you can communicate your concerns,&rdquo; Creeks said. </p><p>&ldquo;A handful of private equity firms, drawing on capital from pension funds, foundations, endowments, insurance companies, and other institutional investors, exert major influence through investments in companies providing services to immigrant detention facilities and migrant shelters around the United States.&rdquo;</p><p>JJ in DC noted that in his work tracking immigration flights, he&rsquo;s been struck by just how opaque the process is. The Department of Homeland Security <a href="https://www.pogo.org/investigations/meet-the-ice-contractor-running-deportation-flights">contracts with its main broker</a>, CSI Aviation, which works with a network of subcontractors including GlobalX, Avelo and Eastern Air Express. Those firms in turn work with FBOs like Signature Aviation. Along the way, airplanes have been made harder to spot &mdash; with some losing all of their external branding or being <a href="https://www.levernews.com/ice-is-using-taylor-swifts-loophole-to-hide-deportation-flights/">taken off public flight trackers</a>, though their information is still available on crowdsourced networks like <a href="https://www.adsbexchange.com/">ADS-B Exchange</a>. (Anyone with <a href="https://www.adsbexchange.com/ways-to-join-the-exchange/">the correct receiver</a> can contribute to the site, which presents location information <a href="https://www.adsbexchange.com/how-it-works/">broadcast by individual aircraft over radio waves</a> as an interactive and real-time, though not always complete, <a href="https://globe.adsbexchange.com/">map</a> of global aviation traffic.) </p><p>The result, in the end, are taxpayer dollars quietly contributing to the portfolios of people like Gates and the Gates Foundation Trust. </p><p>&ldquo;This is a big pressure point,&rdquo; JJ in DC told HuffPost. &ldquo;And if more people apply pressure, it&rsquo;s going to hurt their operations, and they&rsquo;re going to have to adjust.&rdquo; </p><p><em>Matt Shuham reported from New York. Ryan Grenoble reported from Denver. </em></p></section></section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 16:55:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://gizmodo.com/trumps-policies-are-shutting-out-americans-from-the-coolest-new-gadgets-2000655535</link><title>Trump's Policies Are Shutting Out Americans From the Coolest New Gadgets (gizmodo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncc9di/trumps_policies_are_shutting_out_americans_from/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncc9di/trumps_policies_are_shutting_out_americans_from/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ncc9di/trumps_policies_are_shutting_out_americans_from/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Tech companies big and small now struggle to tantalize you with tech without telling you how much it will cost, or&mdash;hell&mdash;whether you can even buy it. The still-ongoing <a href="https://gizmodo.com/live-updates-from-ifa-2025-in-berlin-%f0%9f%94%b4-2000649907">IFA 2025 tech conference</a> in Berlin proved how merely shipping tech to the U.S. is more tenuous than at any time in the last few decades. From what I saw and heard both on the floor and off, it became clear that the era of plentiful, affordable, and cool shit will melt away in favor of an epoch of dull and ever-more expensive tech.</p><p>IFA&rsquo;s timing lands early in September for tech companies to have the chance to promote their products before the holiday rush. It&rsquo;s a big conference for European- and Asian-based companies, especially those that focus on smart home tech. For us journalists, IFA is also an opportunity to dive into the weird and wacky products that may or may not float to the U.S. from across the pond.</p><p>This year, the annual conference took a different tenor. IFA came months after <a href="https://gizmodo.com/here-comes-the-pain-from-trumps-tariffs-2000632110">U.S. tariffs had been causing havoc</a> with pricing on existing products. Future devices won&rsquo;t just be more expensive; more and more companies indicated they were holding off shipping to the U.S. or were writing off Uncle Sam altogether until things change. It was as if every public relations professional&rsquo;s toothy smile hid a single word&mdash;tariff&mdash;whispered but never fully uttered through their teeth.</p><h2>U.S. policies are leaving us guessing on price and availability</h2> <figure><img src="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1.jpg" alt="Tcl Qm9k Tv 1" width="1920" height="1280" srcset="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1.jpg 1920w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1-336x224.jpg 336w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1-1280x853.jpg 1280w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1-768x512.jpg 768w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1-672x448.jpg 672w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1-960x640.jpg 960w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/08/TCL-QM9K-TV-1-1600x1067.jpg 1600w"><figcaption>The TCL QM9K TV is a month away from launch, and still the company did not want to tell us its price. &copy; Kyle Barr / Gizmodo</figcaption></figure><p>Some international tech giants bearing truly unique products are being barred completely from the States. DJI, the company most known for making drones, has found itself <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/16/24272188/dji-blames-us-customs-block-import-some-drones">soft-banned</a> from importing gear to the U.S. There&rsquo;s a long and fraught history with DJI and the U.S. market, but the end result is Americans locked out of an entire line of products. At IFA, DJI had its new <a href="https://gizmodo.com/djis-first-360-camera-is-gunning-for-insta360s-class-leading-x5-2000637154">Osmo 360</a> camera proudly displayed. You can go to the <a href="https://store.dji.com/product/osmo-360-standard-combo?vid=194091">DJI store page</a> now, and it currently says &ldquo;Out of Stock&rdquo; if you&rsquo;re checking in from the U.S. DJI has in-store availability slated for the rest of this year, but people in the U.S. won&rsquo;t be able to easily buy it. At least <a href="https://gizmodo.com/after-using-this-360-drone-ill-never-look-at-flying-cameras-the-same-way-again-2000641466">Insta360 and its Antigravity A1 360-degree camera drone</a> are still getting a U.S. launch.</p><p>Some tech companies have managed to cajole President Donald &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not a dictator&rdquo; Trump by <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/09/05/trump-tech-dinner-ceo-zuckerberg-musk">heaping praise</a> and <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/737757/apple-president-donald-trump-ceo-tim-cook-glass-corning">gaudy 24K gold statues</a> on the capricious commander in chief. Those companies that haven&rsquo;t <a href="https://gizmodo.com/nvidia-just-dodged-an-8-billion-bullet-thanks-to-donald-trump-2000641188">kissed the ring</a> find themselves on the outside. At IFA, we checked out several new products from Roborock, including a new robo lawnmower and a <a href="https://gizmodo.com/roborocks-washer-and-dryer-combo-also-doubles-as-a-robot-vacuum-dock-2000653302">washing machine/dryer combo with a doggy door for a robovac</a>. Neither are coming to the U.S. in the immediate future, the company told us. The U.S. has easily the highest demand for lawnmowers in the world.</p><figure><img src="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360.jpg" alt="Dji Osmo 360" width="1920" height="1280" srcset="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360.jpg 1920w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360-336x224.jpg 336w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360-1280x853.jpg 1280w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360-768x512.jpg 768w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360-672x448.jpg 672w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360-960x640.jpg 960w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/DJI-Osmo-360-1600x1067.jpg 1600w"><figcaption>You can&rsquo;t buy the DJI Osmo 360 camera in the U.S., as much as you may want to. &copy; Kyle Barr / Gizmodo</figcaption></figure><p>Over and over again, I asked companies about U.S. pricing and availability, and was told they didn&rsquo;t have those details available, at least not yet. Companies like Anker, Mova, and Dreame crafted their own blend of robotic suits for <a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-robot-vacuums-next-trick-climbing-stairs-2000654928">robovacs to help them climb stairs</a>. The <a href="https://gizmodo.com/eufys-got-a-little-stair-climbing-mech-suit-for-its-robot-vacuums-2000653284">Eufy MarsWalker,</a> Dreame CyberX, and Mova Zeus 60 should be around sometime next year. No, of course, there&rsquo;s no suggested price. Want more wacky gadgets? Too bad. <a href="https://gizmodo.com/finally-you-can-cuddle-with-a-cute-camera-clad-ai-robot-that-feels-jealousy-2000653993">SwitchBot&rsquo;s Kata Friends</a>, an AI-powered family &ldquo;pet&rdquo; that looks like a teddy bear filled with several sensors, still doesn&rsquo;t have a price or availability for U.S. consumers. The company simply wouldn&rsquo;t suggest when its products will ever come to the U.S.</p><p>That&rsquo;s not to say it was the case with all tech on the show floor. There are plenty of new gadgets, like these <a href="https://gizmodo.com/these-headphones-with-bose-sound-and-100-hours-of-battery-wont-destroy-your-wallet-2000655436">long-lasting Bose headphones, the </a>updated<a href="https://gizmodo.com/withings-updates-scanwatch-2-with-35-day-battery-life-the-apple-watch-could-only-dream-of-2000654923"> Withings ScanWatch 2, </a>Anker&rsquo;s <a href="https://gizmodo.com/ankers-new-prime-300w-power-bank-is-the-last-portable-battery-youll-ever-need-2000654231">Prime power banks</a>, and the massive <a href="https://gizmodo.com/ankers-mammoth-projector-is-now-so-big-you-should-just-call-it-r2-d2-2000650601">Nebula X1 Pro</a> will come to the U.S. Companies are more hesitant than ever to even mention prices. <a href="https://gizmodo.com/tcls-bright-as-hell-flagship-4k-tv-is-filled-with-enticing-features-and-ai-2000650784">TCL&rsquo;s new QM9K TV</a> should be available &ldquo;later this month,&rdquo; but the company refused to provide an idea about price, which is perhaps the most important element of a renowned budget TV brand.</p><h2>The PC market looked dire at IFA 2025</h2> <figure><img src="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2-.jpeg" alt="Lenovo Legion Go 2" width="1920" height="1280" srcset="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2-.jpeg 1920w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2--336x224.jpeg 336w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2--1280x853.jpeg 1280w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2--768x512.jpeg 768w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2--672x448.jpeg 672w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2--960x640.jpeg 960w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Lenovo-Legion-Go-2--1600x1067.jpeg 1600w"><figcaption>The new Legion Go 2 is $350 more expensive than the starting price of the original Legion Go. &copy; Kyle Barr / Gizmodo</figcaption></figure><p>Unlike with CES, companies don&rsquo;t have to come to IFA if they hope to make a splash. It&rsquo;s not a sure sign there are internal or external struggles. But in conversations with companies, it&rsquo;s clear the only answer they have to Trump&rsquo;s tariffs is to delay release or obfuscate pricing. Asus launched several laptops at IFA 2024. The company told Gizmodo it was skipping the 2025 show. That wasn&rsquo;t entirely true, though. Asus&rsquo; gaming-centric brand&mdash;Republic of Gamers&mdash;took up a corner booth space in the back of one of the halls with two <a href="https://gizmodo.com/can-hollow-knight-silksong-make-me-love-the-xbox-handheld-2000652336">Asus ROG Xbox Ally X handhelds</a> on display. The company still refused to say how much it would cost. There&rsquo;s a reason customers should be concerned.</p><p>Handhelds are one of the fastest-growing and most innovative markets for both gaming and PCs. At IFA, one company promised a <a href="https://gizmodo.com/live-updates-from-ifa-2025-in-berlin-%f0%9f%94%b4-2000649907#live-54331f1cfa53d7bb958b47c50969ae99">handheld-laptop hybrid</a> with a stereoscopic 3D display akin to the Nintendo 3DS. While we saw more handhelds at <a href="https://gizmodo.com/gizmodos-best-of-ces-2025-awards-see-the-winners-2000548586">CES 2025</a>, the situation post-tariffs is far more tenuous. <a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-pretty-screen-on-lenovos-legion-go-2-will-almost-make-you-forget-about-its-price-2000649925">Lenovo&rsquo;s Legion Go 2</a> was all set to hit a home run with its OLED display. Then we saw the price. Lenovo said the handheld PC would start at $1,050. Things are worse when you look at the true costs. A version of the handheld with the higher-end processor, the AMD Ryzen Z2 Extreme, starts at $1,350. The original Legion Go demanded $700 at launch late in 2023.</p><figure><img src="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1.jpeg" alt="Acer Swift 16 Air Hands On 1" width="1920" height="1280" srcset="https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1.jpeg 1920w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1-336x224.jpeg 336w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1-1280x853.jpeg 1280w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1-672x448.jpeg 672w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1-960x640.jpeg 960w, https://gizmodo.com/app/uploads/2025/09/Acer-Swift-16-Air-Hands-On-1-1600x1067.jpeg 1600w"><figcaption>Want to know how much the Acer Swift 16 Air will cost? So do we. &copy; Kyle Barr / Gizmodo</figcaption></figure><p>Few people want to spend over $1,000 for a device with only marginal performance gains. It does not bode well for the Xbox Ally X, which contains the same Ryzen Z2 Extreme chip. We were also hoping to see Acer finally drop details on its <a href="https://gizmodo.com/acer-nitro-blaze-7-hands-on-staying-within-the-speed-limit-2000495157">Nitro Blaze 7</a> and <a href="https://gizmodo.com/the-acer-nitro-blaze-11-is-the-anti-nintendo-switch-2000545560">Nitro Blaze 11</a> handhelds. While the handheld has already been on sale in various countries in Asia, Europe, and the Middle East, Acer told me it had &ldquo;no updates for U.S. on handhelds.&rdquo; Acer was also unwilling to share any pricing for its upcoming laptops, like the <a href="https://gizmodo.com/i-cant-tell-if-acers-new-predator-laptop-is-better-for-gamers-or-working-stiffs-2000651850">ultra-light Swift 16 Air</a>.</p><p>Tech companies may be taking a wait-and-see strategy, but there&rsquo;s no sign Trump will end his love affair with import taxes, at least for those U.S. firms unwilling to give up a stake in their company&mdash;<a href="https://gizmodo.com/u-s-government-now-controls-10-of-intel-trump-says-2000647121">like Intel has</a>&mdash;or go Nvidia&rsquo;s route and be stuck agreeing to ever-more unfavorable demands. Trump&rsquo;s fascistic tendencies naturally lean on the industry, but those who can&rsquo;t or (increasingly rarely) won&rsquo;t give themselves to Trump will simply have to avoid the U.S. and its many gadget-hungry consumers. Nobody knows how this will all shake out, but U.S. users better get used to holding onto their aging gear for far longer.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 12:44:27 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.404media.co/ice-spends-millions-on-clearview-ai-face-recognition-to-find-people-assaulting-officers/</link><title>ICE Spends Millions on Clearview AI Facial Recognition to Find People ‘Assaulting’ Officers (404media.co)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nc4flz/ice_spends_millions_on_clearview_ai_facial/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nc4flz/ice_spends_millions_on_clearview_ai_facial/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nc4flz/ice_spends_millions_on_clearview_ai_facial/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.404media.co/content/images/2025/09/54294950863_34908a198f_c.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) recently spent nearly four million dollars on facial recognition technology in part to investigate people it believes have assaulted law enforcement officers, according to procurement records reviewed by 404 Media.</p><p>The records are unusual in that they indicate ICE is buying the technology to identify people who might clash with the agency&rsquo;s officers as they continue the Trump administration&rsquo;s mass deportation efforts. Authorities have repeatedly claimed members of the public have assaulted or otherwise attacked ICE or other immigration enforcement officers, only later for <a href="https://www.nbclosangeles.com/news/local/ontario-medical-center-ice-raid/3766578/?ref=404media.co"><u>charges to be dropped or lowered</u></a> when it emerged <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jul/28/doj-la-protesters-false-claims?ref=404media.co"><u>authorities misrepresented what happened</u></a> or <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/19/jose-manuel-mojica-la-protester-charges-dropped?ref=404media.co"><u>brutally assaulted protesters themselves</u></a>. In other cases, <a href="https://www.oregonlive.com/crime/2025/07/facial-recognition-software-used-to-identify-reed-college-grad-accused-of-assaulting-ice-officer.html?ref=404media.co"><u>prosecutions are ongoing</u></a>.</p><div><p>&#128161;</p><p><b><strong>Do you know anything else about how ICE is using facial recognition tech or other tools? I would love to hear from you. Using a non-work device, you can message me securely on Signal at joseph.404 or send me an email at joseph@404media.co.</strong></b></p></div><p>&ldquo;This award procures facial recognition software, which supports Homeland Security Investigations with capabilities of identifying victims and offenders in child sexual exploitation cases and assaults against law enforcement officers,&rdquo; the procurement records reads. The September 5 purchase awards $3,750,000 to well-known and controversial facial recognition firm Clearview AI. The record indicates the total value of the contract is $9,225,000.</p></div><div><div><h2>This post is for paid members only</h2><p>Become a paid member for unlimited ad-free access to articles, bonus podcast content, and more.</p><p><a href="https://www.404media.co/membership/">Subscribe</a> </p></div><div><h2>Sign up for free access to this post</h2><p>Free members get access to posts like this one along with an email round-up of our week's stories.</p><p><a href="https://www.404media.co/signup/">Subscribe</a> </p></div><p>Already have an account? <a href="https://www.404media.co/signin/">Sign in</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 05:47:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://theintercept.com/2025/09/08/department-of-war-defense-stream-keys-hackers-livestream-hack-security/</link><title>Department of War Doesn’t Defend its Web Streams From Hackers (theintercept.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbufg8/department_of_war_doesnt_defend_its_web_streams/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbufg8/department_of_war_doesnt_defend_its_web_streams/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbufg8/department_of_war_doesnt_defend_its_web_streams/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://theintercept.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/AP25248850922118-e1757352906252.jpg?fit=4500%2C2250&w=1200&h=800' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>The newly renamed</span> Department of War has publicly posted the stream keys of its Facebook, X, and YouTube channels for years, potentially allowing hackers to hijack its official social media accounts and broadcast whatever they want.</p><p>A stream key is like an account password for livestreaming content on social media. Before a stream goes live on a user&rsquo;s social media account, they must input a stream key into their broadcast software of choice.</p><p>Google, which owns YouTube, <a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/answer/9854503?hl=en#zippy=%2Cstream-key">describes</a> stream keys as being akin to &ldquo;your YouTube stream&rsquo;s password and address.&rdquo; Facebook <a href="https://www.facebook.com/fbgaminghome/creators/getstarted">tells streamers</a> &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t share your stream key. Anyone who has access to it can stream video from your page.&rdquo;</p><p>The Department of War, however, routinely posts stream keys on its Defense Visual Information Distribution Service (DVIDS) website, a portal hosting military videos and photos for media usage. The website is open to the public and doesn&rsquo;t require an account to browse &ndash; or to come across stream keys.</p><p>An Intercept analysis found that the Department of War has publicly posted stream keys on this service for years. The stream keys are typically posted prior to upcoming scheduled streams. For example, Twitter stream keys were posted for the U.S. Cyber Command change of command ceremony live stream in 2018. X and YouTube keys were also posted for last year&rsquo;s West Point commencement ceremony. More recently, the stream keys for the department&rsquo;s X, YouTube, and Facebook accounts were posted in the hours leading up to a livestream of Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth giving burgers to the the National Guard in Washington, D.C. in August. &nbsp;</p><p>They aren&rsquo;t hard to find. The stream key posted on the DVIDS site can be seen by browsing the portal&rsquo;s sequentially-numbered webcast URLs, or querying search engines for terms such as &ldquo;stream key&rdquo; and &ldquo;DVIDS.&rdquo; At times the Department of War uses stream keys that expire after each stream, allowing the takeover of one specific upcoming event but preventing persistent unauthorized access. Sometimes, however, the Department of War leaves stream keys unchanged for years, allowing for the takeover of upcoming streams on various social media platforms even if the stream keys for a specific event aren&rsquo;t posted for that event.</p><p>This vulnerability wouldn&rsquo;t allow attackers to take over social media feeds at any time. A hacker would need to wait for an upcoming Department of War webcast and then use the keys to start broadcasting their own content. The Pentagon maintains a public schedule of upcoming webcasts on their DVIDS site.</p><p>Stream keys are not made public for all Department of War streams. For instance, the keys were not publicly disclosed on September 5 for the livestream of President Trump signing an executive order rebranding the Department of Defense as the Department of War.</p><p>The Department of War did not respond to multiple requests for comment.</p><p>The Intercept has found no evidence that stream keys have been exploited to take over a Department of War stream. But past security incidents show the danger of such vulnerabilities. Imposters, for instance, have used artificial intelligence tools to impersonate politicians, including <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/national-security/2025/07/08/marco-rubio-ai-imposter-signal/">mimicking</a> Secretary of State Marco Rubio&rsquo;s voice to contact various U.S. politicians and foreign ministers. If this kind of deceptive content appeared on official government channels, even briefly, the consequences could be significant, warned security technologist Bruce Schneier. &ldquo;You can imagine this being used for some kind of confusion event,&rdquo; he cautioned.</p><p>AI-based hoaxes can have wide-ranging implications. In 2023, for example, a fake image of smoke coming from a building near the Pentagon caused a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/23/business/ai-picture-stock-market.html">dip</a> in the stock market. The Department of War is no stranger to security lapses, including <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/04/25/pentagon-defense-secretary-pete-hegseth-leaks-signal/">discussing</a> a bombing campaign in Yemen on Signal with journalists earlier this year.</p><p>Exposing stream keys &ldquo;doesn&rsquo;t rise to the level of putting strangers on your Signal chat,&rdquo; Schneier said, but he considers it a sloppy practice that should be fixed immediately.</p><p>Cooper Quintin, Senior Staff Technologist at the Electronic Frontier Foundation, said that the &ldquo;concern here is less that an adversary would spread disinformation &mdash; our own federal government is doing plenty of that already.&rdquo;</p><p>The bigger risk, Quintin said, is that the vulnerability could be used to discredit real footage. &ldquo;This could be used to lend plausible deniability to any legitimate videos that got posted to that account.&rdquo;</p><p>In other words, the government could use this as justification to erase any official stream &ndash; say an embarrassing press conference or a hot mic moment &ndash; by claiming it was manipulated content posted by a hacker, not a video posted by the Department of War itself.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 23:11:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/job-market-hell/684133/?gift=Vowm9zXD_VpjYJtYApIfy6iqYdFY6568omVJ07mz1tc</link><title>The Job Market Is Hell: Young people are using ChatGPT to write their applications; HR is using AI to read them; no one is getting hired. (theatlantic.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/J-0rMrIxnE3yFSvDEPugUb2U1Zk=/0x43:2000x1085/1200x625/media/img/mt/2025/09/2025_6_7_Impossible_To_Get_A_Job/original.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Listen to more stories on the <a href="https://newsoveraudio.com/?offerId=atl_reader_exclusive_jks1kjl"> Noa</a> app.</p></div><section><p>Harris started looking for his first real job months before his graduation from UC Davis this spring. He had a solid r&eacute;sum&eacute;, he thought: a paid internship at a civic-consulting firm, years of volunteering at environmental-defense organizations, experience working on farms and in parks as well as in offices, a close-to-perfect GPA, strong letters of recommendation. He would move anywhere on the West Coast, living out of his car if he had to. He would accept a temporary, part-time, or seasonal gig, not just a full-time position. He would do anything&mdash;filing paperwork, digging trenches&mdash;to build his dream career protecting California&rsquo;s wildlife and public lands.</p><p>He applied to 200 jobs. He got rejected 200 times. Actually, he clarified, he &ldquo;didn&rsquo;t get <em>rejected</em> 200 times.&rdquo; A lot of businesses never responded.</p><p>Right now, millions of would-be workers find themselves in a similar position. Corporate profits <a href="https://www.bea.gov/data/income-saving/corporate-profits">are strong</a>, the jobless rate is 4.3 percent, and wages are <a href="https://www.atlantafed.org/chcs/wage-growth-tracker">climbing in turn</a>. But payrolls have been essentially frozen for the past four months. The hiring rate has declined to <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/JTSHIR">its lowest point</a> since the jobless recovery following the Great Recession. Four years ago, employers were adding four or five workers for every 100 they had on the books, month in and month out. Now they are adding three.</p><p>At the same time, the process of getting a job has become a late-capitalist nightmare. Online hiring platforms have made it easier to find an opening but harder to secure one: Applicants send out thousands of AI-crafted r&eacute;sum&eacute;s, and businesses use AI to sift through them. What Bumble and Hinge did to the dating market, contemporary human-resources practices have done to the job market. People are swiping like crazy and getting nothing back.</p><p>Every time Harris logged in to LinkedIn or Indeed, he would see scores of gigs that seemed like they might be a good fit. He would read a posting carefully, scrub his r&eacute;sum&eacute;, tailor an introductory note, answer the company&rsquo;s screening questions, hit &ldquo;Send,&rdquo; hope for the best, and hear nothing in response&mdash;again and again and again.</p><p>Other job seekers described similar experiences. In suburban Virginia, a paralegal named Martine got laid off by a government contractor in April. (Like Harris, she did not want to dim her employment prospects by providing her full name.) She saw plenty of jobs being advertised at nonprofits, law firms, consultancies, and universities. She sent out dozens of applications. She even got to the second round a few times. But she never came close to being hired. &ldquo;I have 10 years of experience,&rdquo; she told me. &ldquo;I would be happy if a person told me no at this point.&rdquo;</p><p>For employers, the job market is working differently too. Businesses receive countless ill-fitting applications, along with a few good ones, for each open position. Rather than poring over the submissions by hand, they use machines. In a recent survey, chief HR officers told the Boston Consulting Group that they are <a href="https://www.bcg.com/publications/2025/ai-changing-recruitment">using AI</a> to write job descriptions, assess candidates, schedule introductory meetings, and evaluate applications. In some cases, firms are using chatbots to interview candidates, too. Prospective hires log in to a Zoom-like system and field questions from an avatar. Their performance is taped, and an algorithm searches for keywords and evaluates their tone.</p><p>Priya Rathod, a career-trends expert at Indeed, told me she understands why job seekers feel as if their r&eacute;sum&eacute;s are &ldquo;going into a void.&rdquo; But she argued that the online platforms make it easier for people to find open positions and that AI can &ldquo;get them to the next stage of the interview quicker,&rdquo; if their applications fit an employer&rsquo;s needs.</p><p>Still, a lot of job applicants never end up in a human-to-human process. The impossibility of getting to the interview stage spurs jobless workers to submit more applications, which pushes them to rely on ChatGPT to build their r&eacute;sum&eacute;s and respond to screening prompts. (Harris told me he does this; he used ChatGPT pretty much every day in college, and finds its writing to be more &ldquo;professional&rdquo; than his own.) And so the cycle continues: The surge in same-same AI-authored applications prompts employers to use robot filters to manage the flow. Everyone ends up in Tinderized job-search hell.</p><p>For months, the economy has been in a low-hire, low-fire equilibrium; virtually every sector of the labor market except for health care has been frozen. The amount of time a worker has spent looking for a job has climbed to an average of <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNU03008276">10 weeks</a>, meaning that Americans are spending two weeks longer on the job market than they were a few years ago. The share of American workers quitting a job has fallen to its lowest <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/JTSQUR">level in a decade</a>, because of concerns about rising prices and jitters about slowing growth.</p><p>The equilibrium now seems to be falling apart, and a full-on recession looks likely. Black workers have experienced a dramatic <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNS14000006">surge in joblessness</a>, in part because of the Trump administration&rsquo;s mass layoffs of federal employees. (The 154,000 civil servants who took the White House&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">&ldquo;</a><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">Fork in the Road</a><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">&rdquo;</a> deferred-resignation offer will receive their last <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/07/31/federal-workers-doge-buyout-paid/">paycheck this month</a>.) More than 10 percent of workers under the age of 24 are searching for <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNS14024887">a job</a>. &ldquo;Performance-based and strategic layoffs are increasing,&rdquo; Lydia Boussour of the consultancy EY-Parthenon wrote in a note to clients last week. &ldquo;Cracks are increasingly showing.&rdquo;</p><p>What is a worker supposed to do? Martine and Harris and millions like them are still trying to figure that out; she keeps on applying, whereas he is doing landscaping and volunteering. Rathod said that she recommends old-fashioned networking: asking recruiters out for coffee, going to in-person job events, and surveying friends and former employers for leads.</p><p>Such strategies might work if employers begin hiring again. But if not, millions more people might be left pitching their CVs into the void.</p></section><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/G3J3fAQrlILC_OcsAGs76IWlZmo=/438x0:1563x1125/80x80/media/img/mt/2025/09/2025_6_7_Impossible_To_Get_A_Job/original.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:25:03 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
