<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=selfhosted&amp;averagePostsPerDay=4&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/selfhosted</title><description>Hot posts in /r/selfhosted (roughly 4 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 08:43:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_32hch-styles-communityIcon_b2t5inv46z331-144x400.png</url><title>/r/selfhosted</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://i.redd.it/2ehdyy1io6qf1.jpeg</link><title>Selfhosted Simple File Converter, PDF OCR and Whisper Transcription (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I wasn&#39;t quite satisfied with the existing self-hosted file converters, as I found many had a clunky UI or lacked support for custom commands. It felt cumbersome to run three separate services for daily tasks like converting markdown with Pandoc or transcribing a voice memo.</p><p>To solve this, I built a simple web app to serve as a personal, self-hosted alternative to the various online converter sites. The project is up on GitHub.</p><p>I&#39;ve created two Docker images: a lightweight one and a full version that includes larger dependencies like the TeX build. I&#39;d appreciate any feedback on usability or bugs you might find. Let me know what you think!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/2ehdyy1io6qf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p><del>What OIDC provider do you use? looks clean. voicauth.,</del> stupid question now I re-read you post, looks nice!</p><p>You may want to remove you client secret and callsbacks from your settings file on github.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/nf5eivy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://github.com/LoredCast/filewizard">https://github.com/LoredCast/filewizard</a></p><p><a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/loredcast/filewizard/">https://hub.docker.com/r/loredcast/filewizard/</a></p><p>Here is the Github and DockerHub Page.<br/>It was built with FastAPI and vanilla frontend, I might port to svelte if the app gets any more complex, but it works for now and is quite light in code. I know it&#39;s just a fancy wrapper for existing tools but I don&#39;t always have a cli with me to do simple file conversions on the go. Right now it uses:<br/>- ocrmypdf, fasterwhisper, libreoffice, pandoc, ghostscript_pdf, calibre, ffmpeg, vips, graphicsmagick, libjxl, resvg, potrace, pngquant, sox and mozjpeg. Let me know which tools you like to be added. You can easily include your own tools by going into the docker image, installing a cli and add an entry to the settings.yml for the command template.<br/>I&#39;m aware of ConvertX, Scriberr and paperless-ngx, which combined serve the same purpose but I didn&#39;t like using them for quick tasks and ConvertX had very little configuration room.</p><p>You can also connect the app to an OAuth provider like authelia or voidauth (I tested with voidauth) for user authentication and per-user history and admin roles.</p><p>NOTE: This is the first release and I do not recommend hosting this publicly unless you know how to setup the authentication and have some understanding of security since I can&#39;t be 100% sure that this can&#39;t lead to Exmploits since it deals with executing commands on your machine. I&#39;ve tried my best to make the command wrapper safe but run at your own risk.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/nf4xsk0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sick! This is something I&#39;ve been needing. Is there anyway for it to be called via webhook from something like n8n?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/nf5hqkt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This looks great. I&#39;ma try this out to replace HRConvert2. It&#39;s probably my least used service but I like the idea of a better interface and OIDC support for when I do need to convert local files.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/nf6mp57/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is amazing! I&#39;ve been looking for something just like this</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/nf6ipln/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thanks for this. Would it be possible to add Translation  support from major languages to English or vice versa for both images and pdf?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/nf6osa2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Can you add text to audio as well using the latest microsft vibe voice or xaomi model ?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nlezmf/selfhosted_simple_file_converter_pdf_ocr_and/nf6uebr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 02:16:10 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/</link><title>Breaking away from Google services with self hosted alternatives has been a bigger project than I expected</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Over the past year I’ve been trying to move more and more of my digital life away from Google. I didn’t realize just how many parts of my daily routine were tied to them until I started digging in. Email, calendar, contacts, photo backups, even random logins all seemed to go back to a Google account somewhere.</p><p>I started small with email. Instead of relying on Gmail, I set up my own domain and pointed it to a mail server I could control. Took some trial and error, but now I can handle my own accounts, aliases, and storage. For calendars and contacts, I moved to CalDAV and CardDAV, syncing across devices with a simple self-hosted service. It’s not as flashy as Google Calendar, but it works without handing everything over.</p><p>Photos and files were supposed to be the next step, so I decided to set up Nextcloud… but honestly, I’m not figuring it out. Between permissions issues, slow performance, and sync errors, I feel like I spend more time troubleshooting than actually using it. I know it’s capable of replacing Drive, Photos, Notes, and more, but so far I haven’t managed to get it stable enough to trust with my data.</p><p>The hardest part has been deciding what’s worth the effort to self-host and what’s better left alone. Some swaps have been straightforward, but others (like Nextcloud) have made me realize just how much Google’s convenience hides behind the scenes but I also don&#39;t want my data everywhere, tired of everything being an info dump so they can sell me anything I talk about. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>I started small with email. </p></blockquote><p>Ah yes, &quot;small&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/nf2lquv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Immich is a really valid alternative. Docker compose is the way to go.For music I use navidrome and Tempo app on android (github). For a Drive alternative I use Owncloud, but Opencloud is a valid one as well. For mail I use Infomaniak, too much hussle setting up a mail server.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/nf1tkqn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>For photos, Immich (as already suggested) is the clear option.</p><p>For files I prefer Seafile.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/nf1tsos/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Same boat as you. I&#39;m waiting for Immich to get better (at least to have working backups) so I can switch from google photos. </p><p>I tried setting up nextcloud but too bloated imo. I can easily setup a storage replacement for drive and choose between countless selfhosted note apps, nextcloud was unnecessary for me.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/nf1u10t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How are you trying Nextcloud what type of hardware? </p><p>I did Nextcloud on my own, but recently switched to Nextcloud AIO, and it has been a much better experience. Much snappier but I’d agree it is heavy but running it on my old gaming rig, and it’s been snappy enough. Specially after switching to AIO. </p><p>I like it because it kinda does a lot of things in one service. I have bookmark backups, calendars, contacts, to-do, notes, files, and it also handles documents with Nextcloud office (as little as I have to use that). </p><p>I even WebDAV Joplin into Nextcloud folder and also the same for KeePassXC.</p><p>AIO was way easier to install than the regular Nextcloud. </p><p>Since you have sync and other things separated maybe try own cloud infinite scale? It’s just files basically.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/nf21i4i/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>I started small with email. </p></blockquote><p>Uh oh.</p><p>Have you tested deliverability to places like gmail, outlook, etc? Getting selfhosted e-mail servers to deliver properly to major players is a chore and a half.</p><p>If you already have, and it was the first thing you tried, I can see how you&#39;d end up thinking this whole thing is quite a bit of work lol</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/nf25blz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Nextcloud took me about a week to fully figure out what was going on with nginx and passing through the PHP requests. Nextcloud heavily benefits from properly setting up the redis server for caching, as well as the PHP tweaks that are all in the documentation. I also had to basically copy and paste their config file for nginx. I had very little experience going in.</p><p>I will say if you get nextcloud working, there is a helpful scanning tool under the &quot;overview&quot; tab, which was crucial to figuring out the performance issues. I just kept tweaking and hunting bugs.</p><p>Right now, I am SO happy with the effort. Nextcloud is extremely snappy and works great. I have synced contacts and calendars from the phone. I use it for workflow between my laptop and desktop, I save a document on either machine and it syncs within seconds. The memories app is what I didn&#39;t know I wanted,  for managing my photos. The map feature is sweet. </p><p>I am an amateur, but I could run you through my set up to see if you can see where you went wrong</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nl0di3/breaking_away_from_google_services_with_self/nf29znl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:25:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/</link><title>Open-source tool to organize adult content [NSFW]</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hi everyone!</p><p>I&#39;ve developed a software to organize and view personal adults movie collection.</p><p>This tool is called ZobTube and aims to help sorting movies by kind (or length), adding actors, categories and channels.</p><p>It aims to be highly customizable, allowing setting everything to match personal preferences.</p><p>It is only available as self-hosted, aka you run it yourself, on your own computer/server.</p><p>It is open-sourced and is based on open-source technologies.</p><p>Feel free to give it a try!</p><p><a href="https://github.com/zobtube/zobtube">https://github.com/zobtube/zobtube</a></p><p>If you have any question, feel free to jump on <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/zobtube/">r/zobtube</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>You have zero screenshots on the GitHub, apps without any are usually more often ignored. Sounds like an alternative to <a href="https://github.com/stashapp/stash">Stash</a>?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/nf1h7sf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Nice to see another tool in this space. Definitely need to provide more information about what it can do and how it compares with Stash.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/nf1ti8n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Goontube</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/nf1zax8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You have to be french!Bravo pour le nom du projet !!!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/nf1v96c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>you had me at organize!</p><p>installing/testing in 3 - 2 - 1...</p><p>edit: is there a docker compose file or am i missing it?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/nf2ebrh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>nicenow give me your adult content collection.😎😎😎</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/nf1nt5x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>An alternative to Stash, good to see. Much like JustWhyRe said about the Screenshots, I&#39;ll have to hold off till I see them. The tiktok esque section you mentioned sounded interesting and probably a good ad. I do know something Myself and others have asked for before with stash was the option for a txt file for AO3 ERP stories.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkynm9/opensource_tool_to_organize_adult_content/nf2hq15/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:41:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/</link><title>Tired of YouTube Music? Here's how I migrated to Jellyfin for good.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey everyone,</p><p>I&#39;ve been moving my music library from YouTube Music to my own Jellyfin server and wanted a better way to export my playlists. I couldn&#39;t find a tool that did exactly what I needed, so I built my own.</p><p>It&#39;s a simple Docker-based tool called YMDE. Here’s a quick rundown of the features:</p><ul><li><strong>Processes Google Takeout</strong>: Works directly with your YouTube Music <code>JSON</code> or <code>CSV</code> playlist files.</li><li><strong>Efficient Downloads</strong>: Uses <code>yt-dlp</code> with parallel processing to download everything quickly.</li><li><strong>Clean Organization</strong>: Saves files in a <code>Playlist Name/Track Title.ext</code> structure.</li><li><strong>Metadata &amp; Thumbnails</strong>: Automatically embeds metadata and video thumbnails into the audio files.</li><li><strong>Playlist Generation</strong>: Creates <code>.m3u8</code> playlists, so media servers like Jellyfin or Plex can import them instantly.</li><li><strong>Smart Deduplication</strong>: Avoids re-downloading tracks that are in multiple playlists.</li></ul><p>My main goal was to create a clean, tagged library that I could just point Jellyfin to. You can run it once and copy the files over, or map your Jellyfin music folder directly in the <code>compose.yml</code> for a seamless sync. No more being locked into Google&#39;s ecosystem.</p><p>The project is still new, but it&#39;s working great for my setup. If you&#39;re trying to do something similar, I&#39;d love for you to check it out and give me some feedback.</p><p>You can find it on GitHub here: <a href="https://github.com/WarreTh/YMDE">WarreTh/YMDE</a></p><p>Let me know what you think</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I wish There was a 3rd party for ios and/or android that would keep a log of ALL music you play on YT music.  Then after a month I would love to run something like this on that log.  I usually listen to the same music all older stuff.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/nezdsvi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Efficient Downloads: Uses yt-dlp with parallel processing to download everything quickly.</p></blockquote><p>I did something similar once for about 600 songs and got IP banned for about 1 month from everything youtube which didn&#39;t surprise me. I didn&#39;t stagger it at all.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/nezb2kl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I love all the homelab/self hosted stuff going on right now. This is another great tool built out of necessity. </p><p>For people looking to do something similar with other services like Tidal or Spotify, checkout Streamrip. <a href="https://github.com/nathom/streamrip">https://github.com/nathom/streamrip</a> This allows you to pull tracks/albums/artists off your service in whatever qualities you want. It&#39;s very customizable. I pair it up with a web ui so my partner can add stuff, <a href="https://github.com/AnOddName/streamrip-web-gui">https://github.com/AnOddName/streamrip-web-gui</a> and then it&#39;s all put into folders that can be monitored by Plex/Jellyfin/Whatever you want. </p><p>Happy self-hosted listening!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/nezu5q4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Definitely gonna add this to my to-do list. Biggest reason i haven&#39;t dropped YouTube music yet.</p><p>Any chance it works with Navidrone though? Or possibly in the future?</p><p>And does Jellyfin do cached downloads like TY music and Navidrone?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/nezavgv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Anyone got good suggestions for music discovery? Already running my music library off of jellyfin and symphonium.. Need a way to find new music</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/nf0xlut/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>maybe it&#39;s just me, I just can&#39;t seem to get the hang of the jellyfin music player. it seems to me to be really really bad.</p><p>I really appreciate this method of easily downloading your music. And I think I need to do that. I just need to find a better way to listen to it then through any jelly fin app that I&#39;ve found so far.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/nezxbu4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Looking good! I will try this out and let you know my feedback</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nkn457/tired_of_youtube_music_heres_how_i_migrated_to/nez4dpj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 04:28:33 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/</link><title>Are there any benefits /drawbacks to putting all of your dockers in 1 compose file?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>New to self hosting and just wondering if there any benefits/drawbacks to putting all of your dockers in 1 compose file?</p><p>Or related dockers together? The Arr stack in one, media/nas in another, productivity in another, helpful tools in another etc. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Just hard to navigate a 2000 line docker file. I myself break it up by app, so one app and any related services go together (e.g. Databases). Then I have one master file that includes the others <a href="https://docs.docker.com/compose/how-tos/multiple-compose-files/include/">https://docs.docker.com/compose/how-tos/multiple-compose-files/include/</a>. You could also break them up by group like media like you said. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/nevae2d/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I went from thinking like you, using portainer as well! And now I have 17 stacks that are all different projects lol. Use portainer, you can go into the settings and make a backup of the stacks, and it keeps every new iteration you create as a version. Super sweet! And yeah, you want multiple stacks because of networking at the minimum. Try and keep each service it&#39;s own network, which could be doable in your single compose but u don&#39;t want to pull down every container when pulling down the stack. Have fun!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/nevblca/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I would use stacks, i.e. individual compose files, with content that belongs together or has dependencies on each other. This has the advantage, among other things, that you can stop and start them separately. Another advantage is that you can use different networks in each stack, which makes the whole thing more secure because services run in isolation from each other.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/neva24d/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But why put them all in one docker compose file? <del>Do you really want to kill all of them at the same time if you just need to kill one of them?</del></p><p>Now imagine if you had 3 applications using mysql. Do you really want to have 3 mysqls inside one compose file? Or do you plan on having all 3 applications share the same mysqls instance?</p><p>And really, what are you saving by bundling all of them in one compose?</p><p>EDIT: I stand corrected. You can group components of an app together using profiles.. But at this point, what&#39;s the benefit? And if I want to down one of them, I have to stop and rm? Just so that I can keep them all in one compose?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/nevck6e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here are reasons to put several services in the same file:</p><ul><li>You need a quick way of communicating privately between the services. Docker will set up automatically a private network and DNS for services in the same file so they can call each other by the service name.</li><li>You need a quick way of sharing a named storage volume between 2+ services. </li><li>You want to establish dependencies between services so they&#39;re started in a certain order, or restarted if one of them gets sick or dies.</li><li>It makes sense to take all the services in the file up or down together.</li></ul><p>If you don&#39;t meet any of these reasons you should not put them in the same file, particularly because of the last reason.</p><p>There&#39;s a big difference between <code>docker start/stop container</code> and <code>docker compose up/down</code> in the service dir, please read up on it. Starting/stopping containers leaves them &quot;dirty&quot; so it should only be used in very particular circumstances. Typically you use up/down (to pick up config changes and to cleanly stop/start), and you don&#39;t want to be doing that to all your services at once.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/nevf3i1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Its a lot easier to manage them individually, I recommend Dockge or Komodo for docker management. They are both fantastic tools.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/nevb0jm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Docker compose aim is to have compound systems of containers. It is nice to say <code>docker compose up</code> and hear all the orchestra start playing (all containers going up/down). Big compose files are bad practice, but you can break them down with <code>include</code>s. My <code>compose.yaml</code> is</p><pre><code>include:  - homer.yaml  - portainer.yaml...</code></pre><p>have a <code>common.yaml</code> for stuff that all containers need</p><pre><code>version: &#39;3.3&#39;services:    base:        restart: unless-stopped    environment:      - TZ=Europe/Madrid...</code></pre><p>and for instance my <code>portainer.yaml</code> starts</p><pre><code>services:  portainer:    container_name: portainer    extends:      file: common.yaml  ...</code></pre><p>all that goes to git. The individual yamls are for containers or interdependent container groups (say the arrs).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nk5ier/are_there_any_benefits_drawbacks_to_putting_all/new3b2p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:49:02 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/</link><title>How To De-Cloudflare?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m self hosting almost everything now, and the one thing that&#39;s left is Cloudflare. I use CF for its WAF, some redirect rules and SSL certificates, and I want to replace it with self-hosted packages.</p><p>I came across BunkerWeb sometime back, but didn&#39;t get around to implementing it. Is this the best CF alternative out there?For anyone using BunkerWeb: is your setup something like this?</p><p>DNS ---&gt; VPS1 hosting BunkerWeb (acts as MITM) ---&gt; VPS2 hosting my services</p><p>If yes, what specs do I need for VPS1?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Some things aren&#39;t meant to be self hosted and that&#39;s okay. </p><p>When it comes to security I have significantly more faith in cloudflare than I do myself. Know your limits</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/neu4mmk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Does the entire world need access to your self hosted stuff? I hid all my stuff behind VPNs and couldn&#39;t be happier.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/neu8ez1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Have you checked if Pangolin plus traefik middleware’s and geoblock does your needs?</p><p>You could even put Cloudflare proxy DNS just for ddos protection</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/neuaqvf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The pipeline is real: </p><p>I don’t want to pay for extra Google drive storage -&gt; why even pay for a password manager?-&gt; I don’t want to pull out my DVDs each time to watch my movies -&gt; what do you mean I ran out of tokens on chatGPT? -&gt; how do I see this from anywhere? -&gt; do I even need Gmail? -&gt; can’t I just download Wikipedia and all of stack overflow? -&gt; what’s the point of cloudflare? Can’t I just DNS myself -&gt; you mean I have to use THEIR electricity?!? Time for some solar panels -&gt; the government has a KEYLOGGER on my intel CPU?! Time to make my own chips! -&gt; oh now I have to pay taxes! Fine I was thinking of living on my own land anyways! Time to build my own island in the ocean.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/newl47q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Might be a noob question, but isn’t the advantage of Cloudflare like services is that they can handle attacks at larger scale, but if you have your own WAF, it can still be DDoSed?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/neu2sbt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You only write about CF and WAF, not their zero trust. But maybe check out pangolin.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/neudrzx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I have a reverse proxy, crowdsec and pocket-id and I believe that the risk is limited. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njz012/how_to_decloudflare/neucpxq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:07:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/</link><title>My homelab's zero-trust edge: Cloudflare Access + Authentik + YubiKey + Cloudflared (PVE stays private via Tailscale)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">r/selfhosted</a>👋</p><p>I design Zero-Trust security architectures for banks and agencies, so I thought I&#39;d create military grade security for our homelab community. While it doesn&#39;t cover everything we do at work, within permissible limits, we can achieve a lot using various freeware platforms.</p><p>I’ve been tightening my external access and would love feedback on the design, trade-offs, and any “gotchas” you see.</p><p>Here is an expanded version of the project.</p><h1>My Zero-Trust Homelab: Cloudflare Access ↔ Authentik (OIDC + YubiKey), Cloudflared Tunnels, Tailscale for Admin, step-ca for Internal TLS</h1><p>I wanted enterprise-style “default-deny” for my homelab without sacrificing usability on the road. This is the design I landed on after a lot of iteration. Posting the full rationale and layout because I don’t see many security-first homelab write-ups.</p><h1>Goals (and why)</h1><ul><li><strong>Zero-trust at the edge</strong>: every public request must prove identity before it can even touch an app.</li><li><strong>Hardware-backed auth</strong>: I want phishing-resistant WebAuthn/YubiKey. Passwords are the fallback, not the default.</li><li><strong>No open inbound ports</strong>: everything uses an outbound tunnel (Cloudflared) or a private overlay (Tailscale).</li><li><strong>Separate public vs. admin paths</strong>: day-to-day portals go through the edge; admin planes (hypervisor, backup, OOB) are VPN-only.</li><li><strong>First-class internal TLS</strong>: private services get real certs from my own CA (step-ca) and auto-renew through my reverse proxy.</li><li><strong>Simple to operate</strong>: as few moving parts as possible for a single-operator lab.</li><li>High-level architecture (redacted IPs &amp; domains)</li></ul><p>Use <a href="http://mydomain.com"><code>mydomain.com</code></a> wherever you see a hostname. Example private IPs are in the <code>10.10.x.x</code> space.</p><ul><li><strong>Edge &amp; tunnel</strong><ul><li><strong>Cloudflare</strong>: DNS, WAF, and <strong>Zero Trust Access</strong>.</li><li><strong>Cloudflared Tunnel</strong> from a small VM inside LAN (no inbound NAT required).</li></ul></li><li><strong>Identity</strong><ul><li><strong>Authentik</strong> (OIDC provider), enforcing <strong>WebAuthn (YubiKey)</strong>; OTP is the fallback.</li><li>Cloudflare Access uses Authentik as the IdP. Short session TTLs.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Public apps (behind Access)</strong><ul><li>Pi-hole (2 instances), Immich, Portainer, Homepage, OctoPrint, Speedtest, Stream, etc.</li><li>Each private service listens on <code>10.10.x.x</code> and is published via Cloudflared → Cloudflare Access policy.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Admin-only apps (no public path)</strong><ul><li>Proxmox VE (<code>10.10.1.80</code>), Proxmox Backup (<code>10.10.1.87</code>), TrueNAS, Unraid, iDRAC.</li><li><strong>Tailscale</strong> overlay provides access; these FQDNs are not published via the tunnel.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Private PKI &amp; reverse proxy</strong><ul><li><strong>step-ca</strong> (internal CA) at <a href="http://10.10.1.240"><code>10.10.1.240</code></a> issues internal server certs.</li><li><strong>Caddy</strong> reverse proxy at <a href="http://10.10.1.200"><code>10.10.1.200</code></a> terminates TLS, requests/renews certs from step-ca automatically (ACME).</li></ul></li><li><strong>DNS path</strong><ul><li><strong>Unbound</strong> + <strong>NextDNS</strong> as upstreams for LAN, with separate rules for clients.</li></ul></li></ul><p><strong>Other architecture:</strong></p><p><strong>Firewall</strong>: UDM-SE</p><p><strong>Switch</strong>: UniFi 48 Enpterrise grade. 5 different Vlans with extremely segmentation for each vlan.</p><p>Several <strong>AP</strong> in the mix: some tied to specific Vlans.</p><h1>Request flows (how a packet actually gets in)</h1><h1>Public user → Pi-hole Admin (replace with any public app)</h1><ol><li>Browser hits <code>https://pihole.mydomain.com</code>.</li><li><strong>Cloudflare Edge (WAF + Access)</strong> evaluates policy → challenges with <strong>OIDC</strong>.</li><li><strong>Authentik</strong> prompts for <strong>WebAuthn (YubiKey)</strong> (OTP fallback if needed); returns token to Access.</li><li>Access injects session → forwards through <strong>Cloudflared Tunnel</strong> to the LAN.</li><li>Caddy routes to the service (optional), or cloudflared goes directly to the app.</li><li>App responds over the tunnel; the browser never sees the LAN IP.</li></ol><h1>Admin user → Proxmox VE</h1><ul><li>User connects to <strong>Tailscale</strong>; then uses <a href="https://10.10.1.80"><code>https://10.10.1.80</code></a> (or an internal FQDN).</li><li>No Cloudflare/Cloudflared in the path. Administrative surfaces are <strong>VPN-only</strong>.</li><li>Certificates are issued by <strong>step-ca</strong>, so the browser sees <strong>valid internal TLS</strong>.</li></ul><h1>Edge (UDM-SE) hardening</h1><ul><li><strong>Segmentation (VLANs)</strong>: <code>Mgmt</code>, <code>Servers</code>, <code>Workstations</code>, <code>IoT</code>, <code>Guest</code>, <code>CCTV</code>, <code>WAN-Mgmt</code>.</li><li><strong>Inter-VLAN policy</strong>: default <strong>deny</strong> between user/IoT/guest ↔ servers; only narrow allows (e.g., clients → DNS :53 to <a href="http://10.10.10.55/56"><strong>10.10.10.55/56</strong></a>, NTP :123, specific app APIs).</li><li><strong>WAN edge</strong>: no port-forwards; Cloudflare Tunnel fronts external HTTPS; <strong>remote admin via Tailnet only</strong> (no Unifi UI from WAN).</li><li><strong>Mgmt surface</strong>: Unifi UI/SSH reachable only from <code>Mgmt</code> VLAN; optional geo-block + rate-limit for any temporary WAN-local services.</li><li><strong>DNS egress control</strong>: block :53 to the Internet from all user VLANs; allow only to <a href="http://10.10.10.55"><strong>10.10.10.55</strong></a> (Pi-hole) and <a href="http://10.10.10.56"><strong>10.10.10.56</strong></a> (Skyhole).</li><li><strong>IPS/IDS</strong>: Suricata on WAN (balanced/sensitive), drop known bads; DoS protections on.</li><li><strong>East-west noise</strong>: scope mDNS/SSDP to casting VLANs (mDNS repeater only where needed; block SSDP across VLANs).</li><li><strong>UPnP</strong>: disabled globally; if needed, scoped per-device/per-VLAN only.</li><li><strong>DHCP guard</strong>: DHCP allowed only from UDM-SE/authorized server; block rogue DHCP.</li><li><strong>Outbound hygiene</strong>: block risky ports (25 outbound except mail relay, 137–139/445 to Internet, etc.); optional country blocks.</li><li><strong>Logging</strong>: Unifi → syslog/Grafana; Cloudflare Zero Trust → dashboards (world-map of hits).</li><li><strong>Backups</strong>: nightly Unifi config export; change log kept “as code”.</li></ul><h1>Tailnet (Tailscale) management</h1><ul><li><strong>Mgmt gateway</strong> <code>tailscale-gw</code> (tag <code>mgmt-gw</code>) advertises only <strong>/32</strong> routes (no broad subnets).</li><li>Example <strong>allowed mgmt targets</strong> (over Tailnet only):<ul><li>PVE: <a href="http://10.10.1.80:8006"><strong>10.10.1.80:8006</strong></a></li><li>PBS: <a href="http://10.10.1.87:8007"><strong>10.10.1.87:8007</strong></a> and <a href="http://10.10.1.87:22"><strong>10.10.1.87:22</strong></a></li><li>iDRAC/ILO &amp; other consoles: <a href="http://10.10.1.67:443"><strong>10.10.1.67:443</strong></a>, <a href="http://10.10.1.99:443"><strong>10.10.1.99:443</strong></a></li></ul></li><li>Split-DNS: internal names like <code>pve.home.server</code>, <code>pbs.home.server</code>, etc., resolve to <strong>10.10.x.x</strong> via Pi-hole/Skyhole; MagicDNS off.</li></ul><h1>Pi-hole flow</h1><p>Clients in user VLANs → <strong>Pi-hole (10.10.10.55) / Skyhole (10.10.10.56)</strong> → <strong>Unbound + NextDNS</strong> → Internet; external FQDNs use Cloudflare Tunnel; <strong>Access + Authentik (OIDC + YubiKey)</strong> gates UIs; Tailnet ACLs restrict SSH/admin ports.</p><h1>Why this shape?</h1><ul><li><strong>Attack surface</strong>: Admin planes are not exposed at all. Public apps are <strong>identity-gated at the edge</strong>. No unauthenticated request reaches a service.</li><li><strong>Cred protection</strong>: WebAuthn/YubiKey significantly reduces phishing and credential stuffing risks.</li><li><strong>Op simplicity</strong>: Cloudflared keeps inbound closed; Tailscale “just works” for admin; step-ca gives painless internal TLS.</li><li><strong>Resilience</strong>: If Authentik is down, public logins pause but the apps keep running; admin still works through Tailscale.</li></ul><h1>What I didn’t do (and why)</h1><ul><li><strong>mTLS at Cloudflare</strong>: powerful, but requires the right plan/feature set. I get similar real-world value by (a) WebAuthn, (b) Access short sessions, and (c) private admin plane via Tailscale. If/when I upgrade, I’ll add client-cert checks as an extra ring.</li><li><strong>Exposing hypervisors</strong>: even behind Access, I prefer <strong>no edge exposure</strong> for hypervisors/backup/OOB.</li></ul><h1>Hardening choices (the fun bits)</h1><ul><li><strong>Cloudflare Access policies</strong><ul><li>Include: my user / group from Authentik OIDC.</li><li><strong>Session TTL short</strong> (e.g., 8h).</li><li>For Pi-hole, added a Cloudflare rule to redirect <code>/</code> → <code>/admin</code>.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Authentik</strong><ul><li><strong>WebAuthn required</strong>, OTP fallback.</li><li>Disable any legacy local login on the apps that support OIDC-only (e.g., Immich).</li></ul></li><li><strong>Caddy + step-ca</strong><ul><li>Caddy uses ACME with the step-ca <strong>ACME provisioner</strong>.</li><li>Internal FQDNs get proper certs; Caddy auto-renews.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Patching &amp; updates</strong><ul><li>Cloudflared and public-facing apps get <strong>regular updates</strong> (manual or a controlled watcher).</li><li>Core infra (IdP, reverse proxy, hypervisor) on a <strong>manual but frequent cadence</strong> to avoid breakage.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Backups &amp; test restores</strong><ul><li>Hypervisor level snapshots + off-box backups.</li><li>Tested restore path for Authentik, Caddy config, step-ca, and the cloudflared token.</li></ul></li></ul><h1>What this buys you (threat-based view)</h1><ul><li><strong>Bot noise &amp; opportunistic scans</strong> die at Cloudflare’s edge.</li><li><strong>Phishing/credential theft</strong> largely mitigated by WebAuthn for the public entry point.</li><li><strong>Privileged planes</strong> (PVE/PBS/iDRAC) are never reachable from the Internet, even with stolen cookies/tokens.</li><li><strong>TLS everywhere</strong> including inside, with cert hygiene handled by step-ca + Caddy.</li></ul><h1>What I’d improve next (nice-to-haves)</h1><ul><li><strong>Add client-cert (mTLS) at the edge</strong> when plan/features allow.</li><li><strong>SIEM hooks</strong> for Access/IdP logs → alerting.</li><li><strong>Service posture checks</strong> (e.g., device compliance claims) if the IdP supports it.</li></ul><h1>Internal TLS details</h1><ul><li><strong>CA</strong>: <code>step-ca</code> (private PKI) on <code>10.10.1.240</code>.</li><li><strong>Issuance</strong>: Caddy obtains certs via ACME from step-ca (using an ACME provisioner).</li><li><strong>Renewal</strong>: Caddy renews automatically before expiry; services behind Caddy always present fresh certs.</li><li><strong>Clients</strong>: Browsers trust the step-ca root (imported on my devices), so internal FQDNs are green-locked.</li></ul><h1>Notes on privacy vs. security trade-offs</h1><ul><li>I’m comfortable with Cloudflare in front for the <strong>public</strong> path because I value the WAF + Access gate more than running my own full edge stack.</li><li>Admin planes (hypervisor/backup) are <strong>not</strong> on Cloudflare at all; they’re <strong>Tailscale-only</strong>.</li></ul><h1>Tooling summary</h1><ul><li><strong>Edge</strong>: Cloudflare DNS, Cloudflare Tunnel (cloudflared), Cloudflare Access (Zero Trust).</li><li><strong>IdP</strong>: Authentik (OIDC), WebAuthn/YubiKey enforced.</li><li><strong>VPN</strong>: Tailscale for admin-only services.</li><li><strong>TLS</strong>: Caddy reverse proxy + step-ca private PKI for internal certificates.</li><li><strong>DNS</strong>: Unbound + NextDNS.</li><li><strong>Apps (examples)</strong>: Pi-hole x2, Immich, Portainer, Homepage, OctoPrint, Speedtest, Stream.</li></ul><p>Happy to answer questions or share specific JSON/policy snippets (scrubbed). If you’re building something similar: start by <strong>separating public and admin planes</strong>, enforce <strong>hardware-backed auth</strong> for anything public, then layer in <strong>internal TLS</strong> so you stop training your browser to accept self-signed certs.</p><p>Short version of the project.</p><p><strong>Goals</strong></p><ul><li>Keep admin planes (Proxmox VE - PVE and Proxmox Backup Server - PBS) off the public Internet.</li><li>Put Internet-facing apps behind Cloudflare Access with my own IdP (Authentik) and YubiKey (WebAuthn).</li><li>Simple, low maintenance, with good audit logs.</li></ul><p><strong>How it works (overview)</strong></p><ul><li><strong>DNS:</strong> All public subdomains on Cloudflare, proxied.</li><li><strong>Tunnel:</strong> Single <strong>cloudflared</strong> tunnel VM routes hostnames to internal services.</li><li><strong>Access:</strong> Cloudflare Access apps → <strong>OIDC</strong> to <strong>Authentik</strong> (YubiKey enforced). Short sessions (~30m).</li><li><strong>Sensitive admin (PVE/PBS):</strong> not published; I use <strong>Tailscale</strong> to reach LAN IPs remotely.</li><li><strong>Extras:</strong> Pi-hole has a Cloudflare Redirect Rule from <code>/</code> → <code>/admin</code>.</li></ul><p><strong>Diagram (sanitized)</strong></p><pre><code>[Internet]  | Cloudflare DNS (proxied)  | cloudflared Tunnel (VM)  |  +-- app1.domain.tld -&gt; http(s)://internal-host:port  +-- app2.domain.tld -&gt; http(s)://internal-host:port  ...  | Cloudflare Access (per-app)      |      +-- OIDC to Authentik (WebAuthn/YubiKey enforced)      +-- short sessions (e.g., 30m)Admin (not public):  Tailscale -&gt; PVE / PBS over LAN IPs</code></pre><p><strong>What I’m happy with</strong></p><ul><li>Clean separation: public apps are gated by Access+OIDC; admin stays private.</li><li>YubiKey enforced at the IdP; short Access sessions reduce “silent long-lived” cookies.</li><li>Easy to add new apps: clone one Access app, change hostname, done.</li></ul><p><strong>Trade-offs / questions</strong></p><ul><li>I considered <strong>mTLS</strong> at the edge for a “hardware cert” check, but Access mTLS looks Enterprise-only. Is anyone layering a free mTLS (e.g., origin Nginx mutual auth) with Access? Worth the complexity vs device posture/WARP?</li><li>I’m toying with adding an <strong>origin JWT check</strong> (validate <code>CF-Access-Jwt-Assertion</code> at the service) for defense-in-depth. Anyone doing this at scale for homelab?</li><li>Any pitfalls with Authentik + Cloudflare Access you’ve hit (silent SSO stickiness, session UX, etc.)?</li></ul><p><strong>Thanks!</strong> Suggestions and critiques welcome</p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/jopfxoshdypf1.jpg?width=3120&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f1194e7e65a553db71d84daaf7e7ef1d62961060">https://preview.redd.it/jopfxoshdypf1.jpg?width=3120&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f1194e7e65a553db71d84daaf7e7ef1d62961060</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I can&#39;t even login to my systems. i put the homelab on the roof so i can&#39;t reach it. #zerotrustgang</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/netu7l5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You don’t say what your apps are so I don’t know if this advice will apply, but most apps I’ve seen that support OIDC will retain local username/password based auth by default. If at all possible you should disable this, or block access to password auth URIs and force OIDC auth only. Immich for example allows you to disable password login entirely. </p><p>Also review any other paths that might be exploited like new user account creation pages, or password reset pages, that might be used to bypass OIDC auth. </p><p>Aside from auth-based attacks the next biggest threat is exploitation of know bugs, so you should have robust patching processes to make sure that you can update your apps promptly. I prefer fully automatic updates but there are downsides to this, such as unanticipated breaking changes. Again this depends on the app though. </p><p>Finally, robust backups with a fully tested restore process so if something does go wrong you can recover quickly.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/neucf5y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I like your setup (to the point that I’m ready to reconsider mine to mimic some of yours). </p><p>I’m part of the ones who thinks (while recognising it’s a bit futile) that having them being server through CloudFlare means reduced privacy. For now I use Pangolin as a replacement (and Pocket Id) but that means no powerful WAF hence lesser security but “higher” privacy. </p><p>I keep switching my opinion on whether it’s worth it or not.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/neu1i76/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I run 30 wordpress sites, plex, jellyfin, pihole, and a shoutcast server. I just unplug it when I&#39;m not using it that way nobody can access it. Works4me.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/neuiwx1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You might like OpenZiti: Zero Trust SDN<a href="https://github.com/openziti">https://github.com/openziti</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/neujsi0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you deploy your services in Kubernetes then you can use mtls via istio.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/netvg3k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>mTLS for cloudflare is actually free but its confusing because there are 2 ways to set it up. You have the mTLS option which requires an enterprise plan, then you have the client certificate option which is free. The way I understand it, you would use the mTLS option when you want to use a private or non cloudflare ca to setup mTLS then use the client certificate option when you want to use the cloudflare ca to setup mTLS. </p><p>Setting up the free option was pretty easy. All I had to do was generate my cert, downdload the file, install it on all my devices then setup a rule in the cloudflare dashboard to block all traffic without a valid cert. When I first visited my site a pop up appeared asking for a cert. Once I provided I was granted access to website. My browser remember my decison so I only had view the popup once. Now devices with certs can access my site while devices without them get blocked.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njxyn9/my_homelabs_zerotrust_edge_cloudflare_access/neusy0r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:10:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/4tfr95ekqspf1.png</link><title>Finally finished my Glance dashboard after a long time of tweaking and creating custom widgets. (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I used a bunch of already existing widgets, made custom widgets, etc. All the services I am hosting are here, essential data about server at the top. Daily info with a search bar to the right. Lastly, some rss feeds at the bottom and reddit on the left. What do you think? Is it good or needs some tweaks?</p><p>Edit: I&#39;ll never do &quot;send to DMs&quot; thing lol. Y&#39;all nuked my DMs. Here you go the Wastebin link for the config. I added theme settings in the comments at the top if you want to use it. Make sure to create a .env file with all the variables that are called in the parts/widgets you are using in your setup. Variables are the ones called with ${} for those who don&#39;t know.</p><p><a href="https://wastebin.spajky.dev/TCOSrWQJQin.yaml">glance.yml</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/4tfr95ekqspf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Fool! I&#39;m now going to use your cool layout to not only improve my own but also copy some of your software solutions!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/nes818r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Damn this is cool! Is there a way to copy this setup and make it my own?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/nestzbu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Looks fire, i like it. What do you use for bookmarks?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/nesa2ml/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>yours is da 2nd Glance page i have seen tonight.  great work.  makes me wanna redo mines as well...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/netn8i8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Looks really nice! Makes me want to set one up again. I just find myself not using it when I do.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/nesfkug/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Look so great! Just finished my Heimdall... It&#39;s so ridiculous compared to your Glance</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/nespnrm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Cool</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njqgyh/finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard_after_a_long/net3rlw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 03:24:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1njos09</link><title>Built my own server monitoring tool (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hi, </p><p>I wanted to make a dashboard / monitoring tool for my homelab but I didn&#39;t like those that were available and I wanted to create something interesting so I just decided to just do it myself. Basically it checks availability of my web services both by pinging an url and by checking if a matching process is running.</p><p>I wanted to by notified immediately so it also contains a discord integration that sends a message to my private channel if availability of any website changes.</p><p>I also added some fun hw monitoring tools like CPU / RAM usage, volume usage and also external temperature and humidity sensor (DHT22, bought it for like 5 bucks and wanted to try somehing hardwarish for my raspberry pi).</p><p>So far it&#39;s not dockerized, it only runs as a process via pm2. Do you like this project and would you be interested in running it, if I were to make it a docker container? Or contribute with some interesting ideas? It&#39;s open-source in and made Kotlin, you can find it here <a href="https://github.com/rex1234/vaponitor">https://github.com/rex1234/vaponitor</a></p><p>cheers</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/0eyhfekedspf1.png?width=2402&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=b8f3dd79d89cc1eaa7f277cdfbe26a28cd2b02ba" height="1540" width="2402" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/wn0w58kedspf1.png?width=2294&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=9b7075d4f8149946fdfd31adff4c88b197013473" height="1636" width="2294" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/18wobdledspf1.png?width=2483&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=026cdf9773da0995f92889afc2abfd47e6797235" height="1858" width="2483" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/6ec9s7kedspf1.png?width=985&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=f16496c16355d30edd0659cb901be15eb3ccd8d3" height="1606" width="985" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/bc1wt7kedspf1.png?width=2352&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=09f029e6267e28c1850ca4ee200f1dcc73fb59e9" height="1370" width="2352" /></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m curious why not build something off of readily available tools like prometheus + grafana? seems like a lot of work to build from scratch</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/nerx7j6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Beszel?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/nerw11z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><del>What’s that „vaporized“ thingy?</del></p><p>Duh ok.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/newdrtk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Looks interesting, another uptime kuma or gatus alternative.</p><p>Also, yeah dockerizing it might help with adoption as many people exclusively use (docker) containers, myself included.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/newvxkg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Looks very interesting do u need any help in dockerising the application</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njos09/built_my_own_server_monitoring_tool/netjvzd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:15:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1njon8x</link><title>I think I finally finished my Glance dashboard (Gallery)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I have been working on customizing my Glance setup and I think it is finally in a good place.</p><ul><li>One main page with some monitoring, internet favorites, and my self-hosted services</li><li>One media page</li><li>A mobile and tablet page (same as desktop but without the monitoring)</li><li>And one homepage page that I still need to finalize</li></ul><p>Thanks to the Reddit community for all the Glance setups shared here — they really helped me build mine in return. I still need to set up a GitHub repo so I can share my config as well.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/7xxh67kodspf1.png?width=2796&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=3044f9cdacc548646b3f481692712179c45d7f13" height="2066" width="2796" /></p><p><img src="https://preview.redd.it/g9hemckodspf1.png?width=2766&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=76bcb8fd259652b2aab67c89098e44aa7d0b1e26" height="2072" width="2766" /></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Seems good but I did not look closely. Just a glance.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/nert2yv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>been waiting for this post since the other day</p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/m2aehbi4gspf1.png?width=596&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c9a024841768810703cd1bc9f3d1dadaf6998d0a">https://preview.redd.it/m2aehbi4gspf1.png?width=596&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=c9a024841768810703cd1bc9f3d1dadaf6998d0a</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/nerujtp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>No you&#39;re not. You&#39;re never finished.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/net5g6b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I really like the custom widget system for glance, which is essentially just Go templates. I&#39;ve made some of my own custom widgets, one that takes multiple google calendar events and lists them in order (The existing community widget only allowed one calendar). Another, which I coincidentally just started and finished today, displays Kanbans and tasks from Todoist:</p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/84ftoalqhtpf1.png?width=3018&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=a74271f7fe1a942fe002a3d93c59d3c38f141fb9">https://preview.redd.it/84ftoalqhtpf1.png?width=3018&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=a74271f7fe1a942fe002a3d93c59d3c38f141fb9</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/nesx1uy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How did you do the F1 Next Race Info?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/nes0kio/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Damn, this looks great. I would love the config for this</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/nerta9p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Aw look, an optimist! They think they’re finished 🥹</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njon8x/i_think_i_finally_finished_my_glance_dashboard/nevr1kw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:10:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/x85efw7c6spf1.png</link><title>PlexAniBridge - Plex to AniList synchronization (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge">https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge</a><br/>Docs: <a href="https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org">https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org</a></p><p>Hello all, this is an announcement for PlexAniBridge, a tool I developed to synchronize your Plex media server with your AniList profile. Even if you don&#39;t use Plex or AniList, you might find the <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings">mappings database</a> this project spawned interesting.</p><p>So, I built this project because I wanted my Plex watch progress and AniList to stay in sync without manual effort - which is why I spent the last year working on something to save me a couple of minutes of effort. Anyways, I also wanted to avoid the pitfalls the existing solutions have - they either rely on fragile title search, require manual AniList to Plex mappings, or are overly simplistic and miss out on a lot of useful fields. This fixes all of that, and a lot more.</p><p>PlexAniBridge runs alongside your Plex server and keeps AniList and Plex aligned: watch status, episode progress, started/completed dates, ratings, reviews, watchlists, rewatch counts, etc. It&#39;s very customizable; it can be conservative, aggressive, or destructive if you explicitly opt in.</p><p>First of all, arguably the most impressive feature of PlexAniBridge is its <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings">curated anime mappings database</a> (shoutout to <a href="https://github.com/LuceoEtzio">Luceo</a> for contributing to so much of the mappings 🤲). This database is a separate repository that contains mappings for, as of September 17, 2025, 19,916 AniList entires. For context the entire AniList database only has <a href="https://anilist.co/site-stats">~21K</a> entries. That&#39;s 94.8% coverage! The coverage is so great that title-based fuzzy search is disabled by default (but can be opted-in). In fact, my personal library has 99.98% coverage; the kicker? That stat is for episode/movie coverage - not entire shows/seasons. Yes, 99.98% of my EPISODES are mapped to AniList, including special seasons. Okay, I just had to nerd-out about that. Thank you again to Luceo on GitHub for the awesome work on this database.</p><h1>Core features</h1><ul><li>Multi-profile: you can setup multiple profiles with dozens of distinct settings and customization (maybe too much); sync different Plex servers, libraries, and accounts to different AniList users</li><li>Sync modes: you can do interval-based scans, poll for changes, or use Plex webhooks for instant updates; or any combination of those</li><li>Per-field control: Exclude any fields (e.g. score or notes) from being synced to AniList if you want to keep them separate</li><li>Web UI: there&#39;s a really nice web UI to look at sync history, stats, and manage mappings (unfortunately no web UI for configuration yet, but it&#39;s coming, hopefully)</li><li>Automatic AniList backups (JSON snapshots) + included restore functionallity through the UI or a CLI script</li><li>Undo: every sync operation is recorded with before/after state; selected operations can be undone via the UI</li><li>Custom mappings: add or override mappings through the UI or by dropping JSON files in the data dir</li><li>Smart matching: Uses a curated anime mappings DB first. Title search fallback is disabled by default; you can turn it on and control how strict (0–100 similarity threshold)</li><li>Local vs &quot;online&quot; Plex metadata mode: honestly, this feature isn&#39;t that stable, but I thought I&#39;d mention it since it&#39;s helped some users before; online mode can be used to query the Plex metadata server for when data in your local Plex server is incomplete or missing</li><li>Dockerized: easy to deploy, minimal dependencies, single container</li><li>More features to come 🔥</li></ul><h1>Nerd stuff</h1><p>Skip this if you don&#39;t care about the nitty-gritty or if you&#39;re not a nerd like me :-)</p><ul><li>Python (FastAPI + SQLAlchemy + async stack), Svelte frontend (served as a static SPA)</li><li>SQLite for internal state and history tracking</li><li>Caching layers: very intelligent caching to memoize and minimize API calls to AniList and Plex</li><li>Rate limit handling: automatic retries with backoff for AniList API limits (seriously how is it still 30 / minute in 2025)</li></ul><h1>Links</h1><ul><li>Repo: <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge">https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge</a></li><li>Docs: <a href="https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org">https://plexanibridge.elias.eu.org</a></li><li>Mappings DB: <a href="https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings">https://github.com/eliasbenb/PlexAniBridge-Mappings</a></li><li>Discord (chat/help): <a href="https://discord.gg/ey8kyQU9aD">https://discord.gg/ey8kyQU9aD</a></li></ul><p>Note: this project is intended for use with the official Plex Metadata agents. Third-party agents (e.g. HAMA) are not supported and may lead to unexpected behavior.</p><p>If this scratches the same itch for you, spin it up, run a dry run, and see if your list settles into shape. Now, fire away with questions.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/x85efw7c6spf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>On the state of the mappings database: as of my most recent pass through of checks, there are only a fairly low double digit amount of TV or ONA entries from a franchise where at least one franchise member has greater than 5k users on Anilist which are not fully covered by the mappings, and primarily because of source database (TVDB) incompletion (and often locked entries as well), or outright not being present.</p><p>That is to say, if it&#39;s not a special, and it&#39;s even remotely popular, there&#39;s a quite literal 99%+ chance it just works™.</p><p>My own personal library (~12k episodes) has a total episode coverage of 99.56% for episodes that are actually candidates to be synced (discluding recaps and other things not covered by anilist), and a 100% coverage for non-special episodes (barring one single show which is intentionally unmapped for technical reasons)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/nes90m1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Awesome I was looking for something to replace plexanisync</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/nesl1q9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The mappings database here rules. I keep having issues with Kometa not matching properly, and I’d love for them to work in tandem with yours tbh.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/net1n86/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is really cool and almost makes me wish I didn&#39;t use Crunchyroll.  But I do.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njnrzn/plexanibridge_plex_to_anilist_synchronization/nex624g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:36:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/zml26e8owppf1.png</link><title>Self-hosted Start Page - Flame (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I found this start-page that can be self-hosted in a Docker container, and so far I love it! I have it set as the home page in Firefox, but I wish I could also set it as the new-tab page. Sometimes I forget all the hostnames and ports for all my various containers, and this makes it so I no longer need to remember them.</p><p>They use the Material-Design-Icons from Google. That icon repository does contain some brand-specific icons, but for the others I had to do some searching online for specific SVGs. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/zml26e8owppf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>[...] but I wish I could also set it as the new-tab page</p></blockquote><p>You can do so. This addon should exactly do what you want: <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/new-tab-override/">https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/new-tab-override/</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/nepa87a/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>IIRC flame hasn’t been updated in a while?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/nep3thp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>since flame hasn&#39;t been updated in 2 years. Consider using <a href="https://github.com/fdarveau/flame">https://github.com/fdarveau/flame</a> instead. I used this for the longest time but have since switched to homepage.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/nepeyq2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There are browser add-ons that can establish your wish. For example: <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/new-tab-homepage/">Link</a>.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/nepay7g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>lmao at the people in this thread trying to bash op for not running bleeding edge node runtime in his closed instance</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/nerelxj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I prefer using Glance as a start page: <a href="https://github.com/glanceapp/glance/tree/v0.8.4">https://github.com/glanceapp/glance/tree/v0.8.4</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/nertjux/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Shopping is just Amazon and Curaleaf? 😏</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1njbyi7/selfhosted_start_page_flame/nesmwu4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:07:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</link><title>Plex Breached 2025-09-09: "Action required: Notice of a potential security incident"</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Thanks <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/LeftBus3319">/u/LeftBus3319</a> + <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/FnnKnn">/u/FnnKnn</a></p><ol><li><p><a href="https://plex.tv/reset">Reset your Plex account password immediately</a>, making sure to check &quot;Sign out connected devices after password change&quot;</p></li><li><p>To <a href="https://support.plex.tv/articles/204281528-why-am-i-locked-out-of-server-settings-and-how-do-i-get-in/">reclaim your server</a> you can use SSH Tunneling to get access to <em>your server&#39;s</em> localhost:32400 on your <em>personal</em> host with <code>ssh -L 32400:localhost:32400 serverUser@serverHost</code> - <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd62qn0/">link</a></p></li></ol><hr/><p>Announcement page:<a href="https://links.plex.tv/s/vb/Vn7XtnwDSSaqqDUYoHu1P57ZgZ1FsHgTO2PTIBl6jEOUiHBH3LGmI3nLdDfopQa54PatUwZQhT0Bz8rKAi--jTM4ATdsBHpe4c1Yljr89VkoCOavEGH5wn5Fi_filLNeOMo-lnNqLSLpJpI/lOe98S8UWKdmPnp9StQz9R1-kOSTpWhr/12">https://links.plex.tv/s/vb/Vn7XtnwDSSaqqDUYoHu1P57ZgZ1FsHgTO2PTIBl6jEOUiHBH3LGmI3nLdDfopQa54PatUwZQhT0Bz8rKAi--jTM4ATdsBHpe4c1Yljr89VkoCOavEGH5wn5Fi_filLNeOMo-lnNqLSLpJpI/lOe98S8UWKdmPnp9StQz9R1-kOSTpWhr/12</a></p><p>Announcement screenshot:<a href="https://i.imgur.com/0PMRvVY.png">https://i.imgur.com/0PMRvVY.png</a></p><blockquote><p>Dear Plex User,</p><p>We have recently experienced a security incident that may potentially involve your Plex account information. We believe the actual impact of this incident is limited; however, action is required from you to ensure your account remains secure.</p><p>What happened</p><p>An unauthorized third party accessed a limited subset of customer data from one of our databases. While we quickly contained the incident, information that was accessed included emails, usernames, and securely hashed passwords.</p><p>Any account passwords that may have been accessed were securely hashed, in accordance with best practices, meaning they cannot be read by a third party. Out of an abundance of caution, we recommend you immediately reset your password by visiting <a href="https://plex.tv/reset">https://plex.tv/reset</a>. Rest assured that we do not store credit card data on our servers, so this information was not compromised in this incident.</p><p>What we&#39;re doing</p><p>We&#39;ve already addressed the method that this third party used to gain access to the system, and we&#39;re undergoing additional reviews to ensure that the security of all of our systems is further hardened to prevent future attacks.</p><p>What you must do</p><p>We kindly request that you reset your Plex account password immediately by visiting <a href="https://plex.tv/reset">https://plex.tv/reset</a>. When doing so, there&#39;s a checkbox to &quot;Sign out connected devices after password change,&quot; which we recommend you enable. This will sign you out of all your devices (including any Plex Media Server you own) for your security, and you will then need to sign back in with your new password. We understand that this means a little more work for you, but it will provide additional security to your account.</p><p>Additional Security Measures You Can TakeWe remind you that no one at Plex will ever reach out to you over email to ask for a password or credit card number for payments. For further account protection, we also recommend enabling two-factor authentication on your Plex account if you haven’t already done so.</p><p>Lastly, we sincerely apologize for any inconvenience this situation may cause you. We take pride in our security systems, which helped us quickly detect this incident, and we want to assure you that we are working swiftly to prevent potential future incidents from occurring.</p><p>For step-by-step instructions on how to reset your password, visit: <a href="https://support.plex.tv/articles/account-requires-password-reset">https://support.plex.tv/articles/account-requires-password-reset</a></p><p>Thank you,</p><p>The Plex Team</p></blockquote></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Going to use this sticky now to remind users that when invalidating your Plex sessions, this will break companion apps and to get a <a href="https://docs.wizarr.dev/plex/obtain-a-plex-token">new token</a> for things like Over/Jellyseerr, Wizarr, Tautulli.</p><hr/><p>TLDR: <a href="https://plex.tv/reset">Reset your Plex account password immediately</a>, making sure to check &quot;Sign out connected devices after password change&quot;</p><p>To <a href="https://support.plex.tv/articles/204281528-why-am-i-locked-out-of-server-settings-and-how-do-i-get-in/">reclaim your server</a> you can use SSH Tunneling to get access to <em>your server&#39;s</em> localhost:32400 on your <em>personal</em> host with <code>ssh -L 32400:localhost:32400 serverUser@serverHost</code></p><p>Edit: some clarification on ssh tunnel example provided</p><hr/><p><a href="https://www.plexopedia.com/plex-media-server/general/claim-server/#claimservermanually">Community resource if you are having trouble claiming your server again</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd62qn0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I didn’t get an email. Interesting.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd5rt4g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I wish services would instead invalidate all affected accounts and auto log them out of all devices. Then users would be forced to reset their passwords for security.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd5recl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Please use a blockquote, not code formatting.  Scrolling a box horizontally is an awful reading experience.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd65757/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is why Plex needs to put authentication in the hands of the end user. If we can serve up streaming video we can handle a few kilobits of authentication data. Auth isn’t the clusterfuck it used to be. Nor is encryption. We have services like let’s encrypt now. </p><p>Give me my fucking control back.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd5y7no/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you login to Plex with Google how does this impact?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd6t1hi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In the chance that people had extreme difficulties claiming server, as I did, and my reply is deep in the comments....I FINALLY reclaimed my server manually by following instructions here under &quot;Claiming your server manually&quot; <a href="https://www.plexopedia.com/plex-media-server/general/claim-server/#:%7E:text=Open%20a%20Web%20browser%20and,Copy%20this%20token.&amp;text=Replace%20%7Bprocessed_machine_identifier%7D%20with%20the%20value,token%20from%20the%20Web%20page">https://www.plexopedia.com/plex-media-server/general/claim-server/#:~:text=Open%20a%20Web%20browser%20and,Copy%20this%20token.&amp;text=Replace%20%7Bprocessed_machine_identifier%7D%20with%20the%20value,token%20from%20the%20Web%20page</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1nc0hto/plex_breached_20250909_action_required_notice_of/nd6wjcw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 03:00:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</link><title>Welcome to /r/SelfHosted! Please Read This First</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><h1>Welcome to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted">/r/selfhosted</a>!</h1><p>We thank you for taking the time to check out the subreddit here! </p><h2>Self-Hosting</h2><p>The concept in which you host your own applications, data, and more. Taking away the &quot;unknown&quot; factor in how your data is managed and stored, this provides those with the willingness to learn and the mind to do so to take control of their data without losing the functionality of services they otherwise use frequently. </p><h2>Some Examples</h2><p>For instance, if you use dropbox, but are not fond of having your most sensitive data stored in a data-storage container that you do not have direct control over, you may consider NextCloud</p><p>Or let&#39;s say you&#39;re used to hosting a blog out of a Blogger platform, but would rather have your own customization and flexibility of controlling your updates? Why not give WordPress a go. </p><p>The possibilities are endless and it all starts here with a server. </p><h2>Subreddit Wiki</h2><p>There have been varying forms of a wiki to take place. While currently, there is no <em>officially</em> hosted wiki, we do have a <a href="https://github.com/r-selfhosted/wiki">github repository</a>. There is also at least one unofficial mirror that showcases the live version of that repo, listed on the index of the <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki">reddit-based wiki</a></p><h2>Since You&#39;re Here...</h2><p>While you&#39;re here, take a moment to get acquainted with our few but important <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/wiki/rules">rules</a></strong></p><p>And if you&#39;re into Discord, <a href="https://discord.gg/UrZKzYZfcS">join here</a></p><p>When posting, please apply an appropriate flair to your post. If an appropriate flair is not found, please let us know! If it suits the sub and doesn&#39;t fit in another category, we will get it added! <strong><a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fselfhosted">Message the Mods</a></strong> to get that started.</p><p>If you&#39;re brand new to the sub, we highly recommend taking a moment to browse a couple of our awesome self-hosted and system admin tools lists.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/Kickball/awesome-selfhosted">Awesome Self-Hosted App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/n1trux/awesome-sysadmin">Awesome Sys-Admin App List</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/veggiemonk/awesome-docker">Awesome Docker App List</a></p><p>In any case, lot&#39;s to take in, lot&#39;s to learn. Don&#39;t be disappointed if you don&#39;t catch on to any given aspect of self-hosting right away. We&#39;re available to help! </p><p>As always, happy (self)hosting!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Really nice introductory post, thanks!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/eopu4xd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hello, I&#39;m new to the whole self-hosting scene, I have an ubuntu server with php, mysql, and apache2, and bookstack installed on it. I&#39;m not really sure how to go about installing other applications alongside of it, does anyone have any tips or could point me in a direction of where I can learn more about this?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/eqxf0er/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>new welcome message? what did we do to deserve this spot of loveliness</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/eoqp2cs/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Moderators, how can new services be added to the list?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/ewf18f1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Why do I have to look at this face everday?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/f1dzdie/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Is there any post which talks about how to get started with self-hosting and what hardware to use for a beginner?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/jj3gcsi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Great stuff, thanks</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/bsp01i/welcome_to_rselfhosted_please_read_this_first/ib11us3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 06:59:15 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
