<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=economics&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;comments=3&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/economics</title><description>Hot posts in /r/economics (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 20:34:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>https://www.redditstatic.com/mweb2x/favicon/76x76.png</url><title>/r/economics</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link></image><item><link>https://www.yahoo.com/finance/news/jerome-powell-signs-ai-bubble-222907233.html</link><title>Jerome Powell on signs of an AI bubble and an economy leaning too hard on the rich: ‘Unusually large amounts of economic activity’ (yahoo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/jieZtutcDvWMWMyeKbQZxA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA-/https://media.zenfs.com/en/fortune_175/4772e2b05c84a3985c4e5a83cb6ef5ec' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>start your watches</p><p>Alan Greenspan&#39;s famous &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; comment was made on December 5, 1996, during a speech at the American Enterprise Institute. The dot-com crash is widely recognized as beginning when the Nasdaq Composite peaked on March 10, 2000, before entering a sharp decline.</p><p>There were about 3 years and 3 months (approximately 39 months) between Greenspan&#39;s &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; speech and the peak that marked the start of the dot-com crash.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nev4nbh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Given so much of the economy is now the top 10%, if we do see a stock market correction, I think the actual change in GDP will be greater than previous corrections. </p><p>Why? Because the rich own most of the stocks and will feel poorer. Their spending is mostly discretionary. They dont need most of anything they buy. They just wont spend it. </p><p>Before when the stock market declined, it didn&#39;t affect consumption nearly as much. Workers just kept spending and didn&#39;t even look at their 401k if they had it. </p><p>Now you&#39;ve got to please this top 10% and if you dont they wont keep propping up the economy single handedly. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/neuhq6k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Every American is a momentarily embarrassed millionaire&quot; is the greatest con perpetuated upon the ethos of USA. The degree to which the poors and working class vote against their own interests never ceases to amaze. The farmers seem to not be enjoying the finding out part. Anyways...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/neuc9b2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:05:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/15/business/chinas-snub-of-us-soybeans-is-a-crisis-for-american-farmers.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mE8.owWy.o4cddSKR3fwk</link><title>China’s Snub of U.S. Soybeans Is a Crisis for American Farmers (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Oh it’s a “crisis” for the people that voted for the guy that said he would do this? The same people that won’t say that they regret their vote? </p><p>That’s not a crisis. It’s a result they voted for.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netjia6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We are now getting to the &quot;finding out&quot; phase after &quot;fucking around&quot;. We&#39;re in for a world of economic hurt, and Trump his &quot;yes men&quot; are all to blame. Plenty of economists warned against this, but I&#39;m sure we&#39;ll hear the usual &quot;how could we have known&quot; responses from Trump et. al.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netkgu7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They wanted this just like last time. Not like it matters. Apparently Brazil has filled the soybean orders for China and by next year they will have replaced American contracts. </p><p>The soybean farmers will move to other crops and what will happen will be an increase in competition for cash crops as more of them switch over causing profitability concerns.</p><p>None of this will translate to cheaper &quot;soybeans&quot; at the super market in America. Because of capitalism, they rather let it rot and lose money than condition you to accept cheaper products</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netn1ey/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:02:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nbcnews.com/business/economy/federal-reserve-interest-rates-decision-rcna231729</link><title>Federal Reserve cuts interest rates for the first time this year (nbcnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630,f_auto,q_auto:best/rockcms/2025-08/250822-Jerome-Powell-ew-1152a-b4625a.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><section><p><time>Sept. 17, 2025, 6:00 AM EDT<span>&nbsp;/&nbsp;</span>Updated&nbsp;Sept. 17, 2025, 3:13 PM EDT</time></p></section><div><p>The Federal Reserve announced a highly anticipated interest rate cut Wednesday, a move indicating that concerns about a slowing labor market now outweigh ongoing worries about inflation.</p><p>It's the Fed's first rate cut this year. Policymakers opted for a quarter-point cut to the central bank's benchmark rate, in line with expectations. It's now set at 4% to 4.25%.</p><p>"The labor market is really cooling off," Fed Chair Jerome Powell said at a news conference Wednesday after the announcement. </p><p>The Trump administration has mounted an unprecedented pressure campaign that has included attacks on Powell for not lowering rates sooner, as well as an effort to unseat a Biden-era Fed appointee over accusations of mortgage fraud. </p><p>But Powell and the Fed had resisted Trump's pressure, saying its dual mandate of keeping both unemployment and inflation low meant it needed to be careful not to overheat the economy and risk a return to rapidly rising prices.</p><p>"We&rsquo;ve done very large rate hikes and very large rate cuts in the last five years, and you tend to do those at a time when you feel that policy is out of place and needs to move quickly to a new place," Powell said. "That&rsquo;s not at all what I feel."</p><p>The vote for the quarter-point cut by the Fed's rate-setting committee was 11 to 1. The sole dissenter, in favor of a larger half-point cut, was<strong> </strong>newly appointed governor Stephen Miran. He was sworn in this week even as he maintains his title as chair of the White House&rsquo;s Council of Economic Advisers, though he is officially on leave from that role.</p><p>President Donald Trump's two other appointed governors, Michelle Bowman and Christopher Waller, both voted for the quarter-point cut.</p><p>In its statement Wednesday, the Fed indicated it expects two more rate cuts this year. However, seven of the 12 officials on the Fed's rate-cutting committee indicated that rates should remain unchanged for the rest of the year. </p><p>The committee will meet again in October and December.<strong> </strong></p><p>The labor market appears to be slowing dramatically.<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/economy/august-2025-jobs-report-how-many-which-industries-what-to-know-rcna228780"> August&rsquo;s jobs report showed</a> that just 22,000 jobs were added, far below economists&rsquo; expectations. That report also showed that the United States lost jobs in June. So far this year, the economy has added 598,000 jobs, compared with 1.4 million for the first eight months of 2024. The unemployment rate also ticked higher last month, to 4.3%, a level not seen since September 2017 outside of the Covid-19 pandemic.</p><p>At the news conference, Powell called the labor market &ldquo;unusual,&rdquo; noting that fewer firms are hiring &mdash; but that the available supply of workers is also declining because of Trump&rsquo;s immigration crackdown. </p><p>Lower rates could help businesses hire as it becomes less expensive to take out loans and credit card rates fall for consumers.</p><p>At the same time, inflation has been creeping up. Since April, when Trump announced his sweeping &ldquo;reciprocal&rdquo; tariffs,<a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/CPIAUCSL#"> inflation has increased</a> from 2.3% to 2.9% in August. The Fed&rsquo;s inflation target is 2%.</p><p>Fed officials said in a separate set of economic projections that they see two additional quarter-point rate cuts this year and a third in 2026. </p><p>&ldquo;After weak July and August employment reports and<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/business/economy/911000-fewer-jobs-created-april-2024-march-2025-bls-says-rcna230065"> a large negative preliminary benchmark revision</a>, job growth now appears to be much lower and below the breakeven rate, the risks still tilt toward further negative revisions, the unemployment rate has risen slightly for two months in a row, and our broader measure of labor market slack has risen a bit more,&rdquo; Goldman Sachs economists wrote.</p></div></div><div><div><p>Heading into Wednesday,<a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/markets/interest-rates/cme-fedwatch-tool.html"> markets were pricing</a> in a high likelihood of a total of three-quarters of a percentage point in cuts by the end of the year.</p><p>In recent interviews and earnings calls, companies have also flagged slower spending by a large chunk of the population.</p><p>McDonald&rsquo;s CEO Chris Kempczinski called it a &ldquo;two-tier economy&rdquo; in a CNBC<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/video/2025/09/02/mcdonaldas-ceo-middle-and-lower-income-consumers-are-under-a-lot-of-pressure-right-now.html"> interview this month.</a> While upper-income households continue to spend freely, &ldquo;middle- and lower-income consumers, they&rsquo;re feeling under a lot of pressure right now.&rdquo;</p><p>Several prominent economists aren&rsquo;t convinced a Fed cut is warranted at this point. Joseph Gagnon, a senior fellow at the Peterson Institute for International Economics, noted last month that inflation was still lingering above the Fed&rsquo;s 2% target even before Trump&rsquo;s tariffs. &ldquo;Price pressures are likely to pick up in coming months as businesses are forced to pass on higher tariff costs to protect their profit margins,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Stock markets are thriving, too.</p><p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not unprecedented for the Fed to ease when stocks are at or near all-time highs,&rdquo; JPMorgan Chase chief U.S. economist Michael Feroli said in early August. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s rarer when stocks are at the highs and inflation is above target and inflecting higher.&rdquo;</p><p>This Fed meeting is also the first with Miran, the newly confirmed governor, who joins the Fed under highly unusual circumstances. Members of the independent central bank historically haven&rsquo;t held other outside roles during their tenures. Miran is on unpaid leave from the economic advisers council and could return to the White House when his Fed term concludes at the end of January. The administration has sought to downplay the arrangement.</p><p>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t think there&rsquo;s anything irregular about it at all,&rdquo; Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent said Tuesday on CNBC.</p><p>&ldquo;Everyone knows that he&rsquo;s going back&rdquo; to the White House, &ldquo;so I think cards on the table it&rsquo;s actually much more transparent,&rdquo; Bessent added.</p><p>The Trump administration has sought to further increase its influence on the Fed by trying to fire Lisa Cook, the first Black woman to work on the board of governors, over allegations of mortgage fraud. Cook hasn&rsquo;t been charged with a crime. An appeals court has ruled she can&rsquo;t be removed while she sues the administration over its attempt to terminate her. For now, Cook remains in place.</p><p>It all comes after months of attacks from Trump. Seeking lower rates, he and others in his administration have hammered Powell with personal insults and have said the entire Fed board should be &ldquo;ashamed&rdquo; of its work.</p><p>But Powell has maintained that the Fed must remain cautious.</p><p>"We&rsquo;ve seen much more challenging economic times, but from a policy standpoint ... it&rsquo;s challenging to know what to do," Powell said Wednesday. "There are no risk-free paths." </p></div><div><div><p><span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/author/steve-kopack-ncpn387336">Steve Kopack</a></span></p><p>Steve Kopack is a senior reporter at NBC News covering business and the economy.</p></div><div><p><span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/author/rob-wile-ncpn1293609">Rob Wile</a></span></p><p>Rob Wile is a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist covering breaking business stories for NBCNews.com.</p></div><div><p>Brian Cheung</p><p>contributed</p><p>.</p></div></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_focal-60x60,f_auto,q_auto:best/newscms/2024_51/3672748/steve_kopack.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_focal-60x60,f_auto,q_auto:best/newscms/2022_13/3544534/xyndgjrf_400x400.jpeg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Is this likely to really have any meaningful ramifications on employment? To me it seems like business are not hiring or planning investments because of policy uncertainty, not because high interest rates are preventing them from doing so.</p><p>It&#39;s the wrong medicine for the underlying disease. I feel like the employment issues gave them the narrative to cut despite inflation. They have to try and get yields down to refinance their debt burden.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqz8lm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Inflation has increased some and is higher than the <a href="https://www.cbo.gov/publication/60870">2.1%</a> CBO projected for this year back in January...but also job growth has slowed dramatically. So it&#39;s not the easiest decision. They decided the risk from a decidely more negative economic outlook surpasses the inflation risk. Never mind that long sought after 2% target.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/ner3x4s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This was basically the only thing to do based on data I suppose.</p><p>The labor market is cooling down and has been this entire year, and while inflation is obviously going up, the unemployment and the economy was the bigger issue for the Fed.</p><p>In an ideal world, the Fed would have cut rates without having to worry about inflation and not because the market was cooling down and had to be saved, but because it was a stable time and they could just look forward.</p><p>Instead.....sigh.</p><p>Anyway, if the people were complaining about inflation last year.....lol.</p><p>What&#39;s funny is that I don&#39;t see even half the cries about inflation now in the media like they did in 2024 with Biden, even though pretty much everything has very noticeably increased and will increase even more. The media environment is so bad that if the same media existed in the 70s, Nixon would never have had to resign. Which of course was the point of Roger Ailes creating Fox News, so his dream came true.</p><p>I sometimes wonder if Trump isn&#39;t just a Russian asset, but also a Democrat asset, because he&#39;s doing everything in his power to ruin the GOP for a generation a la Herbert Hoover lmao. Not that it will happen, people love their parties like its their family dynasty.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqvves/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:36:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.fastcompany.com/91405390/u-s-credit-scores-suffer-largest-two-year-drop-since-great-recession</link><title>U.S. credit scores suffers largest 2-year drop since Great Recession (fastcompany.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The new national average is 715, down from 718 two years ago, as household debt climbs and inflation bites.</p><p>The data also shows that compared with 2021, more Americans are falling into the low and high ends of the credit score range rather than the middle. In 2021, 38% of scores were between 600 and 749; in 2025, that percentage is 33.8%. The highest FICO score is 850.</p><p>U.S. borrowers continue to grapple with high interest rates, a side effect of the Federal Reserve’s efforts to rein in the soaring post-pandemic inflation that’s driving high prices. In spite of those efforts—and with rate cuts imminent—President Trump’s tariffs are pushing inflation up yet again, making the cost of gas, groceries, clothes, and other essentials even less affordable. </p><p>“The recent K-shaped economy has led to financial stress for some borrowers impacted by affordability concerns stemming from inflation and higher interest rates, while others have benefited from increases in their stock market portfolios and home price appreciation,” the FICO report states. That data reflects America’s wealth gap, wherein the rich get richer and the poor get poorer, hollowing out the middle class in the process.</p><p>Falling credit scores among young people are linked to resumed student loan delinquency reporting, which reappeared on credit reports in February for the first time after the CARES Act. While only 17% of the broader U.S. population is still paying down a student loan, that percentage is 34% for Gen Z. It’s no surprise then that 14% of Gen Zers had a 50-point score drop in the last year, with late student loan payments hitting their credit reports for the first time.</p><p>For people in the U.S distant from the stock market’s highs, the economy is starting to feel like America during a very different era—a malaise backed by the new data. “Delinquency rates on auto loans, credit cards, and personal loans are at or near their highest levels since 2009, during the Great Recession—and are more consistent with an economy in recession than one still in expansion,” the FICO report states.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/neob80n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I don’t know enough about credit scoring in aggregate, but wouldn’t this be a sign that we are already underway an economic event? Scores fluctuate with 30, 60, and 90 day delinquencies and defaults, along with high balances being carried over? Doesn’t seem like it’s a good indicator of economic health.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/nepp69y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s down 3 points in 2 years. The range is 300-850, or 550 points. The average score is down 0.55% of the range. In other words, a 3 point change over 2 years is hardly concerning. Also, we should consider that the way credit scores are calculated isn&#39;t publicly available. These private companies have most likely tweaked their scoring systems.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/nept2ud/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:44:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wsj.com/economy/jobs/fired-bls-chief-breaks-silence-calls-her-dismissal-a-dangerous-step-7e3a6a86?mod=mhp</link><title>Fired BLS Chief Breaks Silence, Calls Her Dismissal a ‘Dangerous Step’ (wsj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nixp9j/fired_bls_chief_breaks_silence_calls_her/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nixp9j/fired_bls_chief_breaks_silence_calls_her/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nixp9j/fired_bls_chief_breaks_silence_calls_her/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><ol><li><p>She still has trust in the data and the process. </p></li><li><p>She was attempting to modernize the data collection and process (she helped at Census do this), but was facing hiring issues, budget issues, and response rate issues for years, before the firing.</p></li><li><p>My hypothesis is that late responses in this economic environment will be negative, and we will continue to see negative revisions for quite some time.</p></li></ol></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nixp9j/fired_bls_chief_breaks_silence_calls_her/nem861y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And because people like to free ride and demand a subsidy, here is the gift link.</p><p><a href="https://www.wsj.com/economy/jobs/fired-bls-chief-breaks-silence-calls-her-dismissal-a-dangerous-step-7e3a6a86?st=3VtGvj&amp;reflink=desktopwebshare_permalink">https://www.wsj.com/economy/jobs/fired-bls-chief-breaks-silence-calls-her-dismissal-a-dangerous-step-7e3a6a86?st=3VtGvj&amp;reflink=desktopwebshare_permalink</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nixp9j/fired_bls_chief_breaks_silence_calls_her/nem8kb7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 05:16:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/africa/forex-dollar-sinks-four-year-low-vs-euro-ahead-fed-rate-decision-2025-09-16/</link><title>Dollar sinks to four-year low vs euro ahead of Fed rate decision (reuters.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ninmfv/dollar_sinks_to_fouryear_low_vs_euro_ahead_of_fed/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ninmfv/dollar_sinks_to_fouryear_low_vs_euro_ahead_of_fed/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ninmfv/dollar_sinks_to_fouryear_low_vs_euro_ahead_of_fed/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>it is impossible to overstate what an absolute blunder in economic policy this is - and it seems that the prevailing political party has forgone their responsibility to oversee policy to a man whose economics professor <a href="https://www.dailykos.com/stories/2017/10/12/1705902/-Former-Wharton-Professor-Donald-Trump-Is-the-Dumbest-Goddam-Student-I-Ever-Had">referred to</a> as: &quot;Donald Trump Was the Dumbest Goddam Student I Ever Had.&quot;</p><p>it all seriousness, it is impossible to square these policies unless you add a huge portion of either sheer stupidity or malevolence.</p><ul><li>DRIVE INFLATION UP WITH TARIFFS</li><li>DRIVE INFLATION VIA MASSIVE DEPORTATIONS</li><li>DEMAND LOWER INTEREST RATES</li><li>REAL INTEREST RATES (NOMINAL-INFLATION) COLLAPSE</li><li>DOLLAR COLLAPSES</li><li>EXPORTS CHEAPER FOR OTHER COUNTRIES</li><li>IMPOSSIBLE TO REFINANCE DEBT</li></ul></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ninmfv/dollar_sinks_to_fouryear_low_vs_euro_ahead_of_fed/nel6emt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is all according to this administration’s plan. They are aimed at selling more goods abroad so those at the top gain more wealth. All while the bottom 95% lose purchasing power, can no longer afford imported goods, and cost of imported raw materials goes up escalating what little domestically manufactured goods go up along with it so domestic goods are even unaffordable here.</p><p>We’re cooked. I’m headed to SE Asia while I have the chance 🫡</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ninmfv/dollar_sinks_to_fouryear_low_vs_euro_ahead_of_fed/nekkf64/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 22:48:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/economics/article/3325666/south-korea-trumps-us350-billion-demand-threatens-financial-meltdown</link><title>In South Korea, Trump’s US$350 billion demand threatens financial meltdown (scmp.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nij4la/in_south_korea_trumps_us350_billion_demand/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nij4la/in_south_korea_trumps_us350_billion_demand/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nij4la/in_south_korea_trumps_us350_billion_demand/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/09/16/bd0b6f59-d246-4f34-aba4-31b15fecd897_621e047a.jpg?itok=wrRhhh3u&v=1757994090' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><p>In Seoul, alarm bells are ringing. Washington is demanding an eye-watering US$350 billion in direct investment, a sum so vast that economists warn it could tip <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/south-korea?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>South Korea</span></a> into a crisis unseen in its modern history.</p><p>US Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick bluntly asserted last week that South Korea must accept the deal or face higher tariffs &ndash; pointing out that <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/japan?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>Japan</span></a> had already agreed to similar terms.</p><p>Under a framework agreement reached in July, the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/united-states?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>United States</span></a> offered to reduce proposed tariffs on South Korean imports from 25 per cent to 15 per cent, but only if Seoul <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/asia/east-asia/article/3320204/us-impose-15-tariff-south-korean-imports-says-trump?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>pledged to invest the US$350 billion</span></a> into sectors chosen by Washington and made additional concessions.</p><p>Yet follow-up talks, including during President <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/lee-jae-myung?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>Lee Jae-myung</span></a>&rsquo;s visit to Washington <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/us/diplomacy/article/3323118/trump-south-koreas-lee-stress-common-ground-white-house-meeting?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>last month</span></a>, have reached an impasse over the structure of the investment package, profit-sharing mechanisms and other conditions. &ldquo;The devil is in the details,&rdquo; as Lutnick put it on Thursday.</p><div><figure><figcaption>A protester holding US dollar banknotes wears a mask of Donald Trump during a rally in July against Trump&rsquo;s tariff policy near the US embassy in Seoul. Photo: AFP</figcaption></figure></div><p>US President <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/donald-trump?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>Donald Trump</span></a> has been sharply critical of South Korea, calling it a rich &ldquo;money machine&rdquo; that exploits its alliance with America, citing trade surpluses he claims are evidence of unfair practices.</p></section><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://img.i-scmp.com/cdn-cgi/image/fit=contain,width=1024,format=auto/sites/default/files/d8/images/canvas/2025/09/16/bd0b6f59-d246-4f34-aba4-31b15fecd897_a9c1e28c.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>US Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick bluntly asserted last week that South Korea must accept the deal or face higher tariffs – pointing out that Japan had already agreed to similar terms.</p><p><strong>Under a framework agreement reached in July, the United States offered to reduce proposed tariffs on South Korean imports from 25 per cent to 15 per cent, but only if Seoul pledged to invest the US$350 billion into sectors chosen by Washington and made additional concessions.</strong></p><p>....</p><p>“South Korea is being coerced to drink from a poisoned chalice. If we accept the US demand as it is, this country would simply go belly up,” said Hur Jung, an economics professor at Sogang University in Seoul.</p><p>“The country’s foreign exchange reserves would become depleted and the won’s value would plunge, sparking a foreign exchange crisis that would make the 1997 IMF bailout look mild by comparison.”</p><p><strong>The deal Washington is pushing would require the South Korean government to channel its investments into US-designated special purpose companies. Profits would be split 90-10 in Seoul’s favour until the investment principal is recouped, after which the US share would surge to 90 per cent.</strong></p><p>US$350 billion amounts to 84 per cent of South Korea’s foreign reserves, compared with Japan’s US$550 billion pledge – just 41.6 per cent of its far larger holdings.</p></blockquote><p>I&#39;ve read some analysis by economists that suggests that it would actually cost South Korea less to just accept 10% higher tariffs and instead invest in subsidies and other measures to help their exports instead of agreeing to this extortionate demand. </p><p>The trouble is that if they refuse, I suspect that Trump, Lutnick and company won&#39;t stop at 25%, and will start looking for various other ways to threaten South Korea&#39;s economy as well as its security against North Korea and China.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nij4la/in_south_korea_trumps_us350_billion_demand/nej59y4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This has nothing to do with economics. It&#39;s purely a protection racket ran by trump and his goons. Going back to his younger days when he was/is indebted to the Russian mafia, protection rackets are quite common in their playbook.</p><p>Trump goes &quot;it&#39;s a shame your business got tariffd/raided, invest x and I&#39;ll &quot;protect&quot; you from future tariffs/raids.&quot;</p><p>Meanwhile, whatever country that does pay finds their funds being siphoned off to enrich trump.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nij4la/in_south_korea_trumps_us350_billion_demand/nejdh9p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They should absolutely refuse extortion like this.  The tariffs will go as soon as the poorly educated figure out who actually paying them.  Also, Epstein didn’t kill himself.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nij4la/in_south_korea_trumps_us350_billion_demand/neje9qt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 20:01:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/15/us/politics/lisa-cook-fed-appeals-court-decision.html</link><title>Appeals Court Says Lisa Cook Can Remain on Fed Board (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ni3ae1/appeals_court_says_lisa_cook_can_remain_on_fed/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ni3ae1/appeals_court_says_lisa_cook_can_remain_on_fed/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ni3ae1/appeals_court_says_lisa_cook_can_remain_on_fed/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Maintains the rather consistent position that the judiciary has displayed about the importance of the independence of the Fed. </p><p>Allows for additional consistency in rate cut decision making, as there are arguments on both sides of the line as to whether a rate cut is appropriate. And if so, by how much.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ni3ae1/appeals_court_says_lisa_cook_can_remain_on_fed/nefzz9s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Will be super interesting if this goes to the Supreme Court given we now know she didnt even do what they are accusing her of.</p><p>I bet the administration appeals, but it doesnt get taken up by the court. They are going to have to either fire Powell soon or just wait for his term to expire</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1ni3ae1/appeals_court_says_lisa_cook_can_remain_on_fed/neg5cyh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 06:12:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/us/no-evidence-primary-residence-violation-by-fed-gov-lisa-cook-says-michigan-2025-09-15/</link><title>No evidence of primary residence violation by Fed Gov Lisa Cook, says Michigan official (reuters.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhywfd/no_evidence_of_primary_residence_violation_by_fed/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhywfd/no_evidence_of_primary_residence_violation_by_fed/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhywfd/no_evidence_of_primary_residence_violation_by_fed/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It was never intended to hold up this long. They expected to get her out first. All part of their &quot;blitzkrieg&quot; method of destroying the Constitution. Judges have gotten wise, so the ones that aren&#39;t in the maga cult are stepping up to protect it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhywfd/no_evidence_of_primary_residence_violation_by_fed/nef4gg7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They don&#39;t want to back down because that is the break the opposing side needs. What if a fed meeting is cancelled because of safety reasons. Delay because we can&#39;t vote. Interesting story unfolding</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhywfd/no_evidence_of_primary_residence_violation_by_fed/nefmd93/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I can&#39;t believe how many people are comfortable with how much &quot;working backwards from your conclusion&quot; shit is happening. </p><p>&quot;I want to fire this person, find me a reason I can fire them&quot; is not what the government should be doing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhywfd/no_evidence_of_primary_residence_violation_by_fed/neg1h2m/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:05:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.axios.com/2025/09/11/trump-tariffs-grocery-prices-rise-cpi</link><title>Trump tariffs help fuel biggest grocery price hike since 2022 (axios.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhud8p/trump_tariffs_help_fuel_biggest_grocery_price/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhud8p/trump_tariffs_help_fuel_biggest_grocery_price/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhud8p/trump_tariffs_help_fuel_biggest_grocery_price/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.axios.com/hidiLVRgYkPvHiCLAEVmWc7oFjE=/0x0:1600x900/1366x768/2025/09/11/1757602825073.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Who could have seen that one coming? Its not like Trump outright said &quot;I&#39;m going to put Tariffs on everything&quot; while everyone warned that it would increase prices.</p><p>It will never not make me laugh that &quot;high prices&quot; was the biggest reason he got re-elected. Its just sad that Trump didn&#39;t even totally lie(he said it wouldn&#39;t increase prices but apart from that he was honest about what he was going to do) and people couldn&#39;t even be bothered to google or believe actual economists who contradicted him.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhud8p/trump_tariffs_help_fuel_biggest_grocery_price/nee7kl6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This dude did a press conference in front of a pile of groceries and it actually convinced people that he was going to make everything less expensive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhud8p/trump_tariffs_help_fuel_biggest_grocery_price/neeaqrq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And all you hear from the Trump voters are crickets. It&#39;s just amazing how they can filter all of this out.</p><p>The stronghold that Donald has over the brains of every Trump voter is truly astonishing. </p><p>I&#39;m no longer surprised by how Jim Jones managed to convince 917 people to kill themselves.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhud8p/trump_tariffs_help_fuel_biggest_grocery_price/neecoee/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:15:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/15/politics/tariffs-tax-cuts-trump-households-deficit-analysis</link><title>Trump’s tariffs are bigger than his tax cuts for most Americans (edition.cnn.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhsgqi/trumps_tariffs_are_bigger_than_his_tax_cuts_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhsgqi/trumps_tariffs_are_bigger_than_his_tax_cuts_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 12 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhsgqi/trumps_tariffs_are_bigger_than_his_tax_cuts_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228223425.jpg?c=16x9&q=w_800,c_fill' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><em>A version of this story appeared in CNN&rsquo;s What Matters newsletter. To get it in your inbox, sign up for free </em><a href="https://www.cnn.com/newsletters/what-matters?source=nl-acq_article"><em>here</em></a><em>.</em> </p><p>Republicans and President Donald Trump want credit for what he has called &ldquo;the largest tax cut in the history of our country&rdquo; for the income tax cuts in his One Big Beautiful Bill Act. </p><p>Democrats and free trade advocates have said Trump&rsquo;s tariff policy, which placed levies on most imported goods from around the world, is one of the largest <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/03/31/economy/tariffs-largest-tax-hike">tax hikes</a> in history. </p><p>Both claims are debatable, but for most Americans how tariffs and tax cuts will affect their daily lives is a highly relevant question. </p><p>The answers are hard to find and nuanced. But the bottom line, according to calculations by the Yale Budget Lab, is that American households could pay $2,300 more, on average, as result of the current tariff policy, nearly three times the average roughly $800 benefit from the OBBBA&rsquo;s new tax provisions. </p><p>&ldquo;For households as a whole, the total tax increase they&rsquo;ll feel from tariffs is larger than the total tax cut they&rsquo;ll feel from the new provisions in the Republican tax package,&rdquo; said John Ricco, the lab&rsquo;s associate director of policy analysis. </p><p>There are multiple variables that complicate things. </p><p>First, tariffs have not yet sparked inflation on the level that many economists have predicted &mdash; although it is <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/11/economy/us-cpi-consumer-price-index-inflation-august">ticking up</a>. There&rsquo;s evidence that some of the impact from tariffs <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/24/economy/us-tariffs-passthrough-consumers">could be delayed,</a> and much of the president&rsquo;s tariff policy has only recently <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/06/business/trump-tariffs-in-effect">kicked in</a>. Plus, the US economy is massive and decentralized and there are many factors beyond tariffs and taxes at play. </p><p>Trump and Republicans have said the tax cuts are much larger than the tariffs, an argument that sidesteps the reality that the bulk of the tax cuts may not be noticed by many Americans. Rather than enact entirely new tax cuts, much of what the bill does is make permanent individual tax cuts that were passed as temporary policy during Trump&rsquo;s first term. </p><p>Plus, specific measures like a temporary reprieve for taxes on tips will only help slivers of the workforce. The tax bill also includes cuts to the social safety net like <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/11/politics/food-stamps-work-requirements-trump-bill">food assistance</a> and <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/07/21/politics/americans-losing-health-insurance-trump-bill">Medicaid</a>, with the expectation that millions of people will lose these benefits, affecting their quality of life and financial resources. </p><p>Even before those cuts, the cost burden of tariffs is expected to push hundreds of thousands of Americans into poverty next year, according to a <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/10/business/trump-trade-prices-poverty-report">separate Yale analysis</a>. </p><p>Tariffs amount to a national sales tax on imported goods, although the rate of tariffs varies by country and continues to change. Their impact could likewise evolve if, as Trump promises, they kickstart a US manufacturing renaissance. </p><p>One detailed comparison of how tariffs and tax cuts will affect Americans comes from the Yale Budget Lab, which concluded in a recent analysis that only those highest on the income ladder will come out ahead over the next decade when tariffs are put alongside tax cuts. </p><p>The top 10% of households, those who on average are making $518,000 per year, will pay about $13,600 less in taxes, according to Yale&rsquo;s analysis. They&rsquo;ll have to spend nearly $5,450 more, on average, because of tariff-fueled price increases. </p><p>That combined effect of tariffs and tax increases will net out to an income boost of about $8,200, or 1.6%, according to Yale. </p><p>Middle-income households, who on average are making between about $105,000 to $122,000, will see their average $1,200 tax cut more than offset by a $2,200 cumulative tariff price hike, in the Yale analysis. </p><p>Those who make the least will be hurt the most. The bottom 10% will see their average annual income drop by almost $2,600, or 6.6%, the lab found. They&rsquo;ll take an average $1,350 hit to their wallets from tariffs coupled with a roughly $1,200 hit, on average, from the &ldquo;big, beautiful bill,&rdquo; largely because the Republican package slashed spending on the nation&rsquo;s safety net to pay for part of the tax breaks. These folks have an average income of just under $39,000. </p><p>Plus, while the higher cost of goods from tariffs affects every household, it will disproportionately hurt lower-income consumers because they spend a higher share of their income than the wealthy do, Ricco said. </p><p>That impact is clear from a separate report Yale issued in early September on Trump&rsquo;s tariff policies. It showed that while the wealthiest Americans will lose nearly $5,250 in disposable income in 2027 because of higher prices, that only amounts to only 1% of their income. </p><p>By contrast, tariffs will cut more than $1,300 out of the income of the bottom 10%, but that accounts for 3.5% of their disposable income, Yale found. </p><p>The real-world effect of the new tax and spending cut bill will be further muted by the fact that most of the tax cuts are extensions of tax cuts that would have expired rather than new tax cuts. </p><p>Looking only at the new measures in the package, including the temporary elimination of taxes on some tips and overtime, the enhanced deduction for senior citizens and the beefed-up child tax credit, Americans will get an $800 break on their taxes in coming years, according to Yale. If extending the expiring cuts is added in, the average tax cut rises to $3,000. </p><p>Different research groups and think tanks use different calculations to gauge tax cuts compared to tariffs, but their bottom-line assessments are the same. </p><p>&ldquo;Tax cuts are higher for higher-income people, whereas tariffs have the opposite effects; they are much more evenly distributed,&rdquo; said Joseph Rosenberg, a senior fellow at the Urban-Brookings Tax Policy Center. That means they will hit lower income Americans harder. </p><p>While the tariffs, as currently constructed, will outweigh the tax cuts for most Americans, it&rsquo;s also important to look at how the two contrasting tax policies will affect the country&rsquo;s bottom line. </p><p>The beefed-up tariffs are projected to lower the federal deficit by $3.3 trillion over the 2025 to 2035 period and to reduce interest costs by an additional roughly $700 billion, for a total impact of $4 trillion, according to the Congressional Budget Office&rsquo;s latest estimate, which looked at tariffs imposed as of August 19. </p><p>The GOP tax and spending cuts package is expected to increase the federal debt by an estimated $4.1 trillion or so between 2025 and 2034, more than Trump&rsquo;s tariffs are forecast to bring in. It is expected to increase the deficit by $3.4 trillion and add roughly $718 billion in interest costs. </p><p>Adam Michel, director of tax policy studies at the libertarian-leaning CATO Institute, said even if the tariffs end up canceling out the impacts of the tax cuts, the effects of the two policies could make the country more unequal. </p><p>The tax cuts are &ldquo;riddled with special interest carveouts that treat similarly situated Americans with vastly different tax systems.&rdquo; Consider the increased state and local tax deductions for many East Coast homeowners, new deductions for oil and gas companies, whalers in Alaska and rum producers in Louisiana, <a href="https://www.cato.org/commentary/three-best-worst-things-trumps-big-tax-law">among others</a>. </p><p>The same is true of tariffs, he said, which will hit some industries harder than others. </p><p>&ldquo;Together, these two changes mean we are moving toward a far more unequal and unstable fiscal system that trades durable reform for lumpy, distortionary breaks and levies that undermine long-run stability and fairness,&rdquo; he said. </p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2025-07-04t222248z-1655257089-rc2yffabmo0f-rtrmadp-3-usa-trump.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This was literally the reason that even back in the 1910s, during the Woodrow Wilson presidency, an income tax was signed into law and supported and ratified by all the states.</p><p>Before then, Tariffs were the main source of revenue rather than income tax, and that was a Republican policy(nothing has changed). Democrats were the anti tariff party because it raised prices for consumers and affected mainly the lower income classes and middle class, while Republicans supported tariffs to support big businesses.</p><p>It was so chaotic and uneven that all the states agreed to go for an income tax instead.</p><p>For some reason, Trump and the GOP think that the pre 1910s model, the gilded age model, is the ideal system in 2025.</p><p>The tariff as a source of revenue concept was such a joke that there&#39;s a reason economists don&#39;t take it seriously. Yet......sigh.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhsgqi/trumps_tariffs_are_bigger_than_his_tax_cuts_for/nedt18a/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Reagan used to warn that tariffs make industries “dependent and lazy” because protection from competition dulls innovation. </p><p>By leaning on emergency tariff powers (????), the GOP is pulling in billions in revenue without having to pass a single tax bill.  Instead of designing real industrial policy or negotiating serious trade agreements, tariffs have become the lazy shortcut.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhsgqi/trumps_tariffs_are_bigger_than_his_tax_cuts_for/neezi5m/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m no economist. I&#39;m trying to learn about all of this, so I can respond appropriately to preserve my purchasing power. It&#39;s my understanding that some economists have speculated that the intention of these tariffs (and other measures taken by the admin) may have been to trigger the Fed Reserve to be forced to lower interest rates. In turn, this would push inflation up, thereby allowing the federal government to pay off the debt easier over a period of time. The time for austerity cuts has long passed. Maybe we could&#39;ve attacked the debt with real growth through green initiatives but the fossil fuel industry (cough Koch Brothers) have cut that off time and time again. </p><p>So, we are left with default or &quot;financial repression&quot;. Am I on the right track here?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nhsgqi/trumps_tariffs_are_bigger_than_his_tax_cuts_for/nee3035/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 23:06:12 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
