<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=economics&amp;averagePostsPerDay=9&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/economics</title><description>Hot posts in /r/economics (roughly 9 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 18:12:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132/img/platforms/reddit.png</url><title>/r/economics</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link></image><item><link>https://newsrepublic.co.uk/2025/09/20/its-going-to-hurt-us-trump-puts-15000-offshore-wind-jobs-at-risk-with-halt-orders/</link><title>'It's Going to Hurt Us': Trump Puts 15,000 Offshore Wind Jobs at Risk With Halt Orders (newsrepublic.co.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlwkkq/its_going_to_hurt_us_trump_puts_15000_offshore/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlwkkq/its_going_to_hurt_us_trump_puts_15000_offshore/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlwkkq/its_going_to_hurt_us_trump_puts_15000_offshore/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Say whatever you want about alternative energy, but it’s energy generation at a time when there’s never been greater demand, and solar/wind has had all the (construction) momentum for the last 20 years. Yes, let’s build more nuclear and even “clean” coal, but it will be a decade before those come online. Enjoy your energy bills that double mo/mo in the meantime. Cutting off any power generation sources right now is a very bad idea.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlwkkq/its_going_to_hurt_us_trump_puts_15000_offshore/nf8kei1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We all know why the current admin not pushing wind or solar. China is leading in solar energy. Also The US has a surplus of oil and coal that it needs to sell.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlwkkq/its_going_to_hurt_us_trump_puts_15000_offshore/nf8nm4y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Revolution wind farm got shut down after all the foundations were in place and the substation is in port waiting to be installed. It’s insane since a huge part of the work has been done. Any environmentally impact has been spent and now there will be no benefits from it. </p><p>It’s crazy but I’m sure it’s just a bargaining chip and will be completed. But it’s fucking over a lot of companies in the process</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlwkkq/its_going_to_hurt_us_trump_puts_15000_offshore/nf94gh3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 17:42:04 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/work/microsoft-urges-h-1b-visa-holders-to-stay-in-us-for-foreseeable-future-after-trump-announces-100000-visa-fee/articleshow/124009637.cms?from=mdr</link><title>Microsoft asks all its foreign staff to return to US by Sunday after Trump's H1-B bombshell (economictimes.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>So, according to the fine print, the US president can determine who gets a waiver on the H1-B annual fee and which corporations don&#39;t.</p><p>Pretty obvious, isn&#39;t it? The Grifter in Chief has a new scam. Lots of extravagant gifts and money in brown paper bags will be required.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/nf7mj27/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And Trump is handing out specific exceptions for his fees but only if you obey what he wants. This isn’t government, it’s grotesque institutional corruption.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/nf8edh2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p><a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/topic/microsoft">Microsoft</a> on Saturday advised its H-1B and H-4 visa employees to return to the United States immediately, ahead of the <strong>September 21 deadline</strong> announced by President <a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/panache/panache-people-101/donald-trump/profileshow/79057526.cms">Donald Trump</a> after he imposed a $100,000 annual fee on the program, according to an internal email seen by Reuters.</p></blockquote><p>Damn, they expect people to return to the USA in 48h?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/nf7irxr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>People don&#39;t understand one thing - tech has been remote for a decade now, long before covid. Trump is just giving them enough fuel to offshore more US jobs. US does not have enough talent by itself</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/nf8j1t1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I am getting a kick out of the MAGA herd saying this is great, sorry Cletus you can’t do these jobs. You don’t have the education nor intelligence to do these jobs. The hubris is amazing, the guy with a GED thinking he can just step into a software engineer job is something. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/nf8hnif/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah,  or just stay and shift your contract to local Microsoft offices.  Really, there&#39;s no need to work in the US. It&#39;s all remote anyway, and the US is a fascist sithole.  Wherever they are,  they are probably better off there, and the local economies can use the influx of money.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/nf7u57l/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Non-paywalled article link minus ads: <a href="https://archive.ph/2025.09.20-125003/https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/work/h1b-visa-the-100k-question-who-pays-the-h-1b-fees-you-or-your-employer/articleshow/124012769.cms">https://archive.ph/2025.09.20-125003/https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/nri/work/h1b-visa-the-100k-question-who-pays-the-h-1b-fees-you-or-your-employer/articleshow/124012769.cms</a></p><p>2025 H-1B Report by NAICS Industry: <a href="https://archive.ph/2025.09.20-134451/https://www.myvisajobs.com/reports/h1b/industry/professional,-scientific,-and-technical-services-54/">https://archive.ph/2025.09.20-134451/https://www.myvisajobs.com/reports/h1b/industry/professional,-scientific,-and-technical-services-54/</a></p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/indianrealestate/s/Vw6PSvm55R">https://www.reddit.com/r/indianrealestate/s/Vw6PSvm55R</a></p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/unitedstatesofindia/s/aNok7KTVTf">https://www.reddit.com/r/unitedstatesofindia/s/aNok7KTVTf</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlqm4q/microsoft_asks_all_its_foreign_staff_to_return_to/nf8yo58/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 11:44:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.axios.com/2025/09/19/bls-cpi-report-inflation</link><title>Bureau of Labor Statistics postpones key data report (axios.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Dear leader was not satisfied with the numbers. They were rookie numbers. Big strong men(not women!), tears in their eyes, are lining up for jobs because of DJT, and if the report doesn&#39;t show that, then the report is wrong. He works so hard that he gets no sleep, the only sleep he gets is during important meetings(they don&#39;t matter anyway because Dear Leader is responsible for the facts).</p><p>and they said to me, &quot;Sir, did you hear about the bad BLS report,&quot; I said I heard about it Pete, it&#39;s a very sad and terrible thing that the Democrats did, and he starts crying, this Big Strong Man starts weeping all over the place, and he&#39;s begging me, &quot;please Sir, please stop the Radical Left from faking the numbers&quot; and I said we&#39;ll be stopping it immediately, and I thought about it, I said why haven&#39;t we had, why did we never get a redo, how come nobody&#39;s ever asked that one before, Robert E. Lee, you remember him, he was a Great General, and he fought and he fought hard, but he was treated very unfairly, not as much as me, but pretty unfair</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/nf6erzo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>welcome to north korea trump edition. </p><p>it never ceases to amaze me how lazy push overs we americans are. </p><p>our grandfathers and great grand fathers fought against fascism </p><p>yet here we are.  the insurrectionist in chief is a shit again on our nation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/nf6rtok/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Where are all the people who said this is run by many responsible economists and statisticians and there’s no way this administration could f@k it up ?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/nf6wqjz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>and some redditors <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/comment/nerhxny/">in this thread on Wednesday</a> still believed that Heritage Foundation would provide accurate reporting... the cognitive dissonance of general population is increasing <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/economics">r/economics</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/nf7h8rt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is extremely destructive for the economy. Shaking faith in the system lowers GDP in all scenarios.</p><p>Trump&#39;s presidency has been worrying so much. I mean his dumb economic ideas are killing his bad political ones.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nllui5/bureau_of_labor_statistics_postpones_key_data/nf8wzkp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 07:24:40 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/stock-market-flashes-warning-seen-080200859.html</link><title>The Stock Market Flashes a Warning Seen During the Dot-Com Bubble. History Says the SP 500 Will Do This Next. (finance.yahoo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>While I do agree that it’s overvalued and the sign is at the door, what I think “it’s different” from before is that previously access from retail and the world in general was way more limited before. Now you can buy fractional stocks whether you are in the us, India or Latin America. So while I think that fundamentally it’s the same issue as previous bubbles, the difference now is that the ceiling will be higher due to basically way more players in the markets.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/nf63dnp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While this is bad, and obviously the disastrous GOP policies are leading to a cooling economy+ high inflation, I&#39;ve lost quite a bit of faith that people will wise up, start caring about politics, realize that &quot;Oh, I&#39;m apolitical&quot; is stupid, and vote properly.</p><p>People say the economy is the most important thing. I disagree. If the economy is the most important thing, then most states would be swing states, but they&#39;re not. When people say the economy is the most important thing, they mean that within a specific set of parameters, and that&#39;s culture issues. The economy is only important in the 7 swing states. Yeah the culture wars are mostly bs, but they exist and that&#39;s the reality, and people just care way more about invisible haitians eating dogs and trans people in bathrooms and &quot;strong vibes&quot; rather than the economy.</p><p>Even if a D president gets elected, they&#39;ll have an extremely divided Congress to work with, won&#39;t be able to pass genuine big structural reform, get all the people mad, and vote GOP again, then complain when things get bad. People love split ticket voting or abstaining because they&#39;re angry with the president but will vote GOP down ballot or whatever and will then proudly champion how &quot;bipartisan and smart&quot; they are. Republican voters might even get angry with the President(although Trump&#39;s as popular with the MAGA cult as ever) but its literally the &quot;One Bad Man&quot; theory where they&#39;ll continue voting GOP in state and Congressional elections.</p><p>In 1932, almost all the states voted FDR, gave Democrats a 200 seat House majority, a 30 seat Senate majority, and most Governorships in the country went D too. Today, the Governorships would barely change, the State legislatures would remain the same, and a D president will barely get elected and have a super divided Congress to work with.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/nf5zkur/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><strong>- Key points</strong></p><ul><li>As of July 2025, the cape ratio stood at 37.8, compared with long term average of 17, close to the dot com bubble&#39;s CAPE ratio of 44</li><li>CAPE ratio is similar to PE ratio but adjusts for economic cycles</li></ul><p><strong>- For those with more time:</strong></p><p><strong>So what&#39;s the issue?</strong></p><p>There&#39;s debate around whether the <strong>current elevated value of the ratio</strong> is an <strong>early warning sign of a market correction</strong>, as it happened in 1929 and the dotcom era of 1990s.</p><p><strong>What is a CAPE ratio?</strong></p><p><strong>The CAPE ratio assesses whether the market is undervalued or overvalued.</strong> It is similar to the PE ratio - it compares stock price to earnings, howeverunlike the PE ratio, it averages earnings over 10 years to adjust for economic cycles. </p><p><strong>Why use the CAPE ratio? And an example pls</strong> <br/>Well, first consider the PE ratio: if you&#39;re using the PE ratio and there&#39;s an expansion or recession, profits rise or fall, and the PE ratio fluctuates massively. </p><p>These fluctuations in profit due to economic cycles are the PE ratio&#39;s downfall. Instead, as the CAPE ratio averages earnings over 10 years, <em>it smooths out short term volatility and is less volatile than the standard P/E ratio.</em></p><p><em>Sorry im repeating myself a lot but this is so it&#39;s understood perfectly ;)</em></p><p><strong>- Limitations of CAPE ratio</strong></p><ul><li>looks at past data (backward looking), instead of future trends</li><li>Relies on GAAP earnings- accounting results that may contain errors</li><li>The results have been skewed by mag7</li></ul><p>any issues with this lmk!<br/>References: <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/cape-ratio.asp">https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/cape-ratio.asp</a><br/>u/<a href="/user/Cloudboy9001/">Cloudboy9001</a> <em>mentioned the CAPE ratio in my last post about an AI Bubble. I thought I&#39;d research further. I summarised the above article about it, with the help of Investopedia.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/nf5xtzo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>People have been screaming we’re in a bubble since 2021. How many different signs and inverted yield curves or whatever did we have predicting a recession in the next few months? They were certain we were on the brink of collapse and yet nothing. Even now with Trump smashing the economy with a sledgehammer, the stock market hasn’t collapsed. I’m sure this time it’s different and we’ll be in a recession in the next few months…</p><p>Predicting downturns has got to be the most stable job in the world as no one actually cares how many times you’re wrong and you eventually get to claim you’re right after decades of failed predictions. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/nf68ga5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The market going up is now dependent on cap ex increasing and profits increasing, related to the build out and probable profit in AI.  When that fades, so does the market.  </p><p>So far the entire market has held up much better than I expected, but I have my reservations about the future.  So far this year I took as many profits as I was willing to pay taxes on, so I am sitting on my hands until the new year.  Today all markets made a new high.  It does feel unstable.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/nf6uq3w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I sure hope this is true. I would be so happy if the Sp500 had a 50% crash and goes back to 3000. Think of the money you will make afterwards.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/nf6xqj8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Democrats will win the next election and do nothing about taxes. The billionaires will have won.  Democrats will find a way to squeeze the middle class and do nothing about inequality. Obama squeezed the middle class, and so did Biden while throwing the border open to suppress wages and outsource jobs.  The Democrats are not pro- labor, only pro-union vote banks.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nljnbs/the_stock_market_flashes_a_warning_seen_during/nf6irhy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 05:36:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://apnews.com/article/h1b-visa-trump-immigration-8d39699d0b2de3d90936f8076357254e</link><title>Trump signs proclamation imposing $100K annual fee for H-1B visa applications (apnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The companies that benefit most from the H1B program are deep in Trump&#39;s pockets. I give this half-baked plan less than 7 Scaramuccis before he walks it back.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5jylb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This strikes me another scam where he gets the tech bros to grovel and bribe, a month from now this isn’t a thing.</p><p>Same scam, different week. Would it be good in some ways to shift hiring domestically? Sure, but as many have pointed out above there are a number of potential negatives as well. </p><p>Again though, I do not see this as serious policy.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5oyu0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This requires congress approval. Will get shut down on a month; and this time of the year there&#39;s a hiring freeze anyways since the holidays are coming up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5j5c2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Proclamation?!?! He’s not a fucking king, not unless we’re talking about the king of sex with underage ladies. When is he gonna crawl back under his rock?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5vj5b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Its not per year. Lutnik doesn&#39;t even read his own proclamations. And all the news just ate it up. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/09/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-suspends-the-entry-of-certain-alien-nonimmigrant-workers/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/09/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-suspends-the-entry-of-certain-alien-nonimmigrant-workers/</a></p><p>Its 100k per petition. So more like 33k/year.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5xbje/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How’s his drug cost proclaiming going? He signed an executive order to lower drug prices a long time ago and NOTHING HAS CHANGED. The rich run this country, I’m sure they had a good laugh about that too.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5loh7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Trump wants Hyundai to come back, then pulls this.... So i guess he wants tariffs to bring manufacturing back to the USA and then use this fee to prevent manufacturing to come back? . . . GOP - masters of double tapping their pinky toe in the same wall because they think the results will be different?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf6vbvm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 04:09:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/19/fed-gov-miran-says-he-did-not-tell-trump-how-he-would-vote-on-rates-this-week.html</link><title>Fed Governor Miran says he did not tell Trump how he would vote on rates this week (cnbc.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s because Trump told him how he would vote. His vote and stances on the issues in the meeting were essentially just the position of the Trump administration for the last 9 months. </p><p>Just wild gaslighting.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/nf3ddez/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>*Winks*</p><p>I am sure he didn&#39;t. Although, I am also sure the Council of Economic Advisers and the President have made their &quot;recommendations&quot; to the Fed and individual positions crystal clear, and have widely discussed the desired path of interest rates.</p><p>Fed minutes will be fun to see what kind of cuts were being looked at and what the consensus appeared to be, especially if there is someone arguing for beyond 50 bps.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/nf39ghd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>No need to tell Trump when all you&#39;re doing is obeying his commands right? I mean, I don&#39;t need my dog to let out a confirmation bark when I tell him to fetch; I just need the ball returned to me.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/nf3dniy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah no kidding.</p><p>Trump TOLD YOU how you were going to vote for this and every meeting from here on out. The entire purpose of Miran being on that board is to be an instru,emt of Trump&#39;s will. The idea of him act6ing autonomously is profoundly stupid.</p><p>Every single person in this admin is a shameless pos.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/nf3fy7p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There’s an interview with Tucker Carlson (or equivalent) that I’ll never forget. Carlson was saying that he isn’t being told what to say - that he actually believes in what he’s saying.  And the guest’s response was along the lines of: “I believe you.  But you’re sitting there because they would only pick someone with your beliefs”. </p><p>Same thing here.  Dude doesn’t need to coordinate with Trump.  He was chosen because he was already going to do the things Trump wants.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/nf3y5zk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They actually think we’re stupid…</p><p><em>”He called me Tuesday morning to congratulate me, and that was it,” the central banker said during a “Money Movers” interview. “I did not talk to him about how I vote. I did not talk to him about about my dots in the [Summary] of Economic Projections.”</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/nf3p1l6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I mean Trump already defined his incentives when he put him in. If anything, I&#39;m glad we now see how Fed &quot;independence&quot; is a facade. Plus how financial regulation is all political. Anyone notice the new bank reg changes and how drastically different it is from a year ago?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl77y6/fed_governor_miran_says_he_did_not_tell_trump_how/nf4dnvq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 21:19:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/09/18/chinas-200m-gig-workers-are-a-warning-for-the-world</link><title>China's 200m gig workers are a warning for the world (economist.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Gig work in general was supposed to be there as a form of supplementary income. The fact that it had become a primary form of earnings for so many is the red flag.</p><p>It is a highlight for how the wealthy wish things were for everyone, and with the massive push for AI globally, they are very likely to get their wish.</p><p>Remember, the goal of AI is not to be transformational; it is to be <em>good enough</em> that it can justify firing workers. Service quality is irrelevant. See: Verizon.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf31qjd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Are these primary jobs or second jobs?</p><p>I know very few people who try to make a living solely on gig work. They are usually working multiple crappy jobs, which is a different kind of economic warning.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf23ltp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>China has a total population of 1.4 billion with a workforce population of about 770 million in 2023. The same ratio as America&#39;s 170 million workforce population to 340 million total population.</p><p>China&#39;s ~200m gig workers represents about 26% of their workforce. America has, by conservative estimates, between 57 to 72 million (36~45%) gig workers. I think America is the warning for the world.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf1txr3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is Trump&#39;s vision for America. No wages or benefits or protections, Just a disjointed working system where people work and pay taxes while costing corporation nothing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf4opcq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:28:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/nuclear-power-could-be-a-10-trillion-industry-that-holds-the-answer-to-the-worlds-power-shortages-090015624.html</link><title>Nuclear power could be a $10 trillion industry that 'holds the answer to the world's power shortages' (finance.yahoo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The US navy has been running Aircraft Carriers and Submarines for over half a century in extremely confined spaces on Nuclear energy.</p><p>The civilian tech is just now beginning to catch up to the military tech from 50 years ago.</p><p>For example, breeder reactors and higher enrichment grade fuels have been highly restricted technologies for decades now. They mostly solve the problem with “spent fuel” and improve the economics significantly.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/nf16kcq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The problem is the dollar amount per Wh. If nuclear power &quot;could&quot; be a 10 Trillion USD industry, then solar+wind+battery &quot;would&quot; be a 3 Trillion USD industry for the same amount of Watt-Hours. The economics of nuclear are just not there.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/nf0trdp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s the bridge between oil and gas and renewables.  Always has been.  Honestly probably more than just a bridge with our current technology but that is to the radiation fear mongering from oil and gas we are decades behind.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/nf5ev35/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I find it interesting how there was a push not to use nuclear power despite all the science with how safe it is. </p><p>But now that we have ever expanding data centers, I&#39;m not seeing any pushback against nuclear.</p><p>Just interesting to see how special interest groups so caring when there&#39;s lots of money involved.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/nf2h96j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The most recent numbers I&#39;ve seen show the three mile island restart (not building a new reactor from scratch!) as 2.5x the cost per megawatt as a large combined cycle gas turbine. Obviously the reactor is zero emissions but in a world where people are super concerned about high utility bills, dumping massive amounts of Capex into the rate base might not be the best idea. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/nf4ob6s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As an aside $10 trillion in nuclear power investment amounts to ~1000GW of capacity.</p><p>The same amount of solar power would cost roughly $10 billion.</p><p>You know, three <strong>orders of magnitude less</strong>. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/nf2s6jb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The main argument given to support the claim that nuclear power is the future for the last 10 years has been an unproven and largely nonexistent technology.  SMRs are a vaporware and astroturf sandwich.   Nuclear has no chance of competing economically with renewables and comes with huge political liabilities (due to genuine risks) that renewables do not have.   There is no rational argument for building it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkuytm/nuclear_power_could_be_a_10_trillion_industry/nf2vj8t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:49:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-19/china-seeks-trade-edge-by-shunning-us-soy-in-first-since-1990s?embedded-checkout=true</link><title>China Seeks Trade Edge by Shunning US Soy in First Since 1990s (bloomberg.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkrlhx/china_seeks_trade_edge_by_shunning_us_soy_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkrlhx/china_seeks_trade_edge_by_shunning_us_soy_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkrlhx/china_seeks_trade_edge_by_shunning_us_soy_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Beijing, with healthy stockpiles in hand, is signaling it has the patience and capacity to wait — and that it’s willing to use commodities as a bargaining chip in broader trade talks. President Xi Jinping is set to speak with Trump on Friday, as the two countries spar over restrictions on semiconductors and rare earths. In the run-up, China has ratcheted up pressure by announcing that a preliminary probe found Nvidia Corp. in violation of anti-monopoly laws.</p></blockquote><p>Really impressed that China actually found great leverage when preparing for Trump’s attacks on them. They talked a big game about how they were ready for anything America could throw at them after Trump’s first term, and it looks like they’re constantly backing up that talk.</p><p>Also as a side note, I’d feel bad for US farmers if they didn’t literally vote for a tariff trade war with China and that they’re going to be bailed out with taxpayer money <strong>again</strong></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkrlhx/china_seeks_trade_edge_by_shunning_us_soy_in/nf03bxv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>China playing chess against a guy struggling with Tic Tac Toe...</p><p>Six bankruptcies is nothing to brag about...</p><p>What does China lose? They pay a bit more for soybeans?</p><p>Damage to USA Farmers? A very real threat to their livelihood...</p><p>This is just another case of Trump&#39;s Art of the Deal... While making other Countries GREAT again!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkrlhx/china_seeks_trade_edge_by_shunning_us_soy_in/nf1n0pu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 07:56:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg9n6vr2eyo</link><title>Why France is at risk of becoming the new sick man of Europe (bbc.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkpim1/why_france_is_at_risk_of_becoming_the_new_sick/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkpim1/why_france_is_at_risk_of_becoming_the_new_sick/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkpim1/why_france_is_at_risk_of_becoming_the_new_sick/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>What I find interesting is that the debt to GDP ratio of France is lower than that of the United States and the debt payments that France has to make are now the (EDIT) third largest part of their budget. IIRC US debt payments are currently 4th behind the big three of military, social security, and healthcare, but not by a very large differential.</p><p>However, there&#39;s no one around to bail the US out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkpim1/why_france_is_at_risk_of_becoming_the_new_sick/nf0buei/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It depends on who holds the debt. Japan has been able to avoid a debt catastrophe because the debt is held domestically. Argentina could never avoid a debt catastrophe because its debt is held by foreigners</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkpim1/why_france_is_at_risk_of_becoming_the_new_sick/nf0j8wf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>France is the sick old man because it’s people refuse to quietly acquiesce to cuts to social programs, but I suppose Hungary that lives off EU subsidy and is run by a dictator is doing fine?</p><p>I don’t know, all this seems like bullshit.  There’s this idea that average people can’t have a decent life because it’s too expensive, but it seems there are plenty of resources in existence it’s just not properly distributed.</p><p>There’s a class of people who own everything, including your information sources, and they’re telling you that you have to have less to maintain a system where they have more? Even if that is true who cares?  Let the thing fall apart then I say, I don’t actually care if they’re kept in luxury.</p><p>I don’t doubt the accuracy of the claims of the article, Frances debt to GDP ratio, but I also can’t pretend that any of this is anything more than self imposed conditions to maintain a specific class and societal hierarchy.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkpim1/why_france_is_at_risk_of_becoming_the_new_sick/nf1wl79/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Isn’t this really just going to be the fate of most European countries? With their populations declining, and less and less younger people, they will have less money to pay for social programs. </p><p>This is exacerbated by the now increase in debt spending to fund defense. </p><p>Europeans on Reddit say the fix is simple, just increase taxes on the rich. But Europe already has high taxes, at some point rich people and businesses will just leave. </p><p>Why stay in France when you can come to the US, have much lower taxes, and if you run a business, access to cheap energy?</p><p>The influx of immigrants was European policy makers last ditch effort to stay relevant in the future but those policies were largely rejected by Europeans. They want to keep their culture at the expense of heir countries future. </p><p>So, the answer will be the Japan model, protect your culture, but you will have to increase productivity by working longer and longer hours, with less and less social safety nets. You will have to work these longer hours just to keep your countries economy stagnant for decades until eventually you collapse anyway.</p><p>Europe had a good run. Those world wars and all the people lost were the death of the continent. It just took a long time to play out. That should be a lesson to Americans. We need to keep our asses out of a large scale war at all costs. That’s how you lose an empire.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkpim1/why_france_is_at_risk_of_becoming_the_new_sick/nezplnj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 06:18:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/2025/09/17/jerome-powell-ai-bubble-inequality-rich/?&amp;</link><title>Jerome Powell on signs of an AI bubble and an economy leaning too hard on the rich: 'Unusually large amounts of economic activity' (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The S&amp;P 500&#39;s CAPE (cyclically adjusted price-to-earnings) ratio is currently ~39, hit an all-time high of 44 during dot-com bubble, and historically averages ~17-18.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezeehu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A few people got really rich and everybody else is going to be really poor and not be able to afford the same lifestyle they had even 6 months ago. </p><p>I have worked so many different recessions so far as both an investment broker and also a banker and also a construction worker and also a contractor. </p><p>The biggest pet peeve I have or the biggest thing that I&#39;m annoyed about is that the farmers who voted for Trump are getting bailouts while everybody else are paying for those bailouts not only by the increased fees due to tariffs but also due to the fact that we&#39;re paying taxes that are going to people who voted against their better interest and now we&#39;re going broke and we now have to pay for them so they don&#39;t commit suicide</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezik88/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is 1929 all over again. The stock market is booming because it has sucked all the money from the rest of the economy and that is a proven recipe for economic collapse. It will not be different this time</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezsdoc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><em>I summarised this article from Fortune.com. Most of the words are the authors - any issues lmk!</em></p><p><strong>- Before we read the article, what is an Economic Bubble?</strong></p><p>&quot;An economic bubble is the <strong>rapid escalation in asset prices that exceeds intrinsic value</strong>, <strong>leading to a sudden market contraction known as a crash</strong> or bubble burst.&quot; - from Investopedia. </p><p><strong>Article summary</strong></p><ul><li>Wall street commentators have worried that the <strong>AI boom looks like a bubble</strong>, with some analysts estimating investment could reach $3 trillion by 2028. </li><li>Very recently they received an <strong>acknowledgment</strong> from the chair of the FED</li><li>&quot;U.S. is seeing &quot;unusually large amounts of economic activity through the AI buildout&quot; - this is skewed towards the wealthy.</li><li>Consumer spending has taken on a K shape- &quot;where the performance of different parts of the economy diverges like the arms of the letter K&quot; (Some parts of the economy may experience growth whilst others decline)</li><li>This K shape is evident today - in the U.S, spending is skewed - todays higher earning consumers are spending more, whilst lower income families cut back on essentials</li><li>Powell notes that layoffs are rare but job creation has slowed - that combined with the concentration of economic gains in AI and among the wealthy risks deepening inequality (K shape!). It also complicates the Fed&#39;s attempt to balance its inflation and employment mandates because of the risk of demand pull inflation and lowering employment rates</li></ul><p>My summary leans slightly on the negative side - but this AI capex isn&#39;t all negative !!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezch2p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So I’m not an economist, but from what I’ve gathered this time is structured different from the dot com bubble - in that crash the companies were all small startups. </p><p>In this economy, ai is being funded and propped up by the wealthiest mega corporations in the world, that have other means of income and (from what I understand) a better ability to weather, outlast, and pivot from downturns and such.</p><p>I’d love to hear from someone more educated about this than me though, how might it play out differently this time?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nf4ivf8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The country’s economy doesn’t work for 80% of the citizens and the economy is based on the spending of the top 10% and the stock market is held up by the whims of the top 1%.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nf56vu4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 05:22:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.marketwatch.com/story/why-mortgage-rates-are-actually-going-up-after-the-fed-cut-interest-rates-87c712bd</link><title>Why mortgage rates are actually going up after the Fed cut interest rates -- 'We actually anticipated the possibility that rates would tick up after the Fed announcement,' economist says (marketwatch.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Say it louder in the back - the Fed doesn&#39;t control mortgage rates and by cutting fed funds rates, housing will get more expensive, just like everything else as the dollar continues to devalue</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neytfp2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s because mortgage rates are mostly correlated with 10Y Treasury yields which while somewhat influenced by the fed funds rate are mostly market driven</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neyuziq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Jesus fuck seriously what is up with the length rule for comments.</p><p>I write actual constructive thoughts and every time I have to come back and add more... because automod deletes it for being too short.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neywijj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And that is why the bond market is important and when countries dump US bonds, the mortgage rates increase. When less people want US debt, it becomes a problem for those who hold the debt.</p><p>Right now despite the interest rate cut, the yield went higher because most investors are scared of US job losses accelerating and market slowdown.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/nf0lsat/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Don’t ignore the impact of QT in the MBS market. The Fed continues to reduce its holdings of MBS and the bond market isn’t interested enough to keep rates from going up. Housing prices need to come down to unfreeze the housing market.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/nezh9w5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>After Jpow is gone they are going to put someone in there that is going to implement &#39;QE with a twist&#39;. They are going to buy up longer term bonds to get the yield on the 30 year lower and to also get mortgage rates lower. Kind of like &#39;operation twist&#39; that they did in 2011-2012 iirc</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neytsc6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Selfishly...good.  I bought points to get a sub-6% rate a year ago, and I wouldn&#39;t mind if rates stayed above that for another 18 months so the cost of the points ended up being worth it.</p><p>But also selfishly, lower interest rates would increase business for my job.</p><p>But also also selfishly, lower rates plus tariffs might turbocharge inflation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neyxyqn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:10:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-trump-lisa-cook-federal-reserve-d7cd7bf7b8bca591b1748591836c3645</link><title>Trump asks the Supreme Court for an emergency order to remove Lisa Cook from the Fed board (apnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This just makes one wonder what the end game is for Trump in this whole thing. Just yesterday the Fed dropped rates 25bp and signaled continued cuts for the foreseeable future.</p><p>What does Trump want that he isn’t getting here? And why is that thing worth blowing up the “full faith and credit” of the US dollar?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newqdss/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Why is it always an emergency when this man doesn&#39;t get what he wants? His parents really should have done something about that spoiled bully attitude when he was younger.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newujpi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Although I’m not an American, Trump’s attempt in controlling the Fed and removing its independence is perhaps the worst thing he has done to the U.S.</p><p>If Trump does manage to effectively control the Fed, it would be a major blow for American hegemony. </p><p>He will inevitably slash rates to rock bottom in a bid to boost the economy. But it will probably lead to inflation because the problem isn’t high interest rates causing rising unemployment, its fiscal uncertainty caused by his erratic economic policy. </p><p>Central Bank’s gained independence precisely to prevent Presidents misusing central banking tools like cutting interest rates at the wrong time to boost the economy leading to high inflation. </p><p>While abusing central banking tools isn’t an inevitability in general, but with Trump at the helm, it’s practically a certainty.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newtxwv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>trump wants fed rates at 1% or less right now to shoot the economy up and hide the stagflationary impacts of his far-right kleptocratic jingoistic economic policy. So he needs to subjeugate the FED right now to proceed.</p><p>By next may it might be too late and people will have begun to feel the consequences of electing this total wreck of a Party to power.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newrn6f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>All evidence undercuts the supposed crime, they should not be allowed to remove people from our most important institution with a bullshit casus belli, and before even being adjudicated? Whatever happened to innocent until proven guilty?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newtfwq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Seeing the dot plot from yesterday and the vote from Miran makes me very worried about him being the new Fed president regardless of what happens to Cook here. Having a corrupt Fed president could lead to issues even if the sane faction continues having a majority. Think of the fallout if a partisan Fed decided to do unlimited QE? Rates are a small fraction of the problem here.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newslgy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I suspect this will be the rare case where they turn him down. This is an opportunity to pretend to be impartial on an issue that has little actual consequence. Even if she was replaced it would not have impacted the decision this week.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newzu92/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:25:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2025-09-18/congress-has-no-good-excuse-to-keep-trading-stocks?srnd=homepage-americas</link><title>Congress Has No Good Excuse to Keep Trading Stocks (bloomberg opinion -- archive link https://archive.is/tllib) (bloomberg.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nk7krf/congress_has_no_good_excuse_to_keep_trading/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nk7krf/congress_has_no_good_excuse_to_keep_trading/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nk7krf/congress_has_no_good_excuse_to_keep_trading/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>They haven&#39;t had a good excuse to be trading stocks for years now.  It would be trivially easy to set up a system by which key government employees could transfer all of their dollars in to simple low cost indexed portfolios with a blind trustee system.  Like trivially easy.  </p><p>Just literally loop in an indexing or direct indexing provider, allow discretion over broad risk profiles, and transfer money then call it a day.  Shit can be done for like 5-10bps.  </p><p>This isn&#39;t the 60s, you don&#39;t need to be out there stock picking.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nk7krf/congress_has_no_good_excuse_to_keep_trading/newkhhj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I can play devil&#39;s advocate here.  Congress critters are some of the most powerful people in the world.  Being humans, the temptation for corruption is too powerful for most, if not all to resist.  The stock trading allows an outlet for that corruption so they at least nominally vote in the best (or maybe better) interests of their constituents/county instead of doing some of the insane shit you see going on in other countries with obscene wealth.</p><p>Not saying I agree with the logic, but if that&#39;s the reasoning, I do understand.  I also understand rejecting this explanation, downvoting and moving on, but I would like to see the reason why you think it&#39;s incorrect.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nk7krf/congress_has_no_good_excuse_to_keep_trading/nexiddl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 18:27:56 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.yahoo.com/finance/news/jerome-powell-signs-ai-bubble-222907233.html</link><title>Jerome Powell on signs of an AI bubble and an economy leaning too hard on the rich: 'Unusually large amounts of economic activity' (yahoo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Does anyone else see a huge risk in this massive AI spending? MIT recently refitted that in a survey of companies adopting it, there was nothing gained. The growth of data centers is consuming large amounts of energy with rates climbing as a result. Wyoming already has data centers using more power than all its residential customers combined. Other states are on the verge of this. If AI fails to provide returns which justify this, isn’t a huge collapse likely?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nevpuj6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Given so much of the economy is now the top 10%, if we do see a stock market correction, I think the actual change in GDP will be greater than previous corrections. </p><p>Why? Because the rich own most of the stocks and will feel poorer. Their spending is mostly discretionary. They dont need most of anything they buy. They just wont spend it. </p><p>Before when the stock market declined, it didn&#39;t affect consumption nearly as much. Workers just kept spending and didn&#39;t even look at their 401k if they had it. </p><p>Now you&#39;ve got to please this top 10% and if you dont they wont keep propping up the economy single handedly. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/neuhq6k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>start your watches</p><p>Alan Greenspan&#39;s famous &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; comment was made on December 5, 1996, during a speech at the American Enterprise Institute. The dot-com crash is widely recognized as beginning when the Nasdaq Composite peaked on March 10, 2000, before entering a sharp decline.</p><p>There were about 3 years and 3 months (approximately 39 months) between Greenspan&#39;s &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; speech and the peak that marked the start of the dot-com crash.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nev4nbh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Every American is a momentarily embarrassed millionaire&quot; is the greatest con perpetuated upon the ethos of USA. The degree to which the poors and working class vote against their own interests never ceases to amaze. The farmers seem to not be enjoying the finding out part. Anyways...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/neuc9b2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The data centers can not make enough profit to pay for themselves, the amount spent is just too high. The technology is obsolete now that there are other systems that use less energy. Our AI is dependent upon things that should be illegal and inevitably will be in the rest of the world. This is beyond buying stock with borrowed money, this is just burning dollars in the furnace to mint pennies.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nev30e0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>AI bubble is no different from the telecom boom &amp; bust of the early 2000s. There will be an excess of GPUs in the market when AI usage does not materialize as expected. AI won’t go away but the bubble would have been pricked.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nev9124/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The die for this economic model was cast over 50 years ago leading into Reagan&#39;s run and eventual 2 term presidency. Accountability for and taxes on the wealthy have been slashed since then, so it&#39;s hardly shocking that we have a 2 tier economy and embarassingly horrific inequality.</p><p>That was the point; funnel as much of the benefits to the top. It wasn&#39;t some fluke. They knew trickle down didn&#39;t work, but this propaganda which is even more extreme today, was designed and implemented for this exact outcome. The plan was an extraordinary success but the wish list still isn&#39;t complete. Project 2025 goals defines most of that. Left unchecked, these people&#39;s aggression will not end. It&#39;s up to the public to stop it. But how bad will things get before then?</p><p>Today orruption abounds and leadership for both parties, brazen and aggressively by one more than the other, caters to the top. A 2 tier justice system has always existed in the country. Most of government has been captured by rent seekers. These discrepancies can be found in court cases, economic data, and anecdotes from every day lives of Americans. Maybe those records will be deleted or whitewashed like government records on terrorism that were deleted this week, or shutdown through censorship that&#39;s ongoing.</p><p>The country&#39;s leaders and millions of uneducated, highly persuadable voters have completely dismissed the idea of democracy altogether and we march down the path of fascism. Yes men replace anyone in the way of personal agendas and grift. We&#39;re always at war or involved with them. We&#39;ve seemingly returned to the time of kings and religion as a state prop.</p><p>Powell sees the writing on the wall. Anyone can observe the points his made and will see an unstable future ahead if they&#39;re honest with themselves. Even this relatively independent institution has been or is being captured now. I think of a cartoon picture I saw where &quot;small government&quot; is promoted and the frames progress from left with checks and balances, to the right with 1 man in control of everything. The country has abandoned everything it was supposed to stand for.</p><p>I&#39;m still optimistic for the country, but to rediscover and motivate the public to return to our idea of &quot;dream,&quot; a lot more suffering is going to take place before then. This feels like opening innings into a dark period ahead.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nevx86l/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:05:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/17/opinion/trump-economy-deportation-inflation.html?unlocked_article_code=1.m08.MDSj.AzwNv8eC_SAJ</link><title>The Trump Fantasy Is Unraveling (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Listen, we should not expect, nor count on, Trump supporters <em>ever</em> admitting fault, or changing direction. If you understand Sunk Cost Fallacy, they have invested so much in Trump, emotional and financial, they can NEVER admit they were wrong.</p><p>History has shown this to be true. Nixon supporters <em>still</em> love Nixon. Likewise, the US came to Iraq expecting to be hailed as liberators. Instead, we faced 30% of the country - the ruling class - who absolutely despised us and <em>loved</em> Saddam Hussein.</p><p>Trump supporters are with him until they breath their last. It&#39;s the rest of us who have to get things back on track.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/nf078lz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I was watching a documentary last night about Mussolini that had a line that resonated with me.</p><p>&quot;Fascists can&#39;t improve the lives of their supporters, but instead offer them the illusion of being involved in great events.&quot;</p><p>So it doesn&#39;t matter what happens to the economy, the facts don&#39;t matter. What matters is how MAGA makes its supporters feel.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/nf3meba/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In the context of the current political discourse in the United States, it can be stated that the Trump administration and its supporters in the Republican Party are taking certain actions aimed at consolidating power. One of the key aspects of this strategy is economic pressure on the population, which, in their opinion, contributes to a decrease in the well-being of citizens and, as a result, a decrease in their ability to resist and defend their rights.</p><p>According to this hypothesis, economic measures aimed at reducing the income of the population and increasing poverty can lead to a decrease in the level of education and overall social mobility. This, in turn, can create conditions for more effective manipulation of public opinion and control over the behavior of citizens. Thus, it is assumed that the poor and less educated segments of the population will be less able to organize mass protests and overthrow the existing political regime.</p><p>This approach is based on the assumption that economic instability and social inequality are factors contributing to the strengthening of authoritarian tendencies in politics. However, it is worth noting that this hypothesis requires further empirical research and analysis to confirm or refute its validity.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/neyqaz2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thanks for sharing the article. Do you think economic pain will cause these people to come to their senses? The farmers still seem to be in denial, even though they complain daily about not having workers and being unable to sell soybeans to China. None of the interviews I&#39;ve seen show people saying they wish they had voted for Kamala or that they would vote blue in the future. So, maybe they&#39;ll be fine with stagflation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/nezux3o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>given that paying legal workers will either cause increased prices or decreased profits, my bet is on contracted prison labor to fill the gap. which will incentivize increasing the prison population — i.e., slavery in name only, the constitutional path to reversal of reconstruction, which a significant block of white nationalist voters have desired since the 1860s</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/nf4jwyk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>For the people saying trump voters will never admit they were wrong: that only applies to like 40-50% of his voters at most.</p><p>I&#39;ve met plenty of people that you&#39;d look at and think right away they were MAGA, but in reality they&#39;re more to the middle and voted for him because they genuinely thought they&#39;d be getting 2017 prices again.</p><p>I think that&#39;s why the administration seems to be moving as swiftly as possible. They know their base is eroding.</p><p>EDIT: grammar</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/nf3a5t7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Is there anyone that sees light at the end of this tunnel? I used to think people would rise up and we would overcome this, but now I really have no faith. When it became obvious that Trump is a pedophile and these people still aren’t backing away from him, I kind of just gave up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyj44/the_trump_fantasy_is_unraveling/nf8v8lq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:41:05 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wsj.com/finance/regulation/debanking-banks-bias-92135ef9?st=Tf7ong</link><title>Banks Race to Prove They're Not Biased Against Conservatives (wsj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>So it looks like he was breaking the rules for his type of account, it got flagged and cancelled on review, then he decided that this was because he was Christian and used it to launch a media campaign claiming victimhood.</p><p>He&#39;s angry he got treated like everyone else and didn&#39;t get a special exception for being a religious person.</p><p>Which is what most conservatives think bias against them is, not being granted special privileges.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/neuoelr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What does a bank being Biased Against Conservatives even mean? They dont give out free money if you have a red hat?</p><p>American is being run by mad fools that are going to run your economy to the ground.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/nety3hq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Steve Happ was packing to leave Tennessee for an evangelical mission to Uganda in 2023 when Bank of America told him it was canceling his church’s bank account and his credit cards. </p><p>Happ, an elder at the Servants of Christ Church in Memphis, started to sweat. He had over $270,000 socked away at Bank of America in three accounts—all getting closed by the bank—including one for his charity that supports churches and orphanages in Uganda. He had bills due, five full-time employees to pay and money that was supposed to go to the orphanages for food.</p><p>Happ drove to his bank branch in Memphis, convinced there was a mistake. The letters from the bank said “we have determined you’re operating in a business type we have chosen not to service.” </p><p>Happ showed the letters to the branch manager he had known for years. She assured him that there must have been an error and left to check. She returned after 10 minutes.</p><p>“She came back sort of like a robot,” Happ said. “All she did was quote that very same line from the letters and say, ‘I’m sorry, I can’t talk to you about this.’” </p><p>Happ concluded that Bank of America didn’t want to work with Christian groups.</p><p>In a statement, Bank of America said it respected the work of Happ’s charity. It said it closed the accounts “solely because it operated a business outside the U.S. and provided debt collection services.” Bank of America said it doesn’t serve small-business clients outside the U.S., and Happ didn’t disclose that one of the accounts was tied to a business in Uganda. </p></blockquote><p>Church elder has a bank account for charity/business dealings in Uganda. Bank of America closes his accounts because they don&#39;t bank for small businesses in foreign countries. Bank of America does a poor job communicating this. Church elder decides he&#39;s being discriminated against for being Christian. </p><p>For fucks sake 🙄</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/neupcf5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s funny how the article goes “this guy runs a church which was banking with BoA. The church does some work in Uganda. BoA closed his accounts claiming the account type does not support business that does work internationally. They did it because he’s Christian”</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/nev5lwp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>church guy runs a business/non-profit in Uganda</p><p>doesn’t tell bank about it</p><p>makes a series of suspicious looking (presumably cash) deposits (from his parish)</p><p>tries to send money to Uganda (still hasn’t told bank about business/ non-profit in Uganda)</p><p>Account gets closed for obvious BSA/AML violations</p></blockquote><p>WHY ARE THESE EVIL “GLOBALIST” BANKS DEBANKING GOD FEARING CHRISTIANS</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/neww6bx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Happ showed the letters to the branch manager he had known for years. She assured him that there must have been an error and left to check. She returned after 10 minutes.</p><p>“She came back sort of like a robot,” Happ said. “All she did was quote that very same line from the letters and say, ‘I’m sorry, I can’t talk to you about this.’” </p></blockquote><p>Almost certainly a FATCA, OFAC, or BSA related close.  Banks are generally very tight lipped about that, they just shut the accounts down and don&#39;t say why.  People tend to think the employees at your local bank have access to this sort of info, they don&#39;t.  That manager almost certainly got on the phone and was told it was shut down by risk management with no additional details.  That&#39;s it.  </p><p>Banks aren&#39;t bad at this either, dude almost certainly had a history of shady looking transactions with countries that are on various OFAC lists.  You do that with any regularity, and the bank absolutely will kick you to the curb.   </p><blockquote><p>Happ concluded that Bank of America didn’t want to work with Christian groups.</p></blockquote><p>Of course he did lol.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/newgsjm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is all just a smoke screen for how often large crypto holders get debanked.  Accounts that are likely to get banks in legal hot water are bad for business.  Large crypto holders are more likely to fall in this category so they get flagged for extra scrutiny.  Sometimes banks decide this extra scrutiny is going to cost more than it&#39;s worth and just preemptively cancel the accounts.  If a new law goes into effect saying you can&#39;t cancel an account over politics, all these crypto bros have a new legal avenue to challenge their account cancellation.  Following that through, the average cost of cancelling an account goes up, the math changes, and they&#39;re less likely to have their account cancelled in the first place.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njya26/banks_race_to_prove_theyre_not_biased_against/newn2qm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 09:27:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2025/09/15/farmers-corn-soybean-economic-pressures-profits/86091737007/</link><title>American farmers warn this year feels especially dire. What happens next? (usatoday.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The majority of them voted for this. A lot of them will declare bankruptcy. They’ll sell their farms to big agro directly or to a middleman, who will then sell their farms to big agro. Maybe, just maybe, the new owners of their former farms will let them stay to work the land as sharecroppers, with the aid of the scarce few hands who haven’t been chased off by our government goon squad. </p><p>Those who are left might get a subsidy check of our tax dollars, if they are lucky, once our administration realizes they still need their votes, least while we continue to have elections anyways. And once the government finally announces some shitty trade deals (with some tariffs still obviously left in place) to sell to their dumbasses, they’ll vote for the bag of dicks who did this to them all over again. Lather, rinse, and repeat.</p><p>But I’m sure China will buy those soybeans any day now.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/netojib/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>These farmers voted for Trump and are begging for financial assistance meanwhile Trump is profiting off of crypto, renovating the White House Ballroom, and deploying soldiers and agents to Washington DC and LA. We&#39;re worse off without farmers, but this is the path they put us in, and they deserve everything that&#39;s happening to them.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/netypod/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Farmers will get an aid package (socialism) and then vote republican again. It will be an endless cycle of them crying when others get bailouts (student loans) but being entitled to a bailout only for themselves.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/nevyaci/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I mean this genuinely. Fuck them. We shouldn&#39;t be bailing out failed businesses. That&#39;s the free market telling them it&#39;s time to close up shop and move on. Grow weed or something else instead.</p><p>We shouldn&#39;t be propping up failed businesses just so they feel better. Adapt or perish. If your soy farms aren&#39;t getting the business they used to, pivot to something else. Don&#39;t expect the government to just bail you out whenever things aren&#39;t going your way.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/netu0ws/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Interestingly, this article doesn’t seem to indicate who a majority of these affected farmers voted for. I wonder if there’s any way to discover which candidates a majority of these farmers voted for? As a great turtle once said, “elections have consequences.”</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/netonml/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They complain, get a government bailout that they delude themselves is different than any other kind of government welfare, refuse to elaborate why it’s not welfare, then gaslight for you thinking that what they got what was objectively socialism, then vote for the same kind of politician that put them in this situation. Rinse and repeat for their entire lives without ever having the courage to admit that they are massive entitled hypocrites.  </p><p>In other words American conservatism.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/neuabf9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The median wealth of farm households in the US is $1.4 million.  Far higher than non farm households.    For non farm households it&#39;s $175,000.   Let not cry for the poor farmers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwvuv/american_farmers_warn_this_year_feels_especially/nevhtor/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:15:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wsj.com/economy/us-economy-analysis-wealthy-low-income-8ba80ccc?st=V1Ue94</link><title>The Two-Speed Economy Is Back as Low-Income Americans Give Up Gains (wsj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwos3/the_twospeed_economy_is_back_as_lowincome/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwos3/the_twospeed_economy_is_back_as_lowincome/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwos3/the_twospeed_economy_is_back_as_lowincome/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>And the blue collar low income vote went to whom? People who voted on the basis of hate for others and never think that it would come back and affect them. Well, leopard eat face.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwos3/the_twospeed_economy_is_back_as_lowincome/netwv6w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>System predicated on the already wealthy getting more wealth and power while those without suffer continues to run. In other news, the moon is in the night sky tonight.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwos3/the_twospeed_economy_is_back_as_lowincome/neua0lp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:05:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/15/business/chinas-snub-of-us-soybeans-is-a-crisis-for-american-farmers.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mE8.owWy.o4cddSKR3fwk</link><title>China's Snub of U.S. Soybeans Is a Crisis for American Farmers (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>They wanted this just like last time. Not like it matters. Apparently Brazil has filled the soybean orders for China and by next year they will have replaced American contracts. </p><p>The soybean farmers will move to other crops and what will happen will be an increase in competition for cash crops as more of them switch over causing profitability concerns.</p><p>None of this will translate to cheaper &quot;soybeans&quot; at the super market in America. Because of capitalism, they rather let it rot and lose money than condition you to accept cheaper products</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netn1ey/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Oh it’s a “crisis” for the people that voted for the guy that said he would do this? The same people that won’t say that they regret their vote? </p><p>That’s not a crisis. It’s a result they voted for.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netjia6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We are now getting to the &quot;finding out&quot; phase after &quot;fucking around&quot;. We&#39;re in for a world of economic hurt, and Trump his &quot;yes men&quot; are all to blame. Plenty of economists warned against this, but I&#39;m sure we&#39;ll hear the usual &quot;how could we have known&quot; responses from Trump et. al.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netkgu7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They suffered eight years ago when Trump did it the first time, did they really expect anything different? They don&#39;t care because they&#39;re the new welfare queens receiving massive payouts any time Trump cripples their industry.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netlprh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Oh no. Anyway, you were saying? Oh you were talking about how some people can&#39;t handle the consequences of their own actions? Like when they fuck up and find out? And when they realize that all the Obama blaming on Fox News is not gonna make their own lives better?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netk4hz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s not a crisis, it’s a way for American soybean farmers to rob their fellow citizens and inflate the currency by way yet another Bailout. They get to hate trans and people of color while receiving cash money from those same individuals. It’s pathetic but it’s no different than the first Trump administration.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netkurv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It would be easier to sympathize if they learned anything from their mistake.  Instead, the lesson they learn is to grab the hot stove harder.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netmoxi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:02:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/15/business/long-term-unemployment-college-grads.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mE8.arOw.vIAHfDsj3jrl</link><title>The Newest Face of Long-Term Unemployment? The College Educated. (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I don’t want to minimize people’s hardship here but I never like when the say things like “the highest in three years.” That really tells us nothing—three years ago the labor market was on an all time heater and pandemic ripple effects were still going on. Why frame it that way when you have a nice 25 year graph right below?</p><p>Secondarily I’m surprised it’s not often the case that college grads are out of work longer. Especially as you get into mid career in white collar work you probably should expect it to take a bit longer to find a good match, but the guy getting fired from Kroger can walk over to Walmart, you know? Is there some bulge of population in the middle of their careers right now?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/netxsg3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We&#39;re really missing the point here if we blame it on &quot;too many grads.&quot; It&#39;s still a classic supply and demand issue.</p><p>Sure, more people have degrees now, so of course they’re a bigger share of the unemployed. But we can&#39;t downplay how employers don’t seem to value degrees the way they used to. Tech layoffs, automation creeping into professional tasks, even government cutbacks; that’s where the real shift is.</p><p>And this isn&#39;t even a new trend, hasn’t the “college premium” been shrinking for years? The “college premium” was based on scarce skills. Once degrees became common and tasks got automated, the scarcity disappeared. That’s why the payoff is shrinking. Feels like the story here isn’t just cyclical weakness but a deeper restructuring of what counts as “skilled” work.</p><p>If that’s true, the question isn’t “why are grads struggling now?” We should be asking whether the degree itself is losing its long-term payoff. It&#39;s hard to say if the demand for the skills of these college graduates are going to rebound with our current direction in AI and tech. We really should be looking into that perspective instead.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/netly7j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Honestly, no one caught this line?</p><blockquote><p>“Such an increase is unprecedented outside of recessions,” said <a href="https://www.richmondfed.org/research/national_economy/macro_minute/2025/july_labor_market_dumbbell_shaped_dangers?utm_source=newsletter&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=newsletter_axiosmarkets&amp;stream=business">an economist</a> at the Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, alluding to a steady worsening of the long-term unemployment rate.</p></blockquote></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/nevph5e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I hear a lot about how college is useless now and there are better investments.</p><p>Ok… show me a billionaires son in trade school.</p><p>My cynical ass is thinking “ok they know their kid is just a nepo baby, and doesn’t have the chops to make it, maybe they just want less competition?”</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/nevk1oa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>White collar job markets are pretty bad right now. As seen by the terrible jobs numbers for pretty much every sector outside of healthcare and eldercare. Long term unemployment being primarily the college educated and new grads just entering the workforce also seem to support this. Usually, people aren&#39;t getting a degree in law to work in blue collar.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/neywq6s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I wonder how the Right is going to weaponize this?  Will they call for &quot;college is bad for folks to get a job, trades/construction are better&quot; to play on their base?</p><p>I already have heard that a ton on reddit and its simply not truth based on data but this narrative that is being pushed is being very very weird.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/nev0vfk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I am a peak-years boomer.  We all had some tough times 1979-82.  We had graduated in the middle of a steep recession and high inflation. Our student loan rates were well over 10% (mine was almost 13%!!).  Starting wages were lower because there were so many of us.  Today&#39;s environment is much better. Stop whining.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwkof/the_newest_face_of_longterm_unemployment_the/newd108/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:00:20 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/live/2024/09/18/business/fed-interest-rates</link><title>Fed lowers interest rates by a quarter point, first time in 9 months (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Inflation has increased some and is higher than the <a href="https://www.cbo.gov/publication/60870">2.1%</a> CBO projected for this year back in January...but also job growth has slowed dramatically. So it&#39;s not the easiest decision. They decided the risk from a decidely more negative economic outlook surpasses the inflation risk. Never mind the 2% target.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/ner0gui/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tariffs are the primary driver of the weak jobs numbers and this is a supply-side issue. While inflation is still sticky, trying to address the jobs with a demand-side rate cut will not fix the problem. If the cause of weakening jobs growth is known, addressing the demand side will not increase the demand. It’ll inflate asset prices and continue to drive up inflation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/ner2edt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Powell did indicate that they will be cautious with future rate cuts (EURUSD immediately reversed from 1.19 when he said that). I&#39;d say that unemployment will keep ticking up while inflation will be sticky (but only around 3%). Of course, 3% is bad but it is still not runaway inflation and if the choice is between 2% inflation with 6% unemployment or 3% inflation with 5% unemployment, then probably the FED will go for the second one in this situation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/ner8dz3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I really don&#39;t see how this helps. The free money era gave us a lot of stock buybacks, ridiculous things like SPACs, even dumber things like crypto as an asset, with not a lot of actual value created.</p><p>I&#39;ll argue it even fueled the housing crisis because cash flow from houses now exceeded borrowing rates.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/ner3cv9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This narrative of &quot;low&quot; unemployment is made possible by the absurdly low threshold to be considered employed in the first place. The BLS just requires having been paid for 1 hour as an employee or as a self-employed person during its reference week, and it&#39;s become much easier to technically meet that low standard via gig work and freelancing, which tend to be dead ends.</p><p>A 4.X% unemployment rate now is arguably much worse than a 4.X% unemployment rate compared to even ~5 years ago. The low and binary standard of employed or not needs more context than just broad sector categorizations. In healthcare, for example, phlebotomists and social workers are lumped together with surgeons and anesthesiologists. It would be helpful to know the median wage of the jobs added/lost on a monthly basis and a breakdown of permanent vs. contract positions.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/ner2f0w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This FOMC, even before Trump, is run by a bunch of idiotic knuckleheads whose #1 priority is to inflate asset prices &amp; please Wall Street. The median FOMC voter has a $5 million+ net worth and is heavily invested in the S&amp;P 500, all the way up to Powell ($50-100M NW)</p><p>Per the SEP, they’re giving themselves until 2028 for inflation to hit 2%. That would be over 7 STRAIGHT YEARS ABOVE TARGET. Meanwhile, unemployment ticked up from 4.2% to 4.3% and they’re scrambling to lower rates again. </p><p>Get ready for a decade of high inflation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/neqyldw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tbh from my own personal economic POV, I’m worried about jobs and growth than if inflation continues to run at 2-4%. This is overall the right decision in my opinion. If it goes above 5% there is definitely time to worry but we are running the risk of a recession or we might actually have been in one outside of AI for the past 3 years as some people say which I tend to agree with</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njksnj/fed_lowers_interest_rates_by_a_quarter_point/ner5vsw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:43:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nbcnews.com/business/economy/federal-reserve-interest-rates-decision-rcna231729</link><title>Federal Reserve cuts interest rates for the first time this year (nbcnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Is this likely to really have any meaningful ramifications on employment? To me it seems like business are not hiring or planning investments because of policy uncertainty, not because high interest rates are preventing them from doing so.</p><p>It&#39;s the wrong medicine for the underlying disease. I feel like the employment issues gave them the narrative to cut despite inflation. They have to try and get yields down to refinance their debt burden.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqz8lm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Inflation has increased some and is higher than the <a href="https://www.cbo.gov/publication/60870">2.1%</a> CBO projected for this year back in January...but also job growth has slowed dramatically. So it&#39;s not the easiest decision. They decided the risk from a decidely more negative economic outlook surpasses the inflation risk. Never mind that long sought after 2% target.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/ner3x4s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This was basically the only thing to do based on data I suppose.</p><p>The labor market is cooling down and has been this entire year, and while inflation is obviously going up, the unemployment and the economy was the bigger issue for the Fed.</p><p>In an ideal world, the Fed would have cut rates without having to worry about inflation and not because the market was cooling down and had to be saved, but because it was a stable time and they could just look forward.</p><p>Instead.....sigh.</p><p>Anyway, if the people were complaining about inflation last year.....lol.</p><p>What&#39;s funny is that I don&#39;t see even half the cries about inflation now in the media like they did in 2024 with Biden, even though pretty much everything has very noticeably increased and will increase even more. The media environment is so bad that if the same media existed in the 70s, Nixon would never have had to resign. Which of course was the point of Roger Ailes creating Fox News, so his dream came true.</p><p>I sometimes wonder if Trump isn&#39;t just a Russian asset, but also a Democrat asset, because he&#39;s doing everything in his power to ruin the GOP for a generation a la Herbert Hoover lmao. Not that it will happen, people love their parties like its their family dynasty.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqvves/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Is inflation really only around 3%. I feel like I&#39;m being gaslit when everyone is saying this yet my budget shows a 20% increase in general expenses.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/ner78l4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As expected. Will be interesting to see how many dissent on both sides (no rate cuts versus larger rate cuts), and what the &quot;dot plot&quot; looks like for the future.</p><p>I think the Fed made the best choice given the data currently available to it (along with likely projected trajectories of labor markets, growth, and inflation).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqw3dy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There&#39;s not much he can really do really; inflation isn&#39;t coming down and the job market even after Trump cooking the books shows the economy isn&#39;t doing well.  Damned if you do, damned if you don&#39;t moment.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqzpd1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Even though inflation is still 3% the Federal Reserve was so worried about unemployment that they had to lower rates. That said pretty much means the economy has fallen into the tank ever since Donald J Trump took office. Sad believe him and all the Republican traitors that follow him.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/nesb2uq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:36:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-17/fico-scores-fall-at-fastest-rate-since-financial-crisis-mfo4a5hy</link><title>Gen Z Leads Biggest Drop in FICO Scores Since Financial Crisis (bloomberg.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I’m assuming that this is almost assuredly tied to the resumption of student loan payments, which had been on deferment until late 2023, then had a 1 year “ramp-up” back to normal ending in late 2024. Since the beginning of this year payments are pretty much back to business as usual (as far as I am aware) and as such, delinquencies are increasing causing credit hits.</p><p>The current state of the labor market certainly isn’t helping this which may be why the Fed was onboard with a rate cut to try and stimulate hiring in some capacity.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/neqzghu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I see a troubling trend with young people: they have zero hope in a better future.</p><p>“Who care about a credit score when I’ll never be able to afford a home?” Is something I can imagine hearing echoed across the generation.</p><p>Our entire society has been structured to siphon off wealth from the poor and young, and funnel it into the greedy mouths of the rich and old. Yet they act surprised when, after robbing all hope of a better life, young people act nihilistically?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nerjqt2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There has been a lot of indications that the economy is being carried by increasing debt and this looks like another one. We are at peak margin loan debt and credit card debt in an environment with very punitive interest rates. At some point, especially for folks &lt;30, it just makes more sense to default and declare bankruptcy. If enough folks do that you end up with a financial crisis. As an anecdotal sidenote, all of my Gen Z family and co-workers seem incredibly flippant about credit in general. It seems to be a combo of ignorance and fatalism. If that mentality proves too common we could have big long term issues.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nerbttl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As a millenial I feel so relieved now that gen z has taken the mantle of dealing with stupid journalists. My advice to them is to save on avocado toast and labubus.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/neuxvf8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There’s no way to sugar-coat this. Fico numbers are basically unreliable at this point. Not only did they not capture student loans until recently, but they also are not fully capturing the bnpl debts which are estimated to be tremendous, given how little time they have existed.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/ner77ty/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is a drop from like 717 to 715 on the overall score whereas the drop before 2008 was a 3 point drop to about 678</p><p>Important context. Although the Gen Z figure is interesting. 676 is where that cohort is at. Would be interested to see where that number has been historically.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nesegbg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Does this country understand that you can just invest in US Stocks and NOT invest in the young people that will have to run and staff those companies? Hello?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nexip0f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:27:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/09/17/business/federal-reserve-interest-rates</link><title>From a purely economic lens, I don't understand why public speculation is tilted towards a rate cut of all things? (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Some of the slowdown in secondary labor market indicators that suggest the likelihood of a recession have increased, along with the credit and borrowing constraints facing low income households based on interest rates, suggest that they view spurring economic activity as more of a need, at this point, relative to inflation (which COULD be one-time from tariffs).</p><p>The WSJ outlined these yesterday, but also pointed out that it was likely that there would be considerable dissensions on both sides (no rate cuts; higher rate cuts than 0.25 pp). Healthy debate on this is important.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/neqe7h2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>WDYM public speculation?  The Fed has been very clearly telegraphing that we&#39;re getting a cut for weeks now.  The only people debating that are the laymen who aren&#39;t paying attention to anything in the actual financial world.  </p><p>There&#39;s no real speculation leading up to these meetings anymore - the Fed very clearly telegraphs intent well in advance.  The more important part of the meeting today is going to be what&#39;s said in the presser after.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/neqcrvo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I expect a decrease of .25% but also an indication that this is a one time and not part of larger trend already being contemplated of further cuts.  I think a small cut says the fed is less worried about inflation than it is of the job market slowing which is I think the bigger danger to the economy now.  The fed has to play a bit of the politic game and give a bit to get the pressure off but also set a tone that any rate cuts are not part of a larger easing on rates</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/neqk286/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They can cut the rate, but this won&#39;t help with any of the stressors playing into the Economy right now. </p><p>We have a rich people economy and a poor people economy, guess what side is gonna hurt with the interest rate cut ... </p><p>This won&#39;t likely reverse the course we are seeing towards a recession but recession is gonna be for the poors not the rich the rich will continue making us fight each other while they take a loan for their 4th jet</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/neqgyjh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>“From a purely economic lens” my good man, we don’t live in a world where can separate things like this. There’s politics involved too, just look at <em>gestures around</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/neqh2tt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I think the rate cut seems to be a relative certainty, though as a lay person I don&#39;t understand how it&#39;s an alleviation of well... anything going on economically right now. Businesses are taking the extra capital and doing stock buybacks, and since tarriffs and other policy items are what is causing a huge instability for them, they are taking the conservative approach and doing no more hiring. I work for a bank, and we&#39;ve been told to expect to be &quot;flat or down&quot; into next year.</p><p>Ultimately if the rate cut happens, I don&#39;t know that unemployment is helped at all because policy issues are why businesses aren&#39;t investing. The dollar being weak through this year already, and then adding a rate cut only making it worse -- just impacts the cost of the goods we buy today, especially as it&#39;s relevant for the average person buying groceries, or electricity, gas, etc.</p><p>The Fed at this point has only a few tools so I understand its limitation, but like I said... I don&#39;t see much improvement from things like this for the average person.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/neqiagr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tariff induced inflation will not be a one-time hit, the length of the impact will depend on several factors.</p><ol><li><p>What we’ve seen is that stockpiles in the U.S. has prevented a widespread surge in prices. Earlier in the year it was suggested stockpiles will last into September. </p></li><li><p>Companies absorb the costs initially to remain competitive, but when profit margins are hit, they begin to raise prices partially. Depending on the impact, they may pass the entire tariff cost to customers at a later time. </p></li><li><p>If competitors go out of business and there are few alternatives. Some unscrupulous sellers may raise prices again to improve profit margins. </p></li><li><p>One thing that is a certainty, all the companies affected by tariffs will NOT raise prices simultaneously. Hence a one time hit is practically an impossibility.</p></li></ol></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nji4i7/from_a_purely_economic_lens_i_dont_understand_why/ner4uy6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 22:06:31 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
