<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:27:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2025/09/job-market-hell/684133/?gift=Vowm9zXD_VpjYJtYApIfy6iqYdFY6568omVJ07mz1tc</link><title>The Job Market Is Hell: Young people are using ChatGPT to write their applications; HR is using AI to read them; no one is getting hired. (theatlantic.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbrilo/the_job_market_is_hell_young_people_are_using/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/J-0rMrIxnE3yFSvDEPugUb2U1Zk=/0x43:2000x1085/1200x625/media/img/mt/2025/09/2025_6_7_Impossible_To_Get_A_Job/original.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Listen to more stories on the <a href="https://newsoveraudio.com/?offerId=atl_reader_exclusive_jks1kjl"> Noa</a> app.</p></div><section><p>Harris started looking for his first real job months before his graduation from UC Davis this spring. He had a solid r&eacute;sum&eacute;, he thought: a paid internship at a civic-consulting firm, years of volunteering at environmental-defense organizations, experience working on farms and in parks as well as in offices, a close-to-perfect GPA, strong letters of recommendation. He would move anywhere on the West Coast, living out of his car if he had to. He would accept a temporary, part-time, or seasonal gig, not just a full-time position. He would do anything&mdash;filing paperwork, digging trenches&mdash;to build his dream career protecting California&rsquo;s wildlife and public lands.</p><p>He applied to 200 jobs. He got rejected 200 times. Actually, he clarified, he &ldquo;didn&rsquo;t get <em>rejected</em> 200 times.&rdquo; A lot of businesses never responded.</p><p>Right now, millions of would-be workers find themselves in a similar position. Corporate profits <a href="https://www.bea.gov/data/income-saving/corporate-profits">are strong</a>, the jobless rate is 4.3 percent, and wages are <a href="https://www.atlantafed.org/chcs/wage-growth-tracker">climbing in turn</a>. But payrolls have been essentially frozen for the past four months. The hiring rate has declined to <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/JTSHIR">its lowest point</a> since the jobless recovery following the Great Recession. Four years ago, employers were adding four or five workers for every 100 they had on the books, month in and month out. Now they are adding three.</p><p>At the same time, the process of getting a job has become a late-capitalist nightmare. Online hiring platforms have made it easier to find an opening but harder to secure one: Applicants send out thousands of AI-crafted r&eacute;sum&eacute;s, and businesses use AI to sift through them. What Bumble and Hinge did to the dating market, contemporary human-resources practices have done to the job market. People are swiping like crazy and getting nothing back.</p><p>Every time Harris logged in to LinkedIn or Indeed, he would see scores of gigs that seemed like they might be a good fit. He would read a posting carefully, scrub his r&eacute;sum&eacute;, tailor an introductory note, answer the company&rsquo;s screening questions, hit &ldquo;Send,&rdquo; hope for the best, and hear nothing in response&mdash;again and again and again.</p><p>Other job seekers described similar experiences. In suburban Virginia, a paralegal named Martine got laid off by a government contractor in April. (Like Harris, she did not want to dim her employment prospects by providing her full name.) She saw plenty of jobs being advertised at nonprofits, law firms, consultancies, and universities. She sent out dozens of applications. She even got to the second round a few times. But she never came close to being hired. &ldquo;I have 10 years of experience,&rdquo; she told me. &ldquo;I would be happy if a person told me no at this point.&rdquo;</p><p>For employers, the job market is working differently too. Businesses receive countless ill-fitting applications, along with a few good ones, for each open position. Rather than poring over the submissions by hand, they use machines. In a recent survey, chief HR officers told the Boston Consulting Group that they are <a href="https://www.bcg.com/publications/2025/ai-changing-recruitment">using AI</a> to write job descriptions, assess candidates, schedule introductory meetings, and evaluate applications. In some cases, firms are using chatbots to interview candidates, too. Prospective hires log in to a Zoom-like system and field questions from an avatar. Their performance is taped, and an algorithm searches for keywords and evaluates their tone.</p><p>Priya Rathod, a career-trends expert at Indeed, told me she understands why job seekers feel as if their r&eacute;sum&eacute;s are &ldquo;going into a void.&rdquo; But she argued that the online platforms make it easier for people to find open positions and that AI can &ldquo;get them to the next stage of the interview quicker,&rdquo; if their applications fit an employer&rsquo;s needs.</p><p>Still, a lot of job applicants never end up in a human-to-human process. The impossibility of getting to the interview stage spurs jobless workers to submit more applications, which pushes them to rely on ChatGPT to build their r&eacute;sum&eacute;s and respond to screening prompts. (Harris told me he does this; he used ChatGPT pretty much every day in college, and finds its writing to be more &ldquo;professional&rdquo; than his own.) And so the cycle continues: The surge in same-same AI-authored applications prompts employers to use robot filters to manage the flow. Everyone ends up in Tinderized job-search hell.</p><p>For months, the economy has been in a low-hire, low-fire equilibrium; virtually every sector of the labor market except for health care has been frozen. The amount of time a worker has spent looking for a job has climbed to an average of <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNU03008276">10 weeks</a>, meaning that Americans are spending two weeks longer on the job market than they were a few years ago. The share of American workers quitting a job has fallen to its lowest <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/JTSQUR">level in a decade</a>, because of concerns about rising prices and jitters about slowing growth.</p><p>The equilibrium now seems to be falling apart, and a full-on recession looks likely. Black workers have experienced a dramatic <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNS14000006">surge in joblessness</a>, in part because of the Trump administration&rsquo;s mass layoffs of federal employees. (The 154,000 civil servants who took the White House&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">&ldquo;</a><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">Fork in the Road</a><a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/02/doge-musk-federal-agencies-takeover/681744/">&rdquo;</a> deferred-resignation offer will receive their last <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/2025/07/31/federal-workers-doge-buyout-paid/">paycheck this month</a>.) More than 10 percent of workers under the age of 24 are searching for <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/LNS14024887">a job</a>. &ldquo;Performance-based and strategic layoffs are increasing,&rdquo; Lydia Boussour of the consultancy EY-Parthenon wrote in a note to clients last week. &ldquo;Cracks are increasingly showing.&rdquo;</p><p>What is a worker supposed to do? Martine and Harris and millions like them are still trying to figure that out; she keeps on applying, whereas he is doing landscaping and volunteering. Rathod said that she recommends old-fashioned networking: asking recruiters out for coffee, going to in-person job events, and surveying friends and former employers for leads.</p><p>Such strategies might work if employers begin hiring again. But if not, millions more people might be left pitching their CVs into the void.</p></section><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://cdn.theatlantic.com/thumbor/G3J3fAQrlILC_OcsAGs76IWlZmo=/438x0:1563x1125/80x80/media/img/mt/2025/09/2025_6_7_Impossible_To_Get_A_Job/original.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:25:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ft.com/content/97e42e98-46ee-4752-b80e-ea0ca947c813</link><title>Donald Trump warns multinationals to respect immigration laws after Hyundai raid -- “We encourage you to LEGALLY bring your very smart people, with great technical talent, to build World Class products,” stated the president (ft.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbnnbj/donald_trump_warns_multinationals_to_respect/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbnnbj/donald_trump_warns_multinationals_to_respect/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbnnbj/donald_trump_warns_multinationals_to_respect/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><div><p><span></span><span>Subscribe to unlock this article</span></p></div><div><h2><span><span>Try unlimited access</span></span></h2><h2><span><span>Only </span><span>Rs100</span><span> for 4 weeks</span></span></h2><p><span><span>Then </span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month. Complete digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Cancel anytime during your trial.</span></span></p></div></div><div><h2>Explore more offers.</h2><div><div><div><p><img src="https://images.ft.com/v3/image/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fbarrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fassets%2Ficons%2Fprimary_product_icon_ftedit.svg?format=svg&amp;source=next-barrier-page" alt></p><h3>FT Edit</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4490</span><span> per year</span></span></p><p><span><span>Access to eight surprising articles a day, hand-picked by FT editors. For seamless reading, access content via the FT Edit page on FT.com and receive the FT Edit newsletter.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Standard Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs2850</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Essential digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Premium Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Complete digital access to quality FT journalism with expert analysis from industry leaders. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div></div></div><div><h2>Explore our full range of subscriptions.</h2><div><div><div><h3>For individuals</h3></div><p>Discover all the plans currently available in your country</p></div><div><div><h3> For multiple readers</h3></div><p>Digital access for organisations. Includes exclusive features and content.</p></div></div></div><div><div><h2>Why the FT?</h2><p>See why over a million readers pay to read the Financial Times.</p></div><p><a href="https://subs.ft.com/whytheft?ft-content-uuid=97e42e98-46ee-4752-b80e-ea0ca947c813">Find out why</a></p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://images.ft.com/v3/image/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fbarrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fassets%2Ficons%2Fprimary_product_icon_standard.svg?format=svg&amp;source=next-barrier-page"></p><p><img src="https://images.ft.com/v3/image/raw/https%3A%2F%2Fbarrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com%2Fassets%2Ficons%2Fprimary_product_icon_premium.svg?format=svg&amp;source=next-barrier-page"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:53:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.techspot.com/news/109365-biden-era-noncompete-ban-collapses-ftc-withdraws-appeal.html</link><title>Biden-era noncompete ban collapses as FTC withdraws appeal | The FTC reversal leaves millions of workers still bound by noncompetes (techspot.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbmkqp/bidenera_noncompete_ban_collapses_as_ftc/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbmkqp/bidenera_noncompete_ban_collapses_as_ftc/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nbmkqp/bidenera_noncompete_ban_collapses_as_ftc/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 18:07:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3324637/top-harvard-mathematician-liu-jun-leaves-us-china</link><title>Top Harvard mathematician Liu Jun leaves US for China (scmp.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb87bl/top_harvard_mathematician_liu_jun_leaves_us_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb87bl/top_harvard_mathematician_liu_jun_leaves_us_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb87bl/top_harvard_mathematician_liu_jun_leaves_us_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/09/07/45fcea36-18e9-4c9b-84ca-2f6143efce05_5ad33423.jpg?itok=9gU6RQL7&v=1757218100' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><p>Liu Jun, one of the world&rsquo;s leading statisticians and a long-time professor at Harvard, has returned to China full-time, accepting a prestigious chair at Tsinghua University last month.</p><p>The move marks the <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3309548/wanted-china-born-researchers-leave-us-work-china-attractive-pay?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>homecoming of an academic</span></a> whose career has spanned research in data science, biostatistics and <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/artificial-intelligence?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>artificial intelligence</span></a> &ndash; and whose early life reflected the complex interplay between intellectual pursuit and political engagement.</p><p>In 1988, Liu Jun transferred from Rutgers University in New Jersey to the University of Chicago, studying under statistician Wing Hung Wong.</p><p>While there, he became deeply interested in human rights issues and spent a considerable amount of time <a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3201760/inspired-rare-protests-mainland-chinese-students-north-america-organise-and-speak-out?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>taking part in student protests</span></a>.</p><p>The student movement he supported did not occur in Chicago, but in Beijing.</p><p>In 1989, students held a <a href="https://www.scmp.com/topics/tiananmen-square-crackdown?module=inline&amp;pgtype=article" title><span>massive demonstration in Tiananmen Square</span></a> and overseas student groups have organised events in support of the cause. Liu was so actively involved in student activities in the United States that his mentor asked him if he wanted to be &ldquo;a politician or a mathematician?&rdquo;</p><p>This question was a turning point for Liu. After careful consideration, he decided to pursue a career in maths.</p></section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 04:57:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.yahoo.com/news/articles/gen-z-laughing-face-ai-123000930.html</link><title>Gen Z is laughing in the face of the AI jobs apocalypse. I see it in my classroom every day (yahoo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb75et/gen_z_is_laughing_in_the_face_of_the_ai_jobs/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb75et/gen_z_is_laughing_in_the_face_of_the_ai_jobs/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb75et/gen_z_is_laughing_in_the_face_of_the_ai_jobs/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/OXXk4G_Z0xF8yIpq2xr_rQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTEyMDA7aD04MDA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://media.zenfs.com/en/fortune_175/98bce0b897220e2a353181756b6cdcc1' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><header><div><p>Jeff LeBlanc</p><div><p><time>Sat, September 6, 2025 at 12:30 PM UTC</time></p><p>4 min read</p></div></div></header><div><figure><figcaption><p>I've seen that laugh many times.</p></figcaption></figure></div></div><div><p>In my strategy class this spring, a student leaned back during a discussion about automation and quipped, &ldquo;Well, we aren&rsquo;t going to get a job anyway because of AI, so who cares?&rdquo; Laughter rippled across the room. It was quick, light&mdash;even comforting. But beneath the jokes lay a tense reality. This feeling is the elephant in the room for many young people: they sense the job market evolving under AI&rsquo;s influence, and they&rsquo;re not sure where they&rsquo;ll fit.</p><p>When I asked several students if they ever talk seriously about AI replacing jobs, one replied, &ldquo;Not really. If you think about it too much, it feels hopeless.&rdquo; Another said, &ldquo;We just figure something else will come along. Or maybe we&rsquo;ll figure out how to work with it.&rdquo; Humor has become a coping tool&mdash;a way to acknowledge the threat without dwelling on it.</p><p>This sentiment is grounded in data.&nbsp;A <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/08/06/goldman-sachs-economist-gen-z-tech-jobs-ai-labor-market/">Goldman Sachs analysis</a> shows that Gen Z tech workers are experiencing higher unemployment than older generations, with rates among 20-to-30-year-olds up nearly 3 percentage points since early 2024&mdash;over four times the national average increase. Joseph Briggs, a senior economist at Goldman Sachs, warns that&nbsp;<a href="https://observenow.com/2025/08/goldman-sachs-economist-warns-gen-z-tech-workers-could-be-first-to-lose-jobs-to-ai/?utm_source=chatgpt.com">&ldquo;those performing the most easily automated tasks&mdash;often the most junior employees&mdash;are naturally the most vulnerable.&rdquo;</a> Yet even among this landscape, roughly 42% of Gen Z workers have used AI to inform career decisions&mdash;the highest of any generation&mdash;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1mll0dp/goldman_sachs_economist_warns_gen_z_tech_workers/?utm_source=chatgpt.com">one in five say AI suggested a career path they hadn&rsquo;t considered before</a>.</p><p>Gen Z isn&rsquo;t the first generation shaped by turbulence. Millennials faced the 2008 recession, Gen <a href="https://fortune.com/company/twitter/">X</a> experienced offshoring, and Boomers watched industries automate. But AI&rsquo;s rapid scope and reach set this moment apart. A&nbsp;2025 SHRM survey found that 80% of employers expect entry-level job descriptions to shift significantly within three years because of AI.</p><p>Some students are already hedging: gravitating toward fields that seem more human-centric&mdash;mental health, skilled trades, education&mdash;and others are diving into AI skills, hoping to stay ahead. A few are building side gigs early: freelancing, tutoring, and part-time creative work. One student captured it best: &ldquo;If AI really changes everything, we can&rsquo;t control it. So I&rsquo;d rather focus on what I can do now.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s a blend of pragmatism and fatalism that feels uniquely Gen Z.</p><p>But the risk is that humor can mask passivity. Laughing off the threat may ease the moment but doesn&rsquo;t set up long-term preparedness. These same laughs surface in TikToks about job interview awkwardness, tales of the &ldquo;Gen Z stare&rdquo; in service roles, and viral &ldquo;workplace hacks&rdquo; like CC-ing fake lawyers to protect oneself from bad bosses&mdash;shared because they make real work anxieties feel relatable.</p><p>Is that enough? According to economist Tyler <a href="https://fortune.com/company/cowen/">Cowen</a> of George Mason University, not entirely. He argues that college curricula are overfocused on routine skills&mdash;content that AI can now handle better&mdash;and recommends dedicating up to <a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/economist-tyler-cowen-college-students-trained-jobs-ai-work-2025-8?utm_source=chatgpt.com">one-third of higher education to teaching students how to use AI</a>, understand its limits, and cultivate critical thinking and mentorship capacities that AI can&rsquo;t replicate.</p><p>The challenge is for educators, employers, and policymakers to build on Gen Z&rsquo;s humor, adaptability, and intelligence&mdash;not shy away from it. Laughter is part of their cultural toolkit, a way to defuse tension and build connection, but it should be paired with clear-eyed preparation. Laughing through uncertainty isn&rsquo;t inherently harmful; in fact, it can signal resilience. Yet if humor becomes the only response, it risks leaving deeper concerns unaddressed.</p><p>Helping this generation see beyond the joke means showing them how to translate quick wit into strategic thinking. That might involve embedding AI literacy into every discipline, encouraging students to treat emerging tools as collaborators rather than threats, or designing workplace mentorship programs that help young employees connect short-term problem-solving with long-term career planning. It also means rewarding adaptability not just when things go wrong, but when it&rsquo;s used proactively to anticipate change.</p><p>AI will reshape work in unexpected ways, touching industries from creative arts to healthcare logistics. It may introduce entirely new career categories, while making others obsolete faster than any previous wave of automation. The real question is whether Gen Z&rsquo;s combination of humor, adaptability, and caution will help them ride that wave&mdash;or whether they will find themselves reacting too late, caught in its undertow. For now, the laughter continues. The work ahead lies in making sure it is paired with the skills and foresight to turn uncertainty into opportunity.</p><div><h2>More in Technology</h2></div><p><em><em>The opinions expressed in Fortune.com commentary pieces are solely the views of their authors and do not necessarily reflect the opinions and beliefs of&nbsp;</em>Fortune<em>.</em></em></p><p>This story was originally featured on <a href="https://fortune.com/2025/09/06/gen-z-is-laughing-in-the-face-of-the-ai-jobs-apocalypse/">Fortune.com</a></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/om8Xf1Ur6UC7bnS6lpBibQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2MDtoPTYwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/2b82d430-3567-11eb-be1f-26e8c03de24e"></p><p><img src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/BkcvsRYihaoBF986onW3RQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2MDtoPTYwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-12/4a8cb0d0-3567-11eb-9bbd-46eddb1d0973"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 04:10:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.npr.org/2025/09/02/nx-s1-5521384/energy-report-scientists-climate-change</link><title>Dozens of scientists find errors in a new Department of Energy climate report (npr.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb04u5/dozens_of_scientists_find_errors_in_a_new/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb04u5/dozens_of_scientists_find_errors_in_a_new/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nb04u5/dozens_of_scientists_find_errors_in_a_new/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 23:32:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wsj.com/politics/trump-tech-ceo-rose-garden-dinner-1fee2de3?st=LbJtjB</link><title>Tech CEOs Take Turns Praising Trump at White House Dinner (wsj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1naw5hz/tech_ceos_take_turns_praising_trump_at_white/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1naw5hz/tech_ceos_take_turns_praising_trump_at_white/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1naw5hz/tech_ceos_take_turns_praising_trump_at_white/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 20:58:33 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.tomshardware.com/speakers/amazon-echo-uses-gigabytes-of-data-despite-not-being-used-its-owner-doesnt-think-hes-being-spied-on</link><title>Amazon Echo is reportedly an internet vampire that uses gigabytes of data per day despite being unused, says owner (tomshardware.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nai1dy/amazon_echo_is_reportedly_an_internet_vampire/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nai1dy/amazon_echo_is_reportedly_an_internet_vampire/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nai1dy/amazon_echo_is_reportedly_an_internet_vampire/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/9JpZbGHhznQN8gJF8s6Een.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><section><div><figcaption> <span>(Image credit: Amazon)</span> </figcaption> </div><div><p>An <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tag/amazon">Amazon</a> Echo owner has taken to social media to complain about their smart speakers, saying that the hardware is using too much data even when it's mostly unused. Dave W. Plummer, who helped develop the Windows Task Manager and ported Space Cadet Pinball to Windows, <a href="https://x.com/davepl1968/status/1963803025572770212">posted on X</a> saying that his two Amazon Echo Show devices, which he said he "never" uses, exceeded 4 GB of data usage in 24 hours.</p><p>According to the image Plummer shared, he has two Amazon Echo Show devices, which are smart speakers with a touchscreen interface designed to serve as a hub for smart homes. However, these devices are more than just digital switches; they also connect to the internet to send you notifications, install updates, and potentially sync with your cloud storage to display your pictures. With the screen, Echo Shows also update often to show traffic reports, news stories, and photos.</p><div><blockquote><p>I know it's a lot of folks' first assumption, but I highly doubt the Echo is always listening and uploading. That would be patently obvious to many people, and would have been detected long ago.Odds are it's (a) a bug, or (b) they both took big updates that day, or (c) it's&hellip;<a href="https://twitter.com/cantworkitout/status/1964006765441450105">September 5, 2025</a></p></blockquote></div><p>Plummer doesn't seem to think that Alexa is always listening to him. In <a href="https://x.com/davepl1968/status/1964006765441450105">a follow-up post</a>, he wrote that "Odds are it's (a) a bug, or (b) they both took big updates that day, or (c) it's cached video content. The Echo Show does video, so for all I know, it's downloading trailers of movies. But it ain't spying, I'd put money on that."</p><p>One commenter on Plummer&rsquo;s post speculated that if the smart speaker hears the activation command, such as &ldquo;Hey, <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tag/google">Google</a>&rdquo; or &ldquo;Alexa,&rdquo; it will record an <a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tag/audio">audio</a> clip of the environment and send it to its servers for processing. So, even if you didn&rsquo;t call the device, but hear something similar, it will still send information for analysis and recording, which will use up your data.</p><p>Other users also pointed to Amazon Sidewalk as the culprit. Sidewalk is a wide mesh network that allows Amazon devices to communicate with each other, even if they&rsquo;re on the edge of your network, by piggybacking on other Sidewalk-enabled devices. Amazon says that this is a low-bandwidth service and should have a 500 MB cap per account per month, but some commenters recommended turning it off to save on data.</p><p>As for the amount of data used by the Amazon Echo, it appears to average out, especially when running a firmware update and syncing files. The only way to know is to check the history of the devices, but if the risk (of both privacy and data usage) is not worth it for you, you can just unplug them to ensure they won&rsquo;t be listening at all.</p><p><em>Follow </em><a href="https://news.google.com/publications/CAAqLAgKIiZDQklTRmdnTWFoSUtFSFJ2YlhOb1lYSmtkMkZ5WlM1amIyMG9BQVAB"><u><em>Tom's Hardware on Google News</em></u></a><em>, or </em><a href="https://google.com/preferences/source?q="><u><em>add us as a preferred source</em></u></a><em>, to get our up-to-date news, analysis, and reviews in your feeds. Make sure to click the Follow button!</em></p><div><section><p>Get Tom's Hardware's best news and in-depth reviews, straight to your inbox.</p></section></div></div><div><p>Jowi Morales is a tech enthusiast with years of experience working in the industry. He&rsquo;s been writing with several tech publications since 2021, where he&rsquo;s been interested in tech hardware and consumer electronics.</p></div></section> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 08:14:27 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.mediaite.com/media/news/unhinged-and-anti-american-critics-erupt-over-trumps-ai-generated-threat/</link><title>‘Unhinged and Anti-American’: Critics Erupt Over Trump‘s AI-Generated Threat | Trump Threatening ‘WAR’ For Chicago and that they are “about to find out why it’s called the Department of WAR” in an AI post showing the city going full Apocalypse Now. (mediaite.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1na7t4x/unhinged_and_antiamerican_critics_erupt_over/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1na7t4x/unhinged_and_antiamerican_critics_erupt_over/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1na7t4x/unhinged_and_antiamerican_critics_erupt_over/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.mediaite.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/Trump-meme.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>&lsquo;Unhinged and Anti-American&rsquo;: Critics Erupt Over Trump&lsquo;s AI-Generated Threat</h2><div><p><span><a href="https://www.mediaite.com/author/jennifer-bowers-bahney" title="Posts by Jennifer Bowers Bahney">Jennifer Bowers Bahney</a></span><span>Sep 6th, 2025, 2:29 pm </span></p></div></div><div><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> critics were beside themselves over the president&rsquo;s <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115158096026629509">Saturday Truth Social</a> post that featured an AI re-imagining of the war movie &ldquo;Apocalypse Now<em>,&rdquo;</em> which he rebranded as &ldquo;Chipocalypse Now.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;I love the smell of deportations in the morning&hellip;&rdquo; <a href="https://www.mediaite.com/media/news/trump-drops-bonkers-post-threatening-war-for-american-city-with-gonzo-ai-pic/">Trump posted</a>. &ldquo;Chicago about to find out why it&rsquo;s called the Department of WAR,&rdquo; in reference to Trump&rsquo;s rebranding of the Department of Defense.</p><p>Behind an AI-generated image of Trump as a key character in the movie is a depiction of Chicago burning with helicopters hovering over the city.</p><p>Chicago Mayor <strong>Brandon Johnson</strong> (D) was quick to respond on X, writing, &ldquo;The President&rsquo;s threats are beneath the honor of our nation, but the reality is that he wants to occupy our city and break our Constitution. We must defend our democracy from this authoritarianism by protecting each other and protecting Chicago from Donald Trump.&rdquo;</p><div><blockquote><p>The President&rsquo;s threats are beneath the honor of our nation, but the reality is that he wants to occupy our city and break our Constitution. </p><p>We must defend our democracy from this authoritarianism by protecting each other and protecting Chicago from Donald Trump. <a href="https://t.co/B7AH1ufByH">pic.twitter.com/B7AH1ufByH</a></p><p>&mdash; Mayor Brandon Johnson (@ChicagosMayor) <a href="https://twitter.com/ChicagosMayor/status/1964384513548570871?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 6, 2025</a></p></blockquote> </div><p>Illinois Gov. <strong>J.B. Pritzker</strong> (D) also posted a response on X, writing, &ldquo;The President of the United States is threatening to go to war with an American city. This is not a joke. This is not normal. Donald Trump isn&rsquo;t a strongman, he&rsquo;s a scared man. Illinois won&rsquo;t be intimidated by a wannabe dictator.&rdquo;</p><div><blockquote><p>The President of the United States is threatening to go to war with an American city. </p><p>This is not a joke. This is not normal. </p><p>Donald Trump isn't a strongman, he's a scared man. Illinois won&rsquo;t be intimidated by a wannabe dictator. <a href="https://t.co/f87Zek7Cqb">pic.twitter.com/f87Zek7Cqb</a></p><p>&mdash; Governor JB Pritzker (@GovPritzker) <a href="https://twitter.com/GovPritzker/status/1964367057052701152?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 6, 2025</a></p></blockquote> </div><p>If Trump does order troops into Chicago, it will be the third American city to have been forcibly invaded, behind Los Angeles and Washington, D.C. California Gov. <strong>Gavin Newsom</strong> (D) warned Americans not to &ldquo;become numb&rdquo; to Trump&rsquo;s heavy-handed tactics.</p><div><blockquote><p>The President of the United States is deploying the military onto US streets and using our troops like political pawns. </p><p>DO NOT ALLOW YOURSELF TO BECOME NUMB TO THIS. <a href="https://t.co/xd9ab4tJMY">pic.twitter.com/xd9ab4tJMY</a></p><p>&mdash; Gavin Newsom (@GavinNewsom) <a href="https://twitter.com/GavinNewsom/status/1964378021898698799?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 6, 2025</a></p></blockquote> </div><p>Below are some additional replies:</p><div><blockquote><p>You knew when the job numbers tanked that <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@POTUS</a> would dial up the crazy.<br>He's TRYING to provoke a confrontation.<br>Don't take the bait, Chicagoans.<br>Protest. Document. Share with the world &amp; the courts.<br>But don't let yourselves become characters in his perverse reality show! <a href="https://t.co/roR3KGeyXK">pic.twitter.com/roR3KGeyXK</a></p><p>&mdash; David Axelrod (@davidaxelrod) <a href="https://twitter.com/davidaxelrod/status/1964371157949567219?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 6, 2025</a></p></blockquote> </div><div><blockquote><p>Donald Trump just declared war on an American city. He&rsquo;s using the military against a state and a city. </p><p>This is completely unhinged and anti-American. <a href="https://t.co/ZL4vsDXvUG">pic.twitter.com/ZL4vsDXvUG</a></p><p>&mdash; Harry Sisson (@harryjsisson) <a href="https://twitter.com/harryjsisson/status/1964380064130400356?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 6, 2025</a></p></blockquote> </div><div><blockquote><p>Using our military against our own people. <br>Never thought I would see this in my lifetime.<br>But it's the lethargic reaction from most Americans that is most troubling. <a href="https://t.co/ybsK1FQMPy">https://t.co/ybsK1FQMPy</a></p><p>&mdash; Sara Spector (@Miriam2626) <a href="https://twitter.com/Miriam2626/status/1964377695703486526?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 6, 2025</a></p></blockquote> </div><p>__</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:32:48 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
