<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=economics&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/economics</title><description>Hot posts in /r/economics (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 17:31:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>https://www.redditstatic.com/mweb2x/favicon/76x76.png</url><title>/r/economics</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link></image><item><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/08/trump-tariff-refund-trade-treasury-bessent-supreme-court.html</link><title>Potential Trump tariff refund bill could top $1 trillion as Supreme Court fight looms (cnbc.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nc6aak/potential_trump_tariff_refund_bill_could_top_1/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nc6aak/potential_trump_tariff_refund_bill_could_top_1/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nc6aak/potential_trump_tariff_refund_bill_could_top_1/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108195470-1757332160877-gettyimages-2234215725-wm107952_jrbozq6c.jpeg?v=1757332223&w=1920&h=1080' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><p>President Donald Trump speaks to reporters after stepping off Air Force One on September 7, 2025 at Joint Base Andrews, Maryland. </p><p>Kevin Dietsch | Getty Images</p></div><div><p>The <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/donald-trump/">United States government</a> has already collected tens of billions of dollars from President <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/donald-trump/">Donald Trump'</a>s "reciprocal tariffs."</p><p>But that money &mdash; and a lot more &mdash; could end up being <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/07/trump-trade-supreme-court-refunds-bessent.html">refunded</a> if the Supreme Court agrees with lower courts that many of the levies on imports from other countries are illegal.</p><p>How much could that end up being?</p><p>Anywhere between $750 billion to a whopping $1 trillion, warned Treasury Secretary <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/05/treasury-secretary-bessent-calls-for-big-changes-at-fed.html">Scott Bessent</a> in a declaration filed with the Supreme Court last week.</p><p>That eye-popping total could include the more than $72 billion in <a href="https://www.cbp.gov/newsroom/stats/trade?ftag=YHF4eb9d17">tariff revenue collected</a> so far by U.S. Border and Customs enforcement since Trump's "Liberation Day" announcement, according to data as of Aug. 24.</p></div><div><p>It would also include money projected to be collected from the at-risk tariffs by next June.</p><p>"Unwinding them could cause significant disruption," Bessent told the Supreme Court.</p><p>Bessent's declaration was part of a request by the Trump administration to have the Supreme Court quickly rule the tariffs are legal, and not wait until next summer, the normal time frame for such a decision.</p><p>The sooner the court rules, the less money the government could be required to refund&nbsp;if a majority of justices find the tariffs to be illegal.</p><p>Refunding tariffs is not an unprecedented situation for the U.S. government. But the amount of tariffs the Trump administration could be forced to refund is.</p></div><div><h2>Read more CNBC politics coverage</h2></div><div><p>Under former President <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/joe-biden/">Joe Biden</a>, importers of some Chinese goods were granted refunds on Section 301 tariffs during a limited period, according to a 2022 Holland &amp; Knight <a href="https://www.hklaw.com/en/insights/publications/2022/03/ustr-reinstates-352-exclusions-from-section-301-tariffs">alert</a>. But those refunds were relatively paltry.</p><p>Bessent said he is "confident" that the Trump administration will get the Supreme Court to reverse the lower court's rulings.</p><p>But if the Supreme Court says that refunds are required, "we'd have to do it," Bessent told <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/trump-administration/treasury-secretary-us-eu-collapse-russian-economy-tariffs-bessent-rcna229616">NBC News</a>' "Meet the Press" on Sunday. And that would be "terrible," he added.</p><p>Two lower courts have ruled Trump overstepped his presidential authority when he invoked the <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/08/29/trump-trade-tariffs-appeals-court-ieepa.html">International Emergency Economic Powers Act</a> to justify imposing steep levies on virtually every U.S. trading partner.</p><p>Last week, the Trump administration asked the Supreme Court to reverse those decisions &mdash; quickly.</p></div><div><p>"The stakes in this case could not be higher," Solicitor General D. John Sauer wrote in the administration's petition to the high court. "To the President and his most senior advisors, these tariffs thus present a stark choice: With tariffs, we are a rich nation; without tariffs, we are a poor nation," Sauer wrote.</p><p>"The President predicts that if "the United States were forced to pay back the trillions of dollars committed to us, America could go from strength to failure the moment such an incorrect decision took effect,' and 'the economic consequences would be ruinous, instead of unprecedented success.' "</p><p>The Supreme Court has not indicated when it might act on the Trump administration's request to take the case.</p><p>But the fact that the Trump administration did not wait until mid-October to ask the high court to take the case "at least increases the odds that we could see a decision from the Supreme Court by the end of the year," said Ryan Majerus, a partner in the international trade team at King &amp; Spalding.</p><p>Major questions remain over how a refund process would work for the administration and the companies hit hardest by the tariffs</p><p>Majerus said it is possible that importers could be required to file claims themselves to secure the refunds.</p></div><div><p>Cargo containers stacked aboard a ship at the Jakarta International Container Terminal in Tanjung Priok Port on Aug. 7, 2025.</p><p>Str | Afp | Getty Images</p></div><div><p>Trade experts are already urging companies to keep meticulous records and prepare to file refund claims, warning that the process could be messy.</p><p>"Documenting import histories and filing necessary paperwork promptly will be&nbsp;key," a recent client alert from Brownstein Hyatt Farber Schreck said.</p><p>If brokers are required to file for their refunds,&nbsp;"the workload for our customs teams would double overnight and be met with importers very eager to get those dollars back," Mike Short, president of global forwarding at C.H. Robinson, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/02/what-trump-court-loss-means-for-billions-in-tariffs-paid-to-government.html">recently told CNBC</a>.</p></div><div><p>The New York Times' DealBook <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/04/business/dealbook/wall-street-trump-tariffs.html">newsletter</a> reported that some importers are being approached about selling their rights to potential refunds to third-party firms at pennies on the dollar. </p><p>Buyers of those rights are effectively betting that the Supreme Court will overturn Trump's tariffs, and give them a handsome return on those wagers.</p><p>The White House did not immediately respond to CNBC's request for comment.</p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108193822-17569206221756920620-41478967091-1080pnbcnews.jpg?v=1756920621&amp;w=750&amp;h=422&amp;vtcrop=y"></p><p><img src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108193336-17568416151756841613-41465423169-1080pnbcnews.jpg?v=1756841614&amp;w=750&amp;h=422&amp;vtcrop=y"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 07:13:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://investorsobserver.com/news/stock-update/trumps-trade-war-dream-collides-with-reality-as-semiconductor-jobs-disappear/</link><title>Trump’s trade war dream collides with reality as semiconductor jobs disappear (investorsobserver.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbyufq/trumps_trade_war_dream_collides_with_reality_as/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbyufq/trumps_trade_war_dream_collides_with_reality_as/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbyufq/trumps_trade_war_dream_collides_with_reality_as/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.investorsobserver.com/images/750w/2025/03/Semi-stocks.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>President Trump&rsquo;s trade war was billed as a pathway to wealth through tariff revenue and a revival of U.S. manufacturing, particularly in advanced industries. </p><p>However, the latest job data suggests the opposite, with employment in one of the trade war&rsquo;s most critical sectors (semiconductors) is plunging.</p><p>&ldquo;The number of people employed in the semiconductor manufacturing industry is plunging,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/KevRGordon/status/1963964450689692063">wrote</a> Kevin Gordon, senior investment strategist at Charles Schwab, citing nonfarm payroll data that show payrolls in the sector have fallen to about 369,000 workers.</p><blockquote><p>The number of people employed in the semiconductor manufacturing industry is plunging <a href="https://t.co/P3aWb8WLP2">pic.twitter.com/P3aWb8WLP2</a></p>undefined Kevin Gordon (@KevRGordon) <a href="https://twitter.com/KevRGordon/status/1963964450689692063?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2025</a></blockquote><p>Semiconductor employment never fully recovered from the Global Financial Crisis, but it rebounded sharply after Covid, climbing to its highest level since 2009. </p><p>The surge was fueled by pandemic-era shortages that exposed America&rsquo;s reliance on overseas producers, prompting U.S. firms to expand domestic capacity.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/117th-congress/house-bill/4346">2022 CHIPS Act</a> added further momentum, with subsidies and tax credits spurring new fabs and reshoring efforts, while booming demand for AI chips supported hiring.</p><p>However, by 2023 and 2024, the tide turned. Companies had overbuilt and oversupplied, inventories swelled, and payrolls began shrinking as production slowed.</p><p>The downturn has been compounded by tariffs, <a href="https://apnews.com/article/ai-nvidia-amd-chips-trump-controls-0e6fbdc1ad8b54d8ecc704393c2a1558">export controls</a>, and restrictions on advanced chip sales to China &mdash; the world&rsquo;s largest semiconductor consumer &mdash; which have curbed demand for U.S.-made chips and weighed on employment.</p><p>While Nvidia (NVDA) &mdash; now <a href="https://investorsobserver.com/news/stock-update/nvidia-nvda-stock-is-now-bigger-than-germany-yes-the-country/">worth more than the entire German stock market</a> &mdash; dominates investor attention, the broader U.S. semiconductor sector is grappling with uncertainty and strategic headwinds.</p><h2>A sector unwinding</h2><p>Concerns about the U.S. semiconductor industry deepened last month when, in a surprising move, the Trump administration secured a 10% equity stake in Intel (INTC), a struggling chipmaker that has cut about 15,000 jobs since early 2024 as part of sweeping cost reductions.</p><p><a href="https://investorsobserver.com/news/stock-update/this-isnt-capitalism-its-something-else-entirely-intels-deal-comes-at-shareholders-expense-analysts-warn/">Some analysts warned</a> the intervention set a troubling precedent, pushing the U.S. closer to a model of &ldquo;state capitalism.&rdquo;</p><p>The trade war targeting semiconductors &mdash; and retaliatory measures from global players &mdash; threaten to drive up production costs and slow the buildout of new U.S. fabs. </p><p>Beyond Intel, Nvidia, AMD, and Dutch equipment supplier ASML have all cautioned about negative fallout tied to the escalating dispute.</p><p>Against this backdrop, Evercore ISI analyst Mark Lipacis recently cut his sales and earnings forecasts for semiconductor companies, particularly those focused on analog chips, which process real-world signals like sound, power, and temperature, and microcontrollers.</p><p>His <a href="https://www.investors.com/news/technology/semiconductor-stocks-face-post-tariff-shocks-q1-2025">downgrade</a> hit firms including Texas Instruments (TXN), Microchip Technology (MCHP), NXP Semiconductors (NXPI), and Analog Devices (ADI).</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 01:56:27 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/supreme-court/supreme-court-allows-trump-fire-ftc-commissioner-rcna229385</link><title>Supreme Court allows Trump to fire FTC commissioner (nbcnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbshlk/supreme_court_allows_trump_to_fire_ftc/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbshlk/supreme_court_allows_trump_to_fire_ftc/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbshlk/supreme_court_allows_trump_to_fire_ftc/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630,f_auto,q_auto:best/rockcms/2025-09/250904-Rebecca-Kelly-Slaughter-vl-412p-c67113.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>WASHINGTON &mdash; The Supreme Court on Monday allowed President Donald Trump to fire a member of the Federal Trade Commission despite a federal law that is intended to restrict the White House&rsquo;s power to control the agency.</p><p>The court, in an order issued by Chief Justice John Roberts, temporarily blocked a judge's ruling that reinstated Rebecca Kelly Slaughter while the case continues.</p><p>The order did not definitively signal how the court would address the Trump administrations emergency request to give the president broader authority to fire independent agency members without cause, but it signals that the court would most likely grant it.</p><p>Slaughter, who briefly returned to the agency as a result of the lower court rulings, said in a statement that she would "see this case through to the end" regardless of the court's decision to let Trump remove her while the litigation continues.</p><p>"In the week I was back at the FTC it became even more clear to me that we desperately need the transparency and accountability Congress intended to have at bipartisan independent agencies," she added.</p><p>Trump fired both Democratic commissioners on the five-person FTC in March, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/fired-ftc-commissioners-fear-trump-will-go-easy-big-tech-donors-rcna197128">Slaughter and Alvaro Bedoya</a>. Both challenged the move, although Bedoya later dropped out of the case. Slaughter is currently listed as a serving commissioner on the <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/about-ftc/commissioners-staff/commissioners">agency&rsquo;s website</a> as the case has made its way through the courts.</p><p>The firings are a direct challenge to a 1935 Supreme Court precedent called Humphrey's Executor v. United States, which upheld limits on the president&rsquo;s ability to fire FTC commissioners without cause, a restriction Congress imposed to protect the agency from political pressure.</p><p>Under the 1914 law that set up the agency, members can be removed only for &ldquo;inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.&rdquo;</p><p>A federal judge in July ruled in favor of Slaughter, citing the 1935 ruling. The U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit reached a similar conclusion.</p><p>But the Supreme Court, whose majority has been skeptical of the concept of independent federal agencies that are not subject to presidential control, has undermined such protections in recent years in a series of cases involving other agencies.</p><p>Lawyers for the Trump administration argue that the removal restrictions unlawfully impose limits on the president's power to control the executive branch as defined by Article 2 of the Constitution.</p><p>This year, Trump has also sought to remove members of other independent federal agencies, which the Supreme Court <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/supreme-court/supreme-court-allows-trump-fire-members-product-safety-agency-rcna218882">has allowed</a>.</p><p>The FTC has five commissioners who serve seven-year terms &mdash;with no more than three from one political party. Slaughter and Bedoya both served as Democratic members, although Trump originally appointed Bedoya in 2018. President Joe Biden reappointed her last year.</p></div><div><p><span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/author/lawrence-hurley-ncpn1298564">Lawrence Hurley</a></span></p><p>Lawrence Hurley is a senior Supreme Court reporter for NBC News. </p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_focal-60x60,f_auto,q_auto:best/newscms/2023_08/3595831/lawrence-hurley-byline-jm-1.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 22:00:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/lumber-prices-are-flashing-a-warning-sign-for-the-u-s-economy-2119c5dc?mod=Searchresults&amp;pos=2&amp;page=1</link><title>Lumber Prices Are Flashing a Warning Sign for the U.S. Economy (wsj.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbs662/lumber_prices_are_flashing_a_warning_sign_for_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbs662/lumber_prices_are_flashing_a_warning_sign_for_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbs662/lumber_prices_are_flashing_a_warning_sign_for_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:49:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/2025/09/08/your-health-insurance-biggest-increase-15-years-since-2010-mercer/</link><title>Health insurance is about to go up by the biggest percentage in 15 years (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbrq0h/health_insurance_is_about_to_go_up_by_the_biggest/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbrq0h/health_insurance_is_about_to_go_up_by_the_biggest/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbrq0h/health_insurance_is_about_to_go_up_by_the_biggest/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://fortune.com/img-assets/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GettyImages-2205706029-e1757345891727.jpg?resize=1200,600' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>Health insurance prices in the U.S. have been spiraling for four consecutive years, and employers are now bracing for the highest spike yet in 2025&mdash;the biggest increase in 15 years, according to a wide-ranging survey of more than 1,700 employers. The <a href="https://www.mercer.com/en-us/about/newsroom/employers-are-bracing-for-the-highest-health-benefit-cost-increase-in-15-years/">National Survey of Employer-Sponsored Health Plans</a> by <a href="https://www.mercer.com/en-us/">Mercer</a>, a subsidiary of <a href="https://www.marshmclennan.com/">Marsh McLennan</a>, is part of the advisory firm&rsquo;s services to help employers manage health insurance costs while seeking to improve employee health and well-being.</p><div><p>Sunit Patel, Mercer&rsquo;s US Chief Actuary for Health and Benefits, said two factors are combining to send costs higher. &ldquo;Health benefit cost trend has two primary components &mdash;&nbsp;healthcare price and utilization. Right now, both are rising.&rdquo; </p><p>The survey projects that total health benefit costs per employee will increase by&nbsp;6.5% in 2026, even with planned cost-reduction measures, the highest jump since 2010. If employers left current plans unchanged, the increase would approach an alarming&nbsp;9%, underscoring the relentless pressure on employer healthcare budgets. This upcoming surge marks the fourth straight year of elevated health benefit cost growth, according to Mercer, breaking from a decade of more modest annual increases of about 3%. </p><h2>Multiple drivers fueling cost surge</h2><p>Some of the increases are due to advances in medical science. Advanced diagnostics and cutting-edge therapeutics, such as new cancer treatments and weight-loss medications, are transforming people&rsquo;s lives and bodies but come at steep costs compared to previous therapies. Provider consolidation into large health systems has strengthened bargaining power to set higher reimbursement rates with insurers. </p><p>Patel said more people have been using various health services over the past two years, likely because of the lingering effect of delayed or missed care due to the pandemic and an easing in healthcare labor constraints. &ldquo;The rise of virtual healthcare &mdash; and growing consumer acceptance of it, particularly in behavioral health &mdash; is also affecting utilization patterns,&rdquo; Patel said, &ldquo;because it removes geographic barriers to care and can be a more convenient option for patients.&rdquo;</p><p>Inflation has also played a significant role, with increased wages across the healthcare sector feeding further cost increases. The pandemic accelerated virtual healthcare adoption, making it easier for people to seek care; paradoxically, this easy access has contributed to higher overall utilization, driving up aggregate claims. </p><p>A Mercer spokesperson said in a statement to Fortune that this is the first 15-year high seen since the survey began in 1987.&nbsp; Previous comparisons include a 13-year high in 2002 (14.7%, the highest since 18.6% in 1988) , and a seven-year high in 2010 (6.9%, the highest since 2002). &ldquo;Cost growth was very volatile from 1987-2002, the early years of managed care, with sharp highs and lows,&rdquo; the spokesperson said, adding that cost growth stabilized to about 6%-7% annually starting around 2004, before slowing in 2012 to around 3%-4% annually.&nbsp; </p><h2>Employer responses: more cost-shifting</h2><p>Facing these mounting pressures, employers are taking aggressive action. The survey found 59% of companies plan to make cost-cutting changes to health plans in 2026, up sharply from 48% in 2025 and 44% in 2024. The predominant strategy involves&nbsp;raising<strong> </strong>deductibles and cost-sharing&nbsp;provisions, resulting in higher out-of-pocket costs for employees when they access care. Yet, many employers are also seeking ways to curb costs without simply passing the burden onto workers. For example, there is increased emphasis on&nbsp;managing high-cost claims and measuring program performance&nbsp;to guarantee value. </p><p>At the same time, enhancing mental-health benefits remains a priority post-pandemic, with about two-thirds of large employers planning to make behavioral healthcare more accessible in the next few years. Mercer&rsquo;s US Health and Benefits Leader, Ed Lehman, notes, &ldquo;Employers recognize it&rsquo;s essential for employee well-being and overall business performance.&rdquo; </p><h2>Your open enrollment this season</h2><p>For workers, the bottom line is the expense: Paycheck deductions for health coverage are expected to climb&nbsp;6% to 7% on average in 2026. This stems from the fact that employee premium shares typically rise in proportion to overall plan costs. In addition to higher premiums, increased deductibles and copays may further boost out-of-pocket expenses, forcing some employees to shoulder even greater financial strain.</p><p>Mercer said employees should &ldquo;carefully weigh premium cost and cost-sharing provisions&rdquo; during open enrollment, balancing premium costs with cost-sharing features to select the most appropriate plan for their needs. Mercer notes that more than a third of large employers will offer non-traditional, high-performance network plans in 2026&mdash;these options can help mitigate out-of-pocket costs by steering patients towards pre-selected providers known for quality and lower expenses. </p><p><em>[This report has been updated with a statement from a Mercer spokesperson.]</em> </p><p><em>For this story,&nbsp;</em>Fortune<em>&nbsp;used generative AI to help with an initial draft. An editor verified the accuracy of the information before publishing.&nbsp;</em></p></div><p><strong>Fortune Global Forum</strong> returns Oct. 26&ndash;27, 2025 in Riyadh. CEOs and global leaders will gather for a dynamic, invitation-only event shaping the future of business. <a href="https://conferences.fortune.com/event/global-forum-2025/summary">Apply for an invitation.</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 21:32:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.ft.com/content/9af0c46d-4665-49ae-b153-15ce7d65ca55</link><title>Americans face biggest increase in health insurance costs in 15 years (ft.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbbh9b/americans_face_biggest_increase_in_health/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbbh9b/americans_face_biggest_increase_in_health/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nbbh9b/americans_face_biggest_increase_in_health/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><div><p><span></span><span>Subscribe to unlock this article</span></p></div><div><h2><span><span>Try unlimited access</span></span></h2><h2><span><span>Only </span><span>Rs100</span><span> for 4 weeks</span></span></h2><p><span><span>Then </span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month. Complete digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Cancel anytime during your trial.</span></span></p></div></div><div><h2>Explore more offers.</h2><div><div><div><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_ftedit.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg" alt></p><h3>FT Edit</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4490</span><span> per year</span></span></p><p><span><span>Access to eight surprising articles a day, hand-picked by FT editors. For seamless reading, access content via the FT Edit page on FT.com and receive the FT Edit newsletter.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Standard Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs2850</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Essential digital access to quality FT journalism on any device. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div><div><div><p></p><h3>Premium Digital</h3></div><p><span><span>Rs4335</span><span> per month</span></span></p><p><span><span>Complete digital access to quality FT journalism with expert analysis from industry leaders. Pay a year upfront and save 20%.</span></span></p></div></div></div><div><h2>Explore our full range of subscriptions.</h2><div><div><div><h3>For individuals</h3></div><p>Discover all the plans currently available in your country</p></div><div><div><h3> For multiple readers</h3></div><p>Digital access for organisations. Includes exclusive features and content.</p></div></div></div><div><div><h2>Why the FT?</h2><p>See why over a million readers pay to read the Financial Times.</p></div><p><a href="https://subs.ft.com/whytheft?ft-content-uuid=9af0c46d-4665-49ae-b153-15ce7d65ca55">Find out why</a></p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_standard.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg"></p><p><img src="https://www.ft.com/__origami/service/image/v2/images/raw/https://barrier-page-components.s3.eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/assets/icons/primary_product_icon_premium.svg?source=next-barrier-page&amp;format=svg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 07:33:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/07/wealth-tax-norway-election</link><title>‘People are so angry’: how wealth tax became a battleground in Norway’s election (theguardian.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1narcuv/people_are_so_angry_how_wealth_tax_became_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1narcuv/people_are_so_angry_how_wealth_tax_became_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 16 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1narcuv/people_are_so_angry_how_wealth_tax_became_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/9cb27bec6f83e9cb25c76afb3b6353479d2988cc/0_0_1037_830/master/1037.jpg?width=1200&height=630&quality=85&auto=format&fit=crop&precrop=40:21,offset-x50,offset-y0&overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&overlay-width=100p&overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&enable=upscale&s=e6bbb853bc9c6e630b782d914548ee28' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>I</span>t is the issue that has set the Norwegian general election alight: whether to keep, cut or abolish the national wealth tax. As the country prepares to go to the polls on Monday, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/norway">Norway</a> is in the grip of a ferocious national argument that is likely to rumble on whichever party wins.</p><p>In an economy less then a seventh the size of Britain&rsquo;s, the <em>formuesskatt</em> raises about 32bn kroner (&pound;2.4bn). Multiply that by the difference in GDP, and the same rules applied in the UK could raise more than &pound;17bn &ndash; serious money in tax terms. Defenders say the wealth tax has another benefit. They see it as the cornerstone of a progressive tax system that has helped to create one of Europe&rsquo;s most equal societies.</p><p>But entrepreneurs are pushing back, financing lobbying campaigns and pouring money into politics and online advertising. There is even a protest song. &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t come to Norway, we will tax you till you&rsquo;re poor, and when you have nothing left, we will tax you a little more,&rdquo; laments a business consultant in a <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/embed/feed/update/urn:li:ugcPost:7188429685863727107">video posted on LinkedIn</a>. On the other side of the divide, the leader of the Socialist Left party has a <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DCZYvsXuQJB/">&ldquo;wall of shame&rdquo;</a> in her office displaying the names of those who oppose or avoid the tax.</p><p>More disturbingly, the experts are under attack. Economists and statisticians have flagged a wave of disinformation, while being subjected to hate mail and targeted by newspapers.</p><p>Annette Alstads&aelig;ter, director of the <a href="https://www.nmbu.no/en/research/skatteforsk-tax-center">Skatterforsk Centre for Tax Research </a>at the Norwegian University of Life Sciences, has spoken in favour of the tax and authored a series of papers on avoidance and offshore wealth. She now weighs her public statements carefully, and has withdrawn from social media because of the risk of online abuse. &ldquo;People are so angry. Either you are very against or very for,&rdquo; she says.</p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been working on this for 15 years and it&rsquo;s always an issue but this time it has exploded,&rdquo; says the economist Mathilde Fasting, a member of the right of centre thinktank <a href="https://civita.no/">Civita</a> and one of those calling for abolition. &ldquo;Each time you talk about economic issues this tax will come up. It&rsquo;s like a symbol of all other things happening.&rdquo;</p><p>In a country where politics still gravitates to the centre, the wealth tax creates a clear dividing line between left and right. The row has evolved into a full culture war, with Trumpian appeals to aspirational young men who may not yet be rich enough to pay the levy, but oppose it on principle. On the YouTube show <em>Gutta</em> (Guys), four muscle-bound presenters filmed themselves <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?app=desktop&amp;v=wUmHJwh9Rw4">pouring champagne over their wrist watches</a> while discussing &ldquo;tax refugees&rdquo;.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Jens Stoltenberg has promised to set up a cross-party commission to review all taxes if Labour is returned to power.</span> Photograph: Fredrik Varfjell/Reuters</figcaption></figure><p>Jens Stoltenberg, the former Nato secretary general and ex-Norwegian premier who returned to frontline politics in February as finance minister, has promised to set up a cross-party commission to review all taxes if Labour is returned to power. Thanks to his wide appeal, his party has risen in the polls, and is now ahead of the populist Progress party, which has promised to do away with the <em>formuesskatt</em>. In third place is the more moderate centre-right <em>H&oslash;yre</em>, which wants to slash the amount raised.</p><p>During his decade at the helm of Nato, Stoltenberg was dubbed &ldquo;the Trump whisperer&rdquo; after convincing the US president not to pull out of the security alliance during his first term. It seems settling the wealth tax dispute will take all of the diplomatic skills he deployed in that role. The trick will be to retain the tax without triggering an exodus of billionaires.</p><p>&ldquo;If a ton of people leave Norway that would be a problem,&rdquo; says the entrepreneur Karl Munthe-Kaas, who supports the tax. &ldquo;But if we let these groups that have all this money hold the rest of the country hostage, I have an issue with that.&rdquo;</p><p>Cut through the noise, and the underlying conversation is nuanced. Norwegians discuss tax with confidence, because they have access to all the right data. Almost uniquely among democratic nations, the tax returns of named individuals are public, <a href="https://www.skatteetaten.no/en/forms/search-the-tax-lists/">in a database</a> that all citizens can access. Likewise, information on companies is detailed and reliable.</p><p>Norway has levied a tax on wealth above a certain value since 1892, some years before securing full independence from Sweden. Along with Spain and Switzerland, it is one of only three European nations to still tax capital in this way. The current rate stands at 1% for those with assets of more than 1.7m kroner (&pound;125,000) and 1.1% for those with more than 20.7m kroner. The tax is collected annually, and is calculated by adding up the value of properties, savings, investments and shares, and deducting any debt. Private companies count as part of their owners&rsquo; wealth. There are discounts &ndash; for example, only 25% of the value of a primary residence is taxable.</p><figure><div><picture><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/af0845b4442a3ed378109162701e784f37dd238e/7_0_3739_2992/master/3739.jpg?width=620&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/af0845b4442a3ed378109162701e784f37dd238e/7_0_3739_2992/master/3739.jpg?width=620&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/af0845b4442a3ed378109162701e784f37dd238e/7_0_3739_2992/master/3739.jpg?width=605&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/af0845b4442a3ed378109162701e784f37dd238e/7_0_3739_2992/master/3739.jpg?width=605&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/af0845b4442a3ed378109162701e784f37dd238e/7_0_3739_2992/master/3739.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/af0845b4442a3ed378109162701e784f37dd238e/7_0_3739_2992/master/3739.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><img alt="Harbor and financial district view of Oslo" src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/af0845b4442a3ed378109162701e784f37dd238e/7_0_3739_2992/master/3739.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none" width="445" height="356.09521262369617"></source></source></source></source></source></source></picture></div><figcaption><span>Norway is one of only three European nations to levy a tax on wealth above a certain value.</span> Photograph: Drazen_/Getty Images</figcaption></figure><p>Although 720,000 citizens pay wealth tax, for most the annual contribution is small. Fasting says about 3,000 have taxable wealth of more than 100m kroner.</p><p>Among the biggest contributors is Gustav Magnar Witz&oslash;e, the heir to the SalMar fish farms business. In 2023, his wealth tax was <a href="https://www-nettavisen-no.translate.goog/nyheter/witzoe-far-330-mill-du-far-12-000-kroner/s/5-95-2500947?_x_tr_sl=no&amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;_x_tr_hl=en&amp;_x_tr_pto=sc">330m kroner</a>. It was the only personal tax he paid as he had no income, according to reports based on his filings. Under the plans put forward by <em>H&oslash;yre</em>,<strong> </strong>it has been reported his bill would fall to zero. This is because the party is proposing to exclude what it calls &ldquo;working capital&rdquo; &ndash; essentially assets that are part of trading businesses.</p><p>Thanks to changes made by Labour the total wealth tax collected has risen from 18bn kroner in 2021, the year of the last election, to 32bn kroner last year. Estimates for 2025 are even higher.</p><gu-island><figure><a href="https://interactive.guim.co.uk/datawrapper/embed/wwNKh/1/">graph</a></figure></gu-island><p>In 2022, the changes prompted departures. More than 30 billionaires and multimillionaires <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/apr/10/super-rich-abandoning-norway-at-record-rate-as-wealth-tax-rises-slightly">left the country</a>, according to research by the newspaper Dagens N&aelig;ringsliv. They included the industrial tycoon Kjell Inge R&oslash;kke, the fourth richest Norwegian, with a fortune of about &pound;1.5bn, who relocated to Switzerland. There were warnings of lost tax revenues and damage to the economy, but three years later, it is clear that the exodus had limited impact.</p><p>In Norway, as elsewhere, the billionaires are getting richer. In 2024, the 400 wealthiest were worth 2.139tn kroner, <a href="https://www.lifeinnorway.net/richest-people/">up 14% in a year</a>, according to the business magazine Kapital. But it also reported half of this wealth was controlled by families relocated abroad.</p><p>Fasting believes more will leave. &ldquo;People are not investing here, not listing their companies, and finally moving out, which is serious. And I am sure that if the Labour party continues after the elections now you will see a boost of people moving,&rdquo; she says.</p><p>Her main argument for scrapping the tax is that it puts Norwegians at a disadvantage compared with foreign company owners. She says they have to take dividends out of their companies to pay the tax authorities, which means less money for growing businesses or starting new ones.</p><figure><a href="https://www.theguardian.com#EmailSignup-skip-link-22">skip past newsletter promotion</a><p>after newsletter promotion</p></figure><p>One of the loudest lobby groups is Aksjon for Norsk Eierskap &ndash; Action for Norwegian Ownership. Its backers include the salmon exporter Roger Hofseth. &ldquo;If the left wins this time, a lot of people will flee to Switzerland,&rdquo; Hofseth told a gathering last month.</p><p>&ldquo;There is this mentality that people who are self-made, they forget they are a product of the system,&rdquo; says Alstads&aelig;ter at the Centre for Tax Research. &ldquo;For me it&rsquo;s about justice. Everyone should pay a little bit. The rich get all these public goods. A stable political system, social security, and a highly educated population with access to free healthcare.&rdquo;</p><p>She believes some reforms are needed, saying the threshold of 1.7m kroner is too low.</p><p>With a sovereign wealth fund that collects the profits from Norway&rsquo;s abundant stocks of oil and gas able to contribute 25% of public spending each year, there is arguably no need for the <em>formuesskatt</em>.</p><p>&ldquo;To me, it&rsquo;s more about fairness,&rdquo; says Simen Markussen, the director of the Ragnar Frisch Centre for Economic Research in Oslo. &ldquo;It ensures that capital owners who don&rsquo;t have labour income are paying a reasonable amount of tax. It redistributes from the richest to everyone.&rdquo;</p><p>For the very rich, it is particularly effective, as it accounts for most of the personal taxes they pay.</p><gu-island><figure><a href="https://interactive.guim.co.uk/datawrapper/embed/vBd8p/1/">graph</a></figure></gu-island><p>While the sums collected are not huge, they are meaningful. &ldquo;Compared with all taxes on personal income it&rsquo;s maybe 4.5%,&rdquo; says Markussen. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s big enough that if a politician says &lsquo;I want to abolish it&rsquo; they should be challenged on how this should be financed. Do you want to maintain those tax revenues, or what do you want to cut?&rdquo;</p><p>Munthe-Kaas founded the Oda grocery delivery business, which became Norway&rsquo;s first &ldquo;unicorn&rdquo;, a term used for startups valued at more than $1bn. He exited the company last year and no longer pays the wealth tax, but has done previously. He believes it works well, and would prefer a cut to corporation tax.</p><p>&ldquo;The wealth tax is not a choice between value creation versus distribution, it gives us both,&rdquo; he says. &ldquo;Any tax you bring in will reduce the ability to either invest or consume, whoever pays it. Taxing the rich isn&rsquo;t different in that sense to taxing a middle-class worker. So when rich people are upset they get less to invest, the same argument goes for anyone.&rdquo;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Karl Munthe-Kaas, who founded the Oda delivery grocery delivery business, believes the wealth tax works well.</span> Photograph: Millionaires for Humanity</figcaption></figure><p>Andr&eacute; Nilsen, a neuroscientist and kroner millionaire thanks to family money and his own investments, pays a small sum in wealth tax each year. He believes the <em>formuesskatt</em> should stay because it helps pay for social security. &ldquo;It is easier to get rich in Norway compared with other countries. You are free to go on wild explorations of ideas because you have a safety net that will catch you if it doesn&rsquo;t work out,&rdquo; he says.</p><p>Although the wealthy often give generously to charity, it cannot replace tax, he believes. &ldquo;There must be some kind of system above everyone that says at least do this.&rdquo;</p><p>There are other ways to target wealth. The UK &ndash; in common with many other countries &ndash; taxes dividends, capital gains and inherited money. But the rates can be much lower than those for wage-based income, and there are many loopholes and discounts.</p><p>Alstads&aelig;ter says the wealth tax is harder to dodge: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s the only tax that cannot be avoided through restructuring while living in Norway, hence the opposition.&rdquo;</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/34f318c2430988975cabaf4ca7840d2ff51e2229/1435_200_5674_4542/master/5674.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"></p><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/36ba738f5680724c5ed011a597ca4bdd091c351a/0_6_3573_2858/master/3573.jpg?width=445&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 17:30:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/postal-traffic-us-fell-trump-administration-stopped-exemption-low-value-parcels/</link><title>Postal traffic to U.S. fell 80% after Trump administration stopped exemption on low-value parcels (cbsnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1na85wg/postal_traffic_to_us_fell_80_after_trump/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1na85wg/postal_traffic_to_us_fell_80_after_trump/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1na85wg/postal_traffic_to_us_fell_80_after_trump/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets1.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/r/2025/09/06/0334d900-d02c-4a01-8059-fa94e29b91a7/thumbnail/1200x630/258ffbd8000b2c2b53949c76805c998d/ap25235550928617.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"> <article><div><header><div><p><time>September 6, 2025 / 1:34 PM EDT</time> / CBS/AP </p></div></header> </div><figure><div><div><div><svg> <use></use> </svg><p><span>Breaking down end of the low-cost tariff exemption </span> </p></div></div></div><figcaption> <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/video/what-the-end-of-the-low-cost-tariff-exemption-means-for-consumers/"> <span>What the end of the low-cost tariff exemption means for consumers</span> <span>02:35</span> </a> </figcaption> </figure> <section><p>Postal traffic into the United States plunged by more than 80% after the Trump administration&nbsp;<span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/de-minimis-us-tariffs-exemption-low-value-imports-ends/">ended a tariff exemption</a></span>&nbsp;for low-cost imports, the United Nations postal agency said Saturday.</p><p>The Universal Postal Union says it has started rolling out new measures that can help postal operators around the world calculate and collect duties, or taxes, after the U.S. eliminated the so-called "de minimis exemption" for lower-value parcels.</p><p>Eighty-eight postal operators have told the UPU that they have suspended some or all postal services to the United States until a solution is implemented with regard to U.S.-bound parcels valued at $800 or less, which had been the cutoff for imported goods to escape customs charges.</p><p>"The global network saw postal traffic to the U.S. come to a near-halt after the implementation of the new rules on Aug. 29, 2025, which for the first time placed the burden of customs duty collection and remittance on transportation carriers or U.S. Customs and Border Protection agency-approved qualified parties," the UPU said in a statement.</p><p>The UPU said information exchanged between postal operators through its electronic network showed traffic from its 192 member countries &mdash; nearly all the world's countries &mdash; had fallen 81% on Aug. 29, compared to a week earlier.</p><p>The Bern, Switzerland-based agency said the "major operational disruptions" have occurred because airlines and other carriers indicated they weren't willing or able to collect such duties, and foreign postal operators had not established a link to CBP-qualified companies.</p><p>The number of low-value parcels entering the U.S. has skyrocketed over the past decade. Between 2015 and 2025, that figure jumped from 134 million shipments per year to about 1.4 billion. U.S. Customs and Border Protection was processing more than 4 million "de minimis" shipments to the U.S. daily, the White House said.&nbsp;</p><p>Before the measure took effect, the postal union sent a letter to U.S. Secretary of State Marco Rubio to express concerns about its impact.</p><p>The <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/de-minimis-us-tariffs-exemption-low-value-imports-ends/">de minimis provision</a></span> was added to the Tariff Act of 1930 several years after the law was passed. It was designed to facilitate trade by eliminating the administrative burden of collecting modest import duties on low-cost goods.&nbsp;</p><p>Purchases that previously entered the U.S. without needing to clear customs now require vetting and are subject to their origin country's applicable tariff rate, which can range from 10% to 50%.</p><p>While the change applies to the products of every country, U.S. residents will not have to pay duties on incoming gifts valued at up to $100, or on up to $200 worth of personal souvenirs from trips abroad, according to the White House.</p><p>The UPU said its members had not been given enough time or guidance to comply with the procedures outlined in the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/07/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-is-protecting-the-united-states-national-security-and-economy-by-suspending-the-de-minimis-exemption-for-commercial-shipments-globally/">executive order President Trump signed</a> on <span><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/trump-ends-de-minimis-loophole-on-imports/">July 30</a></span> to eliminate the duty-free eligibility of low-value goods.</p><ul> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/united-states-postal-service/">United States Postal Service</a></li> <li><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/tag/trump-administration/">Trump Administration</a></li> </ul> </section> </article> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets1.cbsnewsstatic.com/hub/i/2025/08/29/f8c0885c-da42-4059-ac01-e7fe3a928553/cbsn-fusion-what-the-end-of-the-low-cost-tariff-exemption-means-for-consumers-thumbnail.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:47:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.spokesman.com/stories/2025/sep/05/hundreds-of-us-colleges-poised-to-close-in-next-de/</link><title>Hundreds of U.S. colleges poised to close in next decade, expert says (spokesman.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9pwk1/hundreds_of_us_colleges_poised_to_close_in_next/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9pwk1/hundreds_of_us_colleges_poised_to_close_in_next/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9pwk1/hundreds_of_us_colleges_poised_to_close_in_next/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://thumb.spokesman.com/l2sMHX5ZvY-IivJJOF8GNS33NSY=/600x0/media.spokesman.com/graphics/2020/08/sr_placeholder.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A dwindling number of prospective students will drive as many as 370 private colleges in the U.S. to shutter or merge with another institution in the next decade, according to a major higher-education consulting firm.</p><p>Huron Consulting Group&rsquo;s prediction is more than triple the total amount of private, nonprofit two- and four-year college closures that the National Center for Education Statistics calculated in the 10 years leading up to 2020.</p><p>The shrinking supply of students stems from a falling national birth rate that started in 2007 and hasn&rsquo;t recovered. The Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education estimates that the graduating class of 2041 will be about 13% smaller than the 2025 cohort.</p><p>&ldquo;Essentially the problem is we have too many seats in too many classrooms and not enough prospective students to fill them,&rdquo; said Peter Stokes, a managing director at Huron. &ldquo;Over the next decade, we&rsquo;re going through a very painful but necessary re-balancing in supply and demand.&rdquo;</p><p>Stokes said the firm analyzed more than 10 years of financial and enrollment data from since-closed and merged institutions in making its prediction, analyzing metrics such as net tuition revenue per student, enrollment, ratings, and the asset-to-liability ratio of closed schools.</p><p>The projected closures and mergers will impact around 600,000 students and affect about $18 billion in endowment funds, according to Stokes.</p><p>&ldquo;These are schools where we see red flashing lights and warning signs that they&rsquo;re in significant financial stress,&rdquo; he said. Huron declined to disclose the names of schools that they expect will close or merge.</p><p>Another 430 institutions with more than 1.2 million students and $134 billion in endowments face moderate existential threats, according to Huron, which serves more than 580 education clients annually, a bulk of which are four-year public and private universities, according to a July earnings presentation.</p><p>In contrast, 114 private, nonprofit colleges shuttered from 2010 to 2020, according to National Center for Education Statistics data, and in the decade prior to that period, 59 schools closed.</p><p>Colleges across the country have already shut down this year, citing the slowdown of high school graduates. Among them are Northland College in Wisconsin and Limestone University in South Carolina. At least 40 schools have announced plans to close since 2020.</p><p>Recent research by the Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia found that a one-time 15% drop in prospective students, known as the &ldquo;demographic cliff,&rdquo; would cause 80 additional colleges to shutter.</p><p>Stokes said that schools need to come up with an early game plan to meet enrollment challenges. Colleges can consider diversifying their student populations by growing graduate, professional and part-time programs, for example.</p><p>&ldquo;If you aren&rsquo;t thinking five years ahead, you&rsquo;re at a significant disadvantage,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;If you only have three years of runway, your chances of survival are less than 50%. If you call us when you&rsquo;ve got nine months of cash, you&rsquo;re dead in the water and it&rsquo;s too late.&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 09:32:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.smh.com.au/world/north-america/a-jobs-slump-spurred-trump-to-sack-his-stats-boss-this-time-around-he-s-got-no-one-to-blame-20250906-p5msve.html</link><title>A jobs slump spurred Trump to sack his stats boss. This time around he’s got no one to blame (smh.com.au)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9nrme/a_jobs_slump_spurred_trump_to_sack_his_stats_boss/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9nrme/a_jobs_slump_spurred_trump_to_sack_his_stats_boss/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9nrme/a_jobs_slump_spurred_trump_to_sack_his_stats_boss/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.2111%2C$multiply_0.7554%2C$ratio_1.777778%2C$width_1059%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/t_smh_analysis_no_age_social_wm/f6cd6cc534b3b8949ad4afc3dc2524a956fa56af' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><article><header></header><div><div><p><strong>Washington: </strong>The latest employment report in the United States is bad news for a president whose agenda revolves around <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p5labn">returning America to a &ldquo;golden age&rdquo;</a>, driven largely by a resurgence in manufacturing.</p><p>It shows jobs growth continues to stagnate, with just 22,000 positions created in August &ndash; while job losses in manufacturing were 12,000 for the month, and 78,000 for the year to date.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>Manufacturing job losses totalled 78,000 for the year so far, despite the Trump administration&rsquo;s bid to restore US factories.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>Bloomberg</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Last time Donald Trump received a weaker than expected jobs report from the Bureau of Labour Statistics &ndash; a month ago &ndash; he <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p5ml53">ordered the sacking of the agency&rsquo;s commissioner</a>, economist Erika McEntarfer.</p><p>This time, there&rsquo;s no figurehead to blame. Trump&rsquo;s pick to replace McEntarfer is yet to be confirmed by the US Senate.</p></div><div><p>The bureau found total non-farm payrolls, a widely watched indicator of US economic health, rose just 22,000 in August &ldquo;and has shown little change since April&rdquo;. Job gains in the healthcare sector were partially offset by losses in the federal government and in mining, quarrying, and oil and gas extraction, it said.</p><p>The August report also made further revisions to earlier months&rsquo; data, finding that in June, the US economy actually lost 13,000 jobs, rather than gaining 14,000 (a number which had already been revised down from 147,000). The July jobs growth figure was revised upward slightly to 79,000.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>The jobs report was the first since Donald Trump sensationally sacked the head of the Bureau of Labour Statistics for announcing weak data.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>Bloomberg</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Kevin Hassett, the director of Trump&rsquo;s National Security Council, told CNBC that while the figures were &ldquo;a little bit disappointing&rdquo;, he expected them to be revised up later.</p><p>That&rsquo;s entirely possible. Survey completion rates have fallen markedly since the pandemic, making it difficult for the bureau to provide accurate data in a timely, monthly fashion. That was true when McEntarfer was sacked for revising figures down, and it&rsquo;s true today.</p></div></div><div><div><div><p>Overall, the unemployment rate ticked up to 4.3 per cent &ndash; the highest since September 2017, outside the COVID-19 spike, though still low.</p><p>Trump reacted to the latest data by repeating his calls for the Federal Reserve to cut interest rates. &ldquo;[Fed chair] <a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p5mj6v">Jerome &lsquo;Too Late&rsquo; Powell</a> should have lowered rates long ago. As usual, he&rsquo;s &lsquo;Too Late!&rsquo;&rdquo; Trump posted on social media.</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>US Federal Reserve chairman Jerome Powell in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, for the Fed&rsquo;s annual gathering of global central bankers.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>Bloomberg</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Speaking at the central bank&rsquo;s annual summit in Jackson Hole, Wyoming last month, Powell gave a strong signal that rate cuts are on the way, noting the risks to employment were rising and &ldquo;may warrant adjusting our policy stance&rdquo;.</p><p>Scott Paul, the president of the Alliance for American Manufacturing, agreed the new report ought to spur a rate cut. But he also warned that Trump needed to finalise his policies on tariffs and trade.</p></div><div><p>&ldquo;Concluding tariff actions and trade deals to provide businesses with the certainty they need to hire, invest in new capital equipment, and realign supply chains,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Manufacturing will be treading water until we see those changes.&rdquo;</p><figure><figcaption><p><span>Sacked BLS chief Erika McEntarfer.</span><cite><span>Credit: </span>US Bureau of Labor Statistics</cite></p></figcaption></figure><p>Justin Wolfers, an Australian economics professor at the University of Michigan, said the data was worrying and indicated rosy assessments of the US economy&rsquo;s resilience were premature. &ldquo;Bad policy leads to bad outcomes, but the actual economy doesn&rsquo;t move at the pace of the political cycle,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Wolfers credited bureau staff for compiling the data &ldquo;despite the arbitrary firing of their boss, uninformed social media insults, and the prospect of being led by an unqualified ideologue&rdquo;.</p><p>Trump&rsquo;s pick for the job, E.J. Antoni, is the chief economist at the Heritage Foundation, a right-wing think tank that produced the conservative blueprint Project 2025. On Friday, CNN reported Antoni once ran a now-deleted Twitter account that contained sexually degrading attacks on Kamala Harris, conspiracy theories and anti-gay remarks.</p></div><div><p>Meanwhile, Trump is engaged in a different form of reality-denial. Hours before the employment data was released, he was asked whether he would accept the numbers. He dismissed the question, saying &ldquo;the real numbers&rdquo; would come out in a year or so, once his economic agenda was realised.</p><p>Life is more difficult when you can&rsquo;t just shoot the messenger.</p><p><b><i>Get a note directly from our foreign </i></b><b><i>correspondents </i></b><b><i>on what&rsquo;s making headlines around the world. </i></b><a href="https://www.smh.com.au/link/follow-20170101-p56l7u"><b><i>Sign up for our weekly What in the World newsletter</i></b></a><b><i>.</i></b></p></div></div><div><section><header><h2>Most Viewed in World</h2></header><p><span><span>Loading</span></span></p></section></div></div></article><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.189%2C$multiply_0.7725%2C$ratio_1.5%2C$width_756%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/c0ac78b194c30249aa466dce98d35c8904cb6918"></p><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.378%2C$multiply_0.7725%2C$ratio_1.5%2C$width_756%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/98d6bda8b8730d5656ecea5ef1abceb81c48bfda"></p><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.378%2C$multiply_0.7725%2C$ratio_1.5%2C$width_756%2C$x_0%2C$y_0/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/79adde6be61b3428b7c0b148f8f8474f5b426859"></p><p><img src="https://static.ffx.io/images/$zoom_0.844%2C$multiply_0.7487%2C$ratio_1%2C$width_378%2C$x_0%2C$y_35/t_crop_custom/q_86%2Cf_auto/6e87f68ac53bafa298818989bda5b97cd9a306aa474f1bd273691b84f39c856e"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 07:41:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/economy-jobs-report-trump-agenda</link><title>Trump’s economy problem is threatening his entire agenda (cnn.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9fcuf/trumps_economy_problem_is_threatening_his_entire/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9fcuf/trumps_economy_problem_is_threatening_his_entire/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 11 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n9fcuf/trumps_economy_problem_is_threatening_his_entire/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2230148969.jpg?c=16x9&q=w_800,c_fill' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>President Donald Trump came into office with massive plans to overhaul the way the US government operates and consolidate power in himself. </p><p>And he&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/11/politics/trump-blowback-looming-analysis">been largely successful</a> in implementing that vision, thanks to a cowed Congress, timid institutions and a languid judiciary. </p><p>But there are growing signs that his entire agenda could be undercut and his party could face massive political consequences because of his hubris on the single most important issue to Americans: the economy. </p><p>A new <a href="https://www.cnn.com/business/live-news/us-jobs-report-august-2025">Bureau of Labor Statistics report</a> Friday confirms some the worst fears about a worsening jobs market. A brief recap: </p><div><ul> <li> <span> Preliminary numbers show just 22,000 jobs added in August, a very low number for an economy that generally needs to create about 100,000 jobs every month to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/11/03/economy/jobs-report-october-final">keep up with population growth</a>. </span> </li> <li> <span> Revisions in other months mean the economy has created only an estimated 107,000 jobs over the last four months combined. Apart from recessions and their aftermaths, those are the worst numbers in decades. </span> </li> <li> <span> June&rsquo;s jobs numbers were revised into negative territory (13,000 jobs lost), making it the first negative month since December 2020. </span> </li> <li> <span> Despite Trump&rsquo;s promises of his tariffs revitalizing U.S. manufacturing boom, that industry has now lost 78,000 jobs this year. </span> </li> </ul> </div><p>The Trump administration has made pains to try to neutralize headlines about these jobs numbers, including last month by <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/08/04/business/bureau-of-labor-statistics-jobs-report-explainer-hnk">baselessly suggesting the numbers are being rigged</a> to make them look bad. (There is no evidence for this, and there are safeguards to prevent such manipulation.) After a bad July jobs report, Trump fired the head of BLS and now aims to replace her with <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/05/politics/kfile-ej-antoni-bureau-of-labor-statistics-twitter-account-vis">a controversial loyalist</a>. </p><p>If Trump&rsquo;s past is predicate, such conspiracy theories are likely to be revisited. But on Friday morning, there was apparently only so much the administration could do to spin these numbers. </p><p>Trump himself took aim at Jerome Powell, re-upping a familiar attack on the Fed Chair over his not lowering interest rates. Others acknowledged the report wasn&rsquo;t what they were hoping for. </p><p>&ldquo;This jobs number was certainly a little bit of a disappointment right now,&rdquo; top White House economic adviser Kevin Hassett said on CNBC, while predicting some upward revisions. </p><p>Labor Secretary Lori Chavez-DeRemer acknowledged on Fox Business that the new report &ldquo;underperformed a bit,&rdquo; while emphasizing that it at least contained some jobs gains (a very low bar, to be sure). </p><p>And Commerce Secretary Howard Lutnick seemed to plead for patience, asking people to judge Trump&rsquo;s jobs record not today but in 12 months. </p><p>&ldquo;You look at the unemployment rate numbers today &ndash; wait until a year from today,&rdquo; Lutnick said in CNBC. &ldquo;Wow. It will be amazing numbers.&rdquo; </p><p>But that&rsquo;s asking a lot. People are already judging Trump&rsquo;s stewardship of the economy more negatively than ever before. And while Trump arguably earned the benefit of the doubt when his tariffs didn&rsquo;t lead to immediate and crushing consequences, he still faces a deeply skeptical public and potentially disastrous political consequences. </p><p>A Quinnipiac University poll in late August showed Trump with his <a href="https://poll.qu.edu/poll-release?releaseid=3929">worst economic approval numbers to date</a>, in either of his two terms: 57% disapproving to 39% approving. </p><p><a href="https://news.gallup.com/poll/694370/trump-ratings-mood-stay-tepid-august.aspx">Gallup</a> pegged his economic approval rating at just 37%, after averaging 52% in his first term. Just 29% of independents approved. </p><p>A <a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/910985644/Yahoo-YouGov-Crime-Poll-August-2025">Yahoo News-YouGov poll</a> showed Americans disapproved of Trump on the &ldquo;cost of living&rdquo; by more than a 2-to-1 margin, 62-29%, and by a large margin on trade and tariffs, 58-35%. </p><div><picture><source height="undefined" width="679" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_679,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="967" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_967,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2228231689.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill" alt="Customers enter a grocery store in Westminster, California, on August 7." height="1600" width="2399"></source></source></source></source></source></picture> </div><p>We&rsquo;re also seeing some real cracks even in Trump&rsquo;s ever-loyal base. The Yahoo poll showed 27% of Republicans disapproved of Trump on the cost of living. And a Pew Research Center poll last month showed <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/politics/2025/08/14/how-americans-view-the-trump-administrations-tariff-policies-and-the-gops-budget-and-tax-bill/">32% of Republican-leaning voters disapproved</a> of his tariffs strategy. </p><p>All of which suggests the patience of even Trump&rsquo;s loyal supporters has already been tested. Are they really going to give him a year to straighten it all out? </p><p>The danger for Trump is that the economic picture turns bad enough that it sours Americans on the entire enterprise. </p><p>Trump&rsquo;s power plays are largely built on acquiescence. People might not like his methods, but they don&rsquo;t necessarily want to fight him on it. As long as these things don&rsquo;t impact them directly, the backlash is limited. </p><p>Indeed, many of Trump&rsquo;s most controversial initiatives are pretty unpopular &ndash; things like deporting people without due process, putting troops on US soil, the Department of Government Efficiency cuts, and Trump&rsquo;s signature agenda bill that cut Medicaid. We&rsquo;ve already seen <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/07/17/politics/gop-malaise-trump-epstein-analysis">cracks in Trump&rsquo;s base on some of these issues</a> &ndash; along with, most pronouncedly, the administration&rsquo;s handling of the Jeffrey Epstein files. </p><p>But none of those issues has caused a real revolt by Congress or anyone who could impede his agenda. </p><p>The economy is perhaps the one thing that could change that rather quickly, and bring these readily apparent concerns about his presidency to the fore. </p><p>Should things continue to turn sour, Trump and Co. can blame BLS data and the Federal Reserve&rsquo;s interest rates all they want. But it won&rsquo;t be difficult for Americans to trace all of it to something that&rsquo;s much easier to grasp and attach to Trump: his economy-rocking moves to unilaterally implement huge tariffs. These are moves that he made without consulting Congress, after all, and despite the (gently expressed) reservations of congressional Republicans who spent decades hailing free trade. </p><p>Trump did this despite persistent inflation that still hadn&rsquo;t really abated. He voluntarily took ownership of an already-tenuous situation and injected it with a huge amount of uncertainty. </p><p>Trump invested gobs of political capital in this. It&rsquo;s looking more and more like a bad bet. </p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/2025-09-05t135925z-374478399-rc2plga3zhi7-rtrmadp-3-usa-economy.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 01:29:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.vox.com/scotus/460312/supreme-court-trump-tariffs-vos-selections</link><title>Trump’s lawyers just inadvertently admitted that his tariffs are illegal (vox.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n96fxd/trumps_lawyers_just_inadvertently_admitted_that/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n96fxd/trumps_lawyers_just_inadvertently_admitted_that/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n96fxd/trumps_lawyers_just_inadvertently_admitted_that/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://platform.vox.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/04/gettyimages-2208184612.jpg?quality=90&strip=all&crop=0%2C10.732984293194%2C100%2C78.534031413613&w=1200' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>The Trump administration formally asked the Supreme Court on Wednesday evening to decide whether President Donald Trump&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26082943-20250903-trump-v-vos-selections-cert-petition/">ever-shifting tariff policy is lawful</a>. Two federal courts, and a total of 10 federal judges, have all concluded that it is not.</p><p>The remarkable thing about Trump&rsquo;s petition asking the justices to take up this case, which is known as <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26082943-20250903-trump-v-vos-selections-cert-petition/"><em>Trump v. V.O.S. Selections</em></a>, it that it opens with a long list of factual claims that, if taken seriously by the Court, would compel the justices to strike down the tariffs. But that would assume the Republican-controlled Supreme Court applies the same limits on executive power to Trump that it <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">imposed on Democratic President Joe Biden</a> &mdash; a <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/458863/supreme-court-nih-public-health-grants-gobbledygook">highly uncertain proposition</a>.</p><div><h2>The tariffs are obviously illegal under the Republican justices&rsquo; &ldquo;major questions doctrine&rdquo;</h2></div><p>During the Biden administration, the Republican justices relied on something called the &ldquo;<a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">major questions doctrine</a>&rdquo; to strike down several of Biden&rsquo;s policies. The Court&rsquo;s Republicans only recently invented this doctrine. It has no basis in law, and it has only ever been used against one president in history: Joe Biden.</p><div><form><div><h2>SCOTUS, Explained</h2><p><span>Get the latest developments on the US Supreme Court from senior correspondent Ian Millhiser.</span></p></div></form></div><p>That said, the Court did preview the doctrine in an Obama-era decision that applied it to a hypothetical regulation. In that case, <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/pdf/12-1146.pdf"><em>Utility Air Regulatory Group v. EPA</em></a> (2014), the Republican justices announced that &ldquo;we expect Congress to speak clearly if it wishes to assign to an agency decisions of vast &lsquo;economic and political significance.&rsquo;&rdquo; The idea was that, even if a federal law can be read to permit the executive to enact a particular policy, courts should read those laws narrowly if the policy is too ambitious.</p><p>Indeed, under Biden, the Court even used this recently made-up doctrine to <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/2023/6/30/23779903/supreme-court-student-loan-biden-nebraska-john-roberts">strike down policies that are unambiguously authorized by federal law</a>. In <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/22pdf/22-506_nmip.pdf"><em>Biden v. Nebraska</em></a> (2023), the Republican justices struck down the Biden administration&rsquo;s attempt to cancel many student loans. But federal law could not possibly have been clearer that the executive is permitted to cancel these loans.</p><p>The <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/STATUTE-117/pdf/STATUTE-117-Pg904.pdf#page=1">relevant statute</a> gave the education secretary broad authority to &ldquo;waive or modify any statutory or regulatory provision applicable to the student financial assistance programs&rdquo; during a national emergency such as the COVID-19 pandemic. The secretary could use this power, moreover, &ldquo;notwithstanding any other provision of law, unless enacted with specific reference to&rdquo; the statute authorizing him to cancel loans.</p><p>Nevertheless, the Republican justices overrode this statute, pointing to the loan cancellation plan&rsquo;s high price tag of &ldquo;<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/22pdf/22-506_nmip.pdf">between $469 billion and $519 billion</a>.&rdquo; The &ldquo;economic and political significance&rdquo; of such a plan, they concluded, &ldquo;is staggering by any measure.&rdquo; And thus the program must be canceled.</p><div><p>Which brings us back to Trump&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26082943-20250903-trump-v-vos-selections-cert-petition/">petition asking the justices to hear the tariffs case</a>. That petition describes the tariffs as Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;most significant economic and foreign-policy initiative.&rdquo; It claims that the tariff is necessary to close US trade deficits of &ldquo;$1.2 trillion per year.&rdquo; It alleges that the tariffs have given Trump leverage to extract multi-trillion-dollar concessions from foreign nations. And it also claims that the increased taxes Trump has unilaterally imposed on imports &mdash; taxes that will <a href="https://budgetlab.yale.edu/research/short-run-effects-2025-tariffs-so-far">largely be paid by the American consumer</a> &mdash; &ldquo;<a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26082943-20250903-trump-v-vos-selections-cert-petition/">will reduce federal deficits by $4 trillion in the coming years</a>.&rdquo;</p></div><p>Trump, in other words, claims that the economic significance of these tariffs is an order of magnitude greater than the significance of the student loan program at issue in <em>Nebraska</em> &mdash; the one the Republican justices said they must strike down because its significance is &ldquo;staggering by any measure.&rdquo;</p><p>To be sure, it&rsquo;s never a good idea for a court to base its decisions on factual claims made by this particular administration. But independent analysis confirms that the economic and political significance of the tariffs is at least as &ldquo;staggering&rdquo; as the significance of Biden&rsquo;s student loan program. An August analysis of the tariffs by Yale&rsquo;s Budget Lab, for example, concluded that Trump&rsquo;s tariffs will cost the average American household $2,400 in 2025, and that the tariffs will <a href="https://budgetlab.yale.edu/research/state-us-tariffs-august-7-2025">raise $2.7 trillion in taxes</a> over a 10-year window.</p><div><h2>At least one of the Court&rsquo;s Republicans appears to think that the major questions doctrine doesn&rsquo;t apply to Trump</h2></div><p>It would seem, then, that a straightforward application of the major questions doctrine compels this Court to invalidate Trump&rsquo;s tariffs. But Justice Brett Kavanaugh already appears to be looking for a way to bail out Trump. Concurring in <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/24pdf/24-354_0861.pdf"><em>FCC v. Consumers&rsquo; Research</em></a> (2025), Kavanaugh suggested that this newly invented doctrine does not apply to &ldquo;foreign policy contexts.&rdquo;</p><p>Trump&rsquo;s petition also suggests <a href="https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26082943-20250903-trump-v-vos-selections-cert-petition/">other ways the Court could exempt him</a> from the doctrine, including a claim that the doctrine doesn&rsquo;t apply when the president personally authorizes a federal policy, instead of promulgating that policy through a federal agency.</p><p>Are these arguments persuasive? The truth is that there&rsquo;s no such thing as a persuasive argument involving the major questions doctrine, because the whole thing is a figment of the Republican justices&rsquo; imagination. The Court has <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/23791610/supreme-court-major-questions-doctrine-nebraska-biden-student-loans-gorsuch-barrett">never published</a> a majority opinion claiming that this doctrine can be found in any provision of the Constitution, or in any federal statute. And while some individual justices have offered their own explanations of where this recently invented doctrine comes from, those explanations range from silly to ridiculous.</p><div><p>Concurring in <em>Nebraska</em>, for example, Justice Amy Coney Barrett claimed that the doctrine is <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/22pdf/22-506_nmip.pdf">implicit in a parable about a babysitter</a>.</p></div><p>Asking whether the doctrine applies to foreign policy decisions, in other words, is a bit like asking your daughter whether her imaginary friend likes fried chicken. The answer is whatever your daughter wants it to be.</p><p>As Justice Clarence Thomas wrote in a concurring opinion earlier this year, &ldquo;judge-made doctrines can be difficult for courts to apply&rdquo; because those courts &ldquo;<a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/24pdf/23-1039_c0n2.pdf">lack an underlying legal authority on which to ground their analysis</a>.&rdquo; If the major questions doctrine derived from a constitutional provision, then the justices could read that provision to determine if it contains a foreign policy exception. If it derived from a statute, they could refer to the statute.</p><p>But, because the major questions doctrine is simply something that the Republican justices made up, there is no principled way to determine if it conveniently contains an exception that just happens to rescue a Republican president&rsquo;s &ldquo;most significant economic and foreign-policy initiative&rdquo; from invalidation.</p><p>That said, courts are supposed to apply the same rules to Democratic presidents that they apply to Republicans. If the Republican justices actually buy Trump&rsquo;s claim that he is exempt, that will leave little doubt that these justices are <a href="https://www.vox.com/scotus/458863/supreme-court-nih-public-health-grants-gobbledygook">simply playing Calvinball</a> &mdash; creating one set of rules to spite Democrats, and a different, far more favorable set of rules for Republicans.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 19:45:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/05/jobs-report-august-2025.html</link><title>Payrolls rose 22,000 in August, less than expected in further sign of hiring slowdown (cnbc.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n941b8/payrolls_rose_22000_in_august_less_than_expected/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n941b8/payrolls_rose_22000_in_august_less_than_expected/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n941b8/payrolls_rose_22000_in_august_less_than_expected/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108194186-1756986229072-gettyimages-2228223483-US_JOBS.jpeg?v=1756986317&w=1920&h=1080' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><p>Job creation sputtered in August, adding to recent signs of labor market weakening and likely keeping the Federal Reserve on track for a widely anticipated interest rate cut later this month.</p><p><a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.nr0.htm">Nonfarm payrolls</a> increased by just 22,000 for the month, while the unemployment rate rose to 4.3%, according to a Bureau of Labor Statistics report Friday. Economists surveyed by Dow Jones had been looking for payrolls to rise by 75,000.</p><p>The report showed a marked slowdown from the July increase of 79,000, which was revised up by 6,000. Revisions also showed a net loss of 13,000 in June after the prior estimate was lowered by 27,000.</p></div><div><p>"The job market is stalling short of the runway," said Daniel Zhao, chief economist at jobs site Glassdoor. "The labor market is losing lift, and August's report, along with downward revisions, suggests we're heading into turbulence without the soft landing achieved."</p><p>Markets largely disregarded the report, with <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/04/stock-market-today-live-updates-.html">stocks up at the open</a> and Treasury yields sharply lower. Traders in the futures markets raised the probability of a quarter percentage point Fed rate cut to 100% and went even further, pricing in a 12% probability of a half-point move, according to the CME Group's <a href="https://www.cmegroup.com/markets/interest-rates/cme-fedwatch-tool.html?redirect=/trading/interest-rates/countdown-to-fomc.html">FedWatc</a>h gauge.</p><p>The payrolls count was the first since President Donald <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/08/01/trump-erika-mcentarfer-jobs-report-fired.html">Trump fired former BLS Commissioner Erika McEntarfer</a> following the release of the July jobs report a month ago. The move came after the report showed not just a weak level of job creation but also dramatic reductions in previous months' totals.</p><p>In McEntarfer's place, the president nominated economist E.J. Antoni, a Trump loyalist from the Heritage Foundation who previously had criticized the BLS numbers as being politically distorted. William Wiatrowski is serving as acting BLS commissioner.</p><p>While the pace of hiring was slow, average hourly earnings increased 0.3% for the month, meeting the estimate, though the annual gain of 3.7% was slightly below the forecast for 3.8%.</p></div><div><p>Hiring was held back by a payroll reduction in the federal government, which reported a decline of 15,000.</p><p>Health care again led sectors, adding 31,000 jobs, while social assistance contributed 16,000. Wholesale trade and manufacturing both saw declines of 12,000 on the month.</p><p>The report comes as markets widely expect the Fed to lower its benchmark interest rate by a quarter percentage point when it releases its next decision Sept. 17. Fed Chair <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/jay-powell/">Jerome Powell</a> and his fellow policymakers also have been under heavy criticism from the president as they have been on hold since last cutting in December 2024.</p><p>Though most economic indicators indicate continued expansion, Fed officials have expressed concern about a slowdown in hiring even as layoffs have held fairly steady. At the same time, policymakers worry that <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/donald-trump/">Trump</a>'s tariffs could reignite inflation, with data indicating a slow but steady increase in prices over recent months.</p><p>"The warning bell that rang in the labor market a month ago just got louder. A weaker-than-expected jobs report all but seals a 25-basis-point rate cut later this month," said Olu Sonola, head of U.S. economic research at Fitch Ratings. "Four straight months of manufacturing job losses stand out. It's hard to argue that tariff uncertainty isn't a key driver of this weakness."</p><p>While the <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.b.htm">establishment survey</a> showed weak job creation, the more volatile <a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.a.htm">household count</a>, used to calculate the unemployment rate, held better news.</p><p>That report showed an increase of 288,000 employed, though the ranks of the unemployed also rose by 148,000. The labor force participation rate edged higher to 62.3% while the labor force swelled by 436,000, accounting for the tick higher in the unemployment rate.</p></div><div><p>A broader measure of unemployment that includes discouraged workers and those holding part-time jobs for economic reasons climbed to 8.1%, a 0.2 percentage point increase and the highest level since October 2021.</p><p>Along with the jobs numbers tally, the BLS on Tuesday will release the initial estimate for annual benchmark revisions to the numbers dating back one year from March 2025.</p><p>Revisions have been a source of controversy, particularly in the post-Covid era as the response rate has declined, particularly for the headline establishment survey that asks businesses and government agencies to detail the pace of hiring.</p><p>The BLS typically releases its initial estimate with the first batch of survey responses it gets, then updates two times as it gets more information. However, Trump has accused the BLS of being politically biased. The firing of McEntarfer drew widespread criticism in the economics and markets community.</p><p>In a <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/05/jobs-hassett-trump-rates.html">CNBC interview</a>, National Economic Council Director Kevin Hassett said he expects the August payrolls count to get revised higher. In the past three years, the initial August count actually was revised lower from the initial estimate.</p><p><em>Correction: The BLS on Tuesday will release the initial estimate for annual benchmark revisions to the numbers dating back one year from March 2025. An earlier version misstated the timing.</em></p></div><div><h2>Don&rsquo;t miss these insights from CNBC PRO</h2></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108194833-17570757121757075709-41506113646-1080pnbcnews.jpg?v=1757075711&amp;w=750&amp;h=422&amp;vtcrop=y"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:03:40 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.kait8.com/2025/09/02/i-have-never-been-worried-i-am-now-arkansas-farmers-gather-share-concerns/</link><title>‘I have never been as worried as I am now’: Arkansas farmers gather to share concerns (kait8.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jxd8/i_have_never_been_as_worried_as_i_am_now_arkansas/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jxd8/i_have_never_been_as_worried_as_i_am_now_arkansas/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jxd8/i_have_never_been_as_worried_as_i_am_now_arkansas/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://gray-kait-prod.gtv-cdn.com/resizer/v2/2R3NXX24ANA2TPFFIJHCPVSAFQ.bmp?auth=3c22d1b6c780110f89cc36a24b7fd2933358e9d0ef586723d7eaddf594b333cb&width=1200&height=600&smart=true' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><article><div><p>BROOKLAND, Ark. (KAIT) - Farmers from across the state are asking for help before it&rsquo;s too late.</p><p>Hundreds of farmers gathered in Brookland to speak with representatives of Arkansas leaders to share with them their urgent plight: the difficulties they face in farming today.</p><p>Many farmers spoke out at the meeting.</p><p>Their message was straightforward: We need help, and we need it now.</p><p>&ldquo;Mr. Trump, you looked at me and said, &lsquo;I love you,&rsquo;&rdquo; Woodruff County farmer Chris King said. &ldquo;Mr. Trump, I need to see the fruit of your love.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;You are going to lose 25 to 30% of the farmers in this country if they don&rsquo;t do something,&rdquo; said Scott Brown, a farmer from Biggers, Arkansas. &ldquo;It has to be done, and it&rsquo;s not just here; it&rsquo;s everywhere.&rdquo;</p><figure><figcaption><span>Hundreds of farmers gathered in Brookland to speak with representatives of Arkansas leaders to share with them their urgent plight: the difficulties they face in farming today.</span><span>(kait)</span></figcaption></figure><h3>Hundreds of farmers gather to share their concerns</h3><p>The line to get into the meeting place, the Woods Chapel Baptist Church, went out the door. Countless farmers from across the state came to voice their concerns about the current state of farming.</p><p>Representatives from U.S. Congressman Rick Crawford, Sen. Tom Cotton, and Sen. John Boozman&rsquo;s offices attended the gathering to hear concerns.</p><p>One of the farmers in attendance, Chris King, spoke about his harvest difficulties.</p><p>He told us this was his 39th harvest, and he has never seen it this bad before. </p><p>&ldquo;I have never been as worried as I am now about whether or not my kids and grandkids will be able to carry on,&rdquo; said Chris King.</p><h3>Lack of profit, export difficulties, and high costs</h3><p>Chris King said the main problem is that they can&rsquo;t sell for profit. </p><p>&ldquo;I just would like to see somebody help us get our markets back,&rdquo; said Chris King. &ldquo;We need our exports, and we just need to be paid for what we do, and that&rsquo;s not happening, and we&rsquo;re in real trouble.&rdquo;</p><p>But this is not the only issue.</p><p>Chris King&rsquo;s wife, Melissa King, and farmer Scott Brown said they are struggling to afford the bare minimum cost to maintain their farms.</p><p>&ldquo;Prices that we are getting now are prices like they were when we were children, and what it costs for us to farm is astronomical now. The price of a combine when we were kids was in the 20,000s, and now it&rsquo;s 100,000,&rdquo; said Melissa King.</p><p>&ldquo;I farm 800 acres by myself, I can&rsquo;t afford any help, I farm with paid-for equipment, all my tractors are 50 years old, and I can&rsquo;t hardly make this deal work,&rdquo; said Brown. &ldquo;How are the guys farming 5 and 10 thousand with 20 hands and million-dollar combines and million-dollar drills going to make it work?&rdquo;</p><h3>Tariffs are hurting farmers</h3><p>Brown said one issue that rounds out all the problems farmers are facing: tariffs.</p><p>&ldquo;I think the tariffs are the ice cream on the cake of a perfect storm,&rdquo; said Brown. &ldquo;When you try and sell a product, okay, U.S. soybeans leaving New Orleans without the tariff to China are cheaper than Brazilian soybeans, at the current market. But when you put the tariff on top of them, Brazilian beans are cheaper.&rdquo; </p><p>What can be done to help farmers? </p><p>&ldquo;In the short term, they have no choice but to mail us a check,&rdquo; said Brown. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know a farmer that likes the check program. Nobody wants to take the taxpayer dollars, but nobody wants to go broke, nobody wants to lose everything. Long term, we have to have options, markets, and places to sell our product.&rdquo; </p><p>The political representatives who attended said they will take these concerns to Washington to share with government leaders and find a way to solve this problem before it&rsquo;s too late.</p><p><i>To report a typo or correction, please </i><a href="https://www.kait8.com/page/tips/"><i>click here</i></a><i>.</i></p><p><i>Copyright 2025 KAIT. All rights reserved.</i></p></div></article><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://gray-kait-prod.gtv-cdn.com/resizer/v2/2R3NXX24ANA2TPFFIJHCPVSAFQ.bmp?auth=3c22d1b6c780110f89cc36a24b7fd2933358e9d0ef586723d7eaddf594b333cb&amp;width=980&amp;height=551&amp;smart=true"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 01:07:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://katv.com/news/local/hundreds-of-struggling-arkansas-farmers-ask-federal-government-to-save-them-agriculture-ag-economy-farm-bill-commodity-prices-safety-net-big-beautiful-bill-derek-haigwood-brookland-farming-delta-farm-bankruptcy-closure-sale-trump-boozman-crawford</link><title>Hundreds of struggling Arkansas farmers ask federal government to save them (katv.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jcvg/hundreds_of_struggling_arkansas_farmers_ask/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jcvg/hundreds_of_struggling_arkansas_farmers_ask/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1n8jcvg/hundreds_of_struggling_arkansas_farmers_ask/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://katv.com/resources/media2/16x9/1280/986/center/90/6f6132c4-2f52-49ec-96cb-30051f776380-PFARMERBANKRUPTCIES.transfer_frame_5123.jpeg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>NEWPORT, Ark. (KATV) &mdash; </span>Hundreds of struggling Arkansas farmers are pleading with the federal government to provide emergency funding amid a farm economy crisis.</p><p>Almost everything that could go wrong for Arkansas farmers went wrong this year, leaving many facing bankruptcy or even the closure of farms that have been passed down for generations.</p><p>A dismal global market and plunging commodity prices mean there&rsquo;s little hope of breaking even, even as input costs soar because of inflation and tariffs&mdash;on top of bad weather earlier in the year.</p><p>&ldquo;This time last year, the rice price was about 40 percent higher than it is now. Inputs costs have gone up, fertilizer has gone up, commodity prices have gotten worse. So, after a horrible year last year where most farmers in Arkansas, Delta, lost money, this year is going to be worse,&rdquo; said Derek Haigwood, a farmer from Independence and Jackson county.</p><p>Though President Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;Big, Beautiful Bill&rdquo; provided a much-needed update to safety net subsidies for farmers, they won&rsquo;t see those federal dollars until late next year. By then, some have projected that as many as one-fourth&mdash;or even one-third&mdash;of Arkansas farmers could face bankruptcy or be forced out of business.</p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m a sixth-generation farmer from Newport, and we made the decision to go out this year, in the spring. So, my son will not be the seventh generation on our farm,&rdquo; said one Newport farmer.</p><p>&ldquo;In the last 14 months, five of my customers have committed suicide. That&rsquo;s how serious this is,&rdquo; said another Arkansas farmer who also works as an ag equipment financier.</p><p>On Tuesday, farmers gathered in Brookland to share their struggles with staffers from Arkansas&rsquo; congressional delegation, asking the state's representatives on Capitol Hill and the governor to convince the president to provide emergency aid to see them through to next year.</p><p>&ldquo;We have to have ad hoc payments right now to make it through this year,&rdquo; Haigwood said.</p><p>&ldquo;If there&rsquo;s no emergency funding this year, there will be one out of three farmers who will file bankruptcy,&rdquo; said Chris King, a Woodruff County farmer.</p><p>Their cries for help did not appear to fall on deaf ears.</p><p>&ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to take your message. We&rsquo;re going to get it back to D.C. and we&rsquo;re going to do everything we can to get you the help you need,&rdquo; said Gene Higginbotham, district director for Congressman Rick Crawford.</p><p>Until then, farmers have no one to turn to but God.</p><p>&ldquo;Farmers, in my opinion, dear Lord, they&rsquo;re closer to you than anyone else on this earth because we deal with your earth every day. Dear Lord, we&rsquo;re hurting, dear Lord. We can&rsquo;t help what&rsquo;s happened to us. We need help, dear Lord,&rdquo; prayed one farmer at Tuesday's meeting.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:45:38 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
