<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=science&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/science</title><description>Hot posts in /r/science (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:17:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_mouw-styles-communityIcon_xtjipkhhefi41-144x400.png</url><title>/r/science</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/students-rate-identical-lectures-differently-based-on-professors-gender-researchers-find/</link><title>Students rate identical lectures differently based on professor's gender, researchers find (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ndleip/students_rate_identical_lectures_differently/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ndleip/students_rate_identical_lectures_differently/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ndleip/students_rate_identical_lectures_differently/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/professor.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Students may judge professors differently based on gender, even when the teaching is identical. A study in <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/09515089.2025.2551237">Philosophical Psychology</a></em> provides evidence that implicit stereotypes continue to shape evaluations in ways that could affect academic careers.</p><p>The study was motivated by concerns about the fairness of student evaluations of teaching, particularly in disciplines like philosophy, which remain heavily male-dominated. Across European academia, women account for a substantial share of early-career researchers but are still underrepresented at the full professor level. In Italy, for example, women make up only 27% of full professors despite being nearly half of the academic workforce at earlier stages.</p><p>Philosophy is one of the disciplines with the most pronounced gender disparities. In Italian philosophy departments, women comprise less than a third of full and associate professors combined. Prior research suggests that fields perceived as &ldquo;male-typed&rdquo; tend to carry implicit expectations that ideal performers embody stereotypically masculine traits like assertiveness, confidence, and authority. This can create a double bind for women, who are often penalized for being too assertive while also being judged as less competent when they express communal or nurturing traits.</p><p>&ldquo;Our project began with personal and anecdotal evidence. In our daily experience, we noticed that students often behaved differently depending on whether they were interacting with men or women professors and these patterns varied with the gender of the students themselves,&rdquo; said study author <a href="https://www.unibo.it/sitoweb/pia.campeggiani2/en">Pia Campeggiani</a>, an associate professor of moral philosophy at the University of Bologna and author of <em><a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/uk/theories-of-emotion-9781350297913/">Theories of Emotion: Expressing, Feeling, Acting</a></em>.</p><p>&ldquo;We wanted to understand whether these impressions were backed up by systematic data and we were surprised to discover that, in the Italian context, no such data existed. This absence in itself seemed telling and it convinced us that we needed to design and conduct our own studies in order to investigate the phenomenon directly.</p><p>&ldquo;Our broader aim is for this research to help build a stronger empirical foundation for institutional policies, which in Italian academia remain largely inadequate for effectively confronting gender discrimination and marginalization. To give just one example of the structural imbalance: in the philosophy department where I work, at Bologna University, the number of women full professors is only one quarter of that of their men colleagues.&rdquo;</p><p>The research team conducted two separate experiments. In both studies, participants were philosophy students or recent graduates from Italian universities. The students were asked to evaluate short lecture excerpts that were identical in content but varied in the gender of the professor attributed to them.</p><p>In the first study, 95 participants read four lecture excerpts on philosophical topics, including Aristotle&rsquo;s ethics and Bourdieu&rsquo;s concept of symbolic power. Each excerpt was randomly assigned a fictitious male or female name. After reading each passage, participants answered questions about the clarity, interest, perceived competence, self-confidence, care, and overall engagement they felt toward the lecturer. These evaluations mirrored the types of items typically found in real-world student evaluations.</p><p>The second study involved 92 participants and used the same lecture excerpts, but this time delivered as audio recordings by voice actors selected to represent typical male and female vocal characteristics. Again, participants evaluated each lecture on the same seven dimensions and completed an additional questionnaire measuring their beliefs about gender roles.</p><p>By manipulating only the apparent gender of the professor&mdash;either via a name or a voice&mdash;the researchers aimed to isolate the effects of gender bias on teaching evaluations.</p><p>In the first study, male participants consistently rated lectures more favorably when they were attributed to a man. This was true across several key dimensions, including clarity, interest, competence, self-confidence, and perceived benefit. Men also showed a greater willingness to take a full course with a male professor. The only area where they rated women higher was in perceived care, consistent with stereotypes that associate women with nurturing roles.</p><p>In contrast, women participants in the first study showed little bias in their evaluations, except when it came to engagement. Like men, they expressed a greater willingness to enroll in a full course when the professor was male. The researchers suggest this may reflect the influence of deeper, possibly unconscious biases that persist even when women consciously attempt to judge content fairly.</p><p>&ldquo;We were surprised by the behaviour of women participants in our first study, which used written texts,&rdquo; Campeggiani told PsyPost. &ldquo;In their evaluations, women participants were relatively unbiased: they rated lectures similarly, regardless of whether they believed the instructor was a man or a woman. Yet when asked whether they would take a full course with that instructor, they showed a clear preference for men.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;We have hypothesized that women participants may have been able to suppress bias in straightforward, text-based evaluations, but that bias re-emerged when their attention shifted toward personal choices and motivations. Another possible explanation is that the low gender salience of the text condition led participants to perceive women professors as exhibiting masculine-coded traits. This may have prompted women participants to evaluate women professors as positively as men, while simultaneously triggering a backlash against counter-stereotypical behavior, expressed in their reluctance to commit to a full course with a woman professor.&rdquo;</p><p>The second study, which used spoken rather than written lectures, found even broader evidence of gender bias. In this version, both male and female participants rated male professors higher across nearly all dimensions, including clarity, interest, competence, and self-confidence. Women were still rated more highly on care. This pattern held even for participants who reported egalitarian views about gender roles.</p><p>&ldquo;In our second study, where the gender of the professors was made more salient through the use of audio recordings, women participants displayed the same gender biases as men participants,&rdquo; Campeggiani said.</p><p>The second study also found that students&rsquo; explicit beliefs about gender equality, as measured by a standardized questionnaire, were not strongly related to their actual evaluations. Even students with progressive attitudes tended to favor male professors. This suggests that implicit biases can operate independently of a person&rsquo;s stated values and may remain influential even when individuals consciously reject traditional gender norms.</p><p>The results indicate that &ldquo;there is still a great deal of work to be done,&rdquo; Campeggiani told PsyPost. &ldquo;One of our findings is that explicit egalitarian beliefs do not necessarily translate into the absence of gender bias. In other words, nobody is immune. We are all at risk of falling prey to these &lsquo;mindbugs&rsquo; and for this reason we must actively cultivate self-awareness and self-criticism. At the same time, we need to put in place procedural safeguards: rules and structures that help ensure our decisions, choices, and assessments are less biased and more impartial.&rdquo;</p><p>But there are a few limitations to note. The study focused specifically on philosophy students in Italy, which may limit the generalizability of the findings to other academic fields or cultural contexts. While the researchers made efforts to select gender-neutral lecture content and control for confounding variables, real-world classroom dynamics involve more interpersonal interaction than what was simulated in the experiments.</p><p>The researchers are interested in extending their work. &ldquo;We are considering several possible next steps,&rdquo; Campeggiani explained. &ldquo;One is to extend this line of research to primary and secondary schools, in order to see how early these patterns of bias emerge. Another is to replicate our study within academia but across different disciplines, to explore whether the dynamics we observed in philosophy are shared more broadly or vary by field.</p><p>&ldquo;It wasn&rsquo;t easy to carry out this study,&rdquo; she added. &ldquo;At various stages we encountered a certain degree of resistance, which in itself speaks to the sensitivity of the topic. I&rsquo;ll leave it at that, but I think the difficulty is part of what makes the work both necessary and worthwhile.&rdquo;</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1080/09515089.2025.2551237">The boys&rsquo; club: gender biases in students&rsquo; evaluations of their philosophy professors</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Pia Campeggiani, Marco Viola, and Marco Marini.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 23:26:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/sep/10/babies-cries-can-make-humans-physically-hotter-research-finds</link><title>Past research found that men were as likely as women to be woken by wailing infants. A new study found that the cry of a distressed baby triggers a rapid emotional response in both men and women that is enough to make them physically hotter. (theguardian.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ndaki8/past_research_found_that_men_were_as_likely_as/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ndaki8/past_research_found_that_men_were_as_likely_as/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ndaki8/past_research_found_that_men_were_as_likely_as/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/de79f3422561fa54bf024bac771f5afdbdb612a9/0_380_1116_893/master/1116.jpg?width=1200&height=630&quality=85&auto=format&fit=crop&precrop=40:21,offset-x50,offset-y0&overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&overlay-width=100p&overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctZGVmYXVsdC5wbmc&enable=upscale&s=5ec1285854cc959ba925f6b7ce81a917' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>The cry of a distressed baby triggers a rapid emotional response in both men and women that is enough to make them physically hotter, researchers say.</p><p>Thermal imaging revealed that people experienced a rush of blood to the face that raised the temperature of their skin when they were played recordings of babies wailing.</p><p>The effect was stronger and more synchronised when babies were more distressed, leading them to produce more chaotic and disharmonious cries. The work suggests that humans respond automatically to specific features in cries that ramp up when babies are in pain.</p><p>&ldquo;The emotional response to cries depends on their &lsquo;acoustic roughness&rsquo;,&rdquo; said Prof Nicolas Mathevon at the University of Saint-Etienne in France. &ldquo;We are emotionally sensitive to the acoustic parameters that encode the level of pain in a baby&rsquo;s cry.&rdquo;</p><p>Evolution equipped baby humans with a hard-to-ignore wail to boost their odds of getting the care they need. But not all infant cries are the same. When a baby is in real distress, they forcefully contract their rib cage, producing higher pressure air that causes chaotic vibrations in the vocal cords. This produces &ldquo;acoustic roughness&rdquo;, or more technically, disharmonious sounds called nonlinear phenomena (NLP).</p><p>To see how men and women responded to infants&rsquo; cries, scientists played recordings to volunteers with little or no experience with babies. While listening, the participants were filmed with a thermal camera that captured subtle changes in their facial temperature.</p><p>The adults listened to 16 different cries over four sessions and rated whether the baby was in discomfort or significant pain. The cries were recorded from babies in different levels of distress, ranging from discomfort in the bath to feeling the scratch of a needle at a vaccine clinic.</p><p>Footage from the thermal camera showed that men and women responded to babies&rsquo; cries in much the same way. The wails with the most NLP, regardless of pitch, were rated as coming from babies in real pain and triggered the greatest changes in the adults&rsquo; facial temperature.</p><p>Writing in <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rsif.2025.0150">Journal of The Royal Society Interface</a>, the scientists describe how NLP in babies&rsquo; cries produces an automatic response in men and women, suggesting people pick up on the acoustic features to distinguish between babies that are merely unhappy and those in real pain.</p><p>&ldquo;The more pain the cries express, the stronger the response of our autonomic nervous system, indicating that we emotionally sense the pain information encoded in the cries,&rdquo; said Mathevon. &ldquo;No one had ever measured our response to cries like this before and it is too early to know if there will be practical applications one day.&rdquo;</p><p>The study follows <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39819066/">work last month</a> from researchers in Denmark that challenges the claim that women are hardwired to wake up more easily than men when a baby starts crying. It found that men were as likely as women to be woken by wailing infants, despite mothers being three times more likely to get up and tend to the child.</p><p>The reasons for the disparity are up for debate, but Prof Christine Parsons, who led the team, suggested two potential factors. First, mothers often took maternity leave before fathers took paternity leave and learned how to calm their baby earlier. Second, when mothers were breastfeeding, it might be sensible for fathers to sleep through.</p><p>&ldquo;Much of the previous work on adults&rsquo; physiological responses to infant crying has looked at heart rate, skin conductance, or even brain responses. So this study is innovating,&rdquo; Parsons said. &ldquo;People often assume there will be a clear distinction between men and women in how they respond to crying. The authors set out to test this, and found no evidence for a difference,&rdquo; she added. &ldquo;We were also surprised at how little difference there was between men and women.&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 16:02:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/artificially-sweetened-beverages-gestational-diabetes-risk/</link><title>Pregnant women who drink 5 or more diet beverages a week face up to an 88% higher risk of gestational diabetes, finds a major new study linking artificial sweeteners to pregnancy complications. The researchers noted a dose-response relationship: the more diet drinks consumed, the greater the risk. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nd9a6n/pregnant_women_who_drink_5_or_more_diet_beverages/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nd9a6n/pregnant_women_who_drink_5_or_more_diet_beverages/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nd9a6n/pregnant_women_who_drink_5_or_more_diet_beverages/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/5b8107e/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2356x1237+0+44/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F8b%2F39%2F5f1579e248dba301f577b1ebb37f%2Fdepositphotos-101720688-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Pregnant women who drink five or more diet beverages a week face up to an 88% higher risk of gestational diabetes, according to a major new study linking artificial sweeteners to pregnancy complications.</p><p><a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/light-exposure-gestational-diabetes/">Gestational diabetes mellitus</a> (GDM) is a kind of diabetes that develops during pregnancy, leading to higher-than-normal blood sugar levels that can produce complications for both mom and baby. It <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34883186/">affects 14%</a> of women globally and typically goes away after pregnancy, but it can increase a woman&rsquo;s risk of developing type 2 diabetes later in life.</p><p>In a new study by the University of Adelaide, researchers investigated whether drinking artificially sweetened beverages, or ASBs, like Diet Coke, diet lemonade or sugar-free cordials, before and during pregnancy increased the risk of developing GDM and other pregnancy-related complications.</p><p>&ldquo;The effects of LCS (low-calorie sweetener) intake during pregnancy on health has had mixed results in other studies, so we aimed to look at the association between preconception and pregnancy artificially sweetened beverage intake and adverse pregnancy outcomes such as gestational diabetes, hypertensive disorder of pregnancy, and preterm birth,&rdquo; said <a href="https://researchers.adelaide.edu.au/profile/bereketgebremichael.menota">Bereket Gebremichael Menota</a>, lead author of the study and PhD candidate with the University&rsquo;s School of Agriculture, Food and Wine.</p><p>The researchers used data from the Australian Longitudinal Study on Women&rsquo;s Health (ALSWH), the largest, longest-running population-based study exploring demographic, environmental, behavioral, physical, and biological factors contributing to the health and well-being of over 57,000 Australian women in four age cohorts. A sample of 3,653 women was analyzed to look for an association between GDM and ASBs. Intake of ASBs in the first six months of pregnancy was considered as pregnancy exposure; preconception exposure was limited to one to two years pre-pregnancy.</p><p>Women reported how often they drank ASBs before and during pregnancy and the researchers used advanced statistical models to adjust for confounders such as age, body mass index (BMI), smoking, diet, and family history of conditions like diabetes and high blood pressure or hypertension. Intake of ASBs was categorized into four categories: no or rare (less than once a month), mild, moderate, and frequent (five or more drinks a week).</p><p>Frequent ASB consumption during pregnancy was linked to an 88% higher risk of GDM compared to no/rare consumption. The researchers noted a dose-response relationship: the more diet drinks consumed, the greater the risk of gestational diabetes. This effect seemed to be partly explained by higher BMI among women who drank more ASBs. Women who frequently drank ASBs possibly had an increased risk of hypertensive disorders of pregnancy, but the results weren&rsquo;t statistically conclusive. There was no clear link found between ASB consumption and preterm birth.</p><div><figure><div><figcaption>The more diet drinks consumed, the greater the risk of gestational diabetes</figcaption></div></figure> </div><p>&ldquo;Women in the frequent intake group (five or more drinks per week) had a higher pre-pregnancy BMI, were more likely to be current smokers and risky drinkers, reported poorer/fairer health, and were less likely to meet the recommended daily servings of fruit compared to women in the other ASB intake group,&rdquo; Menota said. &ldquo;Preconception dietary risk factors, along with other risks, can establish patterns that affect the well-being of the mother and their baby&rsquo;s long-term health.</p><p>&ldquo;As a result, we can see women adopting lifestyle changes, including diet modification and weight loss, during this period, which can include replacing sugar with low-calorie sweeteners, which can be found in these drinks, as a strategy for weight loss.&rdquo;</p><p>There are limitations to the study. Women self-reported their drink consumption, which may be inaccurate. Only diet sodas and diet cordials were considered, but <a href="https://newatlas.com/diet-nutrition/artificial-sweeteners-cognitive/">artificial sweeteners</a> are found in many foods, so the findings may underestimate the risk associated with exposure to ASBs. Drink habits may have changed during pregnancy but weren&rsquo;t tracked. Different artificial sweeteners (aspartame, sucralose, etc.) may have different effects, but this wasn&rsquo;t assessed. Importantly, because the study was observational, it can&rsquo;t say ASBs directly caused complications.</p><p>Despite its limitations, the study has important real-world applications, especially the finding that frequent diet drink consumption during pregnancy may increase the risk of GDM, especially in women who already struggle with their weight. The findings could influence dietary recommendations for women planning pregnancy or who are already pregnant. Further studies &ndash; randomized controlled trials, ideally &ndash; are needed to clarify whether specific artificial sweeteners, or diet drinks in general, are driving these risks.</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S016882272500436X?via%3Dihub"><i>Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.adelaide.edu.au/newsroom/news/list/2025/09/03/artificially-sweetened-beverage-consumption-lifts-gestational-diabetes-risk">University of Adelaide</a></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/917d847/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1333+0+0/resize/1440x960!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F53%2F16%2F85c74e004ba2a16516ef273dbe24%2Fdepositphotos-81883376-l.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 14:43:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://english.cas.cn/newsroom/research_news/life/202506/t20250620_1045926.shtml</link><title>Scientists Use Engineered Cells to Reverse Aging in Primates (english.cas.cn)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nd27ng/scientists_use_engineered_cells_to_reverse_aging/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nd27ng/scientists_use_engineered_cells_to_reverse_aging/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nd27ng/scientists_use_engineered_cells_to_reverse_aging/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='http://english.cas.cn/images/share_logo.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>As we age, our bodies gradually lose their ability to repair and regenerate. Stem cells diminish, making it increasingly difficult for tissues to heal and maintain balance. This reduction in stem cells is a hallmark of aging and a key driver of age-related diseases. Scientists have long debated whether this decline is the root cause of aging or a side effect. Efforts to use stem cell transplants to reverse aging have faced many challenges, such as ensuring the cells survive and integrate into the body without causing serious side effects, like tumors.</p><p>In a recent study published in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2025.05.021"><em>Cell</em></a>, researchers from the Chinese Academy of Sciences and Capital Medical University introduced a new type of human stem cell called senescence-resistant mesenchymal progenitor cells (SRCs)&nbsp;by reprogramming&nbsp;the genetic pathways associated with longevity. These cells, which resist aging and stress without developing tumors, were tested on elderly crab-eating macaques, which share physiological similarities with humans in their 60s and 70s.</p><p>The research team conducted a 44-week experiment on&nbsp;these&nbsp;macaques. The macaques received biweekly intravenous injections of SRCs, with a dosage of 2&times;10<sup>6</sup>cells per kilogram of body weight. The researchers found&nbsp;no adverse effects among the macaques. Detailed assessments confirmed that the transplanted cells did not cause tissue damage or tumors.</p><p>The researchers discovered that SRCs&nbsp;triggered a multi-system rejuvenation, reversing key markers of aging across 10 major physiological systems and 61 different tissue types. The treated macaques exhibited improved cognitive function, and tissue analyses indicated a reduction in age-related degenerative conditions such as brain atrophy, osteoporosis, fibrosis, and lipid buildup.</p><p>At the cellular level, SRCs decreased the number of senescent cells, reduced inflammation, and increased progenitor cell populations in neural and reproductive tissues. They even stimulated sperm production. At the molecular level, SRCs enhanced genomic stability, improved responses to oxidative stress, and restored protein balance. More than 50% of the examined tissues showed a reversal of aging-related gene expression profiles to a younger state. Single-cell analyses revealed significant reversals in gene expression among peripheral blood cells (33%), the hippocampus (42%), and ovarian tissue (45%). Machine learning-based aging clocks estimated that the biological age of immature neurons was reversed by six-seven&nbsp;years, and that of oocytes by five&nbsp;years.</p><p>Furthermore, the researchers found that tiny particles called exosomes, released by the SRCs, were the key agents of rejuvenation. These exosomes suppressed chronic inflammation while preserving genomic and epigenomic integrity. When isolated SRC exosomes were administered to aged mice, they significantly reduced organ degeneration. In vitro studies demonstrated that these exosomes could rejuvenate various human cell types, including neurons, ovarian, and liver cells. This discovery suggests that exosome signaling could be a fundamental pathway for reversing aging.</p><p>These findings highlight SRC therapy as a promising intervention for multi-system aging. It&nbsp;demonstrates protective efficacy across interconnected systems like the nervous, reproductive, and immune systems, presenting a holistic approach that surpasses single-target therapies.</p><p><span>SRC Reverses Lipid Buildup in Aged Monkeys' Skeletal Muscle: Control Group (Left); SRC-Treated Group (Right). (Image by LIU Guanghui's lab)</span></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 07:47:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://news.osu.edu/keto-diet-linked-to-reduced-depression-symptoms-in-college-students/?&amp;&amp;</link><title>A new study shows an association between 10-12 weeks of following a well-formulated ketogenic diet and a roughly 70% decrease in depression symptoms among a small group of college students. Participantsâ€™ global well-being increased nearly 3-fold and performance improved on several cognitive tasks. (news.osu.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nczzd8/a_new_study_shows_an_association_between_1012/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nczzd8/a_new_study_shows_an_association_between_1012/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nczzd8/a_new_study_shows_an_association_between_1012/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://content.presspage.com/uploads/2170/403e391a-c22b-4ae5-beba-3102dc7fdd1f/1920_gettycopyketomeal.jpeg?10000' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><h2 title="Study suggests well-formulated ketogenic diet is feasible add-on mental health therapy">Study suggests well-formulated ketogenic diet is feasible add-on mental health therapy</h2><div><p>A new study shows an association between at least 10 weeks of following a well-formulated <a href="https://www.webmd.com/diet/ss/slideshow-ketogenic-diet">ketogenic diet</a> and a roughly 70% decrease in depression symptoms among a small group of college students.&nbsp;</p><p>Beyond the reduction in self-reported and clinician rated depression, the students&rsquo; global well-being increased nearly three-fold and their performance improved on several cognitive tasks. All but one participant also lost weight.&nbsp;</p><p>The 16 students who completed the pilot trial were receiving medication, counseling, or both for major depressive disorder before beginning the keto diet. The findings suggest achieving <a href="https://www.webmd.com/diabetes/what-is-ketosis">nutritional ketosis</a> through diet is a feasible adjunctive therapy for depression and pave the way for a larger clinical trial, researchers say.&nbsp;</p><p>The pilot study did not have a non-keto control group for comparison. Previous research has suggested medications and counseling reduce depressive symptoms by about 50% in a similar time period.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;So many people are suffering right now, so it&rsquo;s rewarding to potentially bring forward a solution,&rdquo; said <a href="https://ehe.osu.edu/human-sciences/directory?id=volek.1">Jeff Volek</a>, PhD, lead author of the study and a professor of <a href="https://ehe.osu.edu/human-sciences">human sciences at The Ohio State University</a>. &ldquo;There is more science yet to do, but because there is evidence of a benefit, expanding accessibility to a well-formulated ketogenic diet as an augmentation to treatment for depression is something to think about.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>The study is published today (Sept. 9, 2025) in the journal <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41398-025-03544-8"><i>Translational Psychiatry</i></a>.&nbsp;</p><p>Volek&rsquo;s lab teamed with Ohio State mental health experts to design and complete the trial with young adults studying at the university.&nbsp;</p><p>Stress, anxiety and depression are the No. 1 impediment to academic performance for U.S. college students, said co-author <a href="https://ccs.osu.edu/people/ryan-patel">Ryan Patel</a>, DO, a psychiatrist in Ohio State&rsquo;s Office of Student Life <a href="https://ccs.osu.edu/">Counseling and Consultation Service</a>: About 40% of college students report depression symptoms, and about half of them are receiving treatment of some kind.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;We have a treatment gap in that we have more students suffering from mental health concerns than can feasibly receive professional treatment,&rdquo; Patel said. &ldquo;There is a need for finding ways of helping students on a large scale. And nutrition is one way we can do that.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>Twenty-four students were enrolled in the trial and 16 students &ndash; 10 women and six men with an average age of 24 &ndash; completed the entire study.&nbsp;</p><p>Participants received extensive education on the keto diet, consisting of fewer than 50 grams of carbs per day combined with higher fat and moderate protein intake. The keto diet converts fat into ketones used by cells in the body and brain as an alternative to glucose, and is designed to&nbsp;put the body in a state of nutritional ketosis, when it has greater access to ketones as both fuel and a signaling molecule. &nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;It was very important to make sure participants knew what they were getting themselves into,&rdquo; said <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Drew-Decker">Drew Decker</a>, MS, first author of the study and a graduate student in <a href="https://lowcarb.osu.edu/">Volek&rsquo;s lab</a>. &ldquo;And a big part of increasing chances for adherence to the diet was talking to each individual about what they like and don&rsquo;t like to eat so we could tailor some suggestions for how they could structure their diet.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>The team also provided 10 complete starter meals, offered consistent advice and snacks for the first half of the trial, and communicated throughout the study with participants through a private app. The students were advised to eat when they were hungry and finish eating when they were full, and not to worry about calories.&nbsp;</p><p>At baseline and over the course of 10 to 12 weeks, the students reported depressive symptoms using the <a href="https://www.apa.org/depression-guideline/patient-health-questionnaire.pdf">Patient Health Questionnaire-9</a> (PHQ-09), the standard instrument to measure the severity of depression in clinical settings, and completed the <a href="https://www.who.int/publications/m/item/WHO-UCN-MSD-MHE-2024.01">World Health Organization-Five Well-Being Index</a> (WHO-5). They also took a series of cognitive tests assessing episodic and working memory, processing speed, executive function, and attention and inhibitory control.&nbsp;</p><p>Co-author <a href="https://psychology.osu.edu/people/cheavens.1">Jennifer Cheavens</a>, PhD, professor of clinical <a href="https://psychology.osu.edu/">psychology</a> at Ohio State, oversaw clinical assessments of participants before and throughout the trial.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;One of the things we really wanted to make sure of is that we were providing a treatment for people who met the diagnostic criteria for having major depressive disorder,&rdquo; Cheavens said. &ldquo;Each participant had about a 2 1/2-hour interview at the beginning, and then weekly assessments of their symptoms.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>Students were also screened to ensure that they did not have any contraindications to a ketogenic diet, such as Body Mass Index under 20, eating disorders, pregnancy or high alcohol consumption.&nbsp;</p><p>Results included:</p><ul><li>Participants achieved ketosis, based on a measure of ketone values in their blood, 73% of the time &ndash; an indication of good adherence to the diet.</li><li>Self-reported depression scores decreased 37% by week two and reached 69% of improvement at week 10-12. The range of symptom severity varied, but nobody&rsquo;s symptoms worsened.</li><li>Clinician-rated assessments of depression at week six and week 10-12 decreased by 59% and 71%, respectively.</li><li>By week two, perceived ratings of global wellness had increased two-fold, which improved to nearly three-fold at the end of the intervention.</li><li>As a group, participants lost an average of 11 pounds and their body fat decreased by 2.4% &ndash; with most exceeding the clinically significant drop of 5% weight loss.</li><li>As a group, participants&rsquo; performance improved on cognitive tasks assessing episodic memory, processing speed and executive function.</li><li>No significant changes in cholesterol or triglycerides were found.</li></ul><p>Patel, who met with the students throughout the trial, said the magnitude of the reduction in depressive symptoms linked to the keto diet was notable.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;The average effect size for medications and counseling after 12 weeks is about 50%, and we saw a substantially greater result,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;That is an impressive finding, that across the board, in this real-world setting, everybody got better, and across the board, our participants did not need more treatment or emergency intervention.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>For over two decades, Volek has been studying therapeutic applications of ketosis for conditions such as heart disease and cancer as well as athletic performance and soldier health and resilience.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;The idea is that the ketogenic diet is working through a variety of potentially different mechanisms &ndash; there&rsquo;s a whole range of physiological metabolic adaptations to the diet that could overlap with some of the pathophysiology of depression,&rdquo; Volek said.&nbsp;</p><p>The team collected a range of biological data on changing levels of proteins related to inflammation and brain function in this pilot that may help inform a future study examining potential mechanisms behind the diet&rsquo;s effects.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;We haven&rsquo;t teased out those mechanisms here because this is a proof-of-concept study for an adjunctive therapy,&rdquo; Volek said. &ldquo;This is one of the first really well-controlled studies and it has limitations, but the results encourage us to want to keep pursuing it.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>This project was supported by a grant from the <a href="https://baszuckigroup.com/">Baszucki Group</a> Brain Research Fund.&nbsp;</p><p>Additional co-authors included Scott Hayes, Whitney Whitted, Ann Lee, Alex Buga, Bradley Robinson, Christopher Crabtree, Justen Stoner, Madison Kackley, Teryn Sapper and Ashwini Chebbi, all of Ohio State.&nbsp;</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://content.presspage.com/uploads/2170/500_volek.1-639397.jpg?x=1757358856914"></p><p><img src="https://content.presspage.com/uploads/2170/628e2d35-f71b-4bba-853a-dcea2f54d4b1/500_ryanpatel.jpg?x=1757359081847"></p><p><img src="https://content.presspage.com/uploads/2170/5fe142b6-6cab-4e12-818b-3a11b260bd01/500_drewdecker.jpg?x=1757359100231"></p><p><img src="https://content.presspage.com/uploads/2170/500_jennifercheavens.png?x=1757359126280"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 06:01:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/many-autistic-adults-feel-torn-about-revealing-their-diagnosis-a-new-study-explores-why/</link><title>Many autistic adults feel torn about revealing their diagnosis. Disclosure can serve meaningful purposes, such as accessing support, fostering self-acceptance, and engaging in activism, but also exposes people to disbelief, stereotyping, and emotional vulnerability. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncv57o/many_autistic_adults_feel_torn_about_revealing/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncv57o/many_autistic_adults_feel_torn_about_revealing/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncv57o/many_autistic_adults_feel_torn_about_revealing/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/sad-depressed-man.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in the journal <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/13623613251337504">Autism</a></em> sheds light on how autistic adults navigate the complex and deeply personal decision to share their autism diagnosis with others. Researchers found that disclosure can serve meaningful purposes, such as accessing support, fostering self-acceptance, and engaging in activism, but also exposes people to disbelief, stereotyping, and emotional vulnerability. The findings suggest that many newly diagnosed adults in the United Kingdom lack adequate guidance on how to manage disclosure and would benefit from more structured post-diagnostic support.</p><p>Autism spectrum conditions affect how people experience the world, often influencing communication, social interaction, and behavior. While autism is frequently diagnosed in childhood, a growing number of people&mdash;especially women and those with less apparent support needs&mdash;are receiving diagnoses in adulthood. This shift reflects increasing awareness and improved diagnostic practices, but it also leaves many adults to navigate their diagnosis without the kind of developmental support available to younger individuals.</p><p>Receiving an autism diagnosis later in life can prompt a major re-evaluation of one&rsquo;s identity and past experiences. But it also raises an important practical and emotional question: should one share this diagnosis with others, and if so, how? Disclosure can be necessary to access workplace accommodations, social services, or healthcare support. Yet many people fear being misunderstood or judged.</p><p>While previous studies have examined autism disclosure in specific contexts like employment, few have explored the broader, everyday experiences of adults who receive a diagnosis later in life. This study sought to fill that gap, focusing on adults in the United Kingdom who were diagnosed within the past ten years.</p><p>To investigate these questions, researchers from the University of Sheffield and Cardiff University used a qualitative method known as interpretative phenomenological analysis. This approach emphasizes understanding how individuals make sense of significant life events&mdash;in this case, the experience of disclosing an autism diagnosis.</p><p>The researchers conducted in-depth interviews with twelve autistic adults who had received their diagnosis in adulthood. Participants ranged in age, gender identity, and life experience. The team analyzed the interview transcripts to identify recurring themes and patterns in how participants thought about and approached diagnostic disclosure.</p><p>The study found that disclosure is rarely a simple or one-time decision. Rather, it is an ongoing process shaped by a person&rsquo;s environment, relationships, and emotional readiness. From the interviews, the researchers identified four major themes: the functions of disclosure, how individuals approached the conversation, the effects of negative preconceptions, and the role of acceptance and community.</p><p>One key theme to emerge was that disclosure often served multiple functions. For some participants, sharing their diagnosis was a practical decision&mdash;it was the only way to access support at work, in healthcare, or in social services. Others saw disclosure as a step toward being more authentic in their relationships or workplace, allowing them to &ldquo;be themselves&rdquo; without masking their traits. For a few, disclosure also became a form of advocacy, as they sought to raise awareness or improve conditions for other autistic people.</p><p>At the same time, disclosing a diagnosis often felt fraught. Some participants described carefully managing who they told, how they explained it, and how they responded to other people&rsquo;s reactions. Others said they began disclosing even before receiving a formal diagnosis, often discussing the possibility with close friends or family. In some cases, this made the eventual diagnosis easier to accept&mdash;for both the person diagnosed and those around them.</p><p>However, many also reported negative responses. Several participants described encountering disbelief, especially when they did not match other people&rsquo;s stereotyped views of autism. Comments like &ldquo;you don&rsquo;t seem autistic&rdquo; were common, leaving participants feeling invalidated or doubting themselves. This led some to experience what they described as &ldquo;imposter syndrome,&rdquo; questioning whether they really &ldquo;deserved&rdquo; the diagnosis.</p><p>These reactions were often shaped by widespread misconceptions about autism&mdash;such as the idea that autistic people must be male, socially isolated, or visibly struggling. Participants said these assumptions made it harder for them to be understood, even when they were seeking support.</p><p>The study found that people&rsquo;s decisions to disclose&mdash;or not to&mdash;were often based on weighing potential risks and benefits. If participants believed disclosure would lead to meaningful support or understanding, they were more likely to share. If they anticipated judgment, discrimination, or indifference, they often withheld the information or disclosed only partially.</p><p>Many adopted what the researchers called &ldquo;partial disclosure&rdquo; strategies. For example, someone might tell an employer that they had specific sensory sensitivities or social challenges without naming autism directly. This allowed them to seek accommodations without risking stigma.</p><p>Others described limiting their disclosures to people they trusted or to environments where neurodiversity was understood and respected. Workplaces or communities that emphasized inclusivity were often seen as safer spaces for disclosure. On the other hand, experiences of dismissal or discrimination in education, healthcare, or employment led some participants to withdraw or avoid further interactions.</p><p>The emotional toll of disclosure was another recurring theme. Some participants spoke of feeling exhausted by having to educate others repeatedly. Others described the tension between wanting to be honest and not wanting to disrupt relationships or be perceived differently. In some cases, loved ones reacted with guilt or denial, especially if the diagnosis prompted them to reflect on their own traits or parenting.</p><p>Despite these challenges, many participants also described disclosure as a source of connection and support. When others responded with openness, curiosity, or a willingness to learn, it often led to stronger relationships. Some participants said that sharing their diagnosis had helped them find supportive communities, both online and in-person, where they felt seen and accepted.</p><p>Disclosure could also spark broader conversations about neurodiversity, both in families and workplaces. Several participants described how their openness had encouraged others to seek their own diagnoses or rethink assumptions about autism. For some, this brought a sense of purpose and belonging.</p><p>These positive experiences were most likely when others were already familiar with autism, had lived experience themselves, or were part of communities that valued inclusion. Participants emphasized that these interactions helped counteract feelings of isolation and reinforced a sense of identity.</p><p>The study&rsquo;s authors argue that there is a significant need for structured post-diagnostic support for adults. At present, many people are left to navigate disclosure alone, without guidance on how to communicate their diagnosis or respond to others&rsquo; reactions.</p><p>The findings suggest that clinicians should incorporate conversations about disclosure into routine post-diagnostic care. This could include discussing who to tell, how to disclose, and how to handle potential challenges. Peer support groups, one-on-one counseling, and access to community resources were all highlighted as helpful by participants.</p><p>But the researchers caution against placing the burden of education solely on autistic individuals. While some participants found activism empowering, others felt overwhelmed by the expectation that they must constantly explain themselves. Services and employers need to improve their own understanding of autism rather than relying on individuals to do that work for them.</p><p>The study&rsquo;s limitations include several factors related both to its design and to the inherent constraints of qualitative research. With a small sample of twelve participants, the findings may not be generalizable to the broader population of autistic adults. Additionally, while interpretative phenomenological analysis allows for deep exploration of lived experiences, it is shaped by the researcher&rsquo;s interpretations and cannot provide objective or quantifiable conclusions.</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/13623613251337504">&lsquo;Am I gonna regret this?&rsquo;: The experiences of diagnostic disclosure in autistic adults</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Sheena K Au-Yeung, Megan Freeth, and Andrew R Thompson.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://sp-ao.shortpixel.ai/client/to_webp,q_glossy,ret_img,w_250,h_85/https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/follow-on-google-news-1.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 02:36:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://news.northeastern.edu/2025/09/09/toxic-forever-chemicals-more-widespread-research-reveals/</link><title>Sites contaminated by toxic â€˜forever chemicalsâ€™ are much more widespread than previously thought, researchers find (news.northeastern.edu)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncv0j0/sites_contaminated_by_toxic_forever_chemicals_are/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncv0j0/sites_contaminated_by_toxic_forever_chemicals_are/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncv0j0/sites_contaminated_by_toxic_forever_chemicals_are/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/090825_AS_water_004.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Toxic per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, also known as PFAS or &ldquo;forever chemicals,&rdquo; are in everything from <a href="https://news.northeastern.edu/2024/04/09/band-aid-pfas-forever-chemicals/">Band-Aids</a> and clothing to water and floss. However, new research reveals they are potentially even more widespread in the U.S. than previously thought.</p><p>The <a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.est.4c14474">research</a> done by Northeastern University&rsquo;s <a href="http://pfasproject.com/">PFAS Project Lab</a> reveals that while there are about 2,200 known sites of PFAS contamination in the U.S., there are close to another 80,000 likely contaminated sites. It presents what the researchers say is a much more complete &mdash; and stark &mdash; picture of PFAS contamination while also presenting legislators, communities and environmental activists with a roadmap of where to focus their efforts.</p><p>The PFAS Project Lab has been mapping sites contaminated by &ldquo;forever chemicals,&rdquo; an entire class of toxic substances, for around a decade. It started as a way to address what remains the biggest issue around PFAS remediation.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;We don&rsquo;t know where PFAS is or where it&rsquo;s coming from,&rdquo; says <a href="https://cssh.northeastern.edu/faculty/kimberly-garrett/">Kimberly Garrett</a>, a postdoctoral research fellow with the PFAS Project Lab and lead on this research.</p><p>As the lab started to map known PFAS contamination sites, they realized that the data was limited. Since PFAS testing is far from widespread &mdash; it&rsquo;s largely up to states or environmental organizations to conduct testing &mdash; they were entirely reliant on an incomplete picture of contamination.</p><p>Their map of known contamination sites makes it appear like California, New England and Michigan are the only areas with heavy PFAS levels, but those are the areas where testing was done.</p><p>To fill in the blanks, they developed a model that helped them map presumptive contamination sites. It relies on information about certain kinds of industrial sites that are known for emitting PFAS. The end result is a more complete sense of just how widespread PFAS contamination in the U.S. likely is.</p><figure><img width="1400" height="933" src="https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg" alt="Several maps depicting the known and presumptive PFAS contamination sites across the United States." srcset="https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg 1400w, https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg?resize=800,533 800w, https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg?resize=768,512 768w, https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg?resize=1100,733 1100w, https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg?resize=196,130 196w, https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg?resize=335,223 335w, https://news.northeastern.edu/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/images_large_es4c14474_0007-copy.jpg?resize=1200,800 1200w"><figcaption>Maps of known PFAS contamination sites and presumptive PFAS contamination sites from the PFAS Project Lab. Courtesy</figcaption></figure><p>According to Garrett, they found that 94% of known PFAS contamination sites had average PFAS groundwater concentrations that were above accepted regulatory levels.</p><p>The lab&rsquo;s recently published paper represents the most up-to-date and complete picture of nationwide PFAS contamination. The most recent updates have given the lab further insight into what kinds of sources, sites and industries are most associated with emitting PFAS.&nbsp;</p><p>&ldquo;We did find that, overall, all of the sites that we knew about had elevated PFAS concentrations that were above health-based guidelines. We found that some were associated with really high values, but they were all associated with unacceptable values.&rdquo;</p><p>Contamination sites were divided into several categories: airports, industrial facilities, military facilities, municipal fire activities and waste treatment plants. What the researchers found was that three of these categories &mdash; airports, military facilities and municipal fire activities &mdash; &ldquo;consistently had significantly higher PFAS detections than the other site types,&rdquo; Garrett says.</p><p>What they all had in common was a substance called aqueous film-forming foam (AFFF), which is used most consistently in fighting fires. AFFF was consistently connected to the highest average PFAS concentrations, something that&rsquo;s been known among those studying PFAS for years.</p><p>What was more surprising was that Garrett and the other researchers on the project were able to partially identify specific industries that are most commonly associated with PFAS contamination: metal and electronics manufacturing.</p><p>&ldquo;Metal manufacturers and electronic manufacturers could use a little more scrutiny in that area, especially as we think about making investments in semiconductor manufacturing and things like that,&rdquo; Garrett says.</p><p>Finding the industrial sources of PFAS contamination is vital, Garrett explains. There have been some <a href="https://news.northeastern.edu/2023/03/14/epa-pfas-regulation/">federal efforts</a> made to curb PFAS pollution, but attention has largely been paid to water treatment plants, not the industrial sources where &ldquo;forever chemicals&rdquo; are flowing from.</p><p>&ldquo;Turning off the tap of PFAS starts at the source,&rdquo; Garrett says. &ldquo;We can&rsquo;t discount the industrial contributions to PFAS contamination.&rdquo;</p><p>By mapping out not only contamination sites but the broader &ldquo;waste stream&rdquo; that these chemicals flow through, <a href="https://cssh.northeastern.edu/faculty/phil-brown/">Phil Brown</a>, co-director of the PFAS Project Lab, hopes this data can help inform legislators and communities about where to target testing and remediation efforts.</p><p>&ldquo;Once you identify the waste stream, you can also say, &lsquo;Near this wastewater treatment plant are potential manufacturers and users,&rsquo;&rdquo; Brown says. &ldquo;We can then tell them that they have to cut down their emissions before it gets into our [treatment] plants.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;We know that resources for testing bodies and regulatory bodies and municipal utilities are very limited, so we hope that our tools can serve as a guide for if a municipality or a state has so much money for testing and they say, what would be the most impactful way to use this?&rdquo; Garrett adds. &ldquo;We think that this paper can contribute to those kinds of decisions.&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 02:30:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamaneurology/article-abstract/2838665</link><title>Post-mortem tissue from people with Alzheimer's Disease revealed that those who lived in areas with higher concentrations of fine particulate matter in the air even just one year had more severe accumulation of amyloid plaques -hallmarks of Alzheimer's pathology compared to those with less exposure (jamanetwork.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncojzt/postmortem_tissue_from_people_with_alzheimers/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncojzt/postmortem_tissue_from_people_with_alzheimers/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncojzt/postmortem_tissue_from_people_with_alzheimers/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 22:33:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newsweek.com/human-evolution-autism-high-rates-2126289</link><title>Human Evolution May Explain High Autism Rates: genetic changes that made our brain unique also made us more neurodiverse. Special neurons underwent fast evolution in humans - this rapid shift coincided with alterations in genes linked to autism, likely shaped by natural selection unique to humans. (newsweek.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncejaw/human_evolution_may_explain_high_autism_rates/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncejaw/human_evolution_may_explain_high_autism_rates/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1ncejaw/human_evolution_may_explain_high_autism_rates/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2717940/3d-medical-background.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><article><div><div><p>By <span> <span><p>Lucy Notarantonio is Newsweek's Senior Lifestyle and Trends Reporter, based in Birmingham, UK. Her focus is trending stories and human interest features ranging from health, pets and travel. Lucy joined Newsweek in August 2022 and previously worked at Mercury Press and Media and other&nbsp;UK national newspapers, the Australian Women Magazines and The New York Post. My focus is human-interest stories ranging from relationships to health, fitness, travel, and home. I am always on the lookout for relationships that go against the "norm" such as age-gap ones along with incredible weight loss stories aimed to inspire and motivate others. Languages: English She is a Derby University graduate You can get in touch with l.notarantonio@newsweek.com.</p></span> <a href="https://www.newsweek.com%20javascript:void(0);%20"> Lucy Notarantonio </a> </span></p><p>Senior Life and Trends Reporter</p></div><div><p>&#127897;&#65039; Voice is AI-generated. Inconsistencies may occur.</p></div><div><p>Scientists have uncovered new evidence suggesting that autism may have it roots in how the human brain has evolved.</p><p>"Our results suggest that some of the same genetic changes that make the human brain unique also made humans more neurodiverse," said the study's lead author, Alexander L. Starr in a statement.</p><p>In the United States, around one in 31 children&mdash;about 3.2 percent&mdash;has been diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (<a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/cdc">CDC</a>).</p><p>Autism spectrum disorder is a complex developmental condition affecting roughly one in 100 children worldwide, according to The World Health Organization.</p><p>It involves persistent challenges with social communication, restricted interests and repetitive behavior.</p><p>Unlike other neurological conditions seen in animals, autism and schizophrenia appear to be largely unique to humans, likely because they involve traits such as speech production and comprehension that are either exclusive to or far more advanced in people than in other primates.</p><figure><figcaption> <span>A stock image of 3D medical background with male head with brain and DNA strands. </span> <span>kirstypargeter/iStock / Getty Images Plus</span> </figcaption> </figure><h2>The Human Brain and Genetic Change</h2><p>Recent advances in single-cell RNA sequencing have allowed scientists to identify an extraordinary diversity of brain cell types.</p><p>Alongside this, large-scale genetic studies have revealed sweeping changes in the human brain that are not seen in other mammals.</p><p>These genomic elements evolved rapidly in <em>Homo sapiens</em> despite remaining relatively stable throughout the rest of mammalian history.</p><p>By analyzing brain samples across different species, researchers found that the most common type of outer-layer neurons&mdash;known as L2/3 IT neurons&mdash;underwent especially fast evolution in humans compared to other apes.</p><p>Strikingly, this rapid shift coincided with major alterations in genes linked to autism&mdash;likely shaped by natural selection factors unique to the human species.</p><h2>Why Did These Changes Occur?</h2><p>Although the findings strongly point to evolutionary pressure acting on autism-associated genes, the evolutionary benefit to human ancestors remains uncertain.</p><p>The team behind the research noted that many of these genes are tied to developmental delay, which may have played a role in the slower pace of postnatal brain growth in humans compared to chimpanzees.</p><p>The unique human ability for speech and language&mdash;often impacted by autism and schizophrenia&mdash;may also be connected.</p><p>One possibility is that the evolution of autism-related genes slowed early <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/scientist-reveals-activity-boost-child-brain-development-1830996">brain development</a> or expanded language capacity, extending the time window for learning and complex thought in childhood.</p><p>This extended development may have offered an evolutionary advantage by fostering more advanced reasoning skills.</p><p><strong>Do you have a tip on a science story that <em>Newsweek</em> should be covering? Do you have a question about autism? Let us know via <a href="https://www.newsweek.commailto:science@newsweek.com">science@newsweek.com</a>.</strong></p><h3><strong>Reference</strong></h3><p>Starr, A. L., &amp; Fraser, H. B. (2025). A general principle of neuronal evolution reveals a human-accelerated neuron type potentially underlying the high prevalence of autism in humans. <em>Molecular Biology and Evolution</em>. <a>https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msaf177</a></p></div></div><div><div><div><h2>Is This Article Trustworthy?</h2><div><p>Newsweek is committed to journalism that is factual and fair</p><p>We value your input and encourage you to rate this article.</p></div></div><div><p>Newsweek is committed to journalism that is factual and fair</p><p>We value your input and encourage you to rate this article.</p></div></div><div><h3>Slide Circle to Vote</h3><p><span>No</span> <span>Moderately</span> <span>Yes</span></p><p><a> VOTE</a></p></div></div></article></div><div><h2> Top stories</h2></div><section><h3>About the writer</h3> <span> <span><p>Lucy Notarantonio is Newsweek's Senior Lifestyle and Trends Reporter, based in Birmingham, UK. Her focus is trending stories and human interest features ranging from health, pets and travel. Lucy joined Newsweek in August 2022 and previously worked at Mercury Press and Media and other&nbsp;UK national newspapers, the Australian Women Magazines and The New York Post. My focus is human-interest stories ranging from relationships to health, fitness, travel, and home. I am always on the lookout for relationships that go against the "norm" such as age-gap ones along with incredible weight loss stories aimed to inspire and motivate others. Languages: English She is a Derby University graduate You can get in touch with l.notarantonio@newsweek.com.</p></span> <a href="https://www.newsweek.com%20javascript:void(0);%20"> Lucy Notarantonio </a> </span><p><span><p>Lucy Notarantonio is Newsweek's Senior Lifestyle and Trends Reporter, based in Birmingham, UK. Her focus is trending stories and human ... <a>Read more</a> </p></span></p></section> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2717940/3d-medical-background.jpg?w=1200&amp;f=6814fc63d8c95b148c09b11d30106626"></p><p><img src="https://g.newsweek.com/www/images/NW_ICON_86x86-CommonGround_2.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 15:16:51 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/adhd-autism/adhd-brains-mri-scans/</link><title>ADHD brains really are built differently â€“ we've just been blinded by the noise | Scientists eliminate the gray area when it comes to gray matter in ADHD brains (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2oxu/adhd_brains_really_are_built_differently_weve/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2oxu/adhd_brains_really_are_built_differently_weve/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2oxu/adhd_brains_really_are_built_differently_weve/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/ae65cf9/2147483647/strip/true/crop/8168x4288+0+578/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F98%2F27%2Fbba57b0044c7ab2a9f2f392a9a2f%2Fdepositphotos-479798050-xl.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study significantly strengthens the case that attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) brains are structurally unique, thanks to a new scanning technique known as the traveling-subject method. It isn't down to new technology &ndash; but better use of it.</p><p>A team of Japanese scientists led by Chiba University has corrected the inconsistencies in brain scans of <a href="https://newatlas.com/tag/adhd/">ADHD</a> individuals, where mixed results from <a href="https://newatlas.com/tag/mri/">magnetic resonance imaging</a> (MRI) studies left researchers unable to say for certain whether neurodivergency could be identified in the lab. Some studies reported smaller <a href="https://newatlas.com/clarity-transparent-brain/27024/">gray matter volumes</a> in children with ADHD compared to those without, while others showed no difference or even larger volumes. With some irony, it's been a gray area for diagnostics and research.</p><p>Here, the researchers employed an innovative technique called the traveling-subject (TS) method, which removed the "technical noise" that has traditionally distorted multi-site MRI studies. The result is a more reliable look at the ADHD brain &ndash; and a clearer picture of how the condition is linked to structural differences.</p><p>Essentially, different hospitals, clinics or research facilities use different scanners, with varying calibration, coils and software. When researchers pool data from multiple sites, they risk confusing biological variation with machine error. Statistical correction tools exist &ndash; like the widely used &ldquo;ComBat&rdquo; method &ndash; but these can sometimes overcorrect, erasing real biological signals along with noise. That&rsquo;s a big problem for conditions like ADHD, where the predicted structural differences are subtle &ndash; so if the measurement noise is louder than the biological effect, results end up contradictory.</p><p>The TS method takes a more hands-on approach &ndash;&nbsp;basically making the scans uniform across a study group. The researchers recruited 14 non-ADHD volunteers and scanned each of them across four different MRI machines over three months. Since the same person&rsquo;s brain doesn&rsquo;t change in that short window, any differences between scans are from the machines themselves. This template served as a sort of neurotypical control, which allowed the researchers to further investigate a much larger dataset from the Child Developmental MRI database, which included 178 "typically developing" children and 116 kids with ADHD.</p><p>What they found was that once the scanner bias was removed, the results became much clearer. Children with ADHD showed smaller brain volumes in the <a href="https://newatlas.com/molecular-scaffold-neurodegenerative-disease-dementia-motor-neuron/32400/">frontotemporal regions</a> compared to their typically developing peers. These brain areas are central to attention and information processing, emotional regulation, executive function and decision-making &ndash;&nbsp;all markers of ADHD.</p><p>"Despite these promising results, this study had some limitations," the team noted in the paper. "The study sample may not fully represent the broader population of children with ADHD. The participants were drawn from specific geographical regions and clinical settings, which could limit the generalizability of the findings to other populations. Additionally, this study only examined the brain structure characteristics in children with ADHD elucidated using harmonization."</p><p>While the new findings will need to be validated on a larger scale, the TS method could help with earlier diagnosis of ADHD and personalized treatments that track how therapies affect brain structure. It could also remove some of the stigma associated with ADHD, offering black-and-white, measurable evidence that <a href="https://newatlas.com/medical/adhd-affects-connectivity-across-whole-brain/">neurodivergent brains are different</a> &ndash; neurobiological evidence that isn't based on behavior or self-reporting.</p><p>The research also shows that, like any biology student who has struggled with experiment design will know, accurate data is all about getting the methods of testing right. </p><p>"This study demonstrated the effectiveness of the TS method in correcting measurement bias in multi-site MRI studies involving children with ADHD," the researchers added. "These findings highlight significant structural differences in the brains of patients with ADHD, particularly in the middle temporal gyrus, and underscore the importance of using robust harmonization techniques to improve the reproducibility and accuracy of neuroimaging research."</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41380-025-03142-6"><i>Molecular Psychiatry</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.chiba-u.ac.jp/e/news/research/_0905_brain_e.html">Chiba University</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 04:31:09 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencealert.com/world-first-physicists-created-a-time-crystal-that-we-can-actually-see</link><title>For the first time, physicists have created a time crystal that can be directly seen by human eyes (video) (sciencealert.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2afc/for_the_first_time_physicists_have_created_a_time/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2afc/for_the_first_time_physicists_have_created_a_time/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc2afc/for_the_first_time_physicists_have_created_a_time/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/crystal.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Physicists have just made a new breakthrough in the enigmatic realm of time crystals.</p><p>For the first time, a <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/time-crystal">time crystal</a> has been built that can be directly seen by human eyes, rippling in an array of neon-hued stripes. The material's construction could open up a whole new world of technological possibilities, including new anti-counterfeiting measures, random number generators, two-dimensional barcodes, and optical devices.</p><p>"They can be observed directly under a microscope and even, under special conditions, by the naked eye," <a href="https://www.colorado.edu/today/2025/09/05/physicists-have-created-new-time-crystal-it-wont-power-time-machine-could-have-many">says physicist Hanqing Zhao</a> of the University of Colorado Boulder.</p><p><b>Related: </b><a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/physicists-have-built-a-two-body-system-using-time-crystals-for-the-first-time"><b>Two Time Crystals Have Been Successfully Linked Together For The First Time</b></a></p><p>Time crystals are a very recent phenomenon. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.109.160402">Predicted</a> <a href="https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.109.160401">in 2012</a> by US theoretical physicist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frank_Wilczek">Frank Wilczek</a>, they were initially dismissed by some physicists as a law-breaking concept that risked breaking a key rule of <a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/thermodynamics">thermodynamics</a>.</p><p>Then, in 2016, a team of US physicists <a href="https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.090402">reported actually observing them</a> in an experiment.</p><p>So here's the short version. Crystalline materials like diamond, quartz, and salt are three-dimensional atomic lattices composed of particles that repeat in space, a bit like a geometric <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jungle_gym">jungle gym</a> with the atoms sitting at the junctions. You can take any section of the lattice and superimpose it over another perfectly.</p><p>A time crystal is a pattern of particles in a temporal dimension: in other words, time crystals repeat not just in space, but in time as well. Their particles oscillate with a timing that repeats in such a way that it, too, can be superimposed. Critically, the oscillation breaks time symmetry, operating in seeming defiance of any rhythms in their environment.</p><figure><img src="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/time-crystal.jpg" alt width="642" height="642" srcset="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/time-crystal.jpg 642w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/time-crystal-415x415.jpg 415w, https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2025/09/time-crystal-600x600.jpg 600w"><figcaption>How the time crystal appears under a microscope. (Zhao and Smalyukh, <em>Nat. Mater.</em>, 2025)</figcaption></figure><p>The potential of time crystals, both for exploration of quantum behavior and for technological applications, is pretty exciting. This is why scientists like to probe their properties and figure out what makes them (ahem) tick.</p><p>Zhao and his colleague, physicist Ivan Smalyukh of the University of Colorado Boulder, created their time crystal out of liquid crystals &ndash; the same material that can be found in the LCDs that are commonly used as screens on clocks and TVs. These consist of rod-shaped molecules that behave a little like a liquid, and a little like a crystal.</p><div></div><p>The researchers sandwiched their liquid crystal between glass plates coated with a photoresponsive dye. When they shone particular types of light on the sample, the dye molecules polarized, or changed their orientation, exerting pressure on the liquid crystal.</p><p>This pressure created kinks in the liquid crystal that interacted with each other in a complex series of steps, generating a pattern of motion that repeated for hours, even under changing light and temperature conditions.</p><p>These patterns were observed in the sample as an undulating series of colored stripes.</p><p>"Everything is born out of nothing," <a href="https://www.colorado.edu/today/2025/09/05/physicists-have-created-new-time-crystal-it-wont-power-time-machine-could-have-many">Smalyukh says</a>. "All you do is shine a light, and this whole world of time crystals emerges."</p><p>While the results of the study meet the stringent requirements to be classified as a time crystal, the researchers say there's ample room for further exploration of time crystal properties in different systems. In exploring how time crystals manifest in different regimes, the researchers believe that different sets of criteria may emerge.</p><p>Meanwhile, the practical application potential that can be seen now is deeply intriguing.</p><p>"Potential technological applications in optical devices, photonic space-time crystal generators, telecommunications, and anti-counterfeiting designs may signal the beginning of an exciting frontier for time and space-time crystals, where fundamental research advances could drive technological utility," <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02344-1">Zhao and Smalyukh write</a>.</p><p>The research has been published in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41563-025-02344-1"><i>Nature Materials</i></a>.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/4z4dY6qVrxo/0.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/8JbQfVwwVxQ/0.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/HnHGLqzQ4L0/0.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 04:13:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-02901-3</link><title>My blue is your blue: different peopleâ€™s brains process colours in the same way. Neuroscientists can predict what colour a person is looking at using a machine-learning tool trained on the brain activity of others. (nature.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc000l/my_blue_is_your_blue_different_peoples_brains/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc000l/my_blue_is_your_blue_different_peoples_brains/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nc000l/my_blue_is_your_blue_different_peoples_brains/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article><div><header><div><ul> <li><span>NEWS</span></li> <li><time>08 September 2025</time></li> </ul><div><p>Neuroscientists can predict what colour a person is looking at using a machine-learning tool trained on the brain activity of others. </p></div></div></header> </div><div><figure><picture><source srcset="//media.nature.com/lw767/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_51430836.jpg?as=webp 767w, //media.nature.com/lw319/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_51430836.jpg?as=webp 319w"><img alt="A happy couple hold up a set of paint colour cards against a blue wall in their home." src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/lw767/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_51430836.jpg"><figcaption><p><span>Our brains seem to respond to specific colours in a similar way. </span><span>Credit: Hispanolistic/Getty</span></p></figcaption></source></picture></figure><p>Is the colour you see the same as what I see? It&rsquo;s a question that has puzzled both philosophers and neuroscientists for decades, but has proved notoriously difficult to answer.</p><p>Now, a study that recorded patterns of brain activity in 15 participants suggests that colours are represented and processed in the same way in the brains of different people. The findings were published in the <i>Journal of Neuroscience </i>on 8 September<sup><a href="https://www.nature.com#ref-CR1">1</a></sup>.</p><p>&ldquo;Now we know that when you see red or green or whatever colour, that it activates your brain very similarly to my brain,&rdquo; says study co-author Andreas Bartels, a cognitive neuroscientist at the University of Tubingen and the Max Planck Institute, both in Tubingen, Germany. &ldquo;Even at a very low level, things are represented similarly across different brains, and that is a fundamentally new discovery.&rdquo;</p><p>Bartels and his colleague Michael Bannert wanted to explore how different colours are represented in parts of the brain associated with vision, and how consistent this is across different people.</p><article><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-01252-3"><img alt src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/w400/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_50911966.jpg"><p>Brand-new colour created by tricking human eyes with laser</p></a></article><p>The pair used functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) to compare activity in the brains of a group of participants while they viewed different colours. This allowed them to create a map of brain activity that showed how each hue was represented neurologically. They then trained a machine learning model called a linear classifier on this data, and used it to predict which colours were being viewed by members of a second group of study participants, on the basis of their brain activity.</p></div><p><em>doi: https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-025-02901-3</em></p><div><h2>References</h2></div><h2>Related Articles</h2> <ul> <li><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-025-01252-3"> <img src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/lw100/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_50911966.jpg" alt> Brand-new colour created by tricking human eyes with laser </a> </p></li> <li><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-021-02696-z"> <img src="https://www.nature.com//media.nature.com/lw100/magazine-assets/d41586-025-02901-3/d41586-025-02901-3_24090952.jpg" alt> Colour me better: fixing figures for colour blindness </a> </p></li> <li><p><a href="https://www.nature.com/news/mantis-shrimp-s-super-colour-vision-debunked-1.14578"> Mantis shrimp's super colour vision debunked </a> </p></li> </ul> <h2>Subjects</h2> <section> <h2>Latest on:</h2> </section> </article> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 02:40:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://ethz.ch/en/news-and-events/eth-news/news/2025/09/press-release-training-to-improve-memory.html</link><title>Stepping Into a Game Helped Older Adults Reclaim Their Memory. Research found not only did memory scores improve, but MRI scans showed the hippocampus and thalamusâ€”brain regions usually shrinking with dementiaâ€”actually grew in volume. (ethz.ch)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbqly3/stepping_into_a_game_helped_older_adults_reclaim/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbqly3/stepping_into_a_game_helped_older_adults_reclaim/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbqly3/stepping_into_a_game_helped_older_adults_reclaim/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><section><div><p>Game-based training improves not only the cognitive abilities of people with initial signs of developing dementia, but also leads to positive changes in the brain. That is according to two new studies by researchers from ETH Zurich and Eastern Switzerland University of Applied Sciences OST.<br> </p></div><div><figure> <img alt="An elderly woman stands in front of a television in her living room, which shows a spoon." src="https://ethz.ch/en/news-and-events/eth-news/news/2025/09/press-release-training-to-improve-memory/_jcr_content/articleLeadImage/image.imageformat.carousel.1686163701.jpg"> <figcaption><p>By stepping to the right, a study participant confirms that the product was on the shopping list.&nbsp;(Image: Jonas Weibel)</p></figcaption> </figure> </div><div><div><h2><b>In brief</b></h2> <ul> <li>Around 40 people with mild cognitive impairment and an average age of 73 trained for around 25 minutes, 5 times a week over a 12-week period.</li> <li>In response to the training, an increase was found in the study participants&rsquo; cognitive performance and in the volume of brain regions responsible for memory.</li> <li>The researchers showed that the changes in the brain were correlated with the improvements in memory and general cognitive performance.</li> </ul> </div><div><p>In Europe, almost one in 10 people over 70 suffers from dementia, and this figure could even triple by 2050 due to rising life expectancy. Over time, those affected lose everything that makes them who they are, including their memory and their ability to go about their everyday lives. Many also suffer from physical deterioration. In an advanced stage of the disorder, dementia patients generally require comprehensive care.</p><p>Now, the first drugs have emerged that can slightly slow down disease progression in the early stages of Alzheimer&rsquo;s &ndash; which is the most common of several different forms of dementia. However, these drugs are not yet authorised in Switzerland and are only relevant to a small group of patients. In recent years, &ldquo;exergames&rdquo; emerged as a low-risk alternative or complement treatment to medications. These fitness games combine physical activity with brain-excerses &ndash; without any undesired side effects. In 2021, a <a href="https://ethz.ch/de/news-und-veranstaltungen/eth-news/news/2021/04/spielend-gegen-demenz.html">study involving researchers from ETH</a> had already shown that this kind of training improves not only cognitive but also physical abilities, as well as the quality of life of people with severe dementia.</p><p>Now, two new ETH studies have shown that training with &ldquo;exergames&rdquo; also works in older individuals with mild cognitive impairment &ndash; an early stage of dementia. &ldquo;Not only did game-based training improve the cognitive performance of study participants, but we also measured significant changes in their brains,&rdquo; explains Patrick Manser, who is now carrying out research at the Karolinska Institute in Stockholm. Both studies emerged from his doctoral thesis at ETH Zurich and confirm the findings obtained in 2021.</p><h2><b>Training for mind and body</b></h2><p>In the two studies, Manser and his colleagues examined around 40 people with mild cognitive impairment and an average age of 73. Study participants trained at home for around 25 minutes, 5 times a week over a 12-week period, using a system consisting of a screen with the game software and a floor panel with four fields that measured the person&rsquo;s steps.</p><p>The participants generally had to solve predefined tasks on the screen by performing a sequence of movements with their feet. For example, they would attempt to memorise a shopping list and then decide by stepping to the right or left whether the product shown was on the list or not. &ldquo;Tasks like these train specific cognitive abilities that deteriorate in dementia patients, such as attention, memory or visuospatial skills,&rdquo; says Manser.</p><p>Following the exercises, the study participants each had to breathe slowly and in a controlled manner for a period of time. By doing so, they regulated their autonomic nervous system by stimulating the &nbsp;Vagus nerve and activated regions of the brain that are relevant to cognitive processes. This was intended to further boost the effectiveness of the training. </p></div><div><h2><b>Memory improves significantly</b></h2><p>In their first study, the researchers showed that there were significant improvements in the cognitive performance and memory of those doing the training. These improvements were not only statistically significant but also noticeable in everyday life &ndash; while shopping, in conversations or when dealing with stress, for example. Study participants reported feeling fitter, more lucid and more self-assured. In contrast, study participants in the control group, who continued with their usual therapies, experienced a worsening of their condition &ndash; which matches the typical disease progression.</p><p>The results are encouraging above all for people showing initial signs of dementia and for their relatives: &ldquo;We hope that, with targeted exergame training, we&rsquo;ll be able to slow down and reduce dementia symptoms,&rdquo; explains project leader and co-author Professor Eling D. de Bruin, who carries out research at ETH Zurich and Eastern Switzerland University of Applied Sciences OST.</p><h2><b>Structural changes in the brain</b></h2><p>In a second study, the researchers investigated whether the cognitive improvements were reflected in the brain. To their surprise, they could indeed detect changes in certain structures. In magnetic resonance images, the researchers found that the volume of the hippocampus &ndash; a region that plays a key role in memory &ndash; and the thalamus increased in those doing the training. They also observed effects in the anterior cingulate cortex, as well as slight improvements in the prefrontal cortex. In participants in the control group, on the other hand, the volume of these areas of the cerebral cortex decreased.</p><p>&ldquo;These regions play an important role in neurodegenerative diseases. Reduced hippocampal volume is even considered an early feature of dementia,&rdquo; explains de Bruin. The fact that the researchers were able to measure structural changes after just 12 weeks is, he says, impressive proof of the brain&rsquo;s plasticity &ndash; even in people showing the first signs of dementia.</p><p>The researchers also showed that the changes in the hippocampus and thalamus were correlated with better cognitive performance and better memory. This is a first indication of a potential causal, disease-modifying effect of the training. &ldquo;Our results give us confidence for the future. However, demonstrating whether the personalised, game-based training can delay or even prevent the development of dementia will require studies in which the participants train for longer than three months. There are already plans for projects of this kind,&rdquo; says de Bruin.</p></div><div><h2><b>References</b></h2><p>Manser P, de Bruin ED: &ldquo;Brain-IT&rdquo;: Exergame training with biofeedback breathing in neurocognitive disorders, Alzheimer&rsquo;s &amp; Dementia 2024, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.13913"><span>external page </span>doi: 10.1002/alz.13913</a></p><p>Manser P, Rosio M, Schmidt A, Michels L, de Bruin ED: Structural Brain Improvements Following Individually Tailored Serious Exergame-based Training in Mild Neurocognitive Disorders: Exploratory Randomized Controlled Trial, Alzheimer's Research &amp; Therapy,&nbsp; 8 September 2025, doi: <a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s13195-025-01835-2"><span>external page </span>10.1186/s13195-025-01835-2</a></p></div><div><h2>Contacts for media questions</h2> </div></div></section> </section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 20:50:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/single-dose-of-psilocybin-linked-to-lasting-symptom-relief-in-treatment-resistant-depression/</link><title>Single dose of psilocybin linked to lasting symptom relief in treatment-resistant depression (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbojsi/single_dose_of_psilocybin_linked_to_lasting/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbojsi/single_dose_of_psilocybin_linked_to_lasting/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbojsi/single_dose_of_psilocybin_linked_to_lasting/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/dried-psilocybin-mushrooms.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study of U.S. military veterans suffering from severe treatment-resistant depression found that a single dose of psilocybin was associated with significant reductions in depressive symptoms that lasted up to 12 months. Six months after the intervention, 50% of participants were in remission and 80% showed a clinically meaningful response. The antidepressant effects began to wane after 9 months. The study was published in the <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2025.119655"><em>Journal of Affective Disorders</em></a>.</p><p>Depression is a mental health disorder characterized by persistent sadness, loss of interest, low energy, and difficulty functioning in daily life. It can impact mood, cognition, and physical well-being, often interfering with work, relationships, and quality of life. Standard treatments include antidepressant medications, psychotherapy, or a combination of both.</p><p>However, many individuals fail to improve with these interventions. When someone does not respond to at least two adequate trials of different antidepressants, their condition is referred to as treatment-resistant depression (TRD). People with TRD tend to experience more severe, longer-lasting depressive episodes and are at greater risk for chronic impairment.</p><p>Mental health professionals often try various strategies for TRD, such as switching medications, combining drugs, or augmenting antidepressants with other agents like antipsychotics or mood stabilizers. However, these alternatives often provide limited relief. As a result, researchers continue to explore more effective options&mdash;including psychedelic compounds such as psilocybin.</p><p>Study author Sara Ellis and her colleagues note that previous studies have shown short-term benefits of psilocybin for depression, but few have examined how long those effects last. Their study sought to track changes in depression symptoms over a 12-month period following a single dose of psilocybin in a group of military veterans.</p><p>Psilocybin is a naturally occurring psychedelic compound found in certain species of mushrooms, often referred to as &ldquo;magic mushrooms.&rdquo; In medical research, psilocybin is being studied for its potential to treat conditions such as depression, anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder, and addiction. When administered in a controlled setting with psychological support, clinical trials suggest psilocybin may produce rapid and lasting improvements. However, it can also cause adverse effects such as distressing hallucinations, anxiety, confusion, and nausea, and it remains a controlled substance in many jurisdictions.</p><p>In this pilot study, the researchers followed 10 U.S. military veterans diagnosed with severe treatment-resistant depression. Although the sample size was small, military veterans represent a high-risk group for depression, particularly forms that are resistant to treatment, making the study especially relevant.</p><p>Before dosing, participants took part in two 60-minute and one 90-minute preparatory therapy sessions. On the dosing day, they each received a single 25 mg capsule of psilocybin. Sessions were conducted at Stanford University School of Medicine with two licensed therapists present, lasting 6 to 8 hours. Participants&rsquo; vital signs were monitored before and after dosing. The next day, they participated in a 90-minute integration session, followed by at least two additional integration sessions&mdash;one during the first week and one at 12 weeks post-treatment.</p><p>Participants were assessed for depressive symptoms, anxiety, and functional impairment at multiple timepoints up to 12 months after dosing. Measures included the Montgomery&ndash;&Aring;sberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS), the Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptoms (QIDS), and the Sheehan Disability Scale (SDS). They also completed the Five-Dimensional Altered States of Consciousness scale to assess their psychedelic experience, and safety and tolerability were monitored throughout.</p><p>The results showed a significant reduction in depression scores across all timepoints. At 6 months, 50% of participants met criteria for remission&mdash;meaning their symptoms were minimal or absent&mdash;and 80% experienced a clinically meaningful reduction in symptoms.</p><p>However, the antidepressant effects began to fade after 6 months. By 12 months, 40% of participants still met response criteria and 30% remained in remission. While scores were higher than at 3 or 12 weeks post-treatment, they were still significantly lower than at baseline.</p><p>&ldquo;In this first-of-kind study on long-term effects of psilocybin for Veterans with severe TRD [treatment-resistant depression], depression scores showed significant sustained reductions up to 12-months. However, the antidepressant effects began to wane at 6 months, and then more substantially after 9 months, although these increases in MADRS did not reach statistical significance. Further research is needed,&rdquo; the study authors concluded.</p><p>The study adds to growing evidence that psilocybin may offer long-term benefits for depression, especially in populations that have not responded to conventional treatments. However, the study had several important limitations. It did not include a control group, and participants were aware they were receiving psilocybin, which raises the possibility of expectancy effects or placebo responses. This introduces the potential for the Hawthorne effect, in which individuals change their behavior because they know they are being observed.</p><p>Without a control condition, it is difficult to determine how much of the observed improvement is due to psilocybin itself, and how much might be attributed to psychological support, natural symptom fluctuations, or other factors. The small sample size further limits the generalizability of the results.</p><p>The paper, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2025.119655">Long-term outcomes of single-dose psilocybin for U.S. military Veterans with severe treatment-resistant depression &ndash; 12-month data from an open-label pilot study</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Sara Ellis, Catherine Bostian, Anna Donnelly, Wendy Feng, Katherine Eisen, Melanie Lean, Elizabeth Conlan, Michael Ostacher, Scott Aaronson, and Trisha Suppes.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:31:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/attraction-goes-beyond-looks-study-shows-voices-scents-and-motion-all-matter/</link><title>Attraction goes beyond looks: Study shows voices, scents, and motion all matter. Physical attraction is not simply about being objectively good-looking. Instead, attraction seems to arise from a mix of shared traits, personal preferences, and subtle non-verbal signals that go beyond facial features. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nblv67/attraction_goes_beyond_looks_study_shows_voices/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nblv67/attraction_goes_beyond_looks_study_shows_voices/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nblv67/attraction_goes_beyond_looks_study_shows_voices/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/couple-in-bed.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>New research published in the <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/bjop.12787">British Journal of Psychology</a></em> provides evidence that physical attraction is not simply about being objectively good-looking. Instead, attraction seems to arise from a complex mix of shared traits, personal preferences, and subtle non-verbal signals that go far beyond facial features. The study examined how people rate others&rsquo; attractiveness based on face, voice, body motion, and scent. While some patterns of agreement emerged, much of what made someone attractive varied across individuals.</p><p>Traditionally, studies on attractiveness have focused heavily on faces, often identifying broad preferences for features like facial symmetry, averageness, and sexual dimorphism. These patterns were interpreted as indicators of biological fitness and often presumed to hold across individuals and contexts. But attraction in the real world is rarely limited to a headshot. People communicate with their voices, bodies, and even their body odor, all of which may contribute to how they are perceived.</p><p>The researchers aimed to move beyond this narrow focus by examining multiple non-verbal cues simultaneously. They also wanted to understand whether patterns of attractiveness are truly universal or shaped by personal compatibility. In particular, they were interested in whether same-sex judgments&mdash;which are typically more platonic&mdash;differ from opposite-sex judgments, which tend to be influenced by mate selection.</p><p>The researchers recruited 61 young adults to serve as &ldquo;non-verbal agents&rdquo;&mdash;individuals who provided various sensory stimuli for evaluation&mdash;and 71 other young adults to serve as &ldquo;perceivers&rdquo; who rated these stimuli. The agent group included both men and women who were photographed, recorded speaking, filmed making neutral expressions, and asked to provide body odor samples by wearing sweat-collecting pads under their arms while exercising. This process was designed to capture information across four sensory channels: sight (photos and video), sound (voice), motion (video), and smell (body odor).</p><p>The perceivers each rated eight agents (a balanced mix of male and female) across these modalities. Each modality was presented separately to avoid cross-contamination of impressions. For example, perceivers smelled odor samples in isolation and were later shown silent videos or heard voice recordings. They rated each stimulus on a seven-point attractiveness scale, alongside questions about emotional impressions and other subjective reactions. However, for this study, only the attractiveness ratings were analyzed.</p><p>The researchers used advanced statistical modeling to examine three main questions: First, do different modalities vary in how attractive they are perceived? Second, are certain modalities redundant&mdash;meaning, does finding someone&rsquo;s voice attractive predict finding their face attractive? Third, do common or personal preferences dominate attractiveness judgments, and does this vary between same- and opposite-sex interactions?</p><p>Across the board, the researchers observed that multimodal stimuli&mdash;videos with synchronized audio&mdash;were rated as most attractive, suggesting that richer, more dynamic inputs provide more favorable impressions. At the other end of the scale, body odor stimuli were rated least attractive on average. Faces, voices, and silent videos landed in the middle.</p><p>However, the variation in attractiveness scores between modalities was relatively small. The biggest difference observed between any two modalities was less than one point on a seven-point scale. This suggests that while people have modest preferences for certain types of input, no single channel dominates the attractiveness landscape.</p><p>There was also evidence that some modalities carried redundant information. For example, people who were rated as attractive based on their voice were often also rated as attractive based on their appearance. This pattern held across both opposite-sex and same-sex judgments.</p><p>The strongest associations were between face and voice, while the weakest were between body odor and photo. However, body odor attractiveness did show a consistent positive link with how someone moved&mdash;implying that more dynamic cues like scent and motion may reflect overlapping traits, such as health or hormonal state.</p><p>Interestingly, the study also revealed that the weight of personal preference varied by context. When people rated opposite-sex individuals, the variation in ratings could be explained equally by traits of the person being rated (common preferences) and the rater themselves (personal preferences).</p><p>In contrast, when participants rated same-sex individuals, the variation was more strongly shaped by personal preferences. This suggests that in same-sex interactions, which tend to be more platonic, subjective compatibility may play a larger role than universally agreed-upon features.</p><p>This finding provides support for the idea that attractiveness serves multiple functions. While traditional theories focus on mate selection, the researchers argue that attraction also influences broader social outcomes, such as friendship formation, team cohesion, or general likability. Previous studies have shown that attractive people are often judged as more trustworthy, intelligent, and socially competent&mdash;a phenomenon known as the halo effect. These impressions can shape interactions in many social domains, not just romantic ones.</p><p>The research took a comprehensive look at various non-verbal cues, but it is not without its limitations. All participants were young adults in good health, and the study was conducted in a controlled laboratory setting. These constraints limit how generalizable the results are to other age groups, health statuses, or more naturalistic social contexts.</p><p>The researchers also focused on isolated impressions rather than interactions, so it remains unclear how these non-verbal cues play out in ongoing relationships. Future research might examine how dynamic impressions change over time or explore how shared attraction influences social bonding in real-world settings.</p><p>Another limitation was that the study did not measure how attraction relates to behavioral outcomes. While certain traits were judged as attractive, the researchers did not examine whether these traits led to greater cooperation, friendship, or romantic interest in actual interactions. Addressing this gap could help clarify the functional consequences of perceiver-driven preferences.</p><p>The researchers also noted the need for further investigation into the specific components of motion and scent that contribute to attractiveness. For instance, future studies might use point-light displays to isolate movement style or analyze odor samples for chemical composition.</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/bjop.12787">Attraction in every sense: How looks, voice, movement and scent draw us to future lovers and friends</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Annett Schirmer, Marcel Franz, Lea Krismann, Vanessa N&ouml;ring, Marlen Gro&szlig;e, Mehmet Mahmut, and Ilona Croy.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://sp-ao.shortpixel.ai/client/to_webp,q_glossy,ret_img,w_250,h_85/https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/follow-on-google-news-1.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 17:34:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/fecal-microbiota-transplant-obese-adolescents/</link><title>A single fecal microbiota transplant in obese teens delivered long-lasting metabolic benefits, shrinking waistlines, reducing body fat and inflammation, and lowering heart disease risk markers, which were still visible four years later. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbjcmt/a_single_fecal_microbiota_transplant_in_obese/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbjcmt/a_single_fecal_microbiota_transplant_in_obese/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbjcmt/a_single_fecal_microbiota_transplant_in_obese/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/9b39a40/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F30%2Faf%2F58bc4a844176b95c8c3026d22fd6%2Fdepositphotos-44814743-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A single fecal microbiota transplant in obese teens delivered long-lasting metabolic benefits, shrinking waistlines, reducing body fat and inflammation, and lowering heart disease risk markers, which were still visible four years later.</p><p>We&rsquo;ve covered <a href="https://newatlas.com/fecal-transplant-super-donor-microbiome-gut-bacteria/58148/">fecal transplantation</a> studies before. While it might not be an appropriate topic for dinner table conversation, the rise in research acknowledging the importance of the <a href="https://newatlas.com/obesity-microbiome-immune-system-gut-bacteria/60766/">gut microbiome</a> on pretty much the <i>entire</i> body has shone a spotlight back on the treatment.</p><p>Eight years ago, 87 adolescents participated in a groundbreaking study led by the University of Auckland, New Zealand, in which they received a single fecal microbiota transplant (FMT) to treat their obesity. The researchers have now published the results of their follow-up study, conducted more than four years later.</p><p>&ldquo;What is impressive is that just a single FMT treatment produced a dramatic reduction in metabolic syndrome that lasted at least four years,&rdquo; said <a href="https://profiles.auckland.ac.nz/w-cutfield">Wayne Cutfield, MD</a>, a Professor of Pediatric Endocrinology at the <a href="https://www.auckland.ac.nz/en/liggins.html">Liggins Institute</a> at the University of Auckland and the study&rsquo;s co-corresponding author. &ldquo;This means participants are at much lower risk of developing diabetes and heart disease over the long term.&rdquo;</p><p>The eighty-seven obese adolescents recruited into the trial were aged between 14 and 18. Half received FMT capsules &ndash; yes, taken via the mouth &ndash; made from healthy, lean donors. The others received placebo capsules. Participants in the treatment group swallowed 28 capsules over two days, each containing gut bacteria from four donors. For the first six months, the trial was a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. After that, participants were unblinded (that is, they knew whether they&rsquo;d received treatment or a placebo) but followed up four years later.</p><p>After around four-and-a-half years, 55 participants (63% of the original group) came back for checks that included DEXA body scans, blood tests, blood pressure measurements, diet and activity questionnaires, and stool samples for gut microbiome analysis. A DEXA (dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry) scan is a non-invasive medical imaging test that uses low-dose X-rays to accurately measure a person&rsquo;s bone density, total body fat, and lean muscle mass.</p><p>The researchers found that while there were no significant differences in weight and body mass index (BMI) between the FMT and placebo groups, those who&rsquo;d had FMT had smaller waistlines (10 cm/3.9 in on average) and around 5% less total body fat on follow-up. They had lower severity scores for <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/fecal-transplant-fiber-supplement-obesity-metabolic-syndrome/">metabolic syndrome</a>, much lower <a href="https://newatlas.com/inflammation-off-switch-itaconate/54003/">inflammation</a>, and higher levels of &ldquo;good&rdquo; <a href="https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/high-density-lipoprotein-cholesterol-glaucoma/">HDL cholesterol</a>. No major difference was seen in blood sugar control or most other cholesterol and lipid markers.</p><p>&ldquo;More than one in three of the original teenage participants in our study had metabolic syndrome,&rdquo; Cutfield said. &ldquo;Metabolic syndrome has severe consequences, including a doubling in risk of death from heart disease or stroke and a five-fold increased risk of type 2 diabetes.&rdquo;</p><p>Astonishingly, FMT led to long-lasting changes in gut bacteria and viruses. The donor-derived bacterial and viral strains that participants in the treatment group had taken were still present after four years. Some participants retained many donor strains, others very few.</p><p>&ldquo;It really makes us think about the timeframes over which we look for the impacts of microbiome-based treatments,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s other corresponding author, <a href="https://profiles.auckland.ac.nz/justin-osullivan">Professor Justin O&rsquo;Sullivan, PhD</a>, Director of the Liggins Institute. &ldquo;Imagine being able to program your microbiome to reduce the risk of conditions before they occur. This work is paving the way for next-generation probiotics that target specific conditions through sustained changes to the microbiome.&rdquo;</p><p>Commercialization of a microbiome-based treatment for metabolic syndrome is the researchers&rsquo; end goal.</p><p>&ldquo;Our holy grail is to develop a super mix of bacteria that can be taken to prevent or moderate metabolic syndrome,&rdquo; said Cutfield. &ldquo;The first step is to prove our bespoke combination of bacteria actually works.&rdquo;</p><p>The study was published in the journal <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-025-62752-4"><i>Nature Communications</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.auckland.ac.nz/en/news/2025/08/28/the-good-shit-helping-obese-teens-study.html">University of Auckland</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:13:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.iza.org/publications/dp/17817/the-daughter-penalty</link><title>Mothers of daughters face larger post-birth earnings and employment penalties than mothers of sons, according to new study (iza.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbik19/mothers_of_daughters_face_larger_postbirth/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbik19/mothers_of_daughters_face_larger_postbirth/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nbik19/mothers_of_daughters_face_larger_postbirth/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Looking at the earnings profiles of men and women after their first child is born, a number of studies establish that women suffer a larger penalty in earnings than men&mdash;a child penalty. Leveraging randomness in the sex of the first birth, we show that the child penalty in the UK is larger when the first born child is a girl. We label this the daughter penalty. Exploiting rich longitudinal survey data, we examine behavioural responses to the birth of a daughter vs. a son to illuminate the underpinnings of the daughter penalty. We find that the birth of a daughter triggers more household specialisation than the birth of a son, with mothers taking on a larger share of household chores and childcare. Mothers suffer a daughter penalty in mental health, while fathers report more satisfaction with their relationship. Our findings imply that girls and boys in the UK are, on average, growing up in different home environments, with girls growing up in households that, by multiple markers, are more gender-regressive. This is potentially a mechanism for the inter-generational transmission of gendered norms.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 14:22:18 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nhm.ac.uk/discover/news/2025/august/ancient-skeleton-reveals-conflict-southeast-asia.html</link><title>The 12000 Year Old Skeleton That Reveals Humanityâ€™s First Known Act of Violence in Southeast Asia. Research found the individual did not die immediately in the attack, but weeks or perhaps months later after suffering an agonizing infection caused by his wounds (nhm.ac.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb5gh3/the_12000_year_old_skeleton_that_reveals/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb5gh3/the_12000_year_old_skeleton_that_reveals/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb5gh3/the_12000_year_old_skeleton_that_reveals/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><article><div><p><span>Science news</span></p><div><p>By James Ashworth</p><p><time>First published 28 August 2025</time></p></div></div><div><p>Some of the world&rsquo;s oldest evidence of human conflict has been discovered in Vietnam.</p><p>Despite dying more than 12,000 years ago, this male victim&rsquo;s painful final months have now been pieced together.</p></div></article><div><p>Incredibly rare evidence of ancient violence has been discovered in a world-renowned beauty spot.</p><p>Amid the soaring peaks and meandering rivers of Tr&agrave;ng An, Vietnam, a 12,000-year-old skeleton was recently found buried in a cave. The body was in relatively good condition for its age, representing a 35-year-old man in seemingly good health.</p><p>Researchers were unsure about what could have killed him, until they came across a fragment of quartz with the body. It appears to have been part of a projectile fired or thrown millennia ago, which shattered a bone in the man&rsquo;s neck and lodged in his body, condemning him to a long, lingering death.</p><p>The study, led by our scientist Dr Christopher Stimpson, has revealed the oldest evidence of human conflict on the southeast Asian mainland.</p><p>&ldquo;After the injury, this man lived for weeks, or even months, with a wound that just wouldn&rsquo;t heal,&rdquo; Christopher says. &ldquo;It seems likely that this became infected and eventually killed him.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;While it&rsquo;s fair to think that people were very tough then, you feel for him nonetheless. It must have been an incredibly painful way to die.&rdquo;</p><p>Dr V. Manh Bui, Director of the <a href="https://dulichninhbinh.com.vn/en/">Ninh Binh Department of Tourism</a>, adds that the discovery provides a welcome insight into a time in the region&rsquo;s history when human remains are extremely rare.</p><p>&ldquo;This is a groundbreaking and significant discovery &ndash; not only in terms of scientific value, but also in its historical and cultural importance. It is a source of local pride and will be invaluable in fostering a deeper appreciation for the heritage of Tr&agrave;ng An in residents and visitors alike.&rdquo;</p><p>The findings of the study were published in the journal Proceedings of the Royal Society B.</p></div><div><h2>How was the Tr&agrave;ng An skeleton found?</h2><p>The skeleton was found in Thung Binh One, a cave in the <a href="https://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1438/">Tr&agrave;ng An Landscape Complex World Heritage Site</a>, in 2017. The team were interested in the site because it was used as a midden, or ancient dump, and the archaeological evidence it could contain about the ancient humans who created it.</p><p>Having found broken pottery, snail shells and animal bones, the researchers were already piecing together the lives of the area&rsquo;s past residents. They weren&rsquo;t expecting to meet one, however.</p><p>&ldquo;My colleague uncovered the right shoulder of a human skeleton, and so we immediately had to go into DNA protocols to try not to contaminate it,&rdquo; Christopher recalls. &ldquo;It was very character-building wearing goggles, masks, gloves and more in such a humid cave!&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;After we&rsquo;d got permission to go ahead with an excavation, we used the orientation of the shoulder to work out where the rest of the skeleton would be, if it was there at all.&rdquo;</p><p>The team dug gradually until they reached the skull. It had been flattened by a rockfall at some point in the past 12,000 years, leaving behind what one of Christopher&rsquo;s colleagues described as &ldquo;a mud pie&rdquo;.</p><p>After attempting to take the skull out piece by piece, the team instead took out the skull and its surrounding sediment in a large block by digging around and under it. The rest of the skeleton followed over the next year.</p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;d previously worked in a few other caves in the local area, but this is probably the most challenging excavation that I&rsquo;ve ever conducted,&rdquo; Christopher says. &ldquo;It was a very small and cosy cave to work in, but finding a skeleton of this age in such good condition made it all worthwhile.&rdquo;</p></div><div><h2>What do we know about the man&rsquo;s life?</h2><p>Back in the lab, a team led by <a href="https://rcbioanth.wordpress.com/alex-wilshaw/">Dr Alex Wilshaw</a> began the painstaking process of removing the bones from the sediment. They were eventually able to reconstruct not just the majority of the body, but most of the skull as well. This has revealed incredible details about the man&rsquo;s life.</p><p>&ldquo;Human remains from this time in southeast Asia&rsquo;s history are relatively uncommon, so the skeletal and DNA evidence that we were able to recover gives us a rare insight into the people living there at the time,&rdquo; Christopher says.</p><p>&ldquo;For instance, we were able to recover a full set of relatively well-preserved teeth &ndash; it&rsquo;s amazing what life without refined sugar can do for dental hygiene!&rdquo;</p><p>The feet bones, meanwhile, show signs of being gnawed at by animals after death. It suggests that the body was kept above ground before burial in a place where animals could access the bones but not carry them away.</p><p>The most intriguing part of the skeleton, however, was the neck. As the sediment was removed, the team found that the man had a cervical rib &ndash; an extra neck bone that&rsquo;s only found in around one in 100 people. It had been damaged, with soft tissue getting into the fractures and stopping the wound from healing properly.</p><p>Inside the same sediment block was the white quartz point, which was immediately suspected as the cause of the break. It&rsquo;s small enough to form part of a projectile, such as an arrow or a dart, but not big enough that it would have been immediately fatal when hitting the neck.</p><p>Closer examination by <a href="https://humanorigins.si.edu/node/144352">Dr Benjamin Utting</a> revealed that it had a small notch on the side, which is characteristic of the damage caused by a stone striking something at high speed. While they can&rsquo;t be completely certain, the team think that being struck by the point is the most likely cause of the man&rsquo;s injury.</p><p>The point is also intriguing because of how it&rsquo;s made. Nothing like it has been found in the nearby area. In fact, the closest comparisons come from southeast Asia&rsquo;s islands, which are thousands of kilometres away from Tr&agrave;ng An.</p><p>Who made the quartz point, and where it came from, are among the many questions about the site that remain. As more of Tr&agrave;ng An&rsquo;s caves are excavated, researchers hope they&rsquo;ll come closer to answering them. </p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 03:00:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://theconversation.com/researchers-watched-150-episodes-of-bluey-they-found-it-can-teach-kids-about-resilience-for-real-life-262202</link><title>Researchers watched 150 episodes of Bluey â€“ they found it can teach kids about resilience for real life. Resilience isnâ€™t just about â€œtoughing it outâ€. Itâ€™s the ability to cope with challenges, adapt to setbacks and recover from difficulties. (theconversation.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb4z3b/researchers_watched_150_episodes_of_bluey_they/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb4z3b/researchers_watched_150_episodes_of_bluey_they/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nb4z3b/researchers_watched_150_episodes_of_bluey_they/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.theconversation.com/files/683154/original/file-20250731-56-42nytz.jpeg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&rect=0%2C125%2C2000%2C1000&q=45&auto=format&w=1356&h=668&fit=crop' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>She&rsquo;s six years old, lives in Brisbane and might just be one of the best resilience coaches on television. </p><p>We&rsquo;re talking about Bluey, the animated Aussie pup whose adventures have captured the hearts of families around the world. </p><p>But as our <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/20590776.2025.2526340">new study</a> reveals, Bluey isn&rsquo;t just entertaining kids, she&rsquo;s modelling how to to deal with life&rsquo;s ups and downs.</p><h2>Why is resilience so important?</h2><p>Resilience isn&rsquo;t just about &ldquo;toughing it out&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s the <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0149763421004930?via%3Dihub">ability</a> to cope with challenges, adapt to setbacks and recover from difficulties. It&rsquo;s a vital part of healthy child <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/2227-9067/5/7/98">development</a>.</p><p>Research shows resilience helps children manage stress, regulate their emotions, build better relationships, and even perform better at school. Without it, children may be more vulnerable to anxiety, depression and poor coping skills later in <a href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10826-022-02424-9">life</a>.</p><p>Children today face growing mental health challenges, including around anxiety and <a href="https://theconversation.com/parents-are-increasingly-saying-their-child-is-dysregulated-what-does-that-actually-mean-221989">emotional dysregulation</a>. For example, a <a href="https://www.adelaide.edu.au/newsroom/news/list/2024/02/06/young-australians-are-still-struggling">2023 national resilience survey</a> of almost 140,000 students found more than one in four primary and one in three secondary students reported high levels of psychological distress.</p><p>Research shows the <a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/psychiatry/articles/10.3389/fpsyt.2025.1594658/full">earlier we support resilience-building, the better</a>. Early interventions help build healthy coping skills before negative patterns take hold. </p><h2>How TV can help</h2><p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/jgc.2021">Storytelling</a> in films, books and TV can show children how to navigate challenges &ndash; not through lectures, but by <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0273229716300983?via%3Dihub">modelling behaviours</a> like emotional regulation, problem-solving and empathy.</p><p><a href="https://cdn.ncte.org/nctefiles/store/samplefiles/journals/la/la0813animals.pdf">Animal characters in storytelling</a> also offer valuable learning opportunities for children, who are naturally drawn to animals. </p><p>Bluey first aired in 2018. It has since become <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2025/jul/21/bbc-targets-adults-in-the-latest-adventure-for-its-top-dog-bluey?">Australia&rsquo;s most successful children&rsquo;s program</a>, with <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/maryroeloffs/2025/07/14/bluey-outranks-streamings-most-popular-originals-including-squid-game/">billions of views</a> worldwide. </p><p>It is known for its realistic portrayal of young family life. Yet until now, no one had systematically examined how it &ndash; or any kid&rsquo;s TV show &ndash; presents resilience on screen.</p><h2>So we watched all 150 Bluey episodes</h2><p>In our study, we analysed every episode of Bluey from seasons one to three. The 150 episodes added up to 18 hours of Bluey, Bingo, Chilli, Bandit and their friends. </p><p>For each episode, we looked closely at the storyline, characters and themes, identifying moments where a character faced a challenge and showed a resilient response.</p><p>To guide our analysis, we used the <a href="https://bibalex.org/baifa/Attachment/Documents/115519.pdf">Grotberg Resilience Framework</a>. This is a widely recognised model in psychology that breaks resilience into three key elements. </p><p><strong>1. I have:</strong> involving the support systems around a child, such as family, friends, and community role models they can rely on.</p><p><strong>2. I can:</strong> involving practical coping skills, like solving problems, managing emotions and asking for help when needed.</p><p><strong>3. I am:</strong> involving a child&rsquo;s inner strengths like confidence, optimism, emotional regulation and a sense of self worth.</p><h2>&lsquo;It&rsquo;s out of our hands&rsquo;</h2><p>Our research found nearly half of all episodes (73 out of 150) included a clear resilience message as either a primary or secondary theme. </p><p>Nearly two-thirds of the resilience moments were facilitated by a parent &mdash; most often Bluey&rsquo;s mum. This fits with the &ldquo;I have&rdquo; category of resilience, which highlights how children draw strength from caring adults when things get tough. </p><p>For example in The Show (season two episode 19), Bingo accidentally drops a breakfast tray and bursts into tears. Mum gently models emotional coaching explaining her coping process: &ldquo;I have a little cry, I pick myself up, dust myself off, and keep going.&rdquo; <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2212657024000278?">Research</a> shows that when caregivers model how to acknowledge distress, express feelings, and then recover with calm, children gradually learn to manage negative emotions effectively.</p><p>Later in the episode, Bingo repeats those exact words when things go wrong again. </p><h2>&lsquo;Well, that was fun&rsquo;</h2><p>Bluey and her sister also frequently demonstrate practical coping skills on their own. </p><p>In Keepy Uppy (season one, episode three), the final balloon in a game pops. The kids pause, take it in, and smile. &ldquo;Well, that was fun,&rdquo; they say. </p><p>In a single moment, we see disappointment, emotional regulation, and reframing &ndash; the core of the &ldquo;I can&rdquo; category.</p><h2>Everyday moments, powerful messages</h2><p>We also see characters overcoming challenges with their own inner strength. In Seesaw (season two, episode 27) Pom Pom shows determination and self-confidence to get to the top of the seesaw and save her friends, in an example of &ldquo;I am&rdquo;. As she declares, &ldquo;Pomeranians are a small but hardy breed&rdquo;.</p><p>We found Bluey touches on almost all of the <a href="https://bibalex.org/baifa/Attachment/Documents/115519.pdf">core elements of resilience</a>: trusting relationships, emotional communication, problem-solving, self-regulation, empathy and more.</p><p>In Sheepdog (season three, episode 11), mum Chilli tells her family she needs &ldquo;20 minutes&rdquo; of alone time. Bluey is worried she&rsquo;s done something wrong. Later, during play, Bluey gently echoes her mum&rsquo;s words to a toy: &ldquo;It&rsquo;s hard work looking after you. I just need 20 minutes.&rdquo;</p><p>That simple moment models self-care and perspective-taking as well as empathy. For kids, learning that grown-ups need rest too is a powerful message.</p><h2>How to watch Bluey with your kids</h2><p>Of course, no screen can replace real relationships. But when parents watch shows like Bluey with their kids, they become powerful teaching <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B978012809481500002X">tools</a>.</p><p>So the next time your child wants to watch an episode for the tenth time, don&rsquo;t feel guilty &ndash; join them. When parents watch too, those moments become conversation starters. For example, &ldquo;What do you think Bluey felt then?&rdquo;, &ldquo;Have you ever felt like that?&rdquo; or &ldquo;What would you do in that situation?&rdquo;</p><p>Talking about what kids see on screen can help them reflect, process, and build the skills they need to cope, adapt and grow. </p><hr><p><em>CQUniversity student Kelly Bohl and co-host of Bluey podcast Gotta Be Done Mary Bolling contributed to the original research on which this article is based.</em></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 02:40:49 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/people-interpret-long-eyelashes-as-a-signal-of-openness-to-casual-relationships/</link><title>People interpret long eyelashes as a signal of openness to casual relationships | However, participants also interpreted longer-than-optimal eyelashes as a signal of sexual receptivity. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nav9rw/people_interpret_long_eyelashes_as_a_signal_of/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nav9rw/people_interpret_long_eyelashes_as_a_signal_of/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1nav9rw/people_interpret_long_eyelashes_as_a_signal_of/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/attractive-woman-with-long-eyelashes.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A study conducted in the United Kingdom found that people perceive eyelashes that are about one-third the width of the eye as the most attractive and healthiest. Both shorter and longer eyelashes were rated less favorably. However, participants also interpreted longer-than-optimal eyelashes as a signal of sexual receptivity&mdash;that is, individuals with longer eyelashes were perceived as more open to casual relationships. The findings were published in the <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-025-03131-4"><em>Archives of Sexual Behavior</em></a>.</p><p>Eyelashes play an important role in shaping how people perceive attractiveness and health. As a subtle facial feature that frames the eyes&mdash;an important focal point in social interaction&mdash;eyelash length can influence impressions in unconscious ways. Previous research shows that moderately long eyelashes are viewed as the most attractive, likely because they enhance the eye&rsquo;s appearance without appearing artificial or exaggerated.</p><p>Very short eyelashes may be associated with poor health or aging, while extremely long or obviously artificial lashes can appear unnatural or even unhealthy. From an evolutionary standpoint, eyelashes help protect the eyes from dust, light, and airflow, so their appearance may serve as an indirect cue of good ocular health. Symmetrical lashes that frame the eyes tend to be linked with facial harmony and beauty. In women, longer lashes are often associated with femininity, youthfulness, and reproductive fitness, while in men, shorter but still noticeable eyelashes contribute to a balanced and healthy appearance.</p><p>Study author Farid&nbsp;Pazhoohi aimed to investigate whether perceptions of health and attractiveness based on eyelash length align&mdash;and whether long eyelashes could also serve as a signal of sexual receptivity. He noted that while people tend to prefer a moderate eyelash length for attractiveness, cosmetic trends such as eyelash extensions remain popular, potentially reflecting other social signaling motives. Based on this, he hypothesized that although very long lashes might be seen as less attractive, they could be perceived as signaling sexual openness or availability.</p><p>The study involved 120 participants residing in the U.K., recruited via Prolific. Seventy-seven were men, and the average age of participants was 32 years.</p><p>To test his hypotheses, Pazhoohi used Daz3D software to create computer-generated images of female faces representing four ethnic groups: Asian, Black, Indian, and White. For each ethnic group, he produced 11 variations of each face that differed only in eyelash length, ranging from none to half the width of the eye. Participants were shown these faces and asked to rate how healthy, attractive, and sexually receptive they perceived each woman to be.</p><p>The results confirmed that perceptions of both health and attractiveness followed an inverted-U pattern, peaking when the eyelash-to-eye-width ratio was around 0.33&mdash;approximately one-third. Both shorter and longer eyelashes were associated with lower ratings of health and attractiveness. This pattern was consistent across all ethnicities and regardless of the participant&rsquo;s sex.</p><p>However, perceptions of sexual receptivity followed a different trend. Faces with longer eyelashes were rated as more sexually receptive, even when those same eyelashes were rated as less attractive or healthy. In other words, very long eyelashes were interpreted as a possible signal of openness to short-term or casual relationships.</p><p>&ldquo;Results showed that eyelash length is positively associated with perceived sexual receptivity, suggesting that longer eyelashes might signal openness to casual relationships, despite lower attractiveness and health ratings at lengths beyond the optimal one-third ratio. This indicates a potential reproductive strategy linked to wearing long eyelashes and reveals that perceptions of attractiveness and sexual receptivity can diverge,&rdquo; Pazhoohi concluded.</p><p>The study sheds light on the way people interpret eyelash length. However, it should be noted that the study focused exclusively on the perception of female faces. Perceptions of eyelashes in male faces might be different. Also, the faces participants evaluated were static illustrations primarily differing in skin color and eyelash length. This differs from how people evaluate psychological characteristics of others in real-world situations.</p><p>The paper, &ldquo;<a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10508-025-03131-4">Long Lashes, Mixed Signals: Investigating the&nbsp;Effect of&nbsp;Eyelash Length on&nbsp;Perceived Health, Attractiveness, and&nbsp;Sexual Receptivity</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Farid&nbsp;Pazhoohi.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 20:24:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/environment/plant-pollen-coral-friendly-sunscreen/</link><title>Experimental new sunscreen forgoes minerals, replacing them with plant pollen. When applied to animal skin in lab tests, it rated SPF 30, blocking 97% UV rays. It had no effect on corals, even after 60 days. By contrast, corals died of bleaching within 6 days of exposure to commercial sunscreens. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naovap/experimental_new_sunscreen_forgoes_minerals/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naovap/experimental_new_sunscreen_forgoes_minerals/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naovap/experimental_new_sunscreen_forgoes_minerals/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/4d86cb1/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1992x1046+0+141/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fb7%2Fce%2Fa0abfc7c4be7acfca7d7c483a42c%2Fscreenshot-2025-09-04-at-9-49-13-am.jpeg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"> <article><div><ps-carousel> <template> </template><div><p>The camellia-pollen-based microgel applied to a test subject's hand (left), alongside its natural source</p><p>NTU Singapore</p></div><div><div><p><span>1</span>/<span>2</span> </p><div><p>(From left) NTU Singapore PhD student Deng Jingyu, Research Fellow Dr. Ferhan Abdul Rahim, Research Fellow Dr. Shahrudin Ibrahim, and Prof. Cho Nam-Joon (holding the raw pollen and the pollen-based sunscreen in a bottle)</p><p>NTU Singapore</p></div></div><div><p><span>2</span>/<span>2</span> </p><div><p>The camellia-pollen-based microgel applied to a test subject's hand (left), alongside its natural source</p><p>NTU Singapore</p></div></div></div></ps-carousel></div><div><p>Minerals such as titanium dioxide and zinc oxide are very effective sunscreen ingredients, but they can harm coral reefs if used in their non-nanoparticle form. An experimental new sunscreen forgoes the minerals altogether, replacing them with "just-as-effective" plant pollen.</p><p>The pollen-based sunscreen was developed by a team of scientists at Singapore's Nanyang Technological University, working with colleagues from Seoul National University in South Korea.</p><p>They experimented with both sunflower and <a href="https://newatlas.com/science/t-budbots-bacterial-biofilms/">camellia flower</a> pollen, getting the best results from the latter. Camellia pollen is considered nonallergenic, and is widely available as a relatively inexpensive health supplement.</p><p>The researchers utilized "a proprietary water-based process that does not involve harsh chemicals or high heat" to remove the inner contents of individual pollen grains. This left behind an outer coating of a tough natural biopolymer known as sporopollenin, which was converted into a transparent microgel no thicker than a human hair.</p><p>When applied to animal skin in lab tests, that gel was found to block harmful ultraviolet rays as effectively as a conventional mineral- or chemical-based sunscreen with an SPF rating of about 30. This means it blocked approximately 97% of the UV rays.</p><p>As an added benefit, because sporopollenin absorbs less energy than regular sunscreen in the visible to near-infrared spectrum, the microgel was found to keep the skin a total of 5 &ordm;C (9 &ordm;F) cooler for 20 minutes after application.</p><p>And importantly, the gel had no effect on corals after being added to the water in which they were living, even after 60 days. By contrast, the corals died of bleaching within six days of exposure to commercial sunscreens.</p><div><figure><div><figcaption>(From left) NTU Singapore PhD student Deng Jingyu, Research Fellow Dr. Ferhan Abdul Rahim, Research Fellow Dr. Shahrudin Ibrahim, and Prof. Cho Nam-Joon (holding the raw pollen and the pollen-based sunscreen in a bottle)</figcaption><p>NTU Singapore</p></div></figure> </div><p>"We know that pollen is naturally UV-resistant, as its shell needs to protect its inner contents from harsh environmental conditions, including sunlight," says the lead scientist, NTU's Prof. Cho Nam-Joon. "We wanted to develop an affordable and effective natural sunscreen that is non-allergenic to humans and eco-friendly to the environment."</p><p>The research is described in a paper that was recently published in the journal <a href="https://advanced.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/adfm.202516936"><i>Advanced Functional Materials</i></a>.</p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.ntu.edu.sg/news/detail/scientists-develop-coral-safe-cooling-sunscreen-from-pollen">Nanyang Technological University</a><br></p></div></article><div><h2>Tags</h2> </div><div><div><p>Based out of Edmonton, Canada, Ben Coxworth has been writing for New Atlas since 2009 and is presently Managing Editor for North America. An experienced freelance writer, he previously obtained an English BA from the University of Saskatchewan, then spent over 20 years working in various markets as a television reporter, producer and news videographer. Ben is particularly interested in scientific innovation, human-powered transportation, and the marine environment. </p></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/2a314cb/2147483647/strip/true/crop/1000x666+0+0/resize/1000x666!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F26%2F7f%2F338a618a44c784a25bb819f45f14%2Fscientists-develop-cooling-sunscreen-from-pollen-which-is-coral-safe.jpeg"></p><p><img src="https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/fe23897/2147483647/strip/true/crop/243x243+60+0/resize/100x100!/format/webp/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F1a%2Fff%2F6c02760f4fe7b724c9be9314ee92%2Fstaff-bio-icon-ben-coxworth.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 14:59:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://theconversation.com/climate-models-reveal-how-human-activity-may-be-locking-the-southwest-into-permanent-drought-262837</link><title>Climate models reveal how human activity may be locking the Southwest into permanent drought (theconversation.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naat53/climate_models_reveal_how_human_activity_may_be/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naat53/climate_models_reveal_how_human_activity_may_be/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1naat53/climate_models_reveal_how_human_activity_may_be/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://images.theconversation.com/files/684830/original/file-20250811-56-afzg9x.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&rect=0%2C714%2C6720%2C3360&q=45&auto=format&w=1356&h=668&fit=crop' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new wave of climate research is sounding a stark warning: Human activity may be driving drought more intensely &ndash; and more directly &ndash; than previously understood.</p><p>The southwestern United States has been in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41558-022-01290-z">a historic megadrought</a> for much of the past two decades, with its reservoirs including <a href="https://droughtmonitor.unl.edu/">lakes Mead and Powell</a> dipping to record lows and legal disputes erupting over <a href="https://theconversation.com/as-the-colorado-river-slowly-dries-up-states-angle-for-influence-over-future-water-rights-254132">rights to use water from the Colorado River</a>.</p><p>This drought has been linked to the <a href="https://www.ncei.noaa.gov/access/monitoring/pdo/">Pacific Decadal Oscillation</a>, a climate pattern that swings between wet and dry phases every few decades. Since a phase change in the early 2000s, the region has endured a <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41558-022-01290-z">dry spell of epic proportions</a>.</p><p>The PDO was thought to be a natural phenomenon, governed by unpredictable natural ocean and atmosphere fluctuations. But <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09368-2">new research</a> published in the journal Nature suggests that&rsquo;s no longer the case.</p><p>Working with hundreds of climate model simulations, our team of atmosphere, earth and ocean scientists found that the PDO is now being strongly influenced by human factors and has been since the 1950s. It should have oscillated to a wetter phase by now, but instead it has been stuck. Our results suggest that drought could become the new normal for the region unless human-driven warming is halted.</p><h2>The science of a drying world</h2><p>For decades, scientists have relied on a basic physical principle to predict rainfall trends: <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/sixth-assessment-report-working-group-i/">Warmer air holds more moisture</a>. In a warming world, this means <a href="https://theconversation.com/the-water-cycle-is-intensifying-as-the-climate-warms-ipcc-report-warns-that-means-more-intense-storms-and-flooding-165590">wet areas are likely to get wetter</a>, while dry regions become drier. In dry areas, as temperatures rise, more moisture is pulled from soils and transported away from these arid regions, intensifying droughts.</p><p>While most climate models simulate this general pattern, they often <a href="https://doi.org/10.1175/JCLI-D-12-00282.1">underestimate its full extent</a>, particularly over land areas.</p><figure> <a href="https://images.theconversation.com/files/684834/original/file-20250811-76-yvxb26.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1000&amp;fit=clip"></a> <figcaption> <span>Arizona Game and Fish Department workers pump water into a wildlife water catchment south of Tucson in July 2023. In normal years, the catchment receives enough rainwater, but years of drought have changed that.</span> <span><a href="https://www.gettyimages.com/detail/news-photo/steve-paz-a-volunteer-with-the-arizona-game-and-fish-news-photo/1558204284">Andrew Caballero-Reynolds/AFP via Getty Images</a></span> </figcaption> </figure><p>Yet countries are already experiencing drought emerging as one of the most immediate and severe consequences of climate change. Understanding what&rsquo;s ahead is essential, to know how long these droughts will last and because severe droughts can have sweeping affects on ecosystems, economies and <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/21/climate/drought-food-prices-coffee-wheat-beef.html">global food security</a>. </p><h2>Human fingerprints on megadroughts</h2><p>Simulating rainfall is one of the greatest challenges in climate science. It depends on a complex interplay between large-scale wind patterns and small-scale processes such as cloud formation.</p><p>Until recently, climate models have not offered a <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/report/ar6/wg1/figures/chapter-8/figure-8-14/">clear picture of how rainfall patterns</a> are likely to change in the near future as greenhouse gas emissions from vehicles, power plants and industries continue to heat up the planet. The models can diverge sharply in where, when and how precipitation will change. Even forecasts that average the results of several models differ when it comes to changes in rainfall patterns.</p><p>The techniques we deployed are helping to sharpen that picture <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09368-2">for North America</a> and <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09319-x">across the tropics</a>.</p><p>We looked back at the pattern of PDO phase changes over the past century using an exceptionally large ensemble of climate simulations. The massive number of simulations, more than 500, allowed us to isolate the human influences. This showed that the shifts in the PDO were driven by an interplay of increasing warming from greenhouse gas emissions and cooling from sun-blocking particles called aerosols that are associated with industrial pollution.</p><p>From the 1950s through the 1980s, we found that increasing <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/science-research/earth-science/climate-science/aerosols-small-particles-with-big-climate-effects/">aerosol emissions</a> from rapid industrialization following World War II drove a positive trend in the PDO, making the Southwest rainier and less parched.</p><p>After the 1980s, we found that the combination of a sharp rise in greenhouse gas emissions from industries, power plants and vehicles and a reduction in aerosols as countries <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250106012650/https:/www.epa.gov/clean-air-act-overview/progress-cleaning-air-and-improving-peoples-health">cleaned up their air pollution</a> shifted the PDO into the negative, drought-generating trend that continues today.</p><p>This finding represents a paradigm shift in our scientific understanding of the PDO and a warning for the future. The current negative phase can no longer be seen as just a roll of the climate dice &ndash; it has been loaded by humans.</p><p>Our conclusion that global warming can drive the PDO into its negative, drought-inducing phase is also supported by <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-025-01726-z">geological records of past megadroughts</a>. Around 6,000 years ago, during a period of high temperatures, evidence shows the emergence of a similar temperature pattern in the North Pacific and widespread drought across the Southwest.</p><h2>Tropical drought risks underestimated</h2><p>The past is also providing clues to future rainfall changes in the tropics and the risk of droughts in locations such as the Amazon.</p><p>One particularly instructive example comes from approximately 17,000 years ago. Geological evidence shows that there was a period of widespread rainfall shifts across the tropics coinciding with a major slowdown of ocean currents in the Atlantic.</p><p>These ocean currents, which play a crucial role in regulating global climate, naturally weakened or partially collapsed then, and they are expected to slow further this century at the current pace of global warming.</p><p>A recent study of that period, using computer models to analyze geologic evidence of earth&rsquo;s climate history, found <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-025-09319-x">much stronger drying</a> in the Amazon basin than previously understood. It also shows similar patterns of aridification in Central America, West Africa and Indonesia.</p><p>The results suggest that rainfall could decline precipitously again. Even a modest slowdown of a major Atlantic Ocean current could dry out rainforests, threaten vulnerable ecosystems and upend livelihoods across the tropics.</p><h2>What comes next</h2><p>Drought is a growing problem, increasingly driven by human influence. Confronting it will require <a href="https://theconversation.com/as-the-colorado-river-slowly-dries-up-states-angle-for-influence-over-future-water-rights-254132">rethinking water management</a>, agricultural policy and adaptation strategies. Doing that well depends on predicting drought with far greater confidence.</p><p>Climate research shows that better predictions are possible by using computer models in new ways and rigorously validating their performance against evidence from past climate shifts. The picture that emerges is sobering, revealing a much higher risk of drought across the world.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://images.theconversation.com/files/684834/original/file-20250811-76-yvxb26.jpg?ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=754&amp;fit=clip"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 02:35:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.durham.ac.uk/news-events/latest-news/2025/09/study-shows-the-lack-of-me-time-for-new-mothers/</link><title>Study shows the lack of â€˜me timeâ€™ for new mothers, and research suggests that insufficient personal time may contribute to higher stress levels, lower mental well-being, and increased risk of postpartum burnout (durham.ac.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8z6r/study_shows_the_lack_of_me_time_for_new_mothers/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8z6r/study_shows_the_lack_of_me_time_for_new_mothers/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8z6r/study_shows_the_lack_of_me_time_for_new_mothers/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.durham.ac.uk/media/durham-university/central-news-and-events-images/New-mums-WEB.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>New mothers only have about an hour out of their waking day for rest, according to new research by our psychologists. </p><div><p>The study also shows that time &lsquo;alone&rsquo; for new mothers is now always with their baby present and this time is rarely restful.</p><p>Instead, it is filled with non-stop chores and emotional overload leading to increased stress, loneliness and emotional exhaustion.</p><h4>Quality me-time</h4><p>When mothers had even small amounts of quality me-time - where they were not looking after the baby or working for example - they felt better.</p><p>The researchers say their findings highlight the need for greater support to help parents get more quality me-time or at least breaks from childcare and chores.</p><p>They suggest looking to other countries where there are examples of government-subsidised services that assist with chores and cooking. This kind of support could help ease the burden for new parents, especially those without support nearby.</p><h4>Loneliness and stress</h4><p>The mothers in the study said that being alone with a baby doesn&rsquo;t always feel like true solitude. For many, it&rsquo;s a mix of feeling isolated, responsible, and constantly on alert - even when no one else is around.</p><p>On average, the mothers in the study had less than a third of their day for &lsquo;personal time,&rsquo; scattered in short bursts. This time included things like showering, eating, or walking, usually done quickly and often with interruptions. The constant physical and mental multi-tasking left many feeling deprived of true me-time.</p><p>Many mothers feel like they are "always on", even during supposed breaks. The emotional and mental demands of caring for a baby, combined with the loss of meaningful alone time, can increase feelings of loneliness and make it harder to recover from daily stress.</p><h4>Time at home</h4><p>The largest share of mothers&rsquo; days, around 60 per cent, was spent at home, much of it devoted to childcare, which took clear priority. Personal time often overlapped with chores, errands, and occasional social activities, while rest and relaxation tended to fall to the bottom of the list.</p><p>The study also showed that loneliness in new mothers isn&rsquo;t always about the lack of people around you. It can come from a loss of personal identity, lack of meaningful social connections, or simply from feeling unsupported. This is especially true for single mothers, those without family support, or those whose babies have additional needs.</p><h4>Find out more</h4> <ul> <li>You can read the <a href="https://doi.org/10.1111/bjop.70019">research paper</a> in the British Journal of Psychology.</li> <li>Visit the <a href="https://www.solitude-lab.com/family-recharge">Solitude Lab</a> to find out more about our research in this area.</li> <li>The research was led by <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/staff/thuy-vy-nguyen/">Dr Thuy-vy Nguyen</a> from our Department of Psychology working with colleagues from the University of York, Leeds Beckett University and University College London. It was funded by the <a href="https://www.ukri.org/councils/esrc/">Economic and Social Research Council</a> (ESRC).</li> <li>Thuy-vy is also a Fellow of the <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/research-methods/">Durham Research Methods Centre</a>, <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/wolfson/">Wolfson Research Institute for Health and Wellbeing</a> and the <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/research/institutes-and-centres/medical-humanities/">Institute for Medical Humanities</a>.</li> <li>Our Department of Psychology is ranked 84th in the QS World University Rankings by Subject 2025.&nbsp;Visit our <a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/">Psychology webpages</a> for more information on our undergraduate and postgraduate programmes.</li> </ul> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 01:19:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/#google_vignette</link><title>Heterosexual men rate partners less favorably after pornography exposure, and research suggests this effect may be linked to altered perceptions of attractiveness and relationship satisfaction (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8tge/heterosexual_men_rate_partners_less_favorably/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8tge/heterosexual_men_rate_partners_less_favorably/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1na8tge/heterosexual_men_rate_partners_less_favorably/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/brain-1.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>The latest psychology and neuroscience discoveries.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 01:13:25 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2475299125029592</link><title>Children following a vegan diet were the most active during leisure time, most active across the week, and most consistently ate fruits compared to vegetarians and omnivores, study of 8799 pupils finds (sciencedirect.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9xabr/children_following_a_vegan_diet_were_the_most/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9xabr/children_following_a_vegan_diet_were_the_most/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9xabr/children_following_a_vegan_diet_were_the_most/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S2475299125X00093-cov150h.gif' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-content"><span><span>Skip to main content</span></span></a><a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com#screen-reader-main-title"><span><span>Skip to article</span></span></a></p><header></header><div><article><h2></h2><p><span>Nutritional epidemiology and public health</span></p><span>Difference in Motives and Basic Health Behavior of 8799 Children and Adolescents Aged 10&ndash;19 Years Following a Vegan, Vegetarian, or Omnivorous Diet</span><div><p><span>Under a Creative Commons </span><a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/"><span><span>license</span></span></a></p><p>Open access</p></div><div><h2>Abstract</h2><div><h3>Background</h3><p>Young generations appear to be pushing for more sustainable food production as part of the trend toward healthier dietary habits. Long-term sustainable healthy behavior from secondary school ages may contribute to the life course prevention of chronic, noncommunicable diseases.</p></div><div><h3>Objectives</h3><p>The present study aimed to analyze the motivations and key health behaviors of secondary school pupils following vegan, vegetarian, and omnivorous diets.</p></div><div><h3>Methods</h3><p>The present study was conducted cross-sectionally with a multi-level, cluster sampling strategy. Secondary school pupils (levels I and II) in Austria were requested to complete an online questionnaire independently or with parent/guardian or teacher supervision, including questions on personal characteristics, physical activity levels, nutrition habits, dietary motives, and alcohol and nicotine habits. The statistical analysis was performed with &chi;<sup>2</sup>and analysis of variance tests.</p></div><div><h3>Results</h3><p>A total of 8799 pupils (3249 boys; 5550 girls) with an mean age of 15.1 <strong>&plusmn;</strong> 2.3 y were classified into the vegan (1.6%), vegetarian (5.6%), or omnivorous diet (92.8%). Boys were found to be more likely to follow an omnivorous diet (97%; <em>P</em> &lt; 0.01). Health was the leading motivation for dietary adherence across the total sample (33.6%; 2959). Sports performance was a leading dietary motivation among the vegan diet subgroup (20.1%). Pupils following a vegan diet were the most active during leisure time (86.6%; <em>P</em> &lt; 0.01) and the most consistently active across the week (3.4 &plusmn; 1.2 d/wk; <em>P</em> &lt; 0.01), and the prevalence of daily fruit and vegetable intake was the highest between the vegan subgroup (81.7% and 80.3%; <em>P</em> &lt; 0.01) followed by the vegetarian subgroup (72.4% and 84.2%).</p></div><div><h3>Conclusions</h3><p>This is the first investigation to examine the differences in motives and basic health behavior between vegan, vegetarian, and omnivorous diets in school pupils. The findings indicate that following a vegan diet during childhood and adolescence is associated with more advantageous basic health behavioral choices.</p></div></div><ul><li><li></ul><div><div><h2>Keywords</h2><p><span>plant-based</span></p><p><span>plant-predominant</span></p><p><span>nutrition</span></p><p><span>diet</span></p><p><span>sport</span></p><p><span>physical exercise</span></p><p><span>physical activity</span></p><p><span>health promotion</span></p><p><span>prevention</span></p><p><span>public health</span></p><p><span>child public health</span></p></div><div><h2>Abbreviations</h2><div><p><span>HEAL</span></p><p><span>healthy eating and active living</span></p></div><div><p><span>NCD</span></p><p><span>noncommunicable disease</span></p></div></div></div><section><header><h2>Cited by (0)</h2></header></section><p><span>&copy; 2025 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. on behalf of American Society for Nutrition.</span></p></article></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 17:03:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/news/study-highlights-cultural-differences-in-parenting-and-reveals-that-how-babies-are-soothed-matters-more-than-how-fast-/</link><title>The way babies are soothed may be more important than how quickly mothers respond. UK mothers responded more quickly, but Ugandan infants recovered faster.â€¯UK mothers used more verbal reassurance and less tactile contact. Ugandan mothers used more tactile strategies, particularly breastfeeding. (durham.ac.uk)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9wnmj/the_way_babies_are_soothed_may_be_more_important/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.durham.ac.uk/media/durham-university/central-news-and-events-images/news/Infant-comforting-web-pic.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><p>The way in which babies are soothed could be more important than how quickly mothers respond, according to new research revealing cultural differences in how babies are comforted.&#8239;&#8239; </p><div><p><span>Researchers including Professor Zanna Clay of our Psychology Department observed mother&ndash;infant interactions in urban UK and rural Ugandan communities.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>They focused on how mothers soothed their babies following naturally occurring episodes of distress.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Challenging assumptions&nbsp;</h4><p><span>They found that although the UK mothers responded to their babies' distress more quickly, Ugandan infants actually recovered faster.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This challenges long-standing assumptions rooted in Western models of parenting by showing that maternal promptness is not the only factor influencing how infants manage their emotions.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Instead, the type of soothing behaviour used, which is shaped by cultural context, may play a key role in helping babies regulate distress.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>While both UK and Ugandan mothers soothed their babies at three months with tactile contact, like breastfeeding, UK mothers tended to use more verbal reassurance and less tactile contact as babies grew older.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>By comparison, Ugandan mothers were more likely to rely on tactile strategies, particularly breastfeeding, even with older infants.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Everyday interactions&nbsp;</h4><p><span>The researchers analysed 147 naturally occurring episodes of infant distress involving 82 infants aged three and six months.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Unlike controlled lab settings or surveys, the observations reflected genuine, everyday spontaneous parent&ndash;infant interactions.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>In both countries, infants recovered more quickly when mothers responded faster.&#8239;&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>But notably, Ugandan mothers - who tended to respond more slowly - soothed their infants more effectively using tactile strategies, like breastfeeding, leading to quicker recovery.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>This effect appears to stem from cultural differences in caregiving style and suggests that soothing methods may be more influential than speed of response alone.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The researchers hope these insights will inform more culturally inclusive approaches to parenting support and early intervention.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The research has been published in the journal Developmental Psychology and was funded by the European Research Council.&#8239;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></p><h4>Find out more&nbsp;</h4> <ul> <li><span>Read the full paper in the journal </span><a href="https://doi.org/10.1037/dev0002038"><span>Developmental Psychology</span></a><span>.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> <li><span>Learn more about the work of </span><a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/staff/zanna-e-clay/"><span>Professor Zanna Clay</span></a><span>.</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> <li><span>Our Department of Psychology is ranked 84th in the QS World University Rankings by Subject 2025. Visit our </span><a href="https://www.durham.ac.uk/departments/academic/psychology/"><span>Psychology webpages</span></a><span> for more information on our undergraduate and postgraduate programmes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</span><span>&nbsp;</span></li> </ul> </div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 16:27:36 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.additudemag.com/chronic-boredom-working-memory-attention-control/</link><title>A new study has found that people with ADHD traits experience boredom more often and more intensely than peers, linked to poor attention control and working memory (additudemag.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n9arrf/a_new_study_has_found_that_people_with_adhd/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i0.wp.com/www.additudemag.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/understand-conditions-adhd-research-and-news.png' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><em>September 1, 2025</em></p><p>Poor working memory and attention control may help explain why people with ADHD experience boredom more often and more acutely than do their non-ADHD peers. &ldquo;Part of the reason individuals with ADHD often experience boredom is due to difficulty controlling their attention and using their working memory effectively, leading to interpretations of that situation as boring,&rdquo; explains a study published last month in the <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/10870547251356723"><em>Journal of Attention Disorders</em></a>.<sup><a href="https://www.additudemag.com#footnote1">1</a></sup></p><p>In the small study, young adults completed self-reported measures of ADHD symptoms (using the Barkley Adult ADHD Rating Scale and the Wender Utah Rating Scale) and <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-so-bored-how-to-cure-boredom-adhd/">propensity for boredom</a> (on the Short Boredom Proneness Scale). They also submitted performance-based cognitive measures of <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/working-memory-deficit-weak-short-term-memory-symptoms-test-adults/">working memory</a> and attentional control. Based on their ADHD symptom self-reports, 31 participants were placed in the ADHD traits group and 57 in the control group.</p><p>Participants in the ADHD group experienced significantly higher levels of proneness to <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-bored-life-is-boring-impulsive-decisions/">boredom</a> compared to the control group (<em>d</em>&thinsp;=&thinsp;2.09), confirming previous research findings. Researchers also discovered that proneness to boredom and inclusion in the ADHD trait group were associated with significantly worse performance on working memory and attention control tests. &ldquo;Both attention control and <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/improve-working-memory/">working memory</a> factors partially mediated the relation between <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/slideshows/i-am-bored-agitation-restlessness/">ADHD and boredom</a>, accounting for 5.8% and 6.4% of the variance in ADHD-related boredom, respectively,&rdquo; researchers explained.</p><p>The findings of the study, the first to connect ADHD traits and boredom to performance-based <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/what-is-executive-function-disorder/">executive function</a> measures, support the Cognitive Theory of Boredom, which suggests that the experience of boredom is a result of the inability to direct attention on the task at hand.</p><p>One of the researchers who originated this theory, John Eastwood, Ph.D., co-author of <a href="https://www.hup.harvard.edu/books/9780674984677"><em>Out of My Skull: The Psychology of Boredom</em></a>, discussed the close association between boredom and ADHD in the recent <em>ADDitude</em> article, <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/im-so-bored-how-to-cure-boredom-adhd/"><em>Why ADHD Brains Go Over-Bored</em></a>,</p><p>&ldquo;Boredom points to our need to have agency, to be the captain of our own ship,&rdquo; Eastwood says, adding that the struggle to be self-directed is common among <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/what-is-adhd-symptoms-causes-treatments/">people with ADHD</a>, who are often corrected and directed by parents and teachers from a young age.</p><p>&ldquo;When a feeling like boredom is uncomfortable, we are sometimes unable to hear its deeper message because we just try to make the feeling go away,&rdquo; explains Eastwood. &ldquo;But boredom often has a message for us. I would encourage people to take boredom seriously, try not to be afraid or intolerant of it. There may be an opportunity to see how you can live in a way that gives fuller expression to who you are.&rdquo;</p><p>Eastwood also offered pragmatic interventions for those who experience chronic boredom, recommending adaptive, intentional responses to replace automatic, <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/stressors-adhd-brain/">stress responses</a>.</p><ul> <li>Instead of using avoidance-based coping strategies, such as a long break in the bathroom during a lecture, <strong>try engagement-based strategies,</strong> such as gamifying the experience &ndash; for instance, noting whenever the professor uses a three-syllable word.</li> <li>Strategies that help people <strong>tolerate intense emotions with a minimal stress response</strong>, such as active forms of <a href="https://www.additudemag.com/mindfulness-meditation-for-adhd/">mindfulness</a>, such as yoga or mindful walking, may also be effective with boredom</li> </ul> <h3>View Article Sources</h3><p><a></a><small><sup>1</sup>Orban, S. A., Blessing, J. S., Sandone, M. K., Conness, B., &amp; Santer, J. (2025). Why Are Individuals With ADHD More Prone to Boredom? Examining Attention Control and Working Memory as Mediators of Boredom in Young Adults With ADHD Traits. <em>Journal of Attention Disorders</em>, <em>0</em>(0). <a href="https://doi.org/10.1177/10870547251356723">https://doi.org/10.1177/10870547251356723</a></small></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 22:31:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/army-basic-training-appears-to-reshape-how-the-brain-processes-reward/</link><title>Army basic training appears to reshape how the brain processes reward. The stress experienced during basic combat training may dampen the brainâ€™s ability to respond to rewarding outcomes. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n93di4/army_basic_training_appears_to_reshape_how_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.psypost.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/us-army-soldiers.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A new study published in <em><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpsc.2025.05.007">Biological Psychiatry: Cognitive Neuroscience and Neuroimaging</a></em> suggests that stress experienced during basic combat training may dampen the brain&rsquo;s ability to respond to rewarding outcomes. Researchers found that Army National Guard recruits showed a measurable decline in neural signals linked to reward processing after completing a physically and emotionally demanding 10-week training program. The findings suggest that real-world stressors can influence how the brain processes both positive and negative feedback, with potential implications for resilience and mental health.</p><p>The ability to respond to rewards is considered an important aspect of healthy emotional functioning. Previous research has shown that greater neural responsiveness to rewards is associated with positive outcomes such as well-being, motivation, and resilience to stress. On the other hand, reduced responsiveness has been linked to symptoms of anhedonia, which refers to the loss of interest or pleasure in typically enjoyable activities. Anhedonia is a symptom seen across many psychiatric disorders, including depression.</p><p>Laboratory studies have demonstrated that acute or chronic stress can reduce the brain&rsquo;s responsiveness to rewards, possibly by disrupting dopamine signaling. However, much of this prior research has either relied on artificial stress manipulations in lab settings or retrospective self-reports of stress that may be biased.</p><p>Few studies have assessed how real-world, naturally occurring stressors affect neural reward processing over time. The authors of the current study sought to fill this gap by using a longitudinal design to examine how stress during a real-world challenge &mdash; basic combat training &mdash; might influence brain function.</p><p>The researchers drew on data from the ARMOR study, a large, ongoing project that investigates resilience and stress responses in military service members. From the broader sample, a subset of 123 Army National Guard recruits participated in a neuroimaging substudy. These participants were assessed before and after completing a 10-week basic combat training program. The training is designed to prepare civilians for military service and is widely recognized as a stressful experience due to its intense physical, psychological, and social demands.</p><p>Participants completed a computerized gambling task while their brain activity was recorded using electroencephalography, a method that tracks electrical signals from the scalp. The task involved choosing between two options to either win or lose points, with the outcome determined at random. This setup allowed the researchers to measure how the brain responded to positive (gain) or negative (loss) feedback. A particular brain signal, known as the reward positivity (or RewP), was used as a marker of reward processing. The RewP typically occurs between 175 and 325 milliseconds after feedback is received.</p><p>In addition to recording brain activity, the researchers also assessed each participant&rsquo;s experience of stress during training using the Basic Training Stressors Scale. This self-report measure captures both the frequency and perceived impact of various stressors related to performance, interpersonal dynamics, and living conditions. The stress survey was completed about two weeks after the end of basic training, prior to the follow-up brain scan.</p><p>The researchers also examined brain activity in specific frequency bands&mdash;delta and theta oscillations&mdash;associated with reward and loss processing, respectively. These time-frequency analyses provide an additional window into the dynamics of neural responses and may tap into different mechanisms than the traditional event-related potentials like the RewP.</p><p>The main finding was that neural responses to both rewards and losses were significantly reduced after the recruits completed basic training. This decrease was observed in the RewP time window and was not explained by the length of time between study visits. Interestingly, the difference between reward and loss responses did not change significantly, indicating that the decline occurred across both types of feedback rather than being specific to one.</p><p>The researchers then looked at whether self-reported stress during basic training was related to these changes in brain activity. They found that higher levels of perceived stress were associated with a smaller neural response to rewards, although this relationship weakened when additional variables were included in the model. This suggests that the subjective impact of stress, more than just the number of stressors, might influence how the brain adapts to stressful situations.</p><p>While the time-domain measures of brain activity showed a clear decline, analyses of delta and theta oscillations did not show consistent changes following training. This distinction may reflect differences in the neural processes captured by each approach. Time-domain signals like the RewP are typically phase-locked to feedback and reflect a more synchronized response, while time-frequency measures capture a broader and more variable range of neural activity. The researchers suggest that stress might reduce the consistency of brain responses rather than their amplitude, which could explain the discrepancy.</p><p>Participants who had stronger delta-band power before training were more likely to report lower levels of stress afterward. This finding hints at the possibility that some individuals may have a form of neural resilience, where their brains are better equipped to maintain reward sensitivity in the face of stress. These individuals may perceive stressful experiences as less overwhelming or disruptive, possibly buffering them from negative psychological outcomes.</p><p>While the study provides new evidence linking real-world stress to reduced reward responsiveness, the authors acknowledge some limitations. Most notably, there was no control group of recruits who completed the same assessments but did not undergo basic training. Without such a comparison, it is not possible to definitively conclude that the observed changes were caused by the stress of training rather than other factors, such as natural brain development or repeated exposure to the task.</p><p>Additionally, while participants reported on their stress shortly after completing training, the follow-up brain assessments occurred several months later. This introduces uncertainty about the timing of changes in reward processing relative to stress exposure. The study also cannot determine whether the observed neural changes have any lasting behavioral or psychological effects. Participants were generally high-functioning and did not show elevated levels of depression or anxiety, so the long-term impact of reduced reward responsiveness remains unclear.</p><p>The study raises important questions about whether these changes are temporary or long-lasting, and whether they might predict vulnerability to future mental health problems. It also suggests that individuals who enter stressful situations with higher reward sensitivity may be more resilient, but further research is needed to explore this possibility.</p><p>The study, &ldquo;<a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S2451902225001661">Neural Response to Reward and Loss Following Basic Combat Training</a>,&rdquo; was authored by Clara Freeman, Eric Rawls, Collin D. Teich, Scott R. Sponheim, Melissa A. Polusny, and Craig Marquardt.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 17:33:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://newatlas.com/health-wellbeing/sedentary-parents-children-mirror/</link><title>The activity level of parents affects the activity level of their kids: When parents sit too much, their kids tend to follow suit. But if parents keep active, children donâ€™t mirror the same sedentary habits. It highlights the power of parents as role models for healthier lifestyles. (newatlas.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/science/comments/1n90us9/the_activity_level_of_parents_affects_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://assets.newatlas.com/dims4/default/5f4932d/2147483647/strip/true/crop/2000x1050+0+38/resize/1200x630!/quality/90/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fnewatlas-brightspot.s3.amazonaws.com%2F90%2Fa8%2F19527eb24ba3b345a3aa55b27d1d%2Fdepositphotos-547980888-l.jpg&na.image_optimisation=0' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>When parents sit too much, their kids tend to follow suit. But if parents keep active, children don&rsquo;t mirror the same sedentary habits, a new study has shown. It highlights the power of parents as role models for healthier lifestyles.</p><p>The <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7700832/">health risks</a> associated with an <a href="https://newatlas.com/30-minutes-sedentary-mortality/51323/">inactive</a> or sedentary lifestyle are pretty well known: <a href="https://newatlas.com/disease/obesity/high-speed-internet-access-obesity/">obesity</a>, heart disease, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, and type 2 diabetes. But what if parents are inactive? Are their children likely to follow suit?</p><p>A new study led by researchers from S&atilde;o Paulo State University (UNESP), Brazil, has investigated how parents&rsquo; activity levels affect the activity levels of their kids.</p><p>&ldquo;The results indicate that parents&rsquo; level of physical activity can directly influence their children&rsquo;s habits,&rdquo; said the study&rsquo;s corresponding author, <a href="https://portaldocentes.unesp.br/portaldocentes/docentes/105083">Diego Christ&oacute;faro, PhD</a>, an assistant professor at UNESP. &ldquo;In other words, when parents maintain a more active routine, their children are less likely to remain seated for long periods.&rdquo;</p><p>The researchers recruited 182 young people (aged six to 17) and their parents (161 mothers, 136 fathers). Participants&rsquo; sedentary behavior and physical activity were objectively measured with accelerometers worn on the hip for seven days. Parents were categorized as &ldquo;physically active&rdquo; if they did 150 minutes or more of moderate-to-vigorous activity per week, or as &ldquo;insufficiently active&rdquo; if they didn't.</p><p>Statistical analysis was used to look at whether sedentary behavior in parents was associated with sedentary behavior in children, adjusting for age, sex, socioeconomic status, and the child&rsquo;s own activity levels. The researchers found high sedentary levels in all groups. Children, mothers, and fathers all averaged around eight to nine hours of sedentary time per day. There was a strong association between mother and child sedentary time, although no significant association when mothers were active. A modest but significant association was seen between father and child sedentary time. As with mothers, there was no association when fathers were active.</p><p>The study&rsquo;s findings suggest that the sedentary habits of children mirror their parents only when the parents are inactive. When parents are active, their kids&rsquo; sedentary behavior doesn&rsquo;t track as closely.</p><p>&ldquo;Sedentary habits are the result of multiple factors, such as lack of access, time, and places where physical activity can be practiced,&rdquo; Christofaro said. &ldquo;However, our study shows that parents&rsquo; habits can affect their children&rsquo;s health. Therefore, we believe that these results can support public policies and campaigns aimed at promoting a more active lifestyle in the family environment.&rdquo;</p><p>Because the study was cross-sectional, it only looked at one point in time, so it can&rsquo;t prove cause and effect. Additionally, families volunteered to take part, which may not represent the general population. The study was conducted in Brazil; results may differ in other cultural or social settings. And the lack of randomization in the study reduces the ability to generalize the findings widely.</p><p>Regardless of these limitations, the study suggests that kids are more likely to adopt sedentary habits if their parents are inactive. Which, in turn, suggests that active parents protect kids from sedentary behavior. So, when parents meet physical activity guidelines, this can break the &ldquo;like parent, like child&rdquo; cycle. Encouraging parents to be more physically active could be an effective strategy to reduce sedentary behavior in children and adolescents.</p><p>The study was funded, in part, by the S&atilde;o Paulo Research Foundation (FAPESP) and published in the journal <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666337625000691"><i>Sports Medicine and Health Science</i></a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p><p>Source: <a href="https://agencia.fapesp.br/study-confirms-that-inactive-parents-contribute-to-sedentary-behavior-in-their-children/55757">Ag&ecirc;ncia FAPESP</a></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 15:15:15 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
