<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;comments=3&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 02:48:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/09/after-getting-jimmy-kimmel-suspended-fcc-chair-threatens-abcs-the-view/</link><title>After getting Jimmy Kimmel suspended, FCC chair threatens ABC’s The View | Carr: "Turn your license in to the FCC, we'll find something else to do with it." (arstechnica.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlfivu/after_getting_jimmy_kimmel_suspended_fcc_chair/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlfivu/after_getting_jimmy_kimmel_suspended_fcc_chair/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 12 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlfivu/after_getting_jimmy_kimmel_suspended_fcc_chair/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/trump-carr-1152x648-1734382746.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article> <header><div><div><p>Carr: "Turn your license in to the FCC, we'll find something else to do with it." </p></div><div><p>President-elect Donald Trump speaks to Brendan Carr, his intended pick for Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, as he attends a SpaceX Starship rocket launch on November 19, 2024 in Brownsville, Texas. <span> Credit: Getty Images | Brandon Bell </span> </p></div></div></header><div><p>After <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/09/fcc-derided-as-federal-censorship-commission-after-pushing-jimmy-kimmel-off-abc/">pressuring ABC to suspend Jimmy Kimmel</a>, Federal Communications Commission Chairman Brendan Carr is setting his regulatory sights on ABC's <em>The View</em> and NBC late-night hosts Seth Meyers and Jimmy Fallon.</p><p>Carr appeared yesterday on the <a href="https://x.com/ScottJenningsKY/status/1968736369670504493">radio show</a> hosted by Scott Jennings, who describes himself as "the last man standing athwart the liberal mob." Jennings asked Carr whether <em>The View</em> and other ABC programs violate FCC rules, and made a reference to President Trump calling on NBC to cancel Fallon and Meyers.</p><p>"A lot of people think there are other shows on ABC that maybe run afoul of this more often than Jimmy Kimmel," Jennings said. "I'm thinking specifically of <em>The View</em>, and President Trump himself has mentioned Jimmy Fallon and Seth Meyers at NBC. Do you have comments on those shows, and are they doing what Kimmel did Monday night, and is it even worse on those programs in your opinion?"</p><p>In response, Carr discussed the FCC's Equal Opportunities Rule, also known as the Equal Time Rule, and said the FCC could determine that those shows don't qualify for an exemption to the rule.</p><p>"When you look at these other TV shows, what's interesting is the FCC does have a rule called the Equal Opportunity Rule, which means, for instance, if you're in the run-up to an election and you have one partisan elected official on, you have to give equal time, equal opportunity, to the opposing partisan politician," Carr said.</p><p>At another point in the interview, Carr said broadcasters that object to FCC enforcement "can turn your license in to the FCC, we'll find something else to do with it."</p><h2>Bona fide news exemption</h2><p>Carr said the FCC hasn't previously enforced the rule on those shows because of an exemption for "bona fide news" programs. He said the FCC could determine the shows mentioned by Jennings aren't exempt:</p><blockquote><p>There's an exception to that rule called the bona fide news exception, which means if you are a bona fide news program, you don't have to abide by the Equal Opportunity Rule. Over the years, the FCC has developed a body of case law on that that has suggested that most of these late night shows, other than <em>SNL</em>, are bona fide news programs. I would assume you could make the argument that <em>The View</em> is a bona fide news show but I'm not so sure about that, and I think it's worthwhile to have the FCC look into whether <em>The View</em> and some of these other programs you have still qualify as bona fide news programs and [are] therefore exempt from the Equal Opportunity regime that Congress has put in place.</p></blockquote><p>The Equal Opportunity Rule applies to radio and TV broadcast stations with FCC licenses to use the airwaves. An <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/sites/default/files/political_programming_fact_sheet.pdf">FCC fact sheet</a> explains that stations giving time to one candidate must provide "comparable time and placement to opposing candidates" upon request. The onus is on candidates to request air time&mdash;"the station is not required to seek out opposing legally qualified candidates and offer them Equal Opportunities," the fact sheet says.</p></div><div><p>The exemption mentioned by Carr means that "appearances by legally qualified candidates on bona fide newscasts, interview programs, certain types of news documentaries, and during on-the-spot coverage of bona fide news events are exempt from Equal Opportunities," the fact sheet says.</p><p>In 1994, the FCC <a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DA-94-1196A1.pdf">said</a> that "Congress removed the inhibiting effect of the equal opportunities obligation upon bona fide news programming to encourage increased news coverage of political campaign activity." Congress gave the FCC leeway to interpret the scope of bona fide news exemptions.</p><p>Referring to its 1988 ruling on <em>Entertainment Tonight</em> and <em>Entertainment This Week</em>, the FCC said it found that "the principal consideration should be 'whether the program reports news of some area of current events... in a manner similar to more traditional newscasts.' The Commission has thus declined to evaluate the relative quality or significance of the topics and stories selected for newscast coverage, relying instead on the broadcaster's good faith news judgment."</p><h2>Carr&rsquo;s allegations</h2><p>Carr <a href="https://x.com/BrendanCarrFCC/status/1852887210330341693">alleged</a> in November 2024 that NBC putting Kamala Harris on <em>Saturday Night Live</em> before the election was "a clear and blatant effort to evade the FCC's Equal Time rule." In fact, <a href="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/business/story/2024-11-04/trump-campaign-gets-equal-time-from-nbc-after-harris-snl-appearance">NBC gave Trump</a> two free 60-second messages in order to comply with the rule.</p><p>Carr didn't cite any specific incidents on <em>The View</em> or late-night shows that would violate the FCC rule. <em>The View</em> has addressed its attempts to get Trump on the show, however. Executive Producer Brian Teta <a href="https://deadline.com/2024/04/the-view-executive-producer-brian-teta-2024-election-1235875936/">told Deadline</a> in April 2024, "We've invited Trump to join us at the table for both 2016 and 2020 elections, and he declined, and at a certain point, we stopped asking. So I don't anticipate that changing. I think he's pretty familiar with how the co-hosts feel about him and doesn't see himself coming here."</p><p>The Kimmel controversy erupted over a monologue in which he said, "We hit some new lows over the weekend with the MAGA gang desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them and with everything they can to score political points from it."</p></div><div><p>With accused murderer Tyler Robinson being described as having liberal views, Carr and other conservatives alleged that Kimmel misled viewers. Carr appeared on right-wing commentator Benny Johnson's <a href="https://youtu.be/uTyX9JC-rhA?t=512">podcast</a> on Wednesday and said, "We can do this the easy way or the hard way. These companies can find ways to change conduct, to take action, frankly on Kimmel, or there's going to be additional work for the FCC ahead."</p><p>Nexstar and Sinclair, two major owners of TV stations, both urged ABC to take action against Kimmel and said their stations would not air his show. The pressure from broadcasters is happening at a time when both <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/broadcaster-fcc-abolish-national-tv-ownership-rule-1236496159/">Nexstar</a> and ABC owner <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-23/doj-probes-disney-fubo-deal-over-competition-concerns">Disney</a> are seeking Trump administration approval for mergers.</p><h2>Democrats accuse Carr of hypocrisy on First Amendment</h2><p>Anna Gomez, the only Democrat on the Republican-majority FCC, said yesterday that Carr overstepped his authority, but "billion-dollar companies with pending business before the agency" are "vulnerable to pressure to bend to the government's ideological demands."</p><p>Democratic lawmakers criticized Carr and <a href="https://democrats-energycommerce.house.gov/sites/evo-subsites/democrats-energycommerce.house.gov/files/evo-media-document/sept-2025-fcc-oig-letter-re-censorship-and-abuse-of-office.pdf">proposed</a> investigations into the chair for abuse of authority. "It is not simply unacceptable for the FCC chairman to threaten a media organization because he does not like the content of its programming&mdash;it violates the First Amendment that you claim to champion," Senate Democrats wrote in a <a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/services/files/82175836-7A72-4746-83B6-6CFFCC0A7A53">letter</a> to Carr. "The FCC's role in overseeing the public airwaves does not give it the power to act as a roving press censor, targeting broadcasters based on their political commentary. But under your leadership, the FCC is being weaponized to do precisely that."</p><p>Democrats pointed to some of Carr's previous statements in which he decried government censorship. During his 2023 re-confirmation proceedings, Senate Democrats asked Carr about social media posts in which he accused Democrats of engaging in censorship like "what you'd see in the Soviet Union."</p><p>"I posted those tweets in the context of expressing my view on the First Amendment that debate on matters of public interest should be robust, uninhibited, and wide open," <a href="https://www.commerce.senate.gov/services/files/8219EE1F-3043-41F0-B1A1-46456C5F295A">Carr wrote in his response to Democratic senators</a>. "I believe that the best remedy to speech that someone does not like or finds objectionable is more speech. I posted them because I believe that a newsroom's decision about what stories to cover and how to frame them should, consistent with the First Amendment, be beyond the reach of any government official."</p></div><div><p>Years earlier, in 2019, Carr posted a <a href="https://x.com/BrendanCarrFCC/status/1096062915201953795">tweet</a> that said, "Should the government censor speech it doesn't like? Of course not. The FCC does not have a roving mandate to police speech in the name of the 'public interest.'"</p><p>Sen. Ted Cruz (R-Texas) also <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/19/ted-cruz-jimmy-kimmel-fcc-carr-mafia.html">criticized</a> Carr's approach, saying it would lead to the same tactics being used against Republicans the next time Democrats are in power.</p><h2>Carr to broadcasters: Give your licenses back to FCC</h2><p>Carr said this week he's only addressing licensed broadcasters, which have public-interest obligations, as opposed to cable and streaming services that don't need FCC licenses. Network programming itself doesn't need an FCC license, but the TV stations that carry network shows require licenses.</p><p>Carr tried to cast Kimmel's suspension as the result of organic pressure from licensed broadcasters, rather than FCC coercion. "There's no untoward coercion happening here," Carr told Jennings. "The market was intended to function this way, where local TV stations get to push back."</p><p>But TV station owners did so in exactly the way that Carr urged them to. "The individual licensed stations that are taking their content, it's time for them to step up and say this garbage isn't something that we think serves the needs of our local communities," Carr said on Johnson's podcast. Carr said that Kimmel's monologue "appears to be some of the sickest conduct possible."</p><p>On the Jennings show, Carr alleged that Democrats in the previous administration implemented "a two-tiered weaponized system of justice," and that his FCC is instead giving everyone "a fair shake and even-handed treatment."</p><p>Carr has repeatedly threatened broadcasters with the FCC's rarely enforced news distortion policy. As we've <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/04/trumps-fcc-chair-invokes-rarely-enforced-news-distortion-policy-to-punish-media/">explained</a>, the FCC technically has no rule or regulation against news distortion, which is why it is called a policy and not a rule. But on Jennings' show, he described it as a rule.</p></div><div><div><p>"We do have those rules at the FCC: If you engage in news distortion, we can take action," Carr said.</p><p>As we've written several times, it is <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/12/trumps-fcc-chair-can-hassle-the-living-daylights-out-of-news-broadcasters/">difficult legally</a> for the FCC to revoke broadcast licenses. But it isn't difficult for Carr to exert pressure on networks and broadcasters through public statements. Carr suggested yesterday that broadcasters turn in their licenses if they don't like his approach to enforcement.</p><p>"If you're a broadcaster and you don't like being held accountable for the first time in a long time through the public interest standard, that's fine. You can turn your license in to the FCC, we'll find something else to do with it," Carr said. "Or you can go to Congress and say, 'I don't want the FCC having public interest obligations on broadcasters anymore, I want broadcasters to be like cable, to be like a streaming service.' That's fine too. But as long as that's the system that Congress has created, we're going to enforce it."</p></div><div><div><p>Jon is a Senior IT Reporter for Ars Technica. He covers the telecom industry, Federal Communications Commission rulemakings, broadband consumer affairs, court cases, and government regulation of the tech industry. </p></div></div><p><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/09/after-getting-jimmy-kimmel-suspended-fcc-chair-threatens-abcs-the-view/#comments" title="159 comments"> 159 Comments </a> </p></div></article> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/ignobles-2022-768x432.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This is why you don’t appease fascists</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlfivu/after_getting_jimmy_kimmel_suspended_fcc_chair/nf52jfv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Remember, don&#39;t call the Right &quot;fascists&quot;. They get really upset when you do.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlfivu/after_getting_jimmy_kimmel_suspended_fcc_chair/nf52g27/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>“Carr appeared yesterday on the radio show hosted by Scott Jennings, who describes himself as &quot;the last man standing athwart the liberal mob.&quot; “</p><p>So exactly who is this mob? The GOP controls all branches of the federal government, the entire ‘administrative state’ is taken over by Trumpists, and they control significant numbers of the states. Plus Trump’s allied oligarchs controls damn near everything.</p><p>They will hold on to their delusions until the very end.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlfivu/after_getting_jimmy_kimmel_suspended_fcc_chair/nf52uuc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 02:37:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.newsweek.com/disney-plus-subscribers-quit-jimmy-kimmel-axe-2132535</link><title>Disney Plus Subscribers Quit in Droves Over Jimmy Kimmel Axe (newsweek.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlaz9k/disney_plus_subscribers_quit_in_droves_over_jimmy/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlaz9k/disney_plus_subscribers_quit_in_droves_over_jimmy/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlaz9k/disney_plus_subscribers_quit_in_droves_over_jimmy/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2726023/jimmy-kimmel.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><article><div><div><p>By <span> <span><p>Aliss Higham is a Newsweek reporter based in Glasgow, Scotland. Her focus is reporting on Social Security, other government benefits and personal finance. She has previously extensively covered U.S. and European politics, Russia's invasion of Ukraine and the British Royal Family. Aliss joined Newsweek full time in January 2024 after a year of freelance reporting and has previously worked at digital Reach titles The Express and The Mirror. She is a graduate in English and Creative Writing from Goldsmiths, University of London. You can get in touch with Aliss by emailing <a href="https://www.newsweek.commailto:a.higham@newsweek.com">a.higham@newsweek.com</a>. Languages: English.</p></span> <a href="https://www.newsweek.com%20javascript:void(0);%20"> Aliss Higham </a> </span></p><p>US News Reporter</p></div><div><p>&#127897;&#65039; Voice is AI-generated. Inconsistencies may occur.</p></div><div><p>Disney streaming services users are cancelling their subscriptions over the suspension of the <em><a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/jimmy-kimmel">Jimmy Kimmel</a> Live!</em> show.</p><p><em>Newsweek</em> has contacted <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/disney-plus">Disney</a> via email for comment.</p><h2>Why It Matters</h2><p><span>On September 15, 2025, Jimmy Kimmel, during his monologue, made remarks about the assassination of <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/its-ok-feel-nothing-charlie-kirks-killing-america-needs-more-that-opinion-2131443">conservative activist Charlie Kirk</a>. He said that "many in MAGA land" were trying to "characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them ... doing everything they can to score political points from it."</span></p><p>Boycott calls have grown after <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/abc">ABC</a>, which is owned by Disney, announced it would <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/jimmy-kimmel-free-speech-week-your-words-2132328">indefinitely suspend the show</a> following complaints from the Federal Communications Commission (FFC) chair, Brendan Carr.</p><p>Trump appointee Carr said Kimmel's comments were "appearing to directly mislead the American public."</p><h2>What To Know</h2><p>Various subscribers have taken to social media to express their anger at the move, with some saying they are cancelling their subscriptions altogether.</p><p>X, formerly <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/twitter">Twitter</a>, user Reed Galen wrote: "Goodbye, @DisneyPlus. I won't miss you," accompanied by an image of his cancelled subscriptions. Actor Misha Collins said he would be "canceling my @DisneyPlus subscription "indefinitely."</p><p>"I believe in free markets and free speech, so I canceled @DisneyPlus ,@Hulu , and @ESPNPlus. Retweet if you're in," wrote Christopher Hale. The post has been reshared 3.3k times.</p><figure><figcaption> <span>Host Jimmy Kimmel attends UCLA Jonsson Cancer Center Foundation's 28th Annual Taste For A Cure at Beverly Wilshire, A Four Seasons Hotel on May 02, 2025 in Beverly Hills, California. </span> <span>Robin L Marshall/GETTY</span> </figcaption> </figure><p>User Jody Vance wrote that the website crashed when she tried to cancel her subscription. "Weird. @DisneyPlus keeps crashing when I try to cancel my subscription," she said. "Wonder if it's a bit busy?"</p><p>The anger isn't just contained online. Protesters gathered outside the Disney studio in Burbank, California, on Thursday in the wake of ABC's decision to take the show off air. Demonstrators told <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/cnn">CNN</a> that they had already canceled their Disney+ subscriptions in protest against the move.</p><p>Actor Jake Ferree, who was holding a sign that read "Disney stop bowing to a dictator," told CNN, "This affects every aspect of free speech. We should be able to express ourselves. That's the point of art."</p><p>Film production accountant Taylor Smith said she hopes that this "wakes people up" as she warned that the implications were bigger than just Kimmel.</p><h2>What People Are Saying</h2><p>The suspension of the show has been met with condemnation and praise from both sides of the political spectrum.</p><p><strong>Brendan <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cr4qe0rz2zvo.amp">Carr said on Thursday</a></strong>: "We're going to continue to hold these broadcasters accountable to the public interest - and if broadcasters don't like that simple solution, they can turn their licence in to the FCC."</p><p><strong>President Donald Trump wrote on Truth Social: </strong>"Great News for America: The ratings challenged <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/trump-white-house-reacts-jimmy-kimmel-live-abc-suspension-2131637">Jimmy Kimmel Show is CANCELLED</a>. Congratulations to ABC for finally having the courage to do what had to be done. Kimmel has ZERO talent, and worse ratings than even Colbert, if that's possible. That leaves Jimmy and Seth, two total losers, on Fake News <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/topic/nbc">NBC</a>. Their ratings are also horrible. Do it NBC!!! President DJT."</p><p><strong>Posting on X, former President Barack Obama wrote</strong>: "After years of complaining about cancel culture, the current administration has taken it to a new and dangerous level by routinely threatening regulatory action against media companies unless they muzzle or fire reporters and commentators it doesn't like."</p><p><strong><a href="https://x.com/RpsAgainstTrump/status/1968463818859725238">X account Republicans Against Trump posted</a></strong>: "Not a big fan of Jimmy Kimmel, but if you think his show should be canceled for this, you're a hack and a total fraud who should never pretend to care about free speech."</p><p><strong><a href="https://x.com/search?q=Jimmy%20Kimmel&amp;src=typeahead_click">Former Transport Secretary Pete Buttigieg posted</a></strong>: "What's happening with Jimmy Kimmel is about politics and power. Any corporation that thinks they can win by playing Trump's game will wind up regretting it, sooner or later, because he will never have enough."</p><h2>What Happens Next</h2><p>The future of Kimmel's show hangs in the balance. Disney executives <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/jimmy-kimmel-live-trump-abc-cancelled-fcc-free-speech-2131701">met with Kimmel on Thursday</a> to discuss the matter.</p></div></div><div><div><div><h2>fairness meter</h2><div><h2>fairness meter</h2><div><p>Newsweek is committed to journalism that's factual and fair.</p><p>Hold us accountable and submit your rating of this article on the meter. <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/fairness-meter"></a></p></div></div></div><div><p>Newsweek is committed to journalism that's factual and fair.</p><p>Hold us accountable and submit your rating of this article on the meter. <a href="https://www.newsweek.com/fairness-meter"><span></span></a></p></div></div><div><figure><p><span>Click On Meter </span><span>To Rate This Article</span></p></figure></div></div></article></div><div><h2> Top stories</h2></div><section><h3>About the writer</h3> <span> <span><p>Aliss Higham is a Newsweek reporter based in Glasgow, Scotland. Her focus is reporting on Social Security, other government benefits and personal finance. She has previously extensively covered U.S. and European politics, Russia's invasion of Ukraine and the British Royal Family. Aliss joined Newsweek full time in January 2024 after a year of freelance reporting and has previously worked at digital Reach titles The Express and The Mirror. She is a graduate in English and Creative Writing from Goldsmiths, University of London. You can get in touch with Aliss by emailing <a href="https://www.newsweek.commailto:a.higham@newsweek.com">a.higham@newsweek.com</a>. Languages: English.</p></span> <a href="https://www.newsweek.com%20javascript:void(0);%20"> Aliss Higham </a> </span><p><span><p>Aliss Higham is a Newsweek reporter based in Glasgow, Scotland. Her focus is reporting on Social Security, other government benefits ... <a>Read more</a> </p></span></p></section> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://d.newsweek.com/en/full/2726023/jimmy-kimmel.jpg?w=1200&amp;f=578dd72499e613e6eab254735069f85b"></p><p><img src="https://g.newsweek.com/www/images/NW_ICON_CommonGround.png"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Disney trying to walk the line and realizing you really cannot. You need to define your values and stick to them. Not throw them out on a whim</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlaz9k/disney_plus_subscribers_quit_in_droves_over_jimmy/nf42xrv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is good, but if you really want to stick it to Disney, they care about the theme parks the most.</p><p>Change your travel plans, cancel your reservations. That will really spook them.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlaz9k/disney_plus_subscribers_quit_in_droves_over_jimmy/nf44bmw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is an actual meaningful boycott because it&#39;s over actual government violations of speech. This isn&#39;t some lame ass boycott over stupid shit like a logo change.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nlaz9k/disney_plus_subscribers_quit_in_droves_over_jimmy/nf43p5z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:40:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/19/technology/kimmel-carr-outrage-online.html?unlocked_article_code=1.nE8.6WeW.ZhCHXwKGe6NX</link><title>How Outrage at Kimmel Grew to a Shout From a Whisper: Right-wing users on social media on Tuesday were frustrated but not yet apoplectic about Jimmy Kimmel’s monologue. Things changed. (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl6u7v/how_outrage_at_kimmel_grew_to_a_shout_from_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl6u7v/how_outrage_at_kimmel_grew_to_a_shout_from_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl6u7v/how_outrage_at_kimmel_grew_to_a_shout_from_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Kimmel’s monologue was seriously tame. Anyone truly offended is a fucking snowflake.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl6u7v/how_outrage_at_kimmel_grew_to_a_shout_from_a/nf36yqn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Multiple stories from all the major news outlets about how this was driven by &#39;online outrage&#39; and &#39;fears of safety&#39; (but not a decree)?</p><p>Seems SUPER organic...</p><p>Also Epstien killed himself, there&#39;s video of no one in the hallway, just ask the news.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl6u7v/how_outrage_at_kimmel_grew_to_a_shout_from_a/nf37cnn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;After years and years of illegal and unconstitutional federal efforts to restrict free expression, I also will sign an executive order to immediately stop all government censorship and bring back free speech to America.&quot; - Donald J. Trump, January 20, 2025  </p><p>Source: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/remarks/2025/01/the-inaugural-address/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/remarks/2025/01/the-inaugural-address/</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl6u7v/how_outrage_at_kimmel_grew_to_a_shout_from_a/nf3is2s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 21:05:04 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/sep/19/donald-trump-jimmy-kimmel-suspension-abc-federal-reserve-lisa-cook-us-politics-live-news</link><title>The President suggests broadcasters could be punished over critical coverage amid Kimmel suspension | The president said major US networks were ‘97% against me’ and that he supported ABC’s decision to suspend Jimmy Kimmel’s show (theguardian.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl0tew/the_president_suggests_broadcasters_could_be/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl0tew/the_president_suggests_broadcasters_could_be/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 63 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl0tew/the_president_suggests_broadcasters_could_be/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/77718a09de57f5dc7e1067fe58f9dfef96fd6e39/244_0_3164_2532/master/3164.jpg?width=1200&height=630&quality=85&auto=format&fit=crop&precrop=40:21,offset-x50,offset-y0&overlay-align=bottom%2Cleft&overlay-width=100p&overlay-base64=L2ltZy9zdGF0aWMvb3ZlcmxheXMvdGctbGl2ZS5wbmc&enable=upscale&s=08f9d0f04261dcbf46e9e20d6026eb05' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><gu-island></gu-island><div><article><header><h2>Trump says he and China's Xi made progress on TikTok and trade, and will meet soon</h2></header><p>Donald Trump and Xi Jinping &ldquo;made progress on many very important issues&rdquo; during their call this morning, according to the US president, including on trade, fentanyl, Russia&rsquo;s war in Ukraine, and the TikTok deal.</p><p>Trump also said he and Xi would have a face-to-face meeting at the APEC summit in South Korea next month, he would travel to China &ldquo;in the early part of next year&rdquo; and Xi would also come to the US at a later date.</p><p>The statement did not spell out the terms of an agreement between the leaders on TikTok, only that Trump &ldquo;appreciates the TikTok approval&rdquo;.</p><p>Trump just posted on his Truth Social platform:</p><blockquote><p>I just completed a very productive call with President Xi of China. We made progress on many very important issues including Trade, Fentanyl, the need to bring the War between Russia and Ukraine to an end, and the approval of the TikTok Deal. I also agreed with President Xi that we would meet at the APEC Summit in South Korea, that I would go to China in the early part of next year, and that President Xi would, likewise, come to the United States at an appropriate time. The call was a very good one, we will be speaking again by phone, appreciate the TikTok approval, and both look forward to meeting at APEC!</p></blockquote></article></div><p><span><gu-island>A federal judge has struck Donald Trump&rsquo;s $15bn defamation lawsuit against the New York Times over its content.</gu-island></span></p>","elementId":"08aea5d3-2683-4072-a5bb-c56f36808d4f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>US district judge Steven Merryday said Trump violated a federal procedural rule requiring a short and plain statement of why he deserves relief, and that <strong>a complaint is not &ldquo;a public forum for vituperation and invective&rdquo; or &ldquo;a protected platform to rage against an adversary&rdquo;</strong>.</p>","elementId":"06249a1a-47df-402b-b4b5-011e5fda55c2"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Merryday gave Trump 28 days to file an amended complaint.</p>","elementId":"22ad719f-8b12-4370-9f29-b0be445369af"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758298317000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"17.11&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758298369000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"17.12&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758298370000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"17.12&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"17.12","title":"Judge strikes Trump's $15bn lawsuit against New York Times over its content","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd804b8f08e4203c9a8044","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A resolution honoring murdered conservative activist Charlie Kirk passed the House of Representatives with bipartisan support on Friday, but only after <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/19/house-resolution-charlie-kirk\"'>causing considerable consternation</a> among Democrats.</p>","elementId":"83533dcc-a634-4f80-b779-3b16facb9bb5"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>All Republicans in attendance voted in favor of <a href='\"https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/house-resolution/719/text\"'>the resolution</a>, which describes Kirk as &ldquo;a courageous American patriot, whose life was tragically and unjustly cut short in an act of political violence&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"1491b439-97cd-440b-ac68-d210a54b2ae5"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Ninety five Democrats supported the resolution, while 58 opposed it. Thirty eight voted present, and 22 did not vote.</p>","elementId":"83289580-167a-479e-90c6-ac57663b681b"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Kirk <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/12/charlie-kirk-young-conservatives-social-media\"'>was instrumental</a> in building support for Donald Trump and conservative causes among younger voters, often by using <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/11/charlie-kirk-quotes-beliefs\"'>racist and discriminatory language</a> and arguments.</p>","elementId":"fc054700-ca62-4e86-b822-1049f428565f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Several Democrats who opposed the resolution said they <strong>condemned his murder, but could not support a figure who used his speech</strong>.</p>","elementId":"d4808a49-46e8-4bea-ab9d-fdcd4be6332c"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;<strong>We should be clear about who Charlie Kirk was</strong>: a man who believed that the Civil Rights Act that granted Black Americans the right to vote was a &lsquo;mistake&rsquo;, who after the violent attack on Paul Pelosi claimed that &lsquo;some amazing patriot out there&rsquo; should bail out his assailant, and accused Jews of controlling &lsquo;not just the colleges &ndash; it&rsquo;s the nonprofits, it&rsquo;s the movies, it&rsquo;s Hollywood, it&rsquo;s all of it,&rsquo;&rdquo; said New York&rsquo;s Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, who voted no.</p>","elementId":"9cb1cb75-c385-4751-a06a-0af347f22a1a"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>She went on: &ldquo;His rhetoric and beliefs were ignorant and sought to disenfranchise millions of Americans &ndash; far from &lsquo;working tirelessly to promote unity&rsquo; as asserted by the majority in this resolution.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"f7ef55e0-4129-477b-a9aa-33db197550ce"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;I cannot vote yes on this resolution because <strong>it grossly misrepresents Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s methods, views, and beliefs while citing Christian nationalist language</strong>. I will always condemn heinous acts of violence, but this resolution <strong>ignores the false and hateful rhetoric that was too often present in his debate</strong>s,&rdquo; said Colorado&rsquo;s Diana DeGette, who voted present.</p>","elementId":"5abc4d03-82aa-4881-9edd-5cad0e69d139"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Maryland&rsquo;s Jamie Raskin said he voted yes on the measure because it &ldquo;repeatedly condemns all political violence, extremism and hatred in unequivocal terms&rdquo;, while adding: &ldquo;We should overlook whatever surplus verbiage is contained in this resolution designed to make the vote difficult for Democrats. We cannot fall for that obvious political trap and should rise above it.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"bf6b8bc6-9b45-4b13-9352-ef6018feca9d"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Congressman Dan Goldman, who voted present said: &ldquo;I condemn political violence of any kind, including the horrific assassination of Mr Kirk. I cannot vote no on a resolution that condemns political violence. I do not support - and indeed <strong>condemn in the strongest possible terms - many of the hateful views Mr Kirk espoused</strong>. <strong>I cannot vote yes on a resolution that celebrates those views</strong>.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"8e8bb68b-8e4a-4c6e-bfa2-ab9359bc406a"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758298187000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"17.09&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758298894000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"17.21&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758298297000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"17.11&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"17.11","title":"House passes bipartisan resolution honoring Charlie Kirk","contributors":[{"name":"Chris Stein","imageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/25/Chris_Stein.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=816e271eec6598b9b8784a001bf54a35","largeImageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/25/Chris_Stein.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=5829f7087d8175b610aa897c2d8ded33"}],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd7bca8f0816a4522be3fe","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Donald Trump&rsquo;s administration asked the supreme court on Friday to intervene in a bid to refuse to issue passports to transgender and nonbinary Americans that reflect their gender identities.</p>","elementId":"eae8f9ba-f99a-4c84-bb3b-a9b6d66447cd"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Reuters reports that the justice department filed an emergency request to lift a federal judge&rsquo;s injunction barring the state department from enforcing a policy it adopted at Trump&rsquo;s direction.</p>","elementId":"bd996b8f-731c-4547-8f25-472a597cc1f1"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The dispute is one of several concerning an executive order Trump signed after returning to office on 20 January directing the government to recognize only two biologically distinct sexes, male and female.</p>","elementId":"41905d76-1a87-450b-9ffb-c041b7d9eb55"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758297034000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"16.50&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758298461000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"17.14&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758297083000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"16.51&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"16.51","title":"Trump asks supreme court to enforce passport policy targeting transgender people","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd78788f08e4203c9a7fa5","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Donald Trump and Xi Jinping &ldquo;made progress on many very important issues&rdquo; during their call this morning, according to the US president, including on trade, fentanyl, Russia&rsquo;s war in Ukraine, and the TikTok deal.</p>","elementId":"64dbc23b-26dc-4df5-b8fb-c863f58f1720"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump also said he and Xi would have a face-to-face meeting at the APEC summit in South Korea next month, he would travel to China &ldquo;in the early part of next year&rdquo; and Xi would also come to the US at a later date.</p>","elementId":"2c364be1-c63c-44bc-9b55-a8451a55625f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The statement did not spell out the terms of an agreement between the leaders on TikTok, only that Trump &ldquo;appreciates the TikTok approval&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"da9b2a10-6e33-46e6-bda6-e587ca0aa1bd"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump just posted on his Truth Social platform:</p>","elementId":"34f92a90-a83f-4f15-9691-f8cd45c78920"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.BlockquoteBlockElement","html":"<blockquote>\n<p>I just completed a very productive call with President Xi of China. We made progress on many very important issues including Trade, Fentanyl, the need to bring the War between Russia and Ukraine to an end, and the approval of the TikTok Deal. I also agreed with President Xi that we would meet at the APEC Summit in South Korea, that I would go to China in the early part of next year, and that President Xi would, likewise, come to the United States at an appropriate time. The call was a very good one, we will be speaking again by phone, appreciate the TikTok approval, and both look forward to meeting at APEC!</p>\n</blockquote>","elementId":"ef456525-86da-4d66-8103-e24076ec9d3e"}],"attributes":{"pinned":true,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758296184000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"16.36&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758297196000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"16.53&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758296485000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"16.41&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"16.41","title":"Trump says he and China's Xi made progress on TikTok and trade, and will meet soon","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd6cea8f0816a4522be2e3","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The US House passed a stopgap funding bill, known as a &lsquo;continuing resolution&rsquo; (CR) &ndash; which would keep the government funded until 21 November.</p>","elementId":"df28171b-aeb8-4e8c-8e9a-7de14a460a51"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Lawmakers in the lower chamber passed the bill 217-212, with two <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/republicans\"'>Republicans</a> voting against it, and one Democrat &ndash;&nbsp;congressman Jared Golden of Maine &ndash; voting for it.</p>","elementId":"35dbd64e-7cdb-449f-acde-55fd28017ca1"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The CR now advances to the Senate, where it needs 60 votes to overcome a filibuster.</p>","elementId":"40e85262-83e5-4a6b-b202-ef92d471f808"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A reminder, that a government funding expires at the end of the month if lawmakers can&rsquo;t pass this short-term solution.</p>","elementId":"baf48fea-f586-4b21-b49d-8ca0694d4204"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758293226000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"15.47&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758295611000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"16.26&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758293584000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"15.53&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"15.53","title":"House passes stopgap funding bill to avert government shutdown","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd546a8f0816a4522be12f","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A new <a href='\"https://apnorc.org/projects/pessimism-about-the-direction-of-the-country-is-growing-among-republicans/\"'>Associated Press-NORC poll</a> shows that there has been a significant drop, among Republicans, that the country is heading in a positive direction.</p>","elementId":"c3255447-0ebd-49c9-ba01-d370628544c7"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>51% of <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/republicans\"'>Republicans</a> said the country is heading in the wrong direction, in a poll conducted between 11 and 15 September.</strong> A 22-point increase from the 29% of Republicans who expressed the same feeling in June of this year.</p>","elementId":"9c6fa234-12bc-44d6-b0c6-fbfd218ac120"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>For Democrats, 92% say the country is heading in the wrong direction &ndash; a number that&rsquo;s stayed consistent since <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> returned to the White House for a second term.</p>","elementId":"8c2873d9-af13-4fa1-89a0-9d5eb6fe8188"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>More broadly, 39% of adults approve of the way Trump is handing his job as president, while 60% disapprove.</p>","elementId":"99f8243e-172a-4e2c-b87a-eea23f7cb8e8"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758286954000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"14.02&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758288154000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"14.22&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758287713000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"14.15&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"14.15","title":"Following Kirk shooting, new poll shows drop in positive direction of the country among Republicans","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd47b78f08e4203c9a7c10","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Today, lawmakers in the House will vote on legislation, known as a &ldquo;continuing resolution&rdquo; (CR), to prevent a looming government shutdown at the end of September.</p>","elementId":"6c65a1db-5adb-49d4-88ad-2aaf9aeeca21"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The bill, introduced by <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/republicans\"'>Republicans</a>, would fund the government until 21 November. According to Politico, House GOP whip <strong>Tom Emmer</strong> was confident, as of Thursday, that his party had enough votes. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re going to pass this,&rdquo; he said in an interview.</p>","elementId":"270060a7-280c-41ca-ad9c-9c475c696fe4"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>A reminder, Republicans only have a very thin majority in the lower chamber, and have already heard push back from some members on certain provisions in the bill.</p>","elementId":"53cc59ac-1eb4-4214-b9da-48bae9d1b1b9"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Democrats have, almost unanimously, said they&rsquo;re bucking the CR as is, taking issue with its lack of health care provisions. &ldquo;The House Republican-only spending bill fails to meet the needs of the American people and does nothing to stop the looming healthcare crisis,&rdquo; senate minority Leader <strong>Chuck Schumer</strong> and House minority Leader <strong>Hakeem Jeffries</strong> said in a joint statement.</p>","elementId":"72f4acca-fef8-4b36-ab59-437e85df0a32"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Democrats in the lower chamber also released their own legislation that would keep the government funded until the end of October.</p>","elementId":"f34ae3c5-900f-4663-a32a-42b32a85bf81"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>For their part, <strong>GOP lawmakers only need a simple majority for their CR to advance to the Senate</strong>, where Democrats can use the filibuster to tank it if it lacks 60 votes. <strong>However, that requires Schumer to ensure that moderate members of his party don&rsquo;t end up voting for the legislation if the threat of a shutdown inches closer.</strong></p>","elementId":"20373d93-8515-43c2-93d1-8889513f09ed"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>This is the problem the top Democrat faced the last time this happened, back in March, when Schumer ended up voting for the Republican-written bill that kept federal agencies funded. At the time, Schumer faced immense pressure from his Democratic colleagues in the House to push back, but ultimately believed a shutdown would carry &ldquo;consequences for America that are much, much worse&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"18b5d781-ac0e-4756-9ba7-15ec73492c92"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758283703000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"13.08&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758285656000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"13.40&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758285656000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"13.40&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"13.40","title":"Congress prepares to vote of funding bills to avert government shutdown","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd45f08f08895801e08688","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The president doesn&rsquo;t have any public events scheduled today, according to the White House.</p>","elementId":"aecef2f4-bec2-4645-8b20-602e26a19b37"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>He&rsquo;s due to sign executive orders at 3pm EST, but that is closed press for the time being. We&rsquo;ll let you know if that opens up.</p>","elementId":"d779a983-b85e-484f-adf3-f56f97a7ea54"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>In less than an hour, Trump is expected to have a call with Chinese leader Xi Jinping.</strong> It&rsquo;s the first time the pair have spoken since June, and Trump said to reporters yesterday that they&rsquo;ll focus on TikTok and trade on their call. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re very close on all of it,&rdquo; the president added.</p>","elementId":"e520dc55-37dc-40fe-99a2-49d223a785c5"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>When we have a readout we&rsquo;ll make sure to bring you the latest lines.</p>","elementId":"7b2508e2-d963-4221-b34e-d650688370a5"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758283248000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"13.00&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758283764000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"13.09&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758283700000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"13.08&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"13.08","title":"Trump expected to focus on TikTok and trade in call with Xi Jinping","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd2da28f08895801e084a6","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Kamala Harris has revealed she was left &ldquo;angry and disappointed&rdquo; when Joe Biden called her hours before her US presidential debate with <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> to suggest powerful associates of Biden&rsquo;s brother refused to support her.</strong></p>","elementId":"ca09adea-aacd-4d3f-bde2-32fbf869b26b"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The former vice-president and Democratic nominee recounts the episode &ndash; and other criticisms of Biden &ndash; in her campaign memoir 107 Days, obtained by the Guardian before its publication next week.</p>","elementId":"5f8904b4-eb1b-454b-89d4-92c7996595ba"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Harris writes that in September she was in a hotel room in Philadelphia, poised to take on Trump in a potentially decisive debate, when the then president called to wish her good luck &ndash; and to ask if she would be back in Philadelphia before the election.</p>","elementId":"dbeeb36c-c258-483e-8c5e-9ae081c4cf8d"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Harris wondered why Biden would ask such a non sequitur. According to the book, he told her: &ldquo;My brother called. He&rsquo;s been talking to a group of real power brokers in Philly.&rdquo; He offered several names and asked if Harris knew them. She did not.</p>","elementId":"078001ba-6120-4e4d-addc-528c3c862711"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Harris writes: &ldquo;Then he got to his point. His brother had told him that those guys were not going to support me because I&rsquo;d been saying bad things about him. He wasn&rsquo;t inclined to believe it, he claimed, but he thought I should know in case my team had been encouraging me to put daylight between the two of us.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"4f0c440e-d382-44af-8630-0cf25737a2a5"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The then vice-president asked Biden to put the group in touch with her directly. But he was not done with the call. He sought to rewrite the history of his own disastrous debate performance against Trump three months earlier.</p>","elementId":"8431b627-8aaf-466b-b665-364f6ad39418"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"&lsquo;Angry and disappointed&rsquo;: Kamala Harris critical of Joe Biden in new book","elementId":"9fe3f9ad-7656-45d7-9b8d-2cfd12dc94ca","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/19/angry-and-disappointed-kamala-harris-critical-of-joe-biden-in-new-book"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758277026000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"11.17&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758283700000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"13.08&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758280903000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"12.21&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"12.21","title":"Kamala Harris critical of Joe Biden in new book: &lsquo;angry and disappointed&rsquo;","contributors":[{"name":"David Smith","imageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/25/David_Smith.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=96a67219643c746ee727051afdf7395a","largeImageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/25/David_Smith.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=8e678f807c7b80aae11b03fbc186f49b"}],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd2c378f0816a4522bde6b","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><strong>Washington DC&rsquo;s long-serving delegate Eleanor Holmes Norton is under renewed pressure to step down after a city council member announced on Thursday he would challenge her in next year&rsquo;s election, saying the federal district needs its &ldquo;strongest fighters&rdquo; as it faces unprecedented interference from <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump\"'>Donald Trump</a> and the Republican party.</strong></p>","elementId":"c5ff044c-4d6f-477e-8e65-4ad263caa74c"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Robert White&rsquo;s decision to jump into the race for the non-voting role in the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/house-of-representatives\"'>House of Representatives</a> comes amid mounting concern over the 88-year-old Norton&rsquo;s ability to continue doing the job at a tense moment for the city.</p>","elementId":"294db24a-5022-4d12-82f4-87a327252e9f"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump in August ordered a temporary federal takeover of the Washington DC police department and dispatched national guard and federal agents onto its streets to fight what he called an &ldquo;out-of-control&rdquo; crime wave, a claim city leaders disputed.</p>","elementId":"cbd7b15a-a4ea-4fb2-9ec5-0b43eb936da0"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p><a href='\"https://x.com/RobertWhite_DC/status/1968762071299838307\"'>In a video</a> announcing his candidacy, White, an at-large council member who made an unsuccessful bid for mayor in 2022, referred to Norton as &ldquo;our lion on the Hill&rdquo; but implied it was time for new leadership.</p>","elementId":"954d5b97-42d2-4f24-aa4e-648b91fb8da9"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;I have never seen my city more vulnerable than we are right now, and in this entire Congress, there is one person whose job it is to protect and stand up for our residents, and we need our strongest fighters,&rdquo; said White. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m ready to take this torch.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"d02acf21-ac1a-47f6-95cb-51e54610c7ef"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The announcement comes days after Donna Brazile, a former chief of staff to Norton who rose to serve as interim chair of the Democratic National Committee, said that she should not seek a 19th term in the office she has held since 1991.</p>","elementId":"cf4a610f-8e90-420d-9a6d-f0068754c908"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Though not allowed to cast votes in the House, Norton was known as a tenacious advocate for the rights of the federal district, but has appeared subdued in recent years.</p>","elementId":"7e44b95f-324d-4e26-a910-671d6bd9fb32"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>She had been pictured requiring the help of an aide at public appearances, and reads haltingly from prepared remarks at committee appearances, even when the topic concerns contentious proposals to change Washington DC&rsquo;s laws.</p>","elementId":"05b0bc61-5f24-481d-933b-6a475fb91fd5"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":true,"summary":false},"blockCreatedOn":1758276663000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"11.11&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758277618000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"11.26&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758277618000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"11.26&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"11.26","title":"DC Democrat challenges long-serving House delegate amid age concerns","contributors":[{"name":"Chris Stein","imageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/25/Chris_Stein.jpg?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=816e271eec6598b9b8784a001bf54a35","largeImageUrl":"https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/25/Chris_Stein.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=5829f7087d8175b610aa897c2d8ded33"}],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"},{"id":"68cd235f8f08895801e08429","elements":[{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Hello and welcome to the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/us-politics\"'>US politics</a> live blog. I&rsquo;m Tom Ambrose and I will be bringing you the latest news lines over the next few hours.</p>","elementId":"74499bac-fbfd-4327-a73c-27da6b63e026"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>We start with news that <strong>Donald Trump suggested on Thursday that TV networks which cover him &ldquo;negatively&rdquo; could be punished by the government after his celebration of ABC suspending late-night host <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/jimmy-kimmel\"'>Jimmy Kimmel</a></strong>.</p>","elementId":"4b7d2189-c38d-4442-8769-d769c1271c21"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>On Air Force One, the president spoke to reporters on his flight back to the US from his state visit to the UK. The president said major US networks were &ldquo;97% against me&rdquo;, though he did not offer evidence to prove this figure or detail how this conclusion was evaluated. He said he read the statistic &ldquo;someplace&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"23bbafdc-00c8-49e2-9685-0b2961dc1a00"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Again, 97% negative, and yet I won easily. I won all seven swing states,&rdquo; Trump said. &ldquo;They give me only bad press. I mean they&rsquo;re getting a license. I would think maybe their licenses should be taken away.&rdquo;</p>","elementId":"d6a8e8e1-8ac8-4430-8b49-e367398cbf13"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>The president&rsquo;s claim that US TV networks need to be licensed by the government to operate is, however, incorrect. While local TV stations do require a license from the Federal Communications Commission, the FCC says clearly <a href='\"https://www.fcc.gov/media/radio/public-and-broadcasting\"'>on its website</a> that it does &ldquo;not license TV or radio networks (such as CBS, NBC, ABC or Fox)&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"e8d3e196-a65b-4beb-a507-fab0c21815ea"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Trump supported ABC&rsquo;s decision to suspend Jimmy Kimmel&rsquo;s late-night show, saying that the comedian was &ldquo;not a talented person&rdquo; who &ldquo;had very bad ratings&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"9e425bab-2bb3-4220-b209-6777ea90742e"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>&ldquo;Well, Jimmy Kimmel was fired because he had bad ratings more than anything else, and he said a horrible thing about a great gentleman known as Charlie Kirk,&rdquo; Trump told reporters during his state visit to the United Kingdom, adding &ldquo;they should have fired him a long time ago&rdquo;.</p>","elementId":"136dd9c9-04c2-42c7-9035-8fd956d48b2c"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>According to Nielsen ratings as reported by <a href='\"https://latenighter.com/news/ratings/late-night-tv-ratings-q2-2025/\"'>LateNighter</a>, although Stephen Colbert&rsquo;s Late Show leads the time slot in total viewers with 2.42 million, Kimmel&rsquo;s show averaged 1.77 million viewers in the second quarter of 2025 and edged out Colbert in the key 18-49 demographic.</p>","elementId":"ebbd4653-9ba7-4dd9-9289-c127310f7e4a"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>However, there was an <a href='\"https://ustvdb.com/networks/abc/shows/jimmy-kimmel-live/\"'>11% drop-off</a> in his show&rsquo;s viewership the last month. Kimmel also has <a href='\"https://www.youtube.com/@JimmyKimmelLive\"'>over 20 million subscribers</a> on YouTube.</p>","elementId":"261b1707-381f-4ca5-a880-7e7aac4044ed"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>Read the full story here:</p>","elementId":"4083c467-537a-434e-9ad9-041ae22233c7"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.RichLinkBlockElement","prefix":"Related: ","text":"Trump suggests punishing TV networks for &lsquo;negative&rsquo; coverage amid outrage over Kimmel suspension","elementId":"9cb47ef6-4d47-4b62-9a6b-b2ecceed0665","role":"thumbnail","url":"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/jimmy-kimmel-show-trump"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<p>In other developments:</p>","elementId":"f0a8df47-fb49-423c-94da-8a93d129e002"},{"_type":"model.dotcomrendering.pageElements.TextBlockElement","html":"<ul>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Barack Obama condemned what he called a &ldquo;dangerous&rdquo; escalation by the Trump administration over the suspension of Jimmy Kimmel&rsquo;s show.</strong> &ldquo;After years of complaining about cancel culture, the current administration has taken it to a new and dangerous level by routinely threatening regulatory action against media companies unless they muzzle or fire reporters and commentators it doesn&rsquo;t like,&rdquo; Obama <a href='\"https://x.com/BarackObama/status/1968679167286763678\"'>wrote on X</a>.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>The indefinite suspension of <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/jimmy-kimmel\"'>Jimmy Kimmel&rsquo;s</a> late-night show has prompted impassioned calls for a boycott against Disney, ABC&rsquo;s parent company, and other major media conglomerates that have refused to air Kimmel&rsquo;s show.</strong> Boycott calls grew after ABC announced it would <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/jimmy-kimmel-suspended-trump\"'>indefinitely suspend </a>the popular show following complaints from the Federal Communications Commission chair, Brendan Carr.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong><a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/kamala-harris\"'>Kamala Harris</a> watched mortified as her running mate, <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/tim-walz\"'>Tim Walz</a>, fell into <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/jd-vance\"'>JD Vance</a>&rsquo;s trap in last year&rsquo;s vice-presidential debate and &ldquo;fumbled&rdquo; a crucial answer, she writes in a campaign memoir.</strong> The former Democratic presidential nominee also admits that Walz had <a href='\"https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2025/09/kamala-harris-running-mate-pete-buttigieg/684249/\"'>not been her first choice</a> for vice-president in her book 107 Days, obtained by the Guardian ahead of its publication next week.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>The Trump administration asked the US supreme court to allow it to fire the <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/business/federal-reserve\"'>Federal Reserve</a> governor <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/aug/26/who-is-lisa-cook-federal-reserve-governor\"'>Lisa Cook</a>, as it continues its extraordinary attack on the central bank&rsquo;s independence.</strong> In a filing on Thursday, Donald Trump&rsquo;s officials requested an emergency order to remove Cook from the Fed&rsquo;s board of governors, after an appeals court refused to go along with efforts to oust her.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Donald Trump accused <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/world/vladimir-putin\"'>Vladimir Putin</a> of letting him down in a joint press conference with Keir Starmer during which the US president piled criticism on his Russian counterpart.</strong> Trump said he had hoped to broker a peace deal between Russia and <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/world/ukraine\"'>Ukraine</a> soon after entering office, but that Putin&rsquo;s actions had prevented him from doing so.</p></li>\n <li>\n<p><strong>Erika Kirk, the widow of Charlie Kirk, has been appointed as the new CEO and chair of the board for Turning Point USA.</strong> The organization announced on Thursday that the late CEO and co-founder of Turning Point USA, who was <a href='\"https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/charlie-kirk-shooting\"'>shot and killed</a> at an event last week, had previously expressed that he would want his wife to lead in the event of his death.</p></li>\n</ul>","elementId":"eeba2771-049a-4da2-add1-f3abe0f39f48"}],"attributes":{"pinned":false,"keyEvent":false,"summary":true},"blockCreatedOn":1758275892000,"blockCreatedOnDisplay":"10.58&nbsp;BST","blockLastUpdated":1758274888000,"blockLastUpdatedDisplay":"10.41&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublished":1758275892000,"blockFirstPublishedDisplay":"10.58&nbsp;BST","blockFirstPublishedDisplayNoTimezone":"10.58","title":"Opening summary","contributors":[],"primaryDateLine":"Fri 19 Sep 2025 18.04 BST","secondaryDateLine":"First published on Fri 19 Sep 2025 10.58 BST"}],"filterKeyEvents":false,"id":"key-events-carousel-mobile","absoluteServerTimes":false,"renderingTarget":"Web"}"&gt;<span><p>Key events</p></span><gu-island><p><label>Show key events only<p><span>Please turn on JavaScript to use this feature</span></p></label></p></gu-island><article><header><div><p><span>Carter Sherman</span></p></div></header><p>In a surprise move, the influential committee that advises the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) on vaccine policy <strong>decided Friday morning to table a planned vote on whether to immunize all newborns against hepatitis B</strong>, an incurable infection that can lead to liver disease and death.</p><p>The CDC has recommended that all US-born babies receive the first of three shots against hepatitis B shortly after birth for more than 30 years. Over that time frame, the lethal illness has virtually vanished among American children. Yet the panel, the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (ACIP), had intended to vote on recommending whether to delay the first shot until a child is at least a month old, as long as the child&rsquo;s mother does not have hepatitis B.</p><p>While parents could still choose to get their baby vaccinated at birth, the committee&rsquo;s recommendations typically determine which vaccines are provided free of charge through the US government, shape state and local laws around vaccine requirements, and influence which vaccines health insurers tend to cover.</p><p>But rather than proceeding, the vote over hepatitis B descended into confusion, as some members pointed out inconsistencies in the wording of the vote and suggested that they would prefer to recommend delaying the hepatitis B vaccine until even later in a child&rsquo;s life. <strong>Although voting had begun, the members ultimately decided to table the vote until at least their next meeting.</strong></p><p>The committee&rsquo;s two-day meeting, which started on Thursday, has already sparked intense debate. After Robert F Kennedy took control of the Department of Health and Human Services, he fired the previous iteration of the committee and <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/cdc-vaccine-committee">replaced it with his own handpicked advisers</a>. Some of whom have little to no documented experience with vaccines, while others have criticized them.</p><p><strong>The members&rsquo; lack of experience with the panel&rsquo;s workings became evident on Thursday, when some of its members seemed unsure of what they were voting on and were unfamiliar with Vaccines for Children, a US government program that provides free vaccines to low-income children. </strong></p><p>The panel did, however, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/cdc-vaccine-policy">vote to recommend</a> that children receive multiple vaccines against mumps, measles, rubella and varicella &ndash; or chicken pox &ndash; rather than a combined vaccine, as was previously recommended. Parents could already decide to give their children separate vaccines, and many do.</p><p>On Thursday, the panel had voted to let Vaccines for Children continue providing coverage for the combined vaccine if parents want it. On Friday morning, however, the panel reversed that decision and instead voted to recommend that Vaccines for Children no longer do so.</p></article><article><header><div><p><span>Julius Constantine Motal</span></p></div></header><p><strong>Photos: mass arrests outside immigration court in New York</strong></p><p>Per that last post, here are some of the images of local elected officials and immigration rights activists who protested outside the Jacob K Javits Federal Building, New York&rsquo;s largest federal immigration court, on Thursday.</p><figure><figcaption><span>Detained immigration activists stand in line to be loaded into a police bus.</span> Photograph: Julius Constantine Motal/The Guardian</figcaption></figure><figure><div><picture><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d62b431de260e1e0f687a893bc30997bc5f8582b/0_0_6194_4129/master/6194.jpg?width=700&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d62b431de260e1e0f687a893bc30997bc5f8582b/0_0_6194_4129/master/6194.jpg?width=700&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d62b431de260e1e0f687a893bc30997bc5f8582b/0_0_6194_4129/master/6194.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=2&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><source srcset="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d62b431de260e1e0f687a893bc30997bc5f8582b/0_0_6194_4129/master/6194.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"><img alt="police handcuff a man and a woman" src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/d62b431de260e1e0f687a893bc30997bc5f8582b/0_0_6194_4129/master/6194.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none" width="465" height="309.9749757830158"></source></source></source></source></picture></div><figcaption><span>Federal police officers arrest comptroller Brad Lander alongside ten other local elected officials on the 10th floor of the Jacob K Javits Federal Building.</span> Photograph: Julius Constantine Motal/The Guardian</figcaption></figure><figure><figcaption><span>Immigration activists chant as police arrest people.</span> Photograph: Julius Constantine Motal/The Guardian</figcaption></figure><p>See more images in our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/gallery/2025/sep/19/arrests-immigration-court-new-york-in-pictures">gallery here</a>.</p></article><article><header></header><p>Yesterday, New York lawmakers, immigrants&rsquo; rights activists and religious leaders were arrested at protests both inside and outside the complex in lower Manhattan where federal officials have been routinely detaining immigrants amid the Trump administration&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/usimmigration">anti-immigration agenda</a>.</p><p>Eleven elected New York officials tried to gain access to an Ice detention facility, while immigration activists tried to block vans carrying detained migrants.</p><p>Here&rsquo;s the story in pictures:</p><figure><gu-island></gu-island></figure></article><article><header><h2>Judge strikes Trump's $15bn lawsuit against New York Times over its content</h2></header><p>A federal judge has struck Donald Trump&rsquo;s $15bn defamation lawsuit against the New York Times over its content.</p><p>US district judge Steven Merryday said Trump violated a federal procedural rule requiring a short and plain statement of why he deserves relief, and that <strong>a complaint is not &ldquo;a public forum for vituperation and invective&rdquo; or &ldquo;a protected platform to rage against an adversary&rdquo;</strong>.</p><p>Merryday gave Trump 28 days to file an amended complaint.</p></article><article><header><h2>House passes bipartisan resolution honoring Charlie Kirk</h2><div><p><span>Chris Stein</span></p></div></header><p>A resolution honoring murdered conservative activist Charlie Kirk passed the House of Representatives with bipartisan support on Friday, but only after <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/19/house-resolution-charlie-kirk">causing considerable consternation</a> among Democrats.</p><p>All Republicans in attendance voted in favor of <a href="https://www.congress.gov/bill/119th-congress/house-resolution/719/text">the resolution</a>, which describes Kirk as &ldquo;a courageous American patriot, whose life was tragically and unjustly cut short in an act of political violence&rdquo;.</p><p>Ninety five Democrats supported the resolution, while 58 opposed it. Thirty eight voted present, and 22 did not vote.</p><p>Kirk <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/12/charlie-kirk-young-conservatives-social-media">was instrumental</a> in building support for Donald Trump and conservative causes among younger voters, often by using <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/11/charlie-kirk-quotes-beliefs">racist and discriminatory language</a> and arguments.</p><p>Several Democrats who opposed the resolution said they <strong>condemned his murder, but could not support a figure who used his speech</strong>.</p><p>&ldquo;<strong>We should be clear about who Charlie Kirk was</strong>: a man who believed that the Civil Rights Act that granted Black Americans the right to vote was a &lsquo;mistake&rsquo;, who after the violent attack on Paul Pelosi claimed that &lsquo;some amazing patriot out there&rsquo; should bail out his assailant, and accused Jews of controlling &lsquo;not just the colleges &ndash; it&rsquo;s the nonprofits, it&rsquo;s the movies, it&rsquo;s Hollywood, it&rsquo;s all of it,&rsquo;&rdquo; said New York&rsquo;s Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, who voted no.</p><p>She went on: &ldquo;His rhetoric and beliefs were ignorant and sought to disenfranchise millions of Americans &ndash; far from &lsquo;working tirelessly to promote unity&rsquo; as asserted by the majority in this resolution.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;I cannot vote yes on this resolution because <strong>it grossly misrepresents Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s methods, views, and beliefs while citing Christian nationalist language</strong>. I will always condemn heinous acts of violence, but this resolution <strong>ignores the false and hateful rhetoric that was too often present in his debate</strong>s,&rdquo; said Colorado&rsquo;s Diana DeGette, who voted present.</p><p>Maryland&rsquo;s Jamie Raskin said he voted yes on the measure because it &ldquo;repeatedly condemns all political violence, extremism and hatred in unequivocal terms&rdquo;, while adding: &ldquo;We should overlook whatever surplus verbiage is contained in this resolution designed to make the vote difficult for Democrats. We cannot fall for that obvious political trap and should rise above it.&rdquo;</p><p>Congressman Dan Goldman, who voted present said: &ldquo;I condemn political violence of any kind, including the horrific assassination of Mr Kirk. I cannot vote no on a resolution that condemns political violence. I do not support - and indeed <strong>condemn in the strongest possible terms - many of the hateful views Mr Kirk espoused</strong>. <strong>I cannot vote yes on a resolution that celebrates those views</strong>.&rdquo;</p></article><article><header></header><p>Reuters is reporting that a federal judge has struck Donald Trump&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/16/donald-trump-says-he-is-suing-new-york-times-15bn-lawsuit-against-newspaper-ntwnfb">$15bn lawsuit against the New York Times</a>. I&rsquo;ll bring you more on this as we get it.</p></article><article><header><h2>Trump asks supreme court to enforce passport policy targeting transgender people</h2></header><p>Donald Trump&rsquo;s administration asked the supreme court on Friday to intervene in a bid to refuse to issue passports to transgender and nonbinary Americans that reflect their gender identities.</p><p>Reuters reports that the justice department filed an emergency request to lift a federal judge&rsquo;s injunction barring the state department from enforcing a policy it adopted at Trump&rsquo;s direction.</p><p>The dispute is one of several concerning an executive order Trump signed after returning to office on 20 January directing the government to recognize only two biologically distinct sexes, male and female.</p></article><article><header><div><p><span>Oliver Laughland</span></p></div></header><p><em>in Chicago </em></p><p>Federal law enforcement officials in Chicago have used tear gas and pepper balls in an attempt to <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/oliverlaughland.bsky.social/post/3lz6r3ihe322g">disperse a group of around 100 protesters</a> who assembled in the early hours of Friday morning at an Ice facility in the suburbs.</p><p>Protesters, who remained peaceful throughout had attempted to block a number of large SUVs entering the facility throughout the morning at an Ice detention and operations facility in Broadview.</p><p>At least two protesters were arrested by masked agents in a number of small skirmishes, which escalated after agents fired volleys of pepper balls and multiple canisters of tear gas following orders to disperse. Masked agents shoved protesters and arrested one using zip ties as two large SUVs exited the building, which is surrounded by razor wire.</p><p>Protesters chanted the name of the Silverio Villegas Gonz&aacute;lez, a 38 year-old father of two who was fatally shot by an immigration officer during a traffic stop in the Chicago area last Friday. Earlier in the morning agents arrested another protester after a group of agents swarmed out from the facility to escorting another vehicle. The protester was dragged inside by two masked agents.</p></article><article><header></header><p>The background on that is a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/17/trump-trans-passport-ban-boston-judge">federal judge in Boston ruled back in June</a> that <strong>transgender and intersex people could obtain passports that align with their gender identity</strong>, in a rebuke to a January executive order from Donald Trump that said passports must conform to the sex citizens were assigned at birth.</p><p>US district judge Julia Kobick issued <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.mad.280559/gov.uscourts.mad.280559.115.0.pdf">a preliminary injunction</a> that expanded an earlier order she issued in April that had stopped the US state department from enforcing the policy in the case of six people, after finding the order was probably unconstitutional.</p><p>Her June order meant that all trans citizens would be able to update their gender markers on their passports while the case against Trump&rsquo;s order proceeds.</p><p>After the president signed <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/defending-women-from-gender-ideology-extremism-and-restoring-biological-truth-to-the-federal-government/">an executive order</a> on the first day of his term in January, Defending Women from Gender Ideology Extremism and Restoring Biological Truth to the Federal Government, the US state department <a href="https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/passports/passport-help/sex-marker.html">announced</a> that it would &ldquo;no longer issue US passports or Consular Reports of Birth Abroad (CRBAs) with an X marker. We will only issue passports with an M or F sex marker that match the customer&rsquo;s biological sex at birth.&rdquo;</p></article><article><header></header><p>We&rsquo;re seeing a line on the wires from Reuters that the Trump administration has asked the supreme court to intervene after a <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jun/17/trump-trans-passport-ban-boston-judge">lower court required the state department</a> to issue passports that reflect an individual&rsquo;s gender identity. I&rsquo;ll bring you more on this as it comes through.</p></article><article><header><h2>Trump says he and China's Xi made progress on TikTok and trade, and will meet soon</h2></header><p>Donald Trump and Xi Jinping &ldquo;made progress on many very important issues&rdquo; during their call this morning, according to the US president, including on trade, fentanyl, Russia&rsquo;s war in Ukraine, and the TikTok deal.</p><p>Trump also said he and Xi would have a face-to-face meeting at the APEC summit in South Korea next month, he would travel to China &ldquo;in the early part of next year&rdquo; and Xi would also come to the US at a later date.</p><p>The statement did not spell out the terms of an agreement between the leaders on TikTok, only that Trump &ldquo;appreciates the TikTok approval&rdquo;.</p><p>Trump just posted on his Truth Social platform:</p><blockquote><p><svg><path></path></svg>I just completed a very productive call with President Xi of China. We made progress on many very important issues including Trade, Fentanyl, the need to bring the War between Russia and Ukraine to an end, and the approval of the TikTok Deal. I also agreed with President Xi that we would meet at the APEC Summit in South Korea, that I would go to China in the early part of next year, and that President Xi would, likewise, come to the United States at an appropriate time. The call was a very good one, we will be speaking again by phone, appreciate the TikTok approval, and both look forward to meeting at APEC!</p></blockquote></article><article><header></header><p><strong>Per my last post, here&rsquo;s some helpful context on the next steps for the CR.</strong></p><p><strong>Next week, lawmakers will be on a week-long recess</strong>. So, to avoid the shutdown stress that has been customary when it comes to stopgap spending bills, congressional <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/republicans">Republicans</a> are hoping that it passes the Senate today.</p><p>Here&rsquo;s why that might be unlikely.</p><p>They&rsquo;ll need <strong>at least seven Senate Democrats</strong> to vote yes on this funding extension as it stands. So far, Democrats in both chambers argue that they had no input on the GOP-written CR, and it lacks several health care provisions that, they say, are non-negotiable. In response, Democrats have even released their own version of the stopgap bill, which also includes measures to inhibit <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> from clawing back congressionally approriated funds.</p><p><strong>Senate minority leader Chuck Schumer is under pressure from House Democrats to make sure that their Senate counterparts don&rsquo;t cross the aisle</strong>, like what happpened in March. They want to call Republicans&rsquo; bluff and force them to shoulder the blame for a possible shutdown if they don&rsquo;t get any say in the CR.</p><p>Both versions of the short-term funding bill are likely to fail on the Senate floor on Friday, as they&rsquo;ll need 60 votes to overcome the filibuster. <strong>That means a vote on any revised legislation might not happen until 29 September &ndash;&nbsp;perilously close to a shutdown that would begin on 1 October. </strong></p></article><article><header><h2>House passes stopgap funding bill to avert government shutdown</h2></header><p>The US House passed a stopgap funding bill, known as a &lsquo;continuing resolution&rsquo; (CR) &ndash; which would keep the government funded until 21 November.</p><p>Lawmakers in the lower chamber passed the bill 217-212, with two <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/republicans">Republicans</a> voting against it, and one Democrat &ndash;&nbsp;congressman Jared Golden of Maine &ndash; voting for it.</p><p>The CR now advances to the Senate, where it needs 60 votes to overcome a filibuster.</p><p>A reminder, that a government funding expires at the end of the month if lawmakers can&rsquo;t pass this short-term solution.</p></article><article><header></header><p>According to the White House press pool <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> actually began his call with Xi Jinping <strong>at 8am EST today</strong> A White House official declined to say whether the call had concluded, but said <strong>updates about the conversation will be shared by the president on Truth Social</strong>.</p></article><article><header></header><p>Per my last post, the American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) responded to the Thursday&rsquo;s vaccine advisory panel meeting <a href="https://www.aap.org/en/news-room/news-releases/aap/2025/aap-continues-to-support-access-to-routine-immunizations-for-every-child-in-every-community/">with a statement</a> that said the committee (which health secretary <strong>Robert F Kennedy Jr</strong> completely replaced earlier this year) <strong>&ldquo;promoted false claims and misguided information about vaccines as part of an unprecedented effort to limit access to routine childhood immunizations and sow fear and mistrust in vaccines&rdquo;</strong>.</p><p>The academy also reshared their guidance for vaccines, which includes &ldquo;giving newborns a dose of the hepatitis B vaccine within 24 hours of birth&rdquo; and a combination MMRV vaccine should &ldquo;remain an option&rdquo; for families. The AAP advises that children receive the shot &ldquo;at 1 year and again at 4-6 years&rdquo;.</p></article><article><header></header><p><strong>We&rsquo;ll get more from the second day of the advisory committee on immunization practices (ACIP) later</strong>. A reminder that on Thursday <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/18/cdc-vaccine-policy">the panel voted </a>on recommending that children receive multiple vaccines to protect against measles, mumps, rubella and chickenpox (MMRV), instead of a single vaccine that can protect against all four diseases.</p><p>As my colleague, Carter Sherman, reports, the committee is scheduled to focus on Covid vaccines today. It will also hold two votes on the recommended timing of the vaccine for hepatitis B &ndash; an incurable infection that can lead to liver disease and death.</p><p>The committee was originally scheduled to vote on the hepatitis B vaccine on Wednesday, but delayed the vote after the committee chair, Martin Kulldorff, noticed &ldquo;slight discrepancies&rdquo; in the wording of the planned votes.</p></article><article><header><h2>Following Kirk shooting, new poll shows drop in positive direction of the country among Republicans</h2></header><p>A new <a href="https://apnorc.org/projects/pessimism-about-the-direction-of-the-country-is-growing-among-republicans/">Associated Press-NORC poll</a> shows that there has been a significant drop, among Republicans, that the country is heading in a positive direction.</p><p><strong>51% of <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/republicans">Republicans</a> said the country is heading in the wrong direction, in a poll conducted between 11 and 15 September.</strong> A 22-point increase from the 29% of Republicans who expressed the same feeling in June of this year.</p><p>For Democrats, 92% say the country is heading in the wrong direction &ndash; a number that&rsquo;s stayed consistent since <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> returned to the White House for a second term.</p><p>More broadly, 39% of adults approve of the way Trump is handing his job as president, while 60% disapprove.</p></article><gu-island></gu-island></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2025/03/25/Carter_Sherman.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=f0bbdaf7f21e3550fad202d9bbe18c40"></p><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2025/03/25/Julius_Motal.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=940a21154206756878d493c2b648768c"></p><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/bb030034fe47cfcd5589be5f16bc2b1249fadbcf/0_0_6720_4480/master/6720.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"></p><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/media/5ca554d90e1136f9ad66b16d89e448f30f5a5a95/0_0_6720_4480/master/6720.jpg?width=465&amp;dpr=1&amp;s=none&amp;crop=none"></p><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2023/05/25/Chris_Stein.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=5829f7087d8175b610aa897c2d8ded33"></p><p><img src="https://i.guim.co.uk/img/uploads/2018/04/05/Oliver_Laughland_v4.png?width=300&amp;quality=85&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=max&amp;s=705ec17b7407c5a776aff698afa42877"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I wonder how trump would feel about pictures of him tied up in the back of a pick up truck.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl0tew/the_president_suggests_broadcasters_could_be/nf1wgcy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>The president said major US networks were ‘97% against me’ </p></blockquote><p>Yeah, the problem definitely isn&#39;t you, it&#39;s them.</p><p>&quot;Everybody hates me. Everyone is an asshole.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl0tew/the_president_suggests_broadcasters_could_be/nf1w4z5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is terrifying. Criticism is part of the job of the press, not a crime</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nl0tew/the_president_suggests_broadcasters_could_be/nf1yq8h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:49:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/18/jimmy-kimmel-charlie-kirk-fcc-carr.html</link><title>FCC Chair Carr says ‘we’re not done yet’ after Jimmy Kimmel suspension by ABC (cnbc.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nknn3h/fcc_chair_carr_says_were_not_done_yet_after_jimmy/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nknn3h/fcc_chair_carr_says_were_not_done_yet_after_jimmy/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nknn3h/fcc_chair_carr_says_were_not_done_yet_after_jimmy/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108200858-1758216183811-gettyimages-2215659003-fcc_approps221_052125.jpeg?v=1758219907&w=1920&h=1080' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><div><p><a href="https://www.fcc.gov/">Federal Communications Commission</a> Chairman <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/06/cnbc-transcript-exclusive-fcc-commissioner-president-elect-trumps-pick-for-fcc-chairman-brendan-carr-speaks-with-cnbcs-squawk-on-the-street-today.html">Brendan Carr</a> said Thursday that ABC late-night host <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/17/charlie-kirk-jimmy-kimmel-abc-disney.html">Jimmy Kimmel</a> appeared to "mislead" the American public about facts regarding conservative activist <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/10/charlie-kirk-uvu-shooting-utah.html">Charlie Kirk</a>'s killing in the days leading up to his show's suspension.</p><p>Carr also told CNBC's "<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/squawk-on-the-street/">Squawk on the Street</a>" that "we're not done yet" with the changes in "the media ecosystem" that are consequences of President <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a>'s election last fall.</p><p>ABC on Wednesday night said it was pulling "Jimmy Kimmel Live!" off the air "indefinitely" because of the host's comments, which linked Kirk's alleged killer, Tyler Robinson, to Trump's "Make America Great Again" movement.</p><p>"The issue that arose here, where lots and lots of people were upset, was not a joke," Carr said Thursday on CNBC.</p></div><div><p>"It was not making fun," said Carr, who hours before Kimmel's show was pulled off the air suggested the FCC might take action against ABC and its parent company, <span><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/DIS/">Disney</a></span>.</p><p>"It was appearing to directly mislead the American public about a significant fact<strong>&nbsp;</strong>that probably one of the most significant political events we've had in a long time, for the most significant political assassination we've seen in a long time," he said.</p><p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/16/charlie-kirk-tyler-robinson-charges.html">Utah court documents</a> filed Tuesday in connection with the murder charge against Robinson say his mother told investigators, "Over the last year or so, her son had become more political and had started to lean more to the left, becoming more pro gay and trans-rights oriented."</p><p>Those documents also say that when Robinson was asked why he killed Kirk, "Robinson explained there is too much evil, and [Kirk] spreads too much hate."</p><p>A day before those documents were filed, Kimmel, in his show's <a href="https://abc.com/episode/e3a6b644-b2c5-4d2b-aa32-2d77ce427304/playlist/PL557226598">opening monologue Monday</a>, said, "The MAGA Gang desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them and doing everything they can to score political points from it."</p><p>Trump on Wednesday evening praised Kimmel's suspension and called on NBC to cancel its own late-night shows, "The Tonight Show Starring Jimmy Fallon," and "Late Night with Seth Meyers."</p><p>"Squawk on the Street" anchor Carl Quintanilla asked Carr about that on Thursday.</p><p>"I asked earlier about Fallon and Seth Meyers, but is the president's view that they should also be taken off the air, shared by the FCC?" Quintanilla asked.</p><p>Carr replied, "I don't speak for the president."</p><p>"Our goal and our obligation here is to make sure that broadcasters are serving the public interest," Carr said.</p></div><div><p>Brendan Carr, commissioner at the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), speaks during the Semafor Innovating to Restore Trust in News Summit in Washington, DC, US, on Thursday, Feb. 27, 2025.</p><p>Kent Nishimura | Bloomberg | Getty Images</p></div><div><p>"And if there's local TV stations that don't think that running that programming does it, then they have every right under the law in their contracts to preempt it. And we'll see how this plays out."</p><p>"I do think that again, we are in the midst of a massive shift in dynamics in the media ecosystem for lots of reasons, again, including the permission structure that President Trump's election has provided," the FCC chief said.</p><p>"And I would simply say we're not done yet with seeing the consequences of that," he said.</p><p>CNBC anchor David Faber followed up on that.</p><p>"What does that mean when you say you're not done yet?" Faber asked. "Then, I mean, will you only be pleased when none of these comedians have a show on broadcast television?"</p><p>Carr replied, "No, it's not any particular show or any particular person. It's just we're in the midst of a very disruptive moment right now, and I just, frankly, expect that we're going to continue to see changes in the media ecosystem."</p><p>Asked by anchor Jim Cramer if the U.S. government should "have someone who reviews the writers before the host says something," Carr said, "No."</p><p>Speaking in England on Thursday, Trump said Kimmel "said a horrible thing about a great gentleman known as Charlie Kirk, and Jimmy Kimmel is not a talented person."</p><p>"He had very bad ratings, and they should have fired him a long time ago. So, you know, you can call that free speech or not," Trump said. "He was fired for lack of talent."</p><p>Kimmel has not been fired.</p></div><div><p>"Jimmy Kimmel Live!" airs every weeknight at 11:35 p.m. ET and features a diverse lineup of guests that include celebrities, athletes, musical acts, comedians and human interest subjects, along with comedy bits and a house band. </p><p>Randy Holmes | Disney General Entertainment Content | Getty Images</p></div><div><p>The president nominated Carr as FCC chair.</p><p>On Wednesday, before ABC yanked Kimmel's show, Carr called Kimmel's comments "truly sick" and said there was a "strong case" for action against ABC and Disney.</p><p>"This is a very, very serious issue right now for Disney. We can do this the easy way or the hard way," Carr told right-wing commentator Benny Johnson that day. "These companies can find ways to take action on Kimmel, or there is going to be additional work for the FCC ahead."</p><p>"They have a license granted by us at the FCC, and that comes with it an obligation to operate in the public interest," Carr said.</p><p>Hours after Carr's comments were reported by Johnson, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/NXST/">Nexstar Media Group</a> said its <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250917021241/en/Nexstar-ABC-Affiliates-to-Preempt-Jimmy-Kimmel-Live-Indefinitely-Beginning-Tonight">stations that are affiliated with ABC</a> would preempt Kimmel's show "for the foreseeable future" because of Kimmel's remarks.</p><p>Nexstar is seeking regulatory approval from the FCC for its planned <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/business/business-news/nexstar-tegna-merger-local-tv-deal-1236347647/">$6.2 billion merger</a> with <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/TGNA/">Tegna</a></p><p>About 10% of ABC affiliates are owned by Nexstar.</p><p>House Democratic leaders on Thursday called for Carr's resignation, alleging that he had engaged "in the corrupt abuse of power."</p><p>In a statement, the Democrats accused the FCC chairman of "bullying ABC, the employer of Jimmy Kimmel, and forcing the company to bend the knee to the Trump administration."</p><p>Former President <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/barack-obama/">Barack Obama</a>, in <a href="https://x.com/BarackObama/status/1968679167286763678">a post on X</a> on Thursday, said, "After years of complaining about cancel culture, the current administration has taken it to a new and dangerous level by routinely threatening regulatory action against media companies unless they muzzle or fire reporters and commentators it doesn't like."</p><p>"This is precisely the kind of government coercion that the First Amendment was designed to prevent &mdash; and media companies need to start standing up rather than capitulating to it," Obama wrote.</p><p><em>Comcast is the parent company of NBCUniversal, which owns CNBC. Versant would become the new parent company of CNBC under a planned spinoff.</em></p><p><em>Correction: This article has been updated to correct a quote from David Faber. A previous version inadvertently omitted a word.</em></p></div><div><h2>Don&rsquo;t miss these insights from CNBC PRO</h2></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108200710-17582054731758205470-41704793290-1080pnbcnews.jpg?v=1758205472&amp;w=750&amp;h=422&amp;vtcrop=y"></p><p><img src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108200701-17582046291758204626-41704638815-1080pnbcnews.jpg?v=1758204628&amp;w=750&amp;h=422&amp;vtcrop=y"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Government officials cannot attempt to coerce private parties in order to punish or suppress views that the government disfavors.&quot; -- SCOTUS ruling, 2024</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nknn3h/fcc_chair_carr_says_were_not_done_yet_after_jimmy/nez9864/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/mollybohannon/2023/08/06/elon-musk-promises-to-cover-legal-fees-for-people-fired-over-tweets">https://www.forbes.com/sites/mollybohannon/2023/08/06/elon-musk-promises-to-cover-legal-fees-for-people-fired-over-tweets</a></p><p>Remember that time Elon told everyone he would cover legal fees for people fired over tweets?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nknn3h/fcc_chair_carr_says_were_not_done_yet_after_jimmy/nez97dl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Putin did the same thing early in his career- started canceling all of the comedians that criticized him.  Pure dictator shit.</p><p>Remember when conservative comedians were complaining that cancel culture was &quot;killing comedy&quot;?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nknn3h/fcc_chair_carr_says_were_not_done_yet_after_jimmy/nez81vq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 04:51:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theverge.com/policy/781148/jimmy-kimmel-charlie-kirk-monologue-brendan-carr-censorship-first-amendment</link><title>Yes, Jimmy Kimmel’s suspension was government censorship. (theverge.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkl8b0/yes_jimmy_kimmels_suspension_was_government/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkl8b0/yes_jimmy_kimmels_suspension_was_government/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkl8b0/yes_jimmy_kimmels_suspension_was_government/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/09/257959_jimmy_kimmel_censorship_CVirginia.jpg?quality=90&strip=all&crop=0%2C10.732984293194%2C100%2C78.534031413613&w=1200' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Yesterday, Disney-owned ABC <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/780471/disney-abc-jimmy-kimmel-live-charlie-kirk">suspended <em>Jimmy Kimmel Live</em></a> &ldquo;indefinitely&rdquo; for a comment Kimmel made about the response to Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s death. The response from Republican commentators has been <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/politics-news/maga-reaction-jimmy-kimmel-suspension-1236374491/">predictably gleeful</a>. They&rsquo;ve positioned the suspension as a reversal of &ldquo;cancel culture,&rdquo; a &ldquo;deplatforming&rdquo; that&rsquo;s simply fair retaliation for antagonizing them. &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel does have Free Speech, he is free to speak just not on ABC,&rdquo; posted comedian <a href="https://x.com/w_terrence/status/1968521190693019710">Terrence Kentrell Williams on X</a>.</p><p>This framing is transparently false. ABC&rsquo;s suspension of Kimmel was the result of an explicit threat from President Donald Trump&rsquo;s Federal Communications Commission Chair Brendan Carr, aimed at Disney and companies that worked with it. The move was effective because of the FCC&rsquo;s authority to regulate broadcast TV and, perhaps more importantly, to approve communications mergers in a hyper-consolidated landscape. It was repeating a playbook Carr recently used on Disney&rsquo;s fellow media giant Paramount. And it&rsquo;s an unabashed attempt at the government dictating the speech of private TV networks and entertainers, as objectionable and un-American as a McCarthyist blacklist.</p><p>The starting point of all this is a pretty tame late-night show monologue. On Monday, Kimmel said the following:</p><p>&ldquo;We hit some new lows over the weekend, with the MAGA gang desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them and doing everything they can to score political points from it.&rdquo;</p><p>The line led into a clip from last week in which Trump <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/16/arts/television/late-night-trump-white-house-ballroom.html">responded to Kirk&rsquo;s death</a> by bragging about the new White House ballroom &mdash; &ldquo;he&rsquo;s at the fourth stage of grief: construction,&rdquo; Kimmel quipped.</p><p>Carr and other Republicans loudly interpreted the remark as claiming Tyler Robinson, who&rsquo;s charged with killing Kirk, was part of MAGA. (An <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2025/09/16/us/tyler-robinson-charges.html">indictment released</a> Tuesday says Robinson believed Kirk was spreading &ldquo;hate&rdquo;; at the time of Kimmel&rsquo;s monologue, the evidence was <a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/777313/charlie-kirks-alleged-killer-scratched-bullets-with-a-helldivers-combo-and-a-furry-sex-meme">mostly confusing</a> and speculation was rife.)</p><p>On Wednesday, Carr <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968359685045838041">appeared in high dudgeon</a> for an interview with conservative commentator Benny Johnson. &ldquo;It appears to be some of the sickest conduct possible,&rdquo; Carr intoned over a clip of Kimmel&rsquo;s statement. It was also, he said, legally actionable. Broadcasters &ldquo;have a license granted by us at the FCC, and that comes with an obligation to operate in the public interest,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;We can do this the easy way or the hard way. These companies can find ways to change conduct and take action, frankly, on Kimmel, or there&rsquo;s going to be additional work for the FCC ahead.&rdquo;</p><p>Carr and Johnson walked out the threat a little further. They noted that Disney and ABC aren&rsquo;t issued a central license to broadcast; licenses are granted to individual TV stations, owned in small numbers by Disney but mainly by separate companies that broadcast ABC and other networks&rsquo; programming. &ldquo;FCC regulatory action focuses on these individual stations,&rdquo; Carr noted. &ldquo;The public interest means you can&rsquo;t be running a narrow partisan circus and still meeting your public interest obligations.&rdquo;</p><p>Citing rules against &ldquo;news distortion&rdquo; and &ldquo;broadcast hoaxes,&rdquo; Carr repeated that &ldquo;there&rsquo;s actions we can take on licensed broadcasters. And frankly, I think it&rsquo;s really past time that a lot of these licensed broadcasters themselves push back on Comcast and Disney and say, &lsquo;Listen, we are going to preempt, we are not going to run Kimmel anymore until you straighten this out, because we, a licensed broadcaster, are running the possibility of fines or license revocation from the FCC if we continue to run content that ends up being a pattern of news distortion.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p><p>This is <a href="https://www.theverge.com/24283652/fcc-license-donald-trump-elon-musk-first-amendment-fairness-doctrine-please-vote-decoder">not how any pre-Carr FCC in recent memory</a> (or arguably before that) has defined the &ldquo;public interest&rdquo; requirement. If the issue is a &ldquo;narrow partisan circus,&rdquo; the highly partisan Fox &mdash; whose news division <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/4/18/23688582/fox-dominion-election-defamation-lawsuit-settled-trial-averted">settled a massive defamation suit</a> for lying about voting machine companies in 2023 &mdash; has been a stolid fixture on TV stations across the country for decades. Carr invoked rules against &ldquo;news distortion&rdquo; and &ldquo;broadcast hoaxes,&rdquo; neither of which makes logical sense as a charge against Kimmel. The bar for stripping a license is typically high &mdash; a rare example is <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/1979/12/07/archives/black-group-is-awarded-license-for-television-station-in.html">the 1989 revocation</a> of aggressively pro-segregationist station WLBT, which among other things, blacked out broadcasts involving civil rights.</p><p>Some commentators on the left <em>have </em>pushed for the FCC to do what Carr threatened, just with Fox instead of ABC, particularly <a href="https://prospect.org/blogs-and-newsletters/tap/2023-08-28-will-fox-lose-its-broadcast-license/">after the defamation settlement</a>. But the FCC has never pulled a station&rsquo;s license as a result of this urging, and <a href="https://deadline.com/2025/09/brendan-carr-jimmy-kimmel-public-interest-1236547721/">in 2019 Carr decried</a> even Democratic commissioner Jessica Rosenworcel&rsquo;s suggestion they crack down on TV and radio e-cigarette ads, saying the FCC &ldquo;does not have a roving mandate to police speech in the name of the &lsquo;public interest.&rsquo;&rdquo;</p><p>Carr&rsquo;s statement on Wednesday was unambiguous: ABC-affiliated TV stations needed to stop airing Kimmel&rsquo;s show ASAP, or they could be fined or lose their license. And the stations&rsquo; parent companies were listening. Nexstar, which owns around 200 stations and reaches roughly 39 percent of US households, <a href="https://www.nexstar.tv/nexstar-abc-affiliates-to-preempt-jimmy-kimmel-live-indefinitely-beginning-tonight/">said quickly</a> that it would no longer air <em>Jimmy Kimmel Live</em>. So did <a href="https://sbgi.net/sinclair-says-kimmel-suspension-is-not-enough-calls-on-fcc-and-abc-to-take-additional-action/">fellow giant Sinclair Broadcast Group</a>.</p><p>Those companies, particularly Nexstar, have reasons beyond station licensing to keep Carr happy. Nexstar is pushing for a $6.2 billion merger with broadcaster Tegna that would require the FCC to loosen the rules on TV station consolidation, something CEO Perry Sook <a href="https://www.newscaststudio.com/2025/08/22/nexstar-ceo-perry-sook-defends-6-2b-tegna-acquisition-as-regulatory-shift-creates-opening/">has expressed hope</a> that Trump&rsquo;s &ldquo;deregulatory moment&rdquo; will enable.</p><p>Carr has shown himself willing to slow-walk deals with companies that earn his ire. A merger between Paramount and Skydance was not approved until Paramount subsidiary CBS <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/696422/paramount-settlement-trump-cbs-lawsuit">agreed to pay $16 million</a> to resolve a blatantly frivolous lawsuit filed by Trump. It proceeded on the grounds that Skydance promote a &ldquo;diversity of viewpoints from across the political and ideological spectrum&rdquo; and employ an ombudsman who would &ldquo;receive and evaluate any complaints of bias or other concerns involving CBS.&rdquo; CBS also ended the show of Kimmel&rsquo;s fellow late-night host Stephen Colbert, a decision <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/709544/stephen-colberts-version-of-the-late-show-will-end-next-may">CBS called financial</a> that was nonetheless widely seen as a concession to Trump &mdash; and that was celebrated by Carr.</p><p>The pressure from Carr, Sinclair, and Nexstar quickly reached ABC, which made a terse announcement it had pulled Kimmel&rsquo;s show off the air. Outlets with inside sources have indicated this wasn&rsquo;t because of public outrage or because Kimmel&rsquo;s bosses found the remarks inappropriate &mdash; <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/tv-movies/tv-movie-news/jimmy-kimmel-out-abc-charlie-kirk-comments-1235430078/"><em>Rolling Stone</em> reports</a> that &ldquo;multiple execs felt that Kimmel had not actually said anything over the line.&rdquo; Instead, they were &ldquo;pissing themselves&rdquo; over the threat of Trump administration retaliation, one source said.</p><p>Disney, too, has pressure points beyond broadcast license fines. The FCC chair has previously threatened to investigate it for having (non-&ldquo;ideological,&rdquo; of course) diversity programs. And as <a href="https://www.status.news/p/jimmy-kimmel-pulled-fcc-decision">Oliver Darcy of <em>Status</em> notes</a>, the company is &ldquo;working to complete a high-stakes deal with the NFL, one that is crucial to the future of ESPN&rdquo; and <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/litigation/espn-nfl-deal-faces-regulatory-hurdles-2025-08-07/">requires regulatory approval</a> from the Department of Justice. Trump <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/justice-department/attorney-general-pam-bondi-doj-hate-speech-rcna231633">incidentally told</a> an ABC journalist this week that the DOJ might &ldquo;come after ABC&rdquo; for &ldquo;hate&rdquo; offenses, responding to questions about a &ldquo;hate speech&rdquo; crackdown declared by Attorney General Pam Bondi after Kirk&rsquo;s death.</p><p>Under the First Amendment, a government official like Carr is allowed to call Kimmel talentless or unfunny. He&rsquo;s allowed to say Kimmel shouldn&rsquo;t be on the air. He&rsquo;s <em>not </em>allowed to accompany this with a clear threat backed by government authority. &ldquo;The easy way or the hard way&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t healthy debate, it&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/20/24346317/trump-gangster-tech-regulation-corruption-grift">gangster talk</a>. Or more precisely, government jawboning.</p><p>Even the substantially Trump-picked, overwhelmingly conservative Supreme Court has condemned something very similar to Carr&rsquo;s conduct. <a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2025/09/17/cowardly-disney-caves-to-brendan-carrs-bogus-censorial-threats-pulling-jimmy-kimmel/">Mike Masnick at <em>Techdirt</em> points out</a> that a ruling last year, in the case <em>NRA v. Vullo</em>, declared flatly that &ldquo;the First Amendment prohibits government officials from relying on the &lsquo;threat of invoking legal sanctions and other means of coercion . . . to achieve the suppression&rsquo; of disfavored speech.&rdquo; That&rsquo;s true even if they do so through intermediaries like Nexstar rather than attacking the speaker directly.</p><p>Disney, of course, didn&rsquo;t have to bow to a clearly unconstitutional threat. CEO Bob Iger and Disney Entertainment chief Dana Walden, according to <em>Status</em>, were among the latest powerful figures who made a cowardly decision to appease Carr and Trump rather than stand up for themselves and their employees in public and, if necessary, in court.</p><p>But even if there&rsquo;s plenty of blame to go around, Carr&rsquo;s threat is impossible to ignore &mdash; and the implicit comparisons to conservative provocateurs being banned on social media, or commentators being fired after outcry for a hateful statement, or any other example of alleged &ldquo;cancel culture,&rdquo; off-base. Whatever the underlying offense, this isn&rsquo;t a private company independently making a business judgment about its public image and financial interests. It&rsquo;s a government official inserting himself into the process of making entertainment, decreeing what a comedian is allowed to say.</p><p>Carr and Johnson aren&rsquo;t denying the pressure campaign. Carr responded to a request for comment from <em>Status</em> with a grinning emoji and <a href="https://x.com/BrendanCarrFCC/status/1968449919221416427">thanked Nexstar on X</a> for &ldquo;doing the right thing.&rdquo; Johnson <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968464339515417001">crowed on X</a> that he had &ldquo;ended Jimmy Kimmel&rsquo;s career&rdquo; by bringing Carr on to &ldquo;announce investigations into ABC and Disney.&rdquo;<br>It&rsquo;s unclear whether Kimmel will come back on the air at some point &mdash; but either way, the Trump administration&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy/779799/republican-charlie-kirk-first-amendment-crackdown-continues">war on free speech</a> is still going strong.</p><p><em><strong>Correction:</strong> The proposed merger between Nexstar and Tegna is worth $6.2 billion, not million.</em></p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy/781148/jimmy-kimmel-charlie-kirk-monologue-brendan-carr-censorship-first-amendment#comments"><span>0 Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Adi Robertson</span></span></span></li><li><li><li><li><li></ul></div></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Jimmy Kimmel doesn&#39;t need to be a part of the conversation. Cut out the part that doesn&#39;t matter. The important subject matter is should the head of the FCC be able to threaten broadcast licenses based on what is said on a specific station?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkl8b0/yes_jimmy_kimmels_suspension_was_government/neyqqvg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Are we okay with this? Would the GOP be okay with this if Obama did it? Is this the new America?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkl8b0/yes_jimmy_kimmels_suspension_was_government/neyqxc4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But Bro Jogan told us that comedy is legal again</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkl8b0/yes_jimmy_kimmels_suspension_was_government/neyprn5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:09:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/09/17/tiktok-to-be-sold-to-trumps-right-wing-billionaire-buddies-and-converted-into-a-propaganda-mill/</link><title>TikTok To Be Sold To Trump’s Right Wing Billionaire Buddies And Converted Into A Propaganda Mill (techdirt.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkk855/tiktok_to_be_sold_to_trumps_right_wing/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkk855/tiktok_to_be_sold_to_trumps_right_wing/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkk855/tiktok_to_be_sold_to_trumps_right_wing/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>And this is all exactly what Brendan Carr said he would do. </p><p><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/amp/news/trump-fcc-brendan-carr-project-2025-what-to-know/">https://www.cbsnews.com/amp/news/trump-fcc-brendan-carr-project-2025-what-to-know/</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkk855/tiktok_to_be_sold_to_trumps_right_wing/neyv4rv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>hopefully this will be like when parents got onto facebook and all the kids left..</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkk855/tiktok_to_be_sold_to_trumps_right_wing/neza784/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The united states is copying every single thing china does, <strong>except the good things</strong>. It&#39;s actually quite impressive. lol</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkk855/tiktok_to_be_sold_to_trumps_right_wing/neyq17q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:30:18 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.pcgamer.com/hardware/its-all-good-its-all-good-says-mark-zuckerberg-as-his-catastrophic-live-demo-of-metas-new-smart-glasses-goes-horribly-wrong-you-spend-years-making-technology-and-then-the-wi-fi-on-the-day-catches-you/</link><title>'It's all good, it's all good' says Mark Zuckerberg as his catastrophic live demo of Meta's new Ray-Ban smart glasses goes horribly wrong: 'You spend years making technology and then the Wi-Fi on the day catches you' (pcgamer.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkgcm8/its_all_good_its_all_good_says_mark_zuckerberg_as/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkgcm8/its_all_good_its_all_good_says_mark_zuckerberg_as/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 12 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkgcm8/its_all_good_its_all_good_says_mark_zuckerberg_as/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/JHxKdNpSdAFDxuHn8j5PDo.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><section><div><figcaption> <span>(Image credit: Meta Developers)</span> </figcaption> </div><div><p>Never work with children or animals, so goes the famous advice for stage performers, entertainers, and anyone having to present something live in front of an audience. Perhaps smart glasses should be added to that list, if yesterday's <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D97ILdUbYww">Meta Connect 2025 livestream</a> is anything to go by&mdash;as the new <a href="https://www.anrdoezrs.net/click-7706533-17145766?sid=pcg-gb-1331860904822642313&amp;url=https://www.ray-ban.com/usa/discover-ray-ban-meta-ai-glasses/clp">Ray-Ban Meta glasses</a> took the opportunity to misbehave at almost every turn.</p><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/D97ILdUbYww?feature=shared&amp;t=2084">Unveiled to great fanfare</a> and a rapt audience by Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg, the second-generation smart glasses were promised to be capable of "empowering people with new abilities" and said to allow users to "make themselves smarter" thanks to the newly-polished AI functionality. Cool stuff, but when it came to the demos, things didn't exactly go to plan.</p><p>Switching over to a livestreamed demonstration, displayed to the audience on a gigantic panel at Zuckerberg's side,<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@CHEFCUSO"> chef Jack Mancuso</a> attempted to use the Live AI functionality of the smart specs to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/D97ILdUbYww?feature=shared&amp;t=2427">help them make a Korean-inspired steak sauce</a>. Standing in front of multiple unprepared ingredients (which the glasses initially appeared to recognise) the Meta specs immediately ignored a prompt to help make the sauce, instead listing the ingredients that might go in it.</p><p>Interrupting, Mancuso asked the AI a reasonable question: "What do I do first?" After a long silence, in which metaphorical pins could be heard dropping in the audience, Mancuso asked again. The AI then merrily informed our now visibly-nervous host that the base of the sauce was already made.</p><p>Another long pause. "What do I do first?" Mancuso asked once more, to laughter from the audience. "You've already combined the base ingredients," the AI continued, helpfully telling Mancuso to grate a pear into the non-existent sauce. "Alright, I think the Wi-Fi might be messed up" said Mancuso, looking embarrassed. "Back to you Mark."</p><figure><figcaption><span>(Image credit: Meta Developers)</span></figcaption></figure><p>"It's all good, it's all good" said Zuckerberg, amid cheers, laughter, and applause from the crowd. "The irony of all this whole thing is that you spend years making technology and then the Wi-Fi on the day kinda... catches you. We'll go check out what he made later."</p><p>Still, more demos were yet to come. Later in the presentation, Zuckerberg donned a pair of Ray-Ban Meta glasses himself, along with a wristband interface said to be able to control the glasses through muscle movements.</p><div><section><p>Keep up to date with the most important stories and the best deals, as picked by the PC Gamer team.</p></section></div><p>"Now, I want to get into this in more detail, we've got two options," said Zuckerberg, laughing nervously. "We've got the slides, or we've got the live demo." At this point, the audience erupted into shouts for the live version, unsurprisingly, along with more laughter.</p><p>Guess how it went. Zuckerberg was able to respond to a video call request with text via hand movements, which is fairly impressive, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/live/D97ILdUbYww?feature=shared&amp;t=3228">but was unable to answer the call itself</a>.</p><figure><figcaption><span>(Image credit: Meta Developers)</span></figcaption></figure><p>"Uh-oh," said the Meta CEO, frantically rubbing his fingers together in an attempt to pick up the line. "Well, I&hellip; let's see what happened there. That's too bad. I don't know what happened. Maybe Boz can try calling me again."</p><p>Nope. Despite multiple attempts, Zuckerberg was left standing on stage twiddling his fingers, as the Meta AI voice digitally crunched to tell him yet another call was incoming that he seemed unable to answer. At one point, Zuckerberg blamed himself for the inability to control the device, but the ringtone continued to play across a deathly-silent hall, despite his best efforts.</p><p>Eventually, the Meta head honcho gave up. "I don't know what to tell you guys," he said, eventually resorting to bringing the now much-awaited Boz onstage, amid a seemingly ever-present ringtone and much tittering from the crowd.</p><figure><div></div><figcaption><span>(Image credit: Meta Developers)</span></figcaption></figure><p>I'll be honest, it's a pretty painful watch. As tempting as it is to make fun of <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/billionaires/profiles/mark-e-zuckerberg/">Meta's multi-billionaire CEO</a> for the borked demo, those of us who have had to present live ourselves will have our head in our hands, as I have while writing this article. It seems the Ray-Ban Meta glasses could do with <em>some work,</em> and while the tech looks very impressive on paper, the demo appears to have revealed some serious flaws in the implementation.</p><p>I can't imagine many will be rushing to order a pair after this particular demonstration, but I can't help but think of another old showbiz clich&eacute;: There's no such thing as bad PR. We're all talking about it at least, and that's the main thing, eh Zuck?<em> </em></p></div><div><p>Andy built his first gaming PC at the tender age of 12, when IDE cables were a thing and high resolution wasn't&mdash;and he hasn't stopped since. Now working as a hardware writer for PC Gamer, Andy spends his time jumping around the world attending product launches and trade shows, all the while reviewing every bit of PC gaming hardware he can get his hands on. You name it, if it's interesting hardware he'll write words about it, with <em>opinions </em>and everything.</p></div></section> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/XV3LLvTJEGpgRq5TDnBneJ.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/FetMzVL8ejhVCUJyYFCYRd.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/GRG8xdYh2JKqR4FhYQDMuS.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/rFPZ5FoZo9zjcmaEAuiBqn.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>When he attempts to be personable it’s like watching Arnie in that Terminator 2 scene where John Connor is trying to teach him how to smile.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkgcm8/its_all_good_its_all_good_says_mark_zuckerberg_as/nexmwmx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is one thing Bill Gates did pretty well. When something fucked up he&#39;d say there were still some bugs to work out. It&#39;s better to just admit it then take your audience as a bunch of dumbasses.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkgcm8/its_all_good_its_all_good_says_mark_zuckerberg_as/nexo2ep/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This joins the (ig)noble list of fucked up demos that includes the Tesla window breaking and the Windows 98 crashing.</p><p>Funny enough - you can have an incomplete product and still make (fake?) a great demo. I remember reading how in the original iPhone the OS was still unfinished and buggy during the demo, and Jobs actually had multiple devices in different pockets to showcase features individually, because it would crash if you tried to use them together.</p><p>EDIT: Fixed to say that it was the Win98 demo, not Win95.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkgcm8/its_all_good_its_all_good_says_mark_zuckerberg_as/nexoyof/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:02:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/entertainment/tv/2025/09/18/jimmy-kimmel-charlie-kirk-abc-off-the-air/</link><title>Jimmy Kimmel’s suspension confirms what many suspected after Colbert’s (washingtonpost.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd3he/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_confirms_what_many/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd3he/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_confirms_what_many/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd3he/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_confirms_what_many/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Comedians, talk show hosts, and reporters taking digs at politicians or the political system are often the canary in the coal mine for the health of a democracy.</p><p>Less than 9 months was all it took for media censorship to arrive as the US continues to slide further into authoritarianism.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd3he/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_confirms_what_many/newz0s5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>its a really dangerous and dark day for this country</p><p>its a clear message that Free Speach itself is under attack</p><p>if you dare say anything against Trump or MAGA they will silence you</p><p>this fucking needs to end.</p><p>Fuck Donald J Trump and the MAGA Cult.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd3he/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_confirms_what_many/nex1blo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They can’t just be afraid of Trump. There has to be money backing him that can hurt these networks financially by pulling ad rev or boycotting</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd3he/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_confirms_what_many/nex0r97/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 22:01:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.advocate.com/news/robert-garcia-jimmy-kimmel-probe?1</link><title>Jimmy Kimmel’s suspension sparks congressional investigation | Rep. Robert Garcia is investigating why the comedian’s popular late-night show was pulled after the FCC commissioner threatened ABC over the host’s speech. (advocate.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd0s1/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_sparks_congressional/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd0s1/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_sparks_congressional/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd0s1/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_sparks_congressional/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.advocate.com/media-library/jimmy-kimmel-robert-garcia.jpg?id=61618306&width=1200&height=600&coordinates=0%2C39%2C0%2C39' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Gay <a href="http://advocate.com/california">California</a> U.S. Rep. <a href="https://www.advocate.com/politics/robert-garcia-democrat-congress">Robert Garcia</a>, the top <a href="http://advocate.com/democratic-party">Democrat</a> on the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, said Thursday he is opening an investigation into what he called &ldquo;corrupt schemes and threats&rdquo; designed to silence critics of President <a href="http://advocate.com/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a>. His announcement came after ABC abruptly pulled <em><em>Jimmy Kimmel Live!</em></em> from the air in response to pressure from Trump allies and the Federal Communications Commission.</p><p><strong>Related: </strong><a href="https://www.advocate.com/voices/trump-regime-cancels-jimmy-kimmel">In canceling Jimmy Kimmel, Trump&rsquo;s censorship regime guts free speech</a></p><p>&ldquo;Every American has a duty to stand up for our First Amendment values,&rdquo; Garcia said. &ldquo;We will not be silent as our freedoms are threatened by corrupt schemes and threats. Anyone who is complicit will need to answer to us.&rdquo;</p><p>The network&rsquo;s decision followed Kimmel&rsquo;s Monday monologue, which took aim at Trump&rsquo;s reaction to the <a href="https://www.advocate.com/newsletter/breaking-news-update-charlie-kirk-has-died">assassination of conservative activist Charlie Kirk</a>. &ldquo;We hit some new lows over the weekend with the MAGA gang desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them, and doing everything they can to score political points from it,&rdquo; Kimmel told his audience. His words were valid. Online, <a href="https://www.advocate.com/news/transgender-woman-charlie-kirk">people on the right falsely blamed</a> a Seattle paralegal who is <a href="https://www.advocate.com/transgender?utm_campaign=SmartLinks">transgender</a> for the shooting. Right-wing media outlets, including the <em><em>Wall Street Journal</em></em> and <em><em>New York Post</em></em>, <a href="https://www.advocate.com/news/new-york-post-charlie-kirk">amplified unverified claims</a> trying to tie the assassination to the <a href="https://www.advocate.com/news/wall-street-journal-charlie-kirk">trans community almost immediately</a>.</p><p><strong>Related: </strong><a href="https://www.advocate.com/news/charlie-kirk-dead-utah-shooting">Wall Street Journal quietly walks back false claim Charlie Kirk shooter had pro-trans messages on his bullets</a></p><p>Kimmel went on to play a clip of Trump answering a reporter&rsquo;s question about Kirk&rsquo;s death by pivoting almost immediately to touting the construction of a new White House ballroom. &ldquo;He&rsquo;s at the fourth stage of grief &mdash; construction,&rdquo; Kimmel said. &ldquo;This is not how an adult grieves the murder of someone he called a friend. This is how a four-year-old mourns a goldfish.&rdquo;</p><p>The quips drew outrage on the right. FCC Chair Brendan Carr accused Kimmel of lying to the American public and suggested the commission could take regulatory action against ABC. &ldquo;We can do this the easy way or the hard way,&rdquo; Carr said on a podcast hosted by far-right commentator Benny Johnson, in remarks that carried unmistakable menace. Hours later, Disney chief executive Robert Iger and television chief Dana Walden decided to pull Kimmel&rsquo;s show indefinitely, the <em><em>New York Times</em></em> <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/17/business/media/abc-jimmy-kimmel.html">reports</a>.</p><p><strong>Related: </strong><a href="https://www.advocate.com/news/charlie-kirk-dead-utah-shooting">Right-wing firebrand Charlie Kirk dead after shooting at university in Utah</a></p><p>The sequence of events amounts to a chilling exertion of political pressure on a major broadcast network &mdash; a move critics say undermines the very notion of a free press and the First Amendment. Senate Minority Leader Chuck Schumer called the suspension &ldquo;despicable, disgusting, and against democratic values,&rdquo; comparing it to tactics used by autocratic governments, according to a Senate <a href="https://www.democrats.senate.gov/newsroom/press-releases/transcript-leader-schumer-joins-outfront-with-erin-burnett-to-discuss-republicans-refusing-to-engage-in-government-shutdown-negotiations-and-free-speech-concerns">transcript</a> of Schumer&rsquo;s appearance on CNN. Trump, traveling in Britain, posted on social media that the development was &ldquo;Great News for America.&rdquo;</p><p>After Carr&rsquo;s threat, affiliate owners quickly fell in line. Nexstar Media Group, which is pursuing a $6.2 billion merger under FCC review, announced it would pre-empt Kimmel &ldquo;for the foreseeable future.&rdquo; Sinclair Broadcast Group, which espouses conservative values, soon followed, demanding an apology to Kirk&rsquo;s family and a donation to Turning Point USA. Carr praised both companies, urging other broadcasters to adopt similar measures.</p><p><strong>Related: </strong><a href="https://www.advocate.com/news/transgender-woman-charlie-kirk">No, this transgender woman is not the Charlie Kirk assassin</a></p><p>The episode comes against a backdrop of escalating entanglements between the administration and the <a href="http://advocate.com/media">media</a> industry. CBS recently canceled <em><em>The Late Show with Stephen Colbert</em></em> as its parent company sought federal approval for a major merger. Trump has sued multiple outlets, including ABC &mdash; which paid $16 million to settle a case &mdash; and <em><em>The New York Times</em></em>, which he targeted again this week.</p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The FCC guy  made it quite clear it was extortion and a Violation of his first amendment rights. They didnt even pretend it was legal.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd0s1/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_sparks_congressional/newx6li/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is absolutely crazy that an appointed official at FCC was able to threaten ABC to cancel Jimmy Kimmel because Trump was personally offended.  What Kimmel said is not celebrating the death of Charlie Kirk, it was questioning political pushes on free speech and accusations of political leaning of the shooter.  So this is absolutely a blow to the idea of constitutional freedom of speech.  Not to mention all the other stuff the Trump administration has done against civil rights. I hope one day the states returns to a democracy, because right now it’s hard to justify that.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd0s1/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_sparks_congressional/newxnre/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I wish these senators/ags had put more effort in prosecuting Trump for Jan 6 (Learn from Brazil), we wouldn’t have been dealing with this stuff now.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nkd0s1/jimmy_kimmels_suspension_sparks_congressional/newwz0k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:58:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/new-bill-aims-to-block-both-online-adult-content-and-vpns/</link><title>New Bill Aims to Block Both Online Adult Content and VPNs (cnet.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njzhsz/new_bill_aims_to_block_both_online_adult_content/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njzhsz/new_bill_aims_to_block_both_online_adult_content/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 9 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njzhsz/new_bill_aims_to_block_both_online_adult_content/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.cnet.com/a/img/resize/ef246c239c12176372768c0e5a98dd7787301b98/hub/2025/09/18/9e166db5-d8fc-419b-9898-06f6a5200472/gettyimages-885980662.jpg?auto=webp&fit=crop&height=675&width=1200' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>A proposed bill in Michigan has a broad reach that covers everything from adult AI content to manga and even depictions of transgender people. It includes a VPN ban to avoid workarounds. </p><div><div><div><div><p><span>Tyler Lacoma</span> <span>Editor / Home Security</span></p></div></div><p>For more than 10 years Tyler has used his experience in smart home tech to craft how-to guides, explainers, and recommendations for technology of all kinds. From using his home in beautiful Bend, OR as a testing zone for the latest security products to digging into the nuts and bolts of the best data privacy guidelines, Tyler has experience in all aspects of protecting your home and belongings. With a BA in Writing from George Fox and certification in Technical Writing from Oregon State University, he's ready to get you the details you need to make the best decisions for your home. On off hours, you can find Tyler exploring the Cascade trails, finding the latest brew in town with some friends, or trying a new recipe in the kitchen!</p><div><p><span>Expertise</span> <span>Smart home | Smart security | Home tech | Energy savings | A/V</span></p></div></div></div></div><div><div><article><p>If you live in Michigan, you might not be able to legally use a VPN soon if a new bill is passed into law. On Sept. 11, Michigan Republican representatives proposed far-reaching legislation banning adult internet content.&nbsp;</p><p>The bill, <a href="https://www.legislature.mi.gov/documents/2025-2026/billintroduced/House/pdf/2025-HIB-4938.pdf">called the Anticorruption of Public Morals Act</a>&nbsp;and advanced by six Republican representatives, would ban a wide variety of adult content online, ranging from ASMR and adult manga to AI content and any depiction of transgender people. It also seeks to ban all <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/best-vpn/">use of VPNs</a>, foreign or US-produced.&nbsp;</p><hr><p><em>Don't miss any of our unbiased tech content and lab-based reviews. </em><a href="https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=cnet.com#link=%7B%22role%22:%22standard%22,%22href%22:%22https://www.google.com/preferences/source?q=cnet.com%22,%22target%22:%22%22,%22absolute%22:%22%22,%22linkText%22:%22Add%20CNET%22%7D"><em>Add CNET</em></a><em> as a preferred Google source.</em></p><hr><p>VPNs, or virtual private networks, are software suites often used as workarounds to avoid similar content bans that have passed in states like Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi and the UK. VPNs can be purchased with subscriptions or downloaded and are also built into some browsers and <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjazbi85-KPAxVtETQIHSKCJQUQFnoECA0QAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnet.com%2Fhome%2Finternet%2Fbest-wi-fi-routers%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw3x6G_NAg6paG4kfEb--21u&amp;opi=89978449">Wi-Fi router</a>s. </p><p>But Michigan's bill would charge internet service providers with detecting and blocking <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/best-free-vpn/">VPN use</a>, as well as banning the sale of <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/how-to-use-a-vpn/">VPNs</a> in the state. Associated fines would be up to $500,000.</p><h2>What the ban could mean for VPNs</h2><figure> <figcaption> <span>Screenshot by CNET</span></figcaption></figure><p>Unlike some laws banning access to adult content, this Michigan bill is comprehensive. It applies to all residents of Michigan, adults or children, targets an extensive range of content and includes language that could ban not <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/best-vpn-for-streaming/">only VPNs</a> but any method of bypassing internet filters or restrictions.&nbsp;</p><p>That could spell trouble for <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/best-vpn-for-windows/">VPN owners</a> and other internet users who leverage these tools to improve their privacy, protect their identities online, prevent ISPs from gathering data about them or <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/best-antivirus/">increase their device safety</a> when browsing on public Wi-Fi.</p><p><strong>Read more</strong>: <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/vpn-survey-2025">CNET Survey: 47% of Americans Use VPNs for Privacy. That Number Could Rise. Here's Why</a></p><p>Bills like these could have unintended side effects. John Perrino, Senior Policy and Advocacy Expert for the nonprofit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.internetsociety.org">Internet Society</a>, mentioned to CNET that adult content laws like this could interfere with what kind of music people can stream, the sexual health forums and articles they can access and even important news involving sexual topics that they may want to read.</p><p>&nbsp;"Additionally, state age verification laws are difficult for smaller services to comply with, hurting competition and an open internet," Perrino said.</p><p>The Anticorruption of Public Morals Act has not passed the Michigan House of Representatives committee or been voted on by the Michigan Senate, and it's not clear how much support the bill has beyond the six Republican representatives who have proposed it. As we've seen with state legislation in the past, sometimes bills like these can serve as templates for other representatives who may want to propose similar laws in their own states.</p><h2>Could VPNs still get around bans like these?</h2><figure><div><picture><source srcset="https://www.cnet.com/a/img/resize/41689d3f88079acf6ad3a417e082f29964f9d62c/hub/2025/08/22/6281cb39-862d-4a0d-99fd-e226c2cc9ee4/pia-vpn-review-multi-hop.png?auto=webp&amp;width=768" alt="PIA VPN multi-hop and obfuscation servers"><source srcset="https://www.cnet.com/a/img/resize/459e6591c269b78c9212ae6fb03b8fc2b8d210f3/hub/2025/08/22/6281cb39-862d-4a0d-99fd-e226c2cc9ee4/pia-vpn-review-multi-hop.png?auto=webp&amp;width=1024" alt="PIA VPN multi-hop and obfuscation servers"><source srcset="https://www.cnet.com/a/img/resize/602336d83849d66df682b32feaf4177cad136f83/hub/2025/08/22/6281cb39-862d-4a0d-99fd-e226c2cc9ee4/pia-vpn-review-multi-hop.png?auto=webp&amp;width=1200" alt="PIA VPN multi-hop and obfuscation servers"> <img src="https://www.cnet.com" alt="PIA VPN multi-hop and obfuscation servers" height="826.3229308005427" width="1200"></source></source></source></picture></div><figcaption> <span>Screenshot by CNET</span></figcaption></figure><p>Could VPNs still get around this type of ban? That's a complex question that this bill doesn't really address.&nbsp;</p><p>"From a technical standpoint, ISPs can attempt to distinguish VPN traffic using deep packet inspection, or they can block known VPN IP addresses," said <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/nordvpn-review/">NordVPN privacy advocate Laura Tyrylyte</a>. "However, deploying them effectively requires big investments and ongoing maintenance, making large-scale VPN blocking both costly and complex."</p><p>Also, VPNs have ways around deep packet inspection and other methods.&nbsp;</p><p>"Some VPNs offer&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/vpn-obfuscation-what-it-is-and-why-you-might-need-it/">obfuscation</a>&nbsp;-- which tries to disguise VPN traffic as standard web traffic -- using dedicated servers or custom VPN protocols, like <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/nordvpn-review/">NordVPN's</a> NordWhisper or Proton VPN's Stealth," said CNET senior editor Moe Long. "But note that obfuscation isn't foolproof."</p><p>There are also no-log features offered by many VPNs to guarantee they don't keep a record of your activity, and <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/nordvpn-backs-up-its-no-log-claims-with-a-new-audit-from-deloitte">no-log audits from third parties like Deloitte</a> that -- well, <a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/services-and-software/vpn-audits-are-important-but-they-dont-paint-a-full-picture/">try to guarantee the guarantee</a>. VPNs can even use server tricks, such as RAM-only servers that automatically reboot to erase data after every browsing session.</p><p>If you're seriously concerned about your data privacy, you can look for features like these in a VPN and see if they are right for you. Changes like these, even on the state level, are one reason we pay close attention to <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjW84XT6OKPAxX3NzQIHdRoL7kQFnoECCAQAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnet.com%2Ftech%2Fservices-and-software%2Fhow-we-evaluate-and-review-vpns%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw02mpuElPg5dQy_Te9ObcR8&amp;opi=89978449">how specific VPNs work during our testing</a>, and recommend the right VPNs for the job, <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjW84XT6OKPAxX3NzQIHdRoL7kQFnoECC8QAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnet.com%2Ftech%2Fservices-and-software%2Ffastest-vpn%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw1FwgSlROtPGB6nr94Xw48Q&amp;opi=89978449">from speedy browsing</a> to <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwjW84XT6OKPAxX3NzQIHdRoL7kQFnoECDIQAQ&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cnet.com%2Ftech%2Fservices-and-software%2Fbest-vpn-for-travel%2F&amp;usg=AOvVaw0xQxEx2bazK31i1Jdfgk9X&amp;opi=89978449">privacy while traveling</a>. </p></article></div><div><p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><span> Other Services &amp; Software </span> </p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.cnet.com/a/img/resize/1b7f51f5560ae0f141c3829c4c5a046caee6610f/hub/2024/01/19/d7cdb7d2-3238-47b2-988d-f58f5f3a8342/screenshot-2024-01-19-at-9-12-19am.png?auto=webp&amp;fit=crop&amp;height=96&amp;width=96"></p><p><img src="https://www.cnet.com/a/img/resize/afea7dfb37a004f5248ea646f6e019106cecf3ae/hub/2024/01/19/d7cdb7d2-3238-47b2-988d-f58f5f3a8342/screenshot-2024-01-19-at-9-12-19am.png?auto=webp&amp;fit=crop&amp;height=84&amp;width=84"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Michigan only at the moment,<br/>Michigan has a Democratic majority in it&#39;s senate, and a Democratic Governor and Lt. Governor.</p><p>The likelihood of this passing is extremely thin, but it&#39;s telling that they are even attempting it.</p><p>EDIT*** Thanks for the upvotes. -------------------------------------------</p><p>Just wanted everyone to know I&#39;m aware of the Heritage playbook, the GOP copy/pasting bills, etc. and am not discounting any part of all of that.</p><p>It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t expect us to see more of this....especially as I&#39;m in Texas, where we are all concerned for what happens with anime/manga in the wake of our new intentionally broadly-worded &quot;protect the kids&quot; bill here that has passed.</p><p>As a member of a state that&#39;s been leading the charge on this kinda stuff, I simply commented to ensure the accurate info about the article contents was here, and the odds of it&#39;s success.</p><p>Wishing you all the strength of heart to fight this bullshit, at whatever levels you can, and to stay informed, even as things continue to grow darker.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njzhsz/new_bill_aims_to_block_both_online_adult_content/neua7y8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How do you even ban VPNs, when many companies use VPNs as a business function for remote employees?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njzhsz/new_bill_aims_to_block_both_online_adult_content/neumpvr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is literally what the right claimed the DemsWould do</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njzhsz/new_bill_aims_to_block_both_online_adult_content/neu8n60/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:35:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://sbgi.net/sinclair-says-kimmel-suspension-is-not-enough-calls-on-fcc-and-abc-to-take-additional-action/</link><title>Sinclair Says Kimmel Suspension is Not Enough, Calls on FCC and ABC to Take Additional Action (sbgi.net)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><b>Sinclair&rsquo;s ABC stations to air a special in remembrance of Charlie Kirk during Jimmy Kimmel Live timeslot on Friday</b></p><div><p><span>BALTIMORE &ndash; </span>Sinclair, the nation&rsquo;s largest ABC affiliate group, objects to recent comments made by Mr. Kimmel concerning the assassination of Charlie Kirk.</p><p>As discussed with ABC earlier today, Sinclair decided to indefinitely preempt &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; beginning tonight. Following these discussions, ABC has suspended production of &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Mr. Kimmel&rsquo;s remarks were inappropriate and deeply insensitive at a critical moment for our country,&rdquo; said Vice Chairman Jason Smith. &ldquo;We believe broadcasters have a responsibility to educate and elevate respectful, constructive dialogue in our communities. We appreciate FCC Chairman Carr&rsquo;s remarks today and this incident highlights the critical need for the FCC to take immediate regulatory action to address control held over local broadcasters by the big national networks.&rdquo;</p><p>Sinclair&rsquo;s ABC stations will air a special in remembrance of Charlie Kirk this Friday, during Jimmy Kimmel Live&rsquo;s timeslot. The special will also air across all Sinclair stations this weekend. In addition, Sinclair is offering the special to all ABC affiliates across the country.</p><p>Sinclair will not lift the suspension of &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; on our stations until formal discussions are held with ABC regarding the network&rsquo;s commitment to professionalism and accountability.</p><p>Sinclair also calls upon Mr. Kimmel to issue a direct apology to the Kirk family. Furthermore, we ask Mr. Kimmel to make a meaningful personal donation to the Kirk Family and Turning Point USA.</p><p>Regardless of ABC&rsquo;s plans for the future of the program, Sinclair intends not to return &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; to our air until we are confident that appropriate steps have been taken to uphold the standards expected of a national broadcast platform.</p><p><b>About Sinclair:</b></p><p>Sinclair, Inc. (Nasdaq: SBGI) is a diversified media company and a leading provider of local news and sports. The Company owns, operates and/or provides services to 178 television stations in 81 markets affiliated with all major broadcast networks; owns Tennis Channel, the premium destination for tennis enthusiasts; multicast networks CHARGE, Comet, ROAR and The Nest. Sinclair&rsquo;s AMP Media produces a growing portfolio of digital content and original podcasts. Additional information about Sinclair can be found at <a href="https://cts.businesswire.com/ct/CT?id=smartlink&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.sbgi.net%2F&amp;esheet=54326232&amp;newsitemid=20250917446021&amp;lan=en-US&amp;anchor=www.sbgi.net&amp;index=1&amp;md5=3bc3e386c1020c2d9425126f5eab3c3a">www.sbgi.net</a>.</p><p>Category: General</p><p><span>View source version on businesswire.com: </span><span><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250917446021/en/">https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250917446021/en/</a></span></p><p>Media contact: Jessica Bellucci <a href="https://sbgi.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#573d35323b3b2234343e7a341724353023217934383a"><span>[email&nbsp;protected]</span></a></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>And this is why kneeling to totalitarians to save your own skin is stupid, because they will simply move the goalpost.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/netft7d/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Kimmel to make a meaningful personal donation to the Kirk Family and Turning Point USA.&quot;</p><p>That&#39;s F&#39;ing extortion.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/netiqht/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This company never addressed <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_J._Mitchell">that they had a Chairman who abused Virginia Giuffre</a> and suddenly they are conservative?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njvxsb/sinclair_says_kimmel_suspension_is_not_enough/netgv0p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 07:29:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nbcnews.com/pop-culture/tv/disneys-abc-pulls-jimmy-kimmel-live-fcc-chair-blasts-hosts-charlie-kir-rcna232033</link><title>Disney's ABC pulls 'Jimmy Kimmel Live!' after FCC chair criticizes the host's comments | The network confirmed to NBC News it is "indefinitely" pulling the show. (nbcnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 8 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_nbcnews-fp-1200-630,f_auto,q_auto:best/rockcms/2025-09/250917-jimmy-kimmel-ew-645p-1c7ecc.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Disney&rsquo;s ABC said Wednesday it has pulled &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; off the air &ldquo;indefinitely&rdquo; following the late-night host&rsquo;s comments Monday about the motivations of the man who authorities say fatally shot <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/charlie-kirk-rose-teenage-activist-maga-star-rcna230943">conservative activist Charlie Kirk</a>.</p><p>During his monologue Monday night, Kimmel criticized Republicans for how they responded to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/suspect-charlie-kirk-shooting-tyler-robinson-rcna230504">Kirk&rsquo;s killing</a>.</p><p>&ldquo;The MAGA gang [is] desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them and doing everything they can to score political points from it,&rdquo; Kimmel said.</p><p>Kimmel&rsquo;s representative did not immediately respond to a request for comment on ABC&rsquo;s decision.</p><p>Tyler Robinson is accused of fatally shooting Kirk during an event at Utah Valley University. Kirk was a co-founder of the prominent conservative activist organization Turning Point USA and a high-profile ally of President Donald Trump.</p><p>In the wake of the killing, some on the left had sought to label Robinson a member of the far right. Text messages from Robinson <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/tyler-robinson-text-messages-roommate-charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect-rcna231732">released Tuesday by authorities</a> said he targeted Kirk because Robinson &ldquo;had enough of his hatred.&rdquo;</p><p>Trump lauded the news about Kimmel&rsquo;s suspension, posting on <a href="https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115222372625104790">Truth Social</a>, in part: &ldquo;Congratulations to ABC for finally having the courage to do what had to be done.&rdquo;</p><p>ABC's move comes just hours after Federal Communications Commission Chair Brendan Carr threatened to &ldquo;take action&rdquo; against Disney and ABC over Kimmel's remarks. </p><p>In an <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968359685045838041?s=46&amp;t=op3KnRWayVQwe0Xuza3lqQ">interview with conservative commentator Benny Johnson</a>, Carr described Kimmel&rsquo;s remarks as &ldquo;the sickest conduct possible,&rdquo; adding that the FCC could move to revoke ABC affiliate licenses as a punishment.</p><p>In an interview with Fox News host Sean Hannity on Wednesday night, Carr repeatedly referred to Trump&rsquo;s election and said, &ldquo;There&rsquo;s more work to go." The "legacy media," he said, "threw everything" at Trump.</p><p>&ldquo;We at the FCC are going to enforce the public interest obligation,&rdquo; Carr said. &ldquo;If there&rsquo;s broadcasters out there that don&rsquo;t like it, they can turn their license in to the FCC.&rdquo; </p><p>FCC member Anna Gomez, a Biden appointee and the lone Democrat on the panel, <a href="https://x.com/AGomezFCC/status/1968406707484144057">sharply criticized Carr on X, </a>saying, &ldquo;This Administration is increasingly using the weight of government power to suppress lawful expression.&rdquo;</p><p>Following Carr's comments to Johnson, Nexstar Media Group Inc. <a href="https://www.nexstar.tv/nexstar-abc-affiliates-to-preempt-jimmy-kimmel-live-indefinitely-beginning-tonight/">announced that the company&rsquo;s</a> ABC affiliates will pre-empt &ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; for the foreseeable future, beginning with Wednesday night&rsquo;s show. Nexstar has more than 200 stations in the United States and is waiting on FCC approval for <a href="https://www.nexstar.tv/nexstar-media-group-inc-enters-into-definitive-agreement-to-acquire-tegna-inc-for-6-2-billion-in-accretive-transaction/">a $6.2 billion acquisition of Tegna</a>.</p><p>Carr <a href="https://x.com/BrendanCarrFCC/status/1968449919221416427">thanked Nexstar on X </a>"for doing the right thing."</p><p>"Local broadcasters have an obligation to serve the public interest," he wrote. "While this may be an unprecedented decision, it is important for broadcasters to push back on Disney programming that they determine falls short of community values." </p><p>Asked for comment, a spokesperson for the FCC referred NBC News to Carr's post on X. </p><p>The American late-night television landscape is embattled amid sagging ratings and other pressures. Two months ago, CBS announced it was permanently ending &ldquo;The Late Show with Stephen Colbert,&rdquo; saying the move was &ldquo;purely a financial decision against a challenging backdrop in late night.&rdquo; Many of Colbert&rsquo;s fans suggested he was being punished for his long history of criticizing Trump.</p><p>Some on the right have called for people who spoke out against Kirk following his killing to face consequences. Since Kirk was killed, institutions from airlines to schools have moved quickly to <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/charlie-kirk-death-teachers-professors-nationwide-fired-disciplined-s-rcna230845">discipline employees</a> accused of celebrating or mocking his death. </p><p>Steve Bannon, a right-wing pundit and former Trump adviser, called for mass arrests and a crackdown on universities, while<a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/national-security/hegseth-pentagon-staff-negative-charlie-kirk-posts-service-members-rcna230915"> Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth</a> has directed staff members to identify and <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/military">discipline service members </a>who mocked or condoned Kirk&rsquo;s killing, two defense officials told NBC News.</p><p>But Kimmel&rsquo;s removal is by far the highest-profile move yet, even as <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/justice-department/attorney-general-pam-bondi-backlash-right-hate-speech-rcna231713">some on the right have criticized the idea</a> of cracking down on people who spoke against Kirk.</p><p>&ldquo;Jimmy Kimmel Live!&rdquo; debuted in 2003, and Kimmel has since cemented himself in the late-night space, becoming one of the highest-profile comedians on television, hosting the Academy Awards and the Emmy Awards. </p><p>He also emerged as a staunch critic of Trump, with <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2024/mar/10/trump-oscars-truth-jimmy-kimmel">Trump at times biting back</a>. </p><p>Trump, who in recent years has ramped up pressure on major media organizations with a series of lawsuits, sued ABC, ABC News and George Stephanopoulos for defamation over an interview with Rep. Nancy Mace, R-S.C. ABC settled the lawsuits for $15 million.</p><p>The president of the American Federation of Musicians of the United States and Canada, the union that represents musicians employed by Kimmel&rsquo;s show, accused the Trump administration of an attack on free speech.</p><p>&ldquo;This is not complicated: Trump&rsquo;s FCC identified speech it did not like and threatened ABC with extreme reprisals,&rdquo; union President Tino Gagliardi <a href="https://www.afm.org/2025/09/statement-kimmel-live/">said in a statement Wednesday night</a>. &ldquo;This is state censorship. It&rsquo;s now happening in the United States of America, not some far-off country. It&rsquo;s happening right here and right now.&rdquo;</p><p>In their own statements, the Writers Guild of America, Screen Actors Guild and the American Civil Liberties Union also condemned Kimmel&rsquo;s suspension and framed it as government overreach. </p><p>&ldquo;If free speech applied only to ideas we like, we needn&rsquo;t have bothered to write it into the Constitution,&rdquo; the WGA said, adding that it &ldquo;stands with Jimmy Kimmel and his writers.&rdquo;</p><p>Comedian Wanda Sykes <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DOuYySkCfPB/?hl=en">said in an Instagram video</a> that she was supposed to be on Kimmel's show Wednesday, and she criticized Trump.</p><p>&ldquo;So, let&rsquo;s see: He didn&rsquo;t end the Ukraine war or solve Gaza within his first week, but he did end freedom of speech within his first year,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;Hey, for those of you who pray, now&rsquo;s the time to do it. Love you, Jimmy.&rdquo;</p></div><div><div><p><span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/author/rebecca-keegan-ncpn1312732">Rebecca Keegan</a></span></p><p>Rebecca Keegan is the senior Hollywood reporter for NBC News Digital, where she covers the entertainment industry.</p></div><div><p><span><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/author/daniel-arkin-ncpn1206">Daniel Arkin</a></span></p><p>Daniel Arkin is a national reporter at NBC News.</p></div><div><p>Emilie Dorn</p><p>, </p><p>Mirna Alsharif</p><p>, </p><p>Jason Abbruzzese</p><p>and </p><p>Phil Helsel</p><p>contributed</p><p>.</p></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media-cldnry.s-nbcnews.com/image/upload/t_focal-60x60,f_auto,q_auto:best/newscms/2024_47/3669551/241118-daniel-arkin.jpg"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Hey do you all remember last month or so when Colbert was cancelled and Trump said &quot;Kimmel is next&quot;? </p><p>The people who claim free speech is being targeted are targeting free speech.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/neso5l4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Brian Kilmeade just said on Fox News we should forcefully euthanize the homeless and he still has his job. If people don’t start making these corporations pay we will lose everything. Boycott Disney, Boycott ABC, Boycott Paramount and start preparing for a General Strike. Power to the people!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/nesrmr4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We&#39;re seeing the erosion of the First Amendment in real time. FCC pressure as a condition of the Paramount merger is leading <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/10/business/media/cbs-news-bari-weiss-free-press.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mk8.CQD7.wxXBlHNkn3tD&amp;smid=url-share">CBS to cede editorial control to the right wing as a demonstration of loyalty</a>.</p><p>Years down the line, even if things get better, I&#39;m never going to forget how easily our legacy media bent to the will of illiberalism.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njsge7/disneys_abc_pulls_jimmy_kimmel_live_after_fcc/nesn0c3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:46:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/tv/tv-news/fcc-jimmy-kimmel-charlie-kirk-monologue-1236373708/</link><title>FCC Chair Threatens Jimmy Kimmel Over Monologue Comments (hollywoodreporter.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/01/174499_0888-H-2025.jpg?w=1296&h=730&crop=1' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/e/live-feed/"> <span>Logo text</span> </a> </p><p><a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/t/jimmy-kimmel/">Jimmy Kimmel</a>&lsquo;s latest monologue has ignited a political firestorm and resulted in ABC suspending the show. </p><p>Kimmel&rsquo;s comments about the <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/t/charlie-kirk/">Charlie Kirk</a> shooting during Tuesday&rsquo;s show drew condemnation from Federal Communications Commission chair <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/t/brendan-carr/">Brendan Carr</a>. That, in turn, prompted one group of ABC affiliates, owned by Nexstar Media Group, to declare they will not air <em>Jimmy Kimmel Live!</em> for the immediate future, which then led ABC to announce the show was being taken off the air &ldquo;indefinitely.&rdquo; </p><p>The uproar started after Kimmel said suspected Kirk assassin Tyler Robinson was a MAGA Republican. &ldquo;We hit some new lows over the weekend with the MAGA gang desperately trying to characterize this kid who murdered Charlie Kirk as anything other than one of them and doing everything they can to score political points from it,&rdquo; Kimmel said. </p><p>Carr was interviewed by <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968359685045838041">YouTuber</a> <a href="https://x.com/bennyjohnson/status/1968359685045838041">Benny Johnson</a> on Wednesday (video also below), where he appeared to threaten ABC affiliate licenses over the comments, which he called &ldquo;the sickest conduct possible.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;[This] appears to be an action by Jimmy Kimmel to play into the narrative that this was somehow a MAGA or Republican-motivated person,&rdquo; Carr said. &ldquo;What people don&rsquo;t understand is that the broadcasters &hellip; have a license granted by us at the FCC, and that comes with it an obligation to operate in the public interest. When we see stuff like this, look, we can do this the easy way or the hard way. These companies can find ways to change conduct, on Kimmel, or there&rsquo;s going to be additional work for the FCC ahead.&rdquo;</p><p>Johnson said he&rsquo;d like to see an apology from Kimmel to Kirk and his family and asked Carr what other punitive steps the FCC might take. </p><p>&ldquo;I think what you said strikes me as a very reasonable, minimal step that can be taken,&rdquo; Carr said. &ldquo;Calls for Kimmel to be fired &mdash; I think, you could certainly see a path forward for a suspension over this. You know, the FCC is going to have remedies.&rdquo;</p><p>Carr then ran down some of the media earthquakes that have transpired under the second Trump administration, from Stephen Colbert&rsquo;s <em>The Late Show</em> being canceled next year, to NPR and PBS being defunded, to CBS News taking steps to be more &ldquo;fact based.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;So I think you see some lashing out from people like Kimmel, who are frankly talentless and are looking for ways to get attention,&rdquo; he said. &ldquo;Their grip on the narrative is slipping. That doesn&rsquo;t mean that it&rsquo;s not still important to hold the public interest standard &hellip; We have a rule on the book that interprets the public interest standard that says &lsquo;news distortion&rsquo; is something that is prohibited &hellip; the FCC has stepped back from enforcing it &hellip; I think it&rsquo;s past time these [affiliates] themselves push back on Comcast and this and say, &lsquo;Listen, we&rsquo;re not going to run Kimmel anymore until you straighten this out because we&rsquo;re running the possibility of license revocation from the FCC if we continue to run content that ends up being a pattern of news distortion.&rsquo; So I think again, Disney needs to see some change here.&rdquo; (Note: Comcast owns NBC Universal; Disney owns ABC.)</p><p>Nexstar then issued the following statement in response to Carr&rsquo;s comments: &ldquo;Nexstar&rsquo;s owned and partner television stations affiliated with the ABC Television Network will preempt <em>Jimmy Kimmel Live!</em> for the foreseeable future beginning with tonight&rsquo;s show. Nexstar strongly objects to recent comments made by Mr. Kimmel concerning the killing of Charlie Kirk and will replace the show with other programming in its ABC-affiliated markets.&rdquo; Nexstar currently operates 28 ABC affiliates across the country, mostly in small or midsize markets, though they include the ABC stations in New Orleans and Salt Lake City. </p><p>&ldquo;Mr. Kimmel&rsquo;s comments about the death of Mr. Kirk are o&#64256;ensive and insensitive at a critical time in our national political discourse, and we do not believe they reflect the spectrum of opinions, views, or values of the local communities in which we are located,&rdquo; added Andrew Alford, President of Nexstar&rsquo;s broadcasting division. &ldquo;Continuing to give Mr. Kimmel a broadcast platform in the communities we serve is simply not in the public interest at the current time, and we have made the di&#64259;cult decision to preempt his show in an e&#64256;ort to let cooler heads prevail as we move toward the resumption of respectful, constructive dialogue.&rdquo;</p><div><p>The affiliate group pulling Kimmel was quickly followed by ABC announcing the show had been suspended. A network spokesperson said&nbsp;<em>Jimmy Kimmel Live!</em>&nbsp;will be &ldquo;pre-empted indefinitely.&rdquo;</p><p>Yet Carr&rsquo;s tactics drew fire from within the department itself as FCC Commissioner Anna Gomez responded on social media by criticizing the Chair&rsquo;s threats.</p></div><p>&ldquo;An inexcusable act of political violence by one disturbed individual must never be exploited as justification for broader censorship or control,&rdquo; <a href="https://x.com/AGomezFCC/status/1968406707484144057">Gomez wrote</a>. &ldquo;This Administration is increasingly using the weight of government power to suppress lawful expression, not because it glorifies violence or breaks the law, but because it challenges those in power or reflects views they oppose.&nbsp;We must stand firm against every attempt to silence dissent, punish satirists and government critics, and erode individual liberty. To surrender our right to speak freely is to accept that those in power, not the people, will set the boundaries of debate that define a free society.&rdquo;</p><figure></figure> <figure><p><iframe title="Jimmy Kimmel LIES About Charlie Kirk Killer, Blames Charlie For His Murder!? Disney Must Fire Kimmel" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uTyX9JC-rhA?feature=oembed"></iframe> </p></figure> </div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Now apply the same standards to Fox News.  Oh what, crickets?  Surprising.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/nerj5yc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How’s that free speech going over there?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/neri956/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The FCC Chair threatening to pull ABC affiliate licensees over content he didn’t like? Now THAT sounds like an actual first amendment violation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njnb5k/fcc_chair_threatens_jimmy_kimmel_over_monologue/nerjd7k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:18:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.polygon.com/steam-discord-twitch-reddit-congress-politics/</link><title>Steam, Discord, and Twitch execs called to testify before Congress over 'radicalization' of users (polygon.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article> <header><p>House Oversight Committee to grill CEOs over platforms being 'exploited for nefarious purposes'</p><h2>Steam, Discord, and Twitch execs called to testify before Congress over 'radicalization' of users</h2> <a><p>Sign in to your <span>Polygon</span> account</p></a><div><figure><picture> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=49&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=480&amp;dpr=2"> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=49&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=767&amp;dpr=2"> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=49&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=943&amp;dpr=2"> <source srcset="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?q=70&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=1140&amp;dpr=1"> <img width="1600" height="900" alt="Photo of Rep. James Comer speaking" src="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/james_comer.jpeg?w=1600&amp;h=900&amp;fit=crop"> </source></source></source></source></picture> <small>Photo: Office of James Comer</small> </figure> </div></header><div><p>The CEOs of Discord, Steam, Twitch, and Reddit have been called to Congress to testify about the "radicalization of online forum users" on those platforms, the <a href="https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-invites-ceos-of-discord-steam-twitch-and-reddit-to-testify-on-radicalization-of-online-forum-users/">House Oversight and Government Reform Committee announced Wednesday</a>.</p><p>"Congress has a duty to oversee the online platforms that radicals have used to advance political violence," said chairman of the House Oversight Committee James Comer, a Republican from Kentucky, in a statement. "To prevent future radicalization and violence, the CEOs of Discord, Steam, Twitch, and Reddit must appear before the Oversight Committee and explain what actions they will take to ensure their platforms are not exploited for nefarious purposes."</p><p>Letters from the House Oversight Committee have been sent to Humam Sakhnini, CEO of Discord; Gabe Newell, president of Steam maker Valve; Dan Clancy, CEO of Twitch; and Steve Huffman, CEO of Reddit, requesting their testimony on Oct. 8. "The hearing will examine radicalization of online forum users, including incidents of open incitement to commit violent politically motivated acts," Comer said in a letter to each CEO.</p><p>The catalyst for Comer's request is the killing of Charlie Kirk, the right-wing political activist and media personality who was shot at Utah Valley University last week. The suspect in that case, Tyler Robinson, is <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/investigations/2025/09/15/charlie-kirk-shooter-suspect-discord-chat/">reported to have used Discord</a> to discuss the killing after the fact, and is alleged to have been <a href="https://www.polygon.com/charlie-kirk-shooter-helldivers-2-meme-tyler-robinson/">steeped in online meme culture</a>.</p><p>Steam and Discord have long been homes for extremists to gather, coordinate, and harass their perceived enemies, despite both platforms being aimed at gamers and designed originally for non-political purposes. The 2017 white supremacist rally Unite the Right in Charlottesville, Virginia was planned through Discord, and the platform was used by far-right mass shooters in the 2022 Buffalo shooting and the Highland Park Parade shooting. In 2024, the <a href="https://www.adl.org/resources/report/steam-powered-hate-top-gaming-site-rife-extremism-antisemitism">Anti-Defamation League</a> reported that Steam was "rife with extremism and antisemitism" across Steam Community groups. Congress has <a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/senator-asks-gabe-newell-why-steam-hosts-so-much-neo-nazi-content/">previously pressed Newell</a> on the "significant presence of users displaying and espousing neo-Nazi, extremist, racial supremacist, misogynistic, and other hateful sentiments" on Steam.</p><p>Discord, Steam, Twitch, and Reddit execs will have the chance to deliver five-minute opening statements prior to answering questions posed by members of the committee during October's testimony.</p></div></article> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static0.polygonimages.com/wordpress%2Fwp-content%2Fauthors%2F685c4d7dc4454-Michael-McWhertor-Green-Purple-2.jpg?fit=crop&amp;w=90&amp;h=90"></p></div></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Born too late for McCarthyismBorn just in time for McCarthyism</p><p>Edited spelling</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/ner0oa8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here comes the censorship hammer, I was wondering what the long game was, shocker it’s the erosion of freedom</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/ner16ax/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s funny that X (formerly Twitter) isn&#39;t included in this, even though that&#39;s arguably the worse out of all of them. I wonder why...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njl1e8/steam_discord_and_twitch_execs_called_to_testify/neqz8ie/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:52:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.techdirt.com/2025/09/16/she-pushed-to-overturn-trumps-loss-in-the-2020-election-now-shell-help-oversee-u-s-election-security/</link><title>She Pushed To Overturn The Loss In The 2020 Election | Now She’ll Help Oversee U.S. Election Security. (techdirt.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: Heather Honey, a high-profile denier of Donald Trump’s loss in the 2020 election, has been appointed to a senior position in the U.S. Department of Homeland Security in which she’ll help oversee the nation’s election infrastructure.</p><p>Honey is a protege of Cleta Mitchell, a lawyer who tried to help Trump overturn the 2020 election results. In 2024, ProPublica reported that Honey had played a key role in Mitchell’s behind-the-scenes effort to change Georgia’s election rules to allow Republican officials to contest a potential Trump loss in that year’s presidential race. Honey also promoted election conspiracy theories, including one Trump cited in a speech to his followers before they stormed the Capitol on Jan. 6, 2021.</p><p>Though states do the on-the-ground work of running elections, DHS supports them with tasks beyond their capacities, such as protecting IT infrastructure and voter databases from foreign intrusions. The agency, with bipartisan support, took on this role in the aftermath of Russia’s interference in the 2016 election.</p><p>Experts on voting and state election officials warned that Honey’s appointment as DHS’ deputy assistant secretary of election integrity could erode trust between state and federal officials, prompting states not to share information with the agency.</p><p>“We are witnessing a dangerous trend: the elevation of known bad-faith actors like Heather Honey,” said Adrian Fontes, Arizona’s Democratic secretary of state, in a statement, citing Honey’s “well-documented history of spreading election lies that have been debunked in court.”</p><p>Fontes called her involvement with DHS “deeply troubling” and said “when the agency gives a platform to individuals who have actively worked to erode public trust, it becomes harder to view DHS as a reliable partner in election security.”</p><p>A DHS spokesperson did not answer questions from ProPublica on Honey’s appointment or the exact nature of her responsibilities. Honey didn’t respond to calls or emails. The White House also didn’t respond to a request for comment. Her name is listed on the organization’s leadership structure online, and her appointment was first reported by the website Democracy Docket.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/nep852u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s not who votes that counts. It&#39;s who counts the votes. - Stalin</p><p>Who else would you use if the only thing that matters is the result, not the integrity of the election?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/nep9ugv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Finally, Trump is keeping a campaign promise. If you voted for him, you’ll never have to vote again. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1njcwto/she_pushed_to_overturn_the_loss_in_the_2020/nepb82t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:47:17 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
