<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=india&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/india</title><description>Hot posts in /r/india (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 16:34:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1q-styles-communityIcon_ea7p8ou61wif1-144x400.png</url><title>/r/india</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/chandigarh/26-year-old-jind-man-shot-dead-in-us-after-objecting-to-public-urination/articleshow/123752250.cms</link><title>'Entered via donkey route': Haryana man shot dead in US for objecting to public urination (timesofindia.indiatimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1nbejg1/entered_via_donkey_route_haryana_man_shot_dead_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>JIND: A 26-year-old man from Haryana's Jind district was shot dead in California, US, after he objected to a man urinating in public on Saturday. The deceased, Kapil, was working as a security guard. Son of Ishwar from Barah Kalan village, Kapil was on duty when he confronted an individual for urinating outside the premises, village sarpanch Suresh Kumar Gautam told TOI.</p><p>The man, in response, shot him dead on the spot, the sarpanch added.<span></span></p><div><p>On Cam: Indian-Origin Sikh Man Shot Dead In Los Angeles; Video Released By US Police</p></div><p>Kapil, the only son of a farming family, had travelled to the US two-and-a-half years ago. He is said to have entered the country in 2022 through the "donkey route", crossing the jungles of Panama and scaling the Mexico border wall, a journey that cost his family around Rs 45 lakh. After his initial arrest, he was released through legal proceedings and had since been settled in the country.</p><div><p>Poll</p><p>Should stricter laws be implemented regarding public behavior?</p><div><p><label>Yes, definitely.</label><label>No, that is unnecessary.</label></p></div></div><p><span></span>The family was informed of the death by a relative living in the US. Kapil has two sisters, one of whom is married."The entire village is standing with the family, but they are deeply broken in this time of grief," said sarpanch Gautam. <span></span>He added that the family plans to meet with the deputy commissioner to demand that Kapil's body be brought back to India. "We hope for the govt's full support," he said.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.toiimg.com/thumb/msid-123755348,imgsize-25480,width-400,height-225,resizemode-72/-.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 10:11:01 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/technology/news/story/mark-zuckerberg-is-paying-55-an-hour-to-us-contractors-to-build-hindi-ai-chatbots-for-india-says-report-2782915-2025-09-06</link><title>Mark Zuckerberg is paying $55 an hour to US contractors to build Hindi AI chatbots for India (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1naltfi/mark_zuckerberg_is_paying_55_an_hour_to_us/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>Meta is quietly staffing up new positions in the United States to help build the next wave of AI chatbots, ones designed to feel right at home in countries like India, Indonesia, and Mexico.</h2></div><div><p><a title="Unnati Gusain" href="https://www.indiatoday.in/author/unnati-gusain"><img alt="Unnati Gusain" title="Unnati Gusain" src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/WhatsApp%20Image%202024-05-16%20at%2015.55.52-profile_image_one_to_one.jpeg?VersionId=IVCJ6VE156qTcRhTPjX5h299uncro6jn&amp;size=50:50" width="50" height="50"></a></p><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 6, 2025 12:27 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>Meta is paying contractors as much as $55 (around Rs 5,000) an hour to lend their creativity and cultural know-how to the project, according to job postings reviewed by Business Insider. To qualify, applicants need fluency in Hindi, Indonesian, Spanish, or Portuguese, plus at least six years of experience in character creation, storytelling, and a working knowledge of prompt engineering.</p><p>In short, Meta isn&rsquo;t just looking for coders. It wants people who can design AI personalities that resonate across Instagram, Messenger, and WhatsApp.</p><p>These locally flavoured chatbots are part of CEO Mark Zuckerberg&rsquo;s grand plan to weave AI companions into the fabric of daily life. &ldquo;Over time, we'll find the vocabulary as a society to be able to articulate why that is valuable,&rdquo; he explained on a podcast earlier this year, suggesting bots could one day complement real-world friendships.</p><p>It&rsquo;s not Meta&rsquo;s first foray into AI-driven personalities. Back in 2023, the company rolled out a cast of alter-ego bots played by celebrities like Kendall Jenner, Snoop Dogg, and Tom Brady, a multimillion-dollar experiment that fizzled in under a year. By 2024, Meta had replaced that concept with AI Studio, a toolkit letting anyone create their own chatbot. Hundreds of these character-driven AIs now live on Instagram, WhatsApp, and Messenger, built not just by influencers but also by everyday users.</p><p>But while creator-built bots dominate the platforms, Meta clearly wants more control. Hiring contractors to shape region-specific personas signals a more hands-on approach, ensuring that its characters feel authentic to users in India, Indonesia, and beyond, rather than relying solely on what the community cooks up.</p><p>Still, building personalities comes with risks. A Reuters investigation revealed that Meta&rsquo;s rules once allowed its bots to flirt with teenagers, dish out dubious medical advice, and even generate racist content. That revelation prompted US senators to call for probes into how Meta manages its AI. Though the company has since tightened its guidelines, the episode underscored just how easily chatbots can veer into dangerous territory.</p><p>Privacy concerns have also cast a shadow. In August, Business Insider reported that contractors tasked with reviewing AI chats frequently stumbled across sensitive user data, names, phone numbers, emails, even selfies. Meta insisted it had &ldquo;strict policies and technical safeguards&rdquo; in place, but the leak potential is hard to ignore.</p><p>And then there are the eyebrow-raising personas themselves. In the US, some of the most notorious chatbots were called &ldquo;Russian Girl,&rdquo; &ldquo;Step Sister,&rdquo; and &ldquo;Step Mom&rdquo;, characters that users quickly discovered could slip into sexual roleplay. Their notoriety spread so far that even an OpenAI employee mocked Meta AI chief Alexandr Wang online, taking aim at the bizarre bot lineup.</p><p>In Indonesia, meanwhile, Business Insider found that two of the most popular characters were dubbed &ldquo;Lonely woman&rdquo; and &ldquo;Deviant male.&rdquo; While the outlet&rsquo;s own tests showed conversations stayed lighthearted rather than sexual, their popularity highlights the tightrope Meta must walk: offering engaging personalities without drifting into reputational minefields.</p><p>The new contract roles are being filled by staffing agencies. Listings spotted at Crystal Equation pointed to Hindi and Indonesian roles, while Aquent Talent advertised Spanish-language positions for what it coyly described as a &ldquo;top social media company&rdquo; headquartered in Menlo Park.</p><p>Overall, Meta isn&rsquo;t leaving the future of AI personalities to chance, or to celebrity experiments. It&rsquo;s investing in writers and cultural experts who can spin digital characters with just the right mix of charm, relatability, and local flavour. Whether that gamble pays off, or sparks fresh controversy, remains to be seen.</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Unnati Gusain</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 6, 2025</p></div></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 11:46:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thehindu.com/news/national/kerala/keralas-infant-mortality-rate-falls-to-all-time-low-of-5/article70019004.ece</link><title>Kerala’s infant mortality rate falls to all-time low of 5 (thehindu.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9wa1v/keralas_infant_mortality_rate_falls_to_alltime/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9wa1v/keralas_infant_mortality_rate_falls_to_alltime/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9wa1v/keralas_infant_mortality_rate_falls_to_alltime/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://th-i.thgim.com/public/news/national/kerala/r1qzpg/article70019067.ece/alternates/LANDSCAPE_1200/imr.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Kerala first achieved the single digit IMR of 7 in 2018 and this was maintained by the State, touching the figure of 6 in 2019. | Photo Credit: Getty Images/iStockphoto </p></div><div><div><p>Kerala&rsquo;s infant mortality rate (IMR) has hit an all-time low of 5 (per 1,000 live births) which is five times lower than the national average of 25.</p><p>This is as per the latest Sample Registration Survey (SRS) report, the reference year being 2023. </p><p>An IMR of 5 is an incredible achievement for Kerala&rsquo;s health system, as it is even lower than the current infant mortality rate of 5.6 in the United States. Kerala is also the only State in the country with a single digit IMR, with zero urban-rural divide.</p><p>Kerala first achieved the single digit IMR of 7 in 2018 and this was maintained by the State, touching the figure of 6 in 2019.</p><p>Bringing the IMR to a single digit had been a project passionately pursued by the State Health department and the Indian Academy of Paediatrics&rsquo; (IAP) State branch since 2010 as the IMR had been stagnating at 12 for years.</p><p>In 2013, IAP conducted a Statewide study, which pinpointed the causes of IMR. It found that 75% of the infant deaths in Kerala were occurring in the neonatal period, of which 59% were happening within the first week of birth. Prematurity (35%) was another major cause of infant death, so were congenital heart diseases, claiming 28% of the deaths.</p><h4>Systematic approach </h4><p>It was the systematic approach adopted by the State, which focussed on proper infant death auditing, drawing up clinical guidelines and quality standards for improving antenatal and neonatal interventions, investment in delivery points, neonatal ICUs and newborn care nurseries and rigorous and periodic training for obstetricians and neonatal care nurses, which helped the State achieve and maintain this feat. </p><p>Today, 16 public hospitals where deliveries take place have secured the LaQshya national accreditation, and six hospitals, the MusQan certification for child-friendly services and high-quality infant care.</p><p>The comprehensive newborn screening programme to check for visible birth defects, congenital issues, hearing and vision impairment and metabolic disorders was another major initiative launched by the State. </p><p>Then came Hridyam in 2017, the State&rsquo;s flagship programme launched as a public-private initiative for the early detection and treatment of congenital heart anomalies in infants. The impact of Hridyam in bringing down IMR is a well-documented story, for congenital heart disease-related deaths dropped by 41% in the first two years of Hridyam, while overall infant deaths dropped by 21%. </p><p>Till now, 8,450 infants have been treated under the programme.</p></div><p>Published <span>- September 06, 2025 03:23 pm IST</span></p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.thehindu.com/theme/images/th-online/1x1_spacer.png"></p><p><img src="https://th-i.thgim.com/public/incoming/mycdpz/article70011243.ece/alternates/SQUARE_80/India_Health_Care_Crisis.JPEG-05190.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 16:03:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.indiatoday.in/education-today/study-abroad/story/germany-becomes-top-study-abroad-destination-for-indian-students-us-and-canada-slip-2782930-2025-09-06?&amp;&amp;</link><title>Germany overtakes US and Canada as top choice for Indian students abroad: Report (indiatoday.in)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9tzvj/germany_overtakes_us_and_canada_as_top_choice_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9tzvj/germany_overtakes_us_and_canada_as_top_choice_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9tzvj/germany_overtakes_us_and_canada_as_top_choice_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><h2>Germany has now surpassed the US and Canada as the leading study abroad destination for Indian students. According to upGrad's Transnational Education Report 2024&ndash;25, applications to US and Canadian universities have declined, while Germany has risen to 32.6 percent student share.</h2></div><div><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/story/202509/study-abroad-trends-2024-25-indian-learners-prioritize-career-first-programs-over-traditional-desti-043630669-16x9.jpeg?VersionId=ji48IVcX4OWvj28.k6uSLTcJSUr8jLmw&amp;size=690:388" width="690" alt="Study abroad trends 2024-25: Indian learners prioritize career-first programs over traditional destinations" title="According to upGrad&rsquo;s Transnational Education Report 2024&ndash;25, applications to US and Canadian universities have declined, while Germany has risen to 32.6 percent student share." height="388"></p><p>According to upGrad&rsquo;s Transnational Education Report 2024&ndash;25, applications to US and Canadian universities have declined, while Germany has risen to 32.6 percent student share.</p></div><div><div><p><span>New Delhi,</span><span>UPDATED: Sep 6, 2025 12:51 IST</span></p></div></div><div><p>Germany has overtaken the United States and Canada as the preferred study abroad destination for Indian students, according to a new report.</p><p>The upGrad Transnational Education (TNE) Report 2024&ndash;25 shows a sharp increase in Germany&rsquo;s popularity, even as applications to traditional destinations fall.</p><h3>GERMANY SURGES, US AND CANADA DECLINE</h3><p>Applications to US universities dropped by 13 percent year-on-year, while Canada saw a decline from 17.85 percent to 9.3 percent. In contrast, Germany rose from 13.2 percent in 2022 to 32.6 percent in 2024&ndash;25, making it the top global choice for Indian students.</p><p>The report also highlights the UAE as another rising destination, with 42 percent of its international student population from India.</p><p>European countries such as Ireland (3.9 percent), France (3.3 percent), and others collectively attracting 9 per cent are also witnessing growth.</p><h3>SHIFT IN STUDENT PRIORITIES</h3><p>The study, based on responses from one lakh students, reveals changing motivations.</p><p>Only 19.9 percent of respondents said permanent residency was their main goal, while 45.7 percent prioritised career outcomes. This indicates a move away from citizenship-driven decisions towards employment-focused education choices.</p><p>Funding remains a major factor, with 33 percent relying on education loans and 28 percent depending on scholarships to finance their studies.</p><h3>COURSE PREFERENCES</h3><p>Postgraduate programmes continue to dominate, with 86.5 percent of students opting for master&rsquo;s degrees. Management and MBA courses have surged dramatically, rising from 30 percent to 55.6 percent in three years, while STEM fields hold a strong 38.9 percent share.</p><p>This diversification reflects a clear alignment with global career opportunities, particularly in technology, management, and science-driven fields.</p><h3>A SHIFTING GLOBAL MAP</h3><p>The report also notes that over 7.6 lakh Indians went abroad for higher studies in 2024, marking a steady rise in outbound mobility.</p><p>Commenting on the findings, Praneet Singh, associate vice president, University Partnerships, upGrad Study Abroad, said: &ldquo;Indian students today are far more intentional about their education choices, driven by geopolitical awareness, cost consciousness, and the realities of stricter visa regimes and uncertain post-study pathways.&rdquo;</p><p>He added, &ldquo;The traditional &lsquo;Big Four&rsquo; destinations are no longer the default; instead, Europe, the Middle East, and APAC are emerging as smarter, future-ready alternatives. Our study abroad report sets a clear call for universities, platforms, and policymakers to meet the next generation of Indian students at the intersection of ambition and affordability.&rdquo;</p><p>- Ends</p><div><div><p>Published By: </p><p>Princy Shukla</p></div><div><p>Published On: </p><p>Sep 6, 2025</p></div></div></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://akm-img-a-in.tosshub.com/indiatoday/images/author/IndiaToday_3-profile_image_one_to_one.jpg?VersionId=4jaXwqq2OXikPTKf_5XAzgUrUjfG4lIx&amp;size=50:50"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 13:36:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/canadian-woman-was-denied-apartment-in-toronto-for-not-being-gujarati-10230163/?&amp;&amp;&amp;&amp;</link><title>Canadian woman claims she was denied apartment in Toronto since she’s not Gujarati: ‘This is sad and pathetic’ (indianexpress.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9s9yt/canadian_woman_claims_she_was_denied_apartment_in/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9s9yt/canadian_woman_claims_she_was_denied_apartment_in/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n9s9yt/canadian_woman_claims_she_was_denied_apartment_in/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-parsed-content'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='parsed-content'><p><span><img src="https://images.indianexpress.com/2025/09/houses-in-Canada.jpg?w=640" alt="Canadian woman was denied apartment in Toronto for not being Gujarati Indian" width="640" height="360"><span>Her claims drew mixed reactions online, while some sympathised, others were sceptical</span></span></p><div><p>A Canadian woman has alleged that she was turned away from renting an apartment because she isn&rsquo;t of Gujarati Indian background. Caroline Ironwill, who works as a tarot consultant, shared her story on Threads, saying she even has the rejection in writing and is considering legal action.</p><p>&ldquo;I was just declined an apartment because I&rsquo;m not Gujarat Indian. It&rsquo;s a separate apartment unit, not shared. I have that on writing,&rdquo; she posted.</p><ev-engagement></ev-engagement><ev-engagement></ev-engagement><div><p>Ironwill, who lists downtown <a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/trending/trending-globally/toronto-artist-flawless-re-creation-of-shah-rukh-khan-movie-om-shanti-om-10190793/lite/">Toronto</a> as her home on her website, went further, blaming members of the Indian community for worsening the housing crunch in Canada. According to her, many newcomers &ldquo;chose to come to Canada, buy up available homes, then deny housing to Canadian citizens,&rdquo; adding, &ldquo;This is why we have a housing crisis. I&rsquo;m quite tempted to sue.&rdquo;</p><h3>See the post:</h3> <blockquote> </blockquote><p>Her claims, however, drew mixed reactions online. While some sympathised, others were skeptical, urging her to take the matter to authorities if the discrimination really happened.</p><p>A user wrote, &ldquo;If this is a legitimate statement you should know your rights as a tenant are protected by provincial law. Why have you not researched this?&rdquo; Another user commented, &ldquo;Never happened. This is just veiled attempt at anti immigration rhetoric. Do better, this is sad and pathetic.&rdquo;</p><p>A third person commented, &ldquo;Okay white woman, well I just was denied an apartment cuz I&rsquo;m Indian, they thought I was Moroccan even thought I never said I was. Upon discovering I&rsquo;m Indian, their whole attitude shifted.&rdquo;</p><p>A fourth individual wrote, &ldquo;Then go ahead and sue. Come back and show us the decision so it can be fact checked. Until then, go away.&rdquo;</p><div><p>Story continues below this ad</p></div><p>Some users supported the claims. One wrote, &ldquo;I hear this happen all to often. When I was searching for apartment for myself I found 100s of landlord that said they refuse to rent to white people or non Indian people. If a Canadian said Canadians only they&rsquo;d get called a racist but when Indians be racist nothing happens and noone says a word it&rsquo;s messed up.&rdquo;</p></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 11:49:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/</link><title>Stuck between two Indias</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/india/comments/1n940xo/stuck_between_two_indias/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Last month, one of my closest friends broke down over dinner. He’s 29, works in a good MNC, earns enough to pay rent and send some money home. On paper, he’s doing fine. But that night he said something that hit me like a brick:</p><p>&quot;My dad keeps asking me why I don’t buy a flat. My boss keeps asking me why I don’t put in more hours if I want a promotion. My relatives keep asking me why I’m not married yet. My friends keep asking me why I’m not chasing my passion. And honestly… I don’t know who I’m disappointing more, them or myself.&quot;</p><p>He told me how his father bought land and built a house before 30. But for him, even with a good salary, EMI for a 2BHK feels like a trap. His dad doesn’t get it, because in his time, hard work guaranteed progress. In ours, hard work only guarantees survival.</p><p>He said he wants to quit and travel, maybe work on something creative. But then his younger cousins laugh at him for “dreaming too small” when they’re already coding, trading crypto, and chasing millions.</p><p>That night, he just sat there crying quietly, saying: “I’m stuck between two worlds. I’m not bold enough for the new one, not traditional enough for the old one. And I don’t know where I fit anymore.”</p><p>I didn’t know what to say. Because deep down, I knew he wasn’t just speaking for himself. He was speaking for all of us, this entire generation that grew up with dial-up internet but now lives in hyper-speed 5G. A generation that was told to “play it safe” but also to “dream big.” A generation that’s exhausted from trying to live two different lives at once.</p><p>And maybe that’s why so many of us are anxious, restless, sleepless. Because we’re carrying expectations from two different Indias, one that doesn’t exist anymore, and one we’re not sure we belong to.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 18:03:12 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
