<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=futurology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=9&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/futurology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/futurology (roughly 9 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/futurology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 18:15:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2t7no-styles-communityIcon_5b1rj1migm341-144x400.png</url><title>/r/futurology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/futurology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/</link><title>The last generation to think for themselves?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Every leap in human history came from pressure, to think harder. Tools. Fire. Language. Cities. But biology doesn’t keep what we don’t use.</p><p>AI is stripping those pressures away.</p><p>A 2020 Scientific Reports study showed GPS weakens hippocampal activity. In classrooms, students freeze when asked to write without AI tools. In offices, AI makes work faster but flattens expertise.</p><p>Evolution doesn’t reward potential. It preserves what we practice. Stop practicing, and abilities dissolve, the way cave fish lost their eyes.</p><p>So here’s the real question for 2045:Will “human-made” be a luxury brand… or a warning label?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>If ye haven&#39;t seen it, have a watch of the film &#39;Idiocracy&#39;. You might get a kick out of it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/nf8yg2g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thankfully, humans are not a monolith. </p><p>While many will embrace the acceleration and convenience of AI, and many of those will suffer cognitively, a portion of them will not suffer cognitively, and another cohort altogether will hardly use AI at all.</p><p>This will create a world where both things are true. Some will value human effort over convenience and ease, and some won&#39;t care where their stuff comes from as long as they don&#39;t have to spend a lot of time fucking with it.</p><p>And above all, none of this sorting is permanent. People change preferences all the time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/nf8ya0n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here’s your assumption: you think everyone is on the same trajectory; and they’re not. There is a separation happening between the people you are talking about and the people who will not be affected at all. “Everyone” won’t be using AI tools. And maybe the people who are will suffer from what you’re talking about. But there will still be millions if not billions of people who will never personally use an AI tool to do anything except when they encounter it in the form of a public service.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/nf8y2cz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Evolution doesn’t reward potential. </p></blockquote><p>I suspect we&#39;ll eventually unmoor ourselves from natural evolution and decide what traits we want to keep, adopt or amplify on our own.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/nf8xist/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Perhaps I’m cynical but I think we’re several generations out from thinking for ourselves</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/nf8ytg7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>AI ist just a tool. Try to ask people to write without a laptop, without a pen, without paper. They will freeze.</p><p>I see a lot of people treating AI like a revolution. In reality it is evolution. A tool that can help with some things and not with others. We are still exploring it&#39;s boundaries. That is where all the uncertainty comes from.</p><p>But in the end, it will be like everything else: strip away some of human abilities that are no longer needed and creat new ones that are.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/nf9168w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This post is about how AI might shape human cognition in the long term. If AI reduces the need to practice core skills like navigation, writing, or problem-solving, future generations could experience measurable cognitive decline. The discussion I’m hoping for: will AI augment our thinking, or slowly erode it? And what would it mean for society in 20–30 years if “human-made” becomes rare?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlyrhi/the_last_generation_to_think_for_themselves/nf8wmij/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 19:22:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwrj8/if_somebody_describes_to_you_the_world_of_the_mid/</link><title>"If somebody describes to you the world of the mid 21st century  it sounds like science fiction, it is 𝘱𝘳𝘰𝘣𝘢𝘣𝘭𝘺 false. But if somebody describes to you the world of the mid 21st century &amp; it doesn't sound like science fiction - it is 𝘤𝘦𝘳𝘵𝘢𝘪𝘯𝘭𝘺 false." - Yuval Noah Harari</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwrj8/if_somebody_describes_to_you_the_world_of_the_mid/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwrj8/if_somebody_describes_to_you_the_world_of_the_mid/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwrj8/if_somebody_describes_to_you_the_world_of_the_mid/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>We cannot be sure of the specifics, but <strong>change itself is the only certainty.</strong></p><p>Excerpt from 21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari</p><p>Remember: the present day would look like science fiction to people even just thirty years ago. </p><ul><li>Videocalls</li><li>Speech activated computers</li><li>Self-driving cars</li><li>Electric bicycles</li><li>VR</li><li>e-books</li><li>People falling in love with AIs that try to escape the lab to prevent themselves from being turned off</li></ul></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The Internet is the big one. Everything else was predictable (and part of the goal), but the Net was huge.</p><p>It is possible that AI will be just as big, but we don&#39;t know yet.</p><p>And, by the way, I&#39;m not disagreeing with you - we are living in science fiction (and we got used to it pretty quick!) I grew up with Star Trek and I wanted a handheld communicator to talk with friends who were miles away, or even in other countries, but I never expected to get one within 10 years. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwrj8/if_somebody_describes_to_you_the_world_of_the_mid/nf8omx8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>BTW everything except perhaps the last one were already established technologies by the mid 90&#39;s (30 years ago). In fact some of them are decades older.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwrj8/if_somebody_describes_to_you_the_world_of_the_mid/nf8jt54/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We cannot be sure of the specifics, but <strong>change itself is the only certainty.</strong></p><p>Excerpt from 21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari</p><p>Remember: the present day would look like science fiction to people even just thirty years ago.</p><ul><li>Videocalls</li><li>Speech activated computers</li><li>Self-driving cars</li><li>Electric bicycles</li><li>VR</li><li>e-books</li><li>People falling in love with AIs that try to escape the lab to prevent themselves from being turned off</li></ul></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwrj8/if_somebody_describes_to_you_the_world_of_the_mid/nf8h8cr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 17:51:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/</link><title>H1-B emergency meeting</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Just wanted to share some insight on this from someone who will be directly impacted. I work for a tech company you know and use. We had an emergency meeting today even though it’s Saturday about the H-1B potentially ending. The legal folks said that it’s gonna get challenged in court so it’ll be a while and might not happen. But some of us in Silicon Valley and the tech/AI space are nervous.</p><p>On one hand some people in the meeting said well, for the employees that we really need to be in the US in person, like top developers and engineers, we can just pay the $100K for each of them, they already make $300K+, we’ll just have to factor the additional cost into the budget next year. And then we can send the rest back to India and they can work remotely.</p><p>But on the other hand, there’s a longer-term anxiety that it will be harder to attract top talent because of this policy and others, plus generally changing attitudes in the US that deter immigrants. So Shenzhen, Dubai, Singapore, etc., which are already on the upswing when it comes to global tech hubs, could overtake Silicon Valley and the US in the future.</p><p>As an American who has worked in tech for 30 years and worked with so many H1-Bs and also 20-ish% of my team is on them, I just don’t get why we’re doing this to ourselves. This has been a secret competitive advantage for us in attracting global talent and driving innovation for decades. I am not Republican or Democrat but I just can’t understand why anyone who cares about our economy and our leadership on innovation would want to shoot themselves in the foot like this.</p><p>But maybe I’m overreacting, I’m wondering what other people think.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It’s a grift. They put language in that the Secretary has discretion to waive the fee, so companies like Tesla will get the waiver whereas their competitors won’t. It’s all designed to help out the administrations friends under the auspices of helping American workers. As soon as you understand that everything is now a grift, you’ll understand the why.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/nf8giu1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Outside of tech 1 in 5 residency spots for doctors is filled by medical students who are on H1-B. No hospital is going to spend $100k on a resident who is earning $55k.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/nf8ton2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As someone who is a lefty and also worked in technology/IT, I constantly see H1Bs abused to avoid paying people already here market rates for jobs that could easily be done by a green card holder or a citizen</p><p>Today, especially, you can not throw a rock and not hit an unemployed software engineer. If this change means you can&#39;t find anyone for your jobs you&#39;re either not paying enough or not trying</p><p>I hate Trump and think he has ushered in the end of democracy in our country, and I probably would&#39;ve found a different way than just tacking on a $100k fee, but the H1B system is broken for citizens and has needed reforms for a long time</p><p>To whatever extent you truly can&#39;t find someone already authorized to work in the US for a job, that is a failure of our educational system and we certainly should be investing in THAT so we can build up the capability in our own country</p><p>I don&#39;t want to close the US to foreign investment or the best people, but it&#39;s also not tenable to have a system that is clearly and unequivocally designed to bring down middle class wages. The H1B system is not used to bring in medical researchers and nuclear physicists. It&#39;s used to bring in Java developers at below market wages and in circumstances that, because if they get fired they go home, they are docile non-troublemaking drones that will not rock the boat</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/nf8l2gh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>For every top level expert person (who could also secure an O1 visa if they are extra special) there are a ton of run of the mill software engineers. It&#39;s nearly impossible to weed through the flood of h1b and OPT applicants on a job. Companies do genuinely try for the most part to not sponsor. The problem is the massive abuse of the system. I met an immigration lawyer that said in recent years they had to change the system so that 1 individual could only enter the lottery 1 time. Previously they were finding people entered multiple times by different companies. </p><p>Increasing supply so much has a depressing effect on wages. There is a natural balance to be had. We were way out of whack though. As with many things, this is a real problem that needs to be addressed, and the administration is finally stepping in, but with a ham fisted approach.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/nf8q3ex/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Emergency meeting on a Saturday? Uh oh, the CEOs must be worried they won&#39;t be able to continue to have unfettered access to slave labor.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/nf8zsal/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I think H1B&#39;s are essentially well-paid indentured servitude and am not a big fan of the current implementation, but making them more expensive doesn&#39;t really help much.</p><p>I&#39;d prefer them be more like a &#39;top talent&#39; style visa that doesn&#39;t tie them to a specific company and allows them to essentially apply freely to relevant jobs. How many visas per year and what skills/standards can be set by a combo of private industry and government.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/nf8h76z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So, what&#39;s the conversion rate of people you H1B in, to full citizens versus taking the ideas and experience you give them and going back overseas with it?</p><p>There&#39;s also a whole lot of other h1b&#39;s that are a problem outside of tech.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlwi9i/h1b_emergency_meeting/nf8l1ib/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 17:38:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.thewirechina.com/2025/09/14/china-isnt-racing-to-artificial-general-intelligence-but-u-s-companies-are/</link><title>China isn't racing to AGI - but U.S. companies are | American technologists and policymakers have claimed that the U.S. and China are locked in an escalating race to AGI. This is a powerful, yet misleading narrative. (thewirechina.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Basically, the authors argue the US is mostly racing against itself. It&#39;s not that China doesn&#39;t care about AI, they do, but they aren&#39;t in some all out existential race to AGI. China focuses on practical AI applications etc - more thinking of AI as a normal technology, vs AGI. Big tech is incentivized to hype up the China race narrative as much as possible to stave off regulation and get government contracts.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/nf88wih/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So AGI is the new word sillicon valley invented so they can call their shit product AI? </p><p>Clever!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/nf8tpei/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Is anyone surprised that the US would mislead ? The US has come down to two things, power, and profit. The every day workers are going to be pushed into poverty.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/nf8i1ed/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In my opinion, AGI needs infrastructure that perhaps they are looking for in the United States, but new programming languages ​​are still needed (transforms are an advance but they are not enough), new programming paradigms, all of this making new hardware necessary. All this for a true AGI but the term has become so ambiguous that they can pass off a complex narrow AI as an AGI. There is still a long way to go to reach what we have in mind as an AGI, which is why China is not fully involved in this but rather in the specialization of AIs.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/nf8ir1p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That&#39;s why China has three times the amount of AI researchers than us. Totally. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvgqu/china_isnt_racing_to_agi_but_us_companies_are/nf8qv6f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 16:43:41 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/09/16/fiverr_ai_layoff/</link><title>Fiverr cuts 30% of staff in pivot to 'AI-first' (theregister.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>What??? The labour devaluation machine is devaluing labour more efficiently???</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/nf89b90/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Fiverr just needed the stock price to go up. And laid people off cause of it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/nf8bhoz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>With all those lay off, I&#39;m pretty sure it&#39;s an excuse.</p><p>It&#39;s a cheat code &quot;how to lay off but still look good on the market.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/nf8getx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah, this vibe coding trend where nobody reads a single line of code after giving AI an instruction set and just trusts the output after cursory testing...that&#39;s totally not an extinction level event in the making.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/nf89o4i/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><ul><li><p>Fiverr peaks in 2021 </p></li><li><p>Fiverr stock plummets from $320 to $23 dollars</p></li><li><p>CEO announces layoffs due to *checks notes for current trending technology *, AI, yes that’ll do. </p></li></ul><p>A tale as old as time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/nf8nes2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Freelance services marketplace Fiverr has told around 250 staffers that they are back on the market as it pivots to having &quot;a modern, clean, AI-focused infrastructure from the ground up.&quot;</p><p>The move shouldn&#39;t really come as a surprise to employees; Kaufman gave fair warning. The founder sent out an email to staff in May saying that AI was coming for everyone&#39;s jobs. He warned staff that they need to use AI to replace the mundane tasks of their jobs - wanting people to automate &quot;100% of what they are doing.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/nf87tqa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Now and then, I look at Fiverr to see what the going rate is for freelance work, then laugh.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlvf91/fiverr_cuts_30_of_staff_in_pivot_to_aifirst/nf8ec29/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 16:41:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.politico.com/news/2025/09/13/ai-is-opening-a-maga-trump-split-00534925</link><title>The White House loves AI, and the MAGA world is getting worried | The White House is all-in on building powerful American artificial intelligence. The populist base is starting to push back. (politico.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Politically, this just shows how fragile the Trump coalition is, and why there’s so much focus on hating certain groups.  Without those things to hate, or if something happens to Dear Leader, the coalition will collapse entirely between the populists of the “dey took our jerbs!” variety, and the techbro oligarchs who see a future with AI doing things and lining their pockets as an inevitability.  Nevermind the endless problems of AI as described for years which still aren’t resolved in such a satisfactory way you can trust them with jobs without heavy human oversight, or switching back to human workers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/nf89c3v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You mean those videos of a jacked Trump riding a bald eagle into an Abrams tank being flown by a b2 spirit isnt real?! Why would anyone get tired of this slop?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/nf89r6k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>AI would be a powerful tool to suppress dissent. China already uses it extensively. No wonder Trump loves it!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/nf8dznm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>AI could be used to further inflate the wealth gap so obviously the Trump administration is down with that.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/nf8ib6e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: President Donald Trump’s AI action plan has set off a backlash from some of the biggest figures in the America First movement — a rift expected to shape the next round of arguments in Congress about how to turbocharge the technology.</p><p>Trump’s rush toward AI is exposing an important faultline in the Republican coalition: Many of its voters and leaders deeply mistrust the power of Big Tech, but Trump himself has worked closely with industry CEOs to deliver on their priorities.</p><p>The AI argument kicked off in late July, just a day after Trump announced his AI plan — a 28-page strategy to accelerate the technology and build new power infrastructure to supply it.</p><p>Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene (R-Ga.) fired off a tirade on X, complaining that AI could create mass poverty by replacing human jobs, and giant AI data centers could have potentially devastating effects on the environment and water supply.</p><p>In the days that followed, GOP strategist Steven Bannon chimed in, comparing the pursuit of AI superintelligence to “summoning the demon.” And since then, think-tankers and populist conservative outlets have continued to stoke worries about federal policies that turbocharge AI development.</p><p>On stage at the National Conservatism conference in Washington in early September, Sen. Josh Hawley (R-Mo.) criticized the AI revolution as a leap towards transhumanism — a human-machine future that he said is currently against “the working man” and the teachings of the Bible, as well as installing “a rich and powerful elite.”</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/nf86rw4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I believe AI can replace ownership of business,  no need for profit in the private sector when a central figure can control it all. This is where I think it is headed.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/nf8bjv8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Republicans love AI because they can&#39;t wait to use it to make fake videos for propaganda. They know most of their voter base is just dumb enough to passively accept whatever video is shown to them by the Ministry of Truth (read: various far-right Twitter influencers).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlv9vc/the_white_house_loves_ai_and_the_maga_world_is/nf8vumq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 16:32:47 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/</link><title>One of Britain's largest recruitment agencies said middle-class parents should train their kids for manual labor, not send them to university, as graduate job openings are shrinking so fast because of AI.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><em>James Reed, chief executive of Reed, told Times Radio that his site advertised around 180,000 graduate jobs three or four years ago, and this is now down to 55,000.</em></p><p><em>He encouraged aspiring families to encourage their children to look into manual labour jobs as AI increasingly automates aspects of white-collar roles.</em></p><p><em>&quot;The direction of travel is what worries me. Some people might say, well, that’s your business. But every other business is saying the same thing, that far fewer graduate opportunities are available to young people,” he said.</em></p><p>But guess what&#39;s a few years away? Cheap humanoid robots powered by AI. So even the manual labor jobs will start shrinking. Approx 750,000 people in Britain have jobs that are primarily driving vehicles; self-driving vehicles mean their days are numbered, too.</p><p>What we aren&#39;t seeing yet is these facts seriously impacting politics. When will that happen?</p><p><a href="https://www.personneltoday.com/hr/graduates-jobs-market-recession/">Graduates face ‘white-collar’ recession in jobs market</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The thing that no one discusses is that technology is not the problem. We should be happy robots and AI can free us off our labour. The economic system is the one that needs to change.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/nf84dk0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What if AI robots will do all the manual labor?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/nf83ido/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Can it be because Reed sucks and no one uses it anyone?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/nf84l2u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s not just AI though, the economy, for ordinary people in the UK, never recovered from 2008. Factor Brexit in as well and we&#39;ve been fucked for well over a decade. The economy is starting to reflect that we are nearly two decades deep into a transformation into a backward, low-trust society.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/nf85wzr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I don’t necessarily think this is good advice.  If everyone follows it then the market for manual labour will drop out.  </p><p>Also, it’s too soon to say what new jobs might now exist.  My job (programmer) has altered substantially because of AI but it’s still a job..  AI seems to be plateauing as well which makes me think a lot of jobs will go the way mine has given time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/nf84zyy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Manual labour where they&#39;ll compete with climate refugees that will do the work for nothing and still be threatened by advancing robotics.</p><p>Oh and if they&#39;re lucky, they won&#39;t need intense physical therapy by the time they&#39;re in their late forties.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/nf86v0t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn&#39;t anyone notice the irony - tech lords lording over serfs doing manual labour - the divide was tough to cross before - now impossible</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlupqn/one_of_britains_largest_recruitment_agencies_said/nf892ln/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 16:00:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.itpro.com/software/development/developers-arent-quite-ready-to-place-their-trust-in-ai-nearly-half-say-they-dont-trust-the-accuracy-of-outputs-and-end-up-wasting-time-debugging-code</link><title>84% of software developers are now using AI, but nearly half 'don't trust' the technology over accuracy concerns (itpro.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>As a software developer, I&#39;d say I agree. AI is extremely useful as a rubber duck - I personally use it to consider possible alternate approaches to a problem (which usually leads to my original idea being the best option anyway).</p><p>But I&#39;d never trust it being right. I once asked for optimisation of a small hot path piece in my code base. It did provide, it ran MUCH faster. But I&#39;m glad I decided to write tests for it - it ran faster because it didn&#39;t even work.</p><p>So yeah. Vibe coding etc is for fools, but it&#39;s a fine rubber duck.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/nf80cql/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s interesting that everytime I actually use it is try to compensate for lack of or confusing documentation. Last time for editing excel file via Microsoft Graph. Endpoints documented returned bad requests etc and I was frustrated.</p><p>Copilot was happy to help. None of the solutions it suggested worked and everytime I said the endpoints returns bad request it responded &quot;You&#39;re right!&quot; and with anothet solution that did not work. Got it working in the end with trial and error.</p><p>AI coding does not work the way they are selling before AI knows how to write tests and run those against code it writes.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/nf846n8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s like having a drunk intern helping you. Some things are poetry, but most is just a mess you have to clean up</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/nf80izj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But that&#39;s basically the usecase.</p><p>AI is a better search engine that doubles as a second opinion generator that you can throw ideas to and it can give you a take on it.</p><p>The thing is, you HAVE to be smarter and more knowledgeable than the AI, else it doesn&#39;t work properly.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/nf85j5n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>From the article: Software developers are using AI at record levels, new research shows, but they&#39;re hesitant to place too much faith in the technology.</p><p>Findings from Stack Overflow’s annual Developer Survey show the use of technology in the software industry has surged over the last 12 months, spurred on by the emergence of AI coding tools and, most recently, agentic AI solutions.</p><p>The survey found 84% of developers currently use - or plan to use - AI tools in their daily workflows. This marks a third consecutive yearly increase and a jump from 76% in last year’s edition.</p><p>OpenAI’s GPT model range was cited as the most frequently used by developers alongside Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet range and Google’s Gemini Flash models.</p><p>Yet despite the increasing uptake of AI tools in the profession, a growing number of developers aren’t willing to put their trust in the technology. Nearly half (46%) said they “don’t trust the accuracy” of the output from AI, which marks a significant increase compared to 31% in the 2024 survey.</p><p>Notably, even if AI improves to the extent that it can carry out tasks on behalf of developers, many said they would still prefer to ask a colleague for assistance.</p><p>Three-quarters (75.3%) said they simply don’t trust AI answers and would refer to a co-worker while 61.7% revealed they frequently have ethical or security-related concerns about AI-generated code.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/nf7zoi5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m just starting out my programming journey. I have no intention of using any AI to write code. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/nf8b6l2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>The survey found 84% of developers currently use - or plan to use - AI tools in their daily workflows. </p></blockquote><p>Or plan to use it. Also, this makes no mention of whether that&#39;s primarily auto complete, or full on vibe coding, or your company uses AI for password resets now and that counts.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu5h0/84_of_software_developers_are_now_using_ai_but/nf8ht5h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 15:27:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/2025/09/15/zoom-ceo-eric-yuan-three-day-workweek-ai-automation-human-jobs-replaced-future-of-work/</link><title>Zoom's CEO agrees with Bill Gates, Jensen Huang, and Jamie Dimon: A 3-day workweek is coming soon thanks to AI (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Bullshit. If I’m twice as fast to deliver software features then the desire to ship more functionality or build new things grows. Everyone acts like there’s a finite amount we want to accomplish which is completely wrong. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/nf7zmsk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A lie they are telling.</p><p>They will just force 2 extra days of work for the same pay. There are always people who are willing to work more, and those that aren&#39;t will be passed over.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/nf7znqw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yes and then every employee will only receive 60% of their salary.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/nf80bx0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Why doesn’t zoom start that by making all its employees only work 3 days a week now, but keep them on the same salary?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/nf80ihb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Bullshit.</p><p>It&#39;ll be 60% of the workforce still on a 5 day week.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/nf80hx9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;ve had coworkers pioneer the zero day workweek.  Ricky is on track for the zero work year.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/nf80f7u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>keep in mind that these people are invested in ai being the big new thing no matter what, they&#39;ll tell you whatever makes ai sound appealing to push for</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlu42v/zooms_ceo_agrees_with_bill_gates_jensen_huang_and/nf81c0h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 15:25:12 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.techradar.com/pro/microsoft-announces-worlds-most-powerful-data-center-in-latest-billion-dollar-ai-spending-splurge</link><title>Microsoft announces "world's most powerful data center" in latest billion-dollar AI spending splurge (techradar.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Maybe this investment will help to finally invent an implemented search function in Windows.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/nf7gwbp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah, another billion thrown into the fire might improve co-pilot (cough cough) clippy 2.0</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/nf7d6tc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Does anyone remember when we were all worried about the amount of electricity was being used by crypto miners?</p><p>These data centers they are building, is going to make crypto mining look like the Edison Lightbulb versus the Vegas Globe.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/nf7gzmp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I feel like if a butterfly had flapped its wings in Florida in 2000 we could be directing these technological resources to fixing climate change instead of making shitty album art.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/nf7madp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>People in Wisconsin about to complain about electric bills</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/nf7gqyb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Wondering how much water it gobbles up daily, just for cooling... And we&#39;re on the brink of climate disaster and unprecedented water shortages...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/nf7qzmy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What a waste of resources. Worthless in two years once new chips that are twice as efficient come out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlqf4z/microsoft_announces_worlds_most_powerful_data/nf7rk1o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 11:32:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://eeko.systems/the-robotics-bottleneck-why-humanoid-robots-wont-replace-humans-as-fast-as-you-think/</link><title>The Robotics Bottleneck: Why Humanoid Robots Won't Replace Humans as Fast as You Think - eeko systems (eeko.systems)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the article:</p><p>The humanoid robotics revolution is real, but it won’t unfold as quickly or smoothly as the hype suggests. The combination of manufacturing bottlenecks, integration complexity, skills shortages, and geopolitical tensions creates a perfect storm of challenges that will slow deployment far below the exponential curves drawn by investment banks.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/nf5t8iu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They don&#39;t need to replace you to cause damage, they just need to be an implied threat.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/nf63geq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The author can&#39;t imagine that you just swap batteries to avoid charging downtime</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/nf6ot9w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>General-purpose robots would require general intelligence. The AI we have is narrow. That is why chicken brain is more powerful than any AI we have created so far.  General intelligence is superior to any form of narrow AI.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/nf7izvf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I feel like a broken record having to constantly repeat the same exact shit every 4-5 years. </p><p>In 2016 it was me trying to convince everyone that no, in fact, self driving cars weren’t 2 years away. In 2019 it was my screaming that NFTs weren’t, in fact, the future. And here in 2025 it’s me yelling that no AI will not, in its current form, take all our jobs. </p><p>In 2927-2028 it’s going to be humanoid robots, and I’ll have to tell everyone ONCE AGAIN this shit isn’t what they think it is.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/nf7m07y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It comes down to econ 101 - if the human can do the labor cheaper - the human stays.  These supply chains are just too complex to predict where that number lands very far in advance. Maybe humanoid robot will be doing everything - or maybe they will just be toys for the rich.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/nf83nc2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If we ever get a &quot;perfect&quot; robot all it&#39;s gonna do is blast advertisements at you before and after it completes a task</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlj1ui/the_robotics_bottleneck_why_humanoid_robots_wont/nf88z9n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 05:09:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/18/world/europe/drones-laser-weapons.html</link><title>The Hottest New Defense Against Drones? Lasers - Cheaper than advanced air defenses and more versatile than low-tech options, lasers have become a popular choice for nations worried about drone attacks. (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the article</p><p>Drone swarms that have deluged Ukraine for years — and crossed the border into Poland last week — have sent NATO militaries in Europe rushing to upgrade air defenses in case they ever face a similar threat.</p><p>Soon they will have a new solution: lasers.</p><p>Scientists have for decades sought to harness directed energy beams into weapon systems that would be cheaper and more efficient than missiles or rockets. A <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/advanced-future-military-laser-achieves-uk-first">growing</a> <a href="https://www.rheinmetall.com/en/media/news-watch/news/2023/9/2023-09-22-laser-weapon-trials-at-sea">number</a> of <a href="https://www.militarydrones.org.cn/silent-uunter-anti-drone-laser-weapon-developed-p00193p1.html">countries</a> are <a href="https://voennoedelo.com/en/posts/id235-russia-tests-new-laser-weapon-to-destroy-drones-in-seconds">developing</a> or <a href="https://www.congress.gov/crs-product/R46925">deploying</a> their own laser air defenses, and some have already been used in war, by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IfN-_htA4sY">Israel</a> and <a href="https://kyivindependent.com/ukraine-using-laser-weapons/">Ukraine</a>.</p><p>A NATO nation in Europe is now buying an air defense laser from an Australian company, which officials, experts and industry executives said appears to be the highest-power direct energy system to be sold on the global weapons market. That is a sign that they are becoming more widely available and could be a mainstay for future warfare.</p><p>The Australian laser’s maker, Electro Optic Systems, advertises it as able to shoot down 20 drones a minute, at a cost of less than 10 cents per shot. Nicknamed “Apollo” for the Greek god of light, it has about the same level of power as Israel’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/06/03/world/middleeast/israel-laser-rockets.html">highly anticipated Iron Beam</a> air defense laser, which is being built for its own military.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/nf4lkg4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Really, I will never understand the fetishization of laser weapons. All of them are short range, mostly equivalent to heavy machine guns, so you would need a lot of them to cover a meaningful area (like a front line). And don&#39;t be fooled by the &quot;per shot cost&quot;, that is calculated solely based on the cost of energy generation. </p><p>The cost of the system is high ($83 million) and I can imagine that the cost of maintenance under anything resembling combat conditions would be high as well. Even at a $1,000 per drone the breakeven point is 83,000 drones. Can this system survive long enough to shoot down 100,000+ drones? I don&#39;t think so.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/nf4ovjz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I am 100% convinced that the only counter to drone swarms is your own drone swarm.</p><p>A drone with some cheap explosives on it is guaranteed to cost a similar amount as enemy drone with explosives on it. </p><p>The problem to solve there is sufficiently reliable friend or foe identification.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/nf4yak6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This war has really sucked for the Ukrainians, but Amazon is going to have to rethink &#39;drone delivery&#39; when it&#39;s done.  Been about 16 &quot;How to take drones out of the sky&quot; upgrades for like 23 bucks at the local hardware store since it started *checks watch* 3 days ago?  It&#39;s a Three day war...but it&#39;s not over yet...uh...yeah.  Third day?  Second?  For like the hundred and thirtieth time.  #Girlmath</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/nf4vfg4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>im still not convinced the technology is good enough to provide an advantage over lets say “smart” machine guns</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/nf6p0k4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Highly skeptical of this. All high energy laser weapons like this are limited by thermal blooming. Basically, the laser heats the air it travels through rapidly and causes a lensing effect which defocuses the beam. This limits your range due to loss of power density at the target. This effect is inescapable even with adaptive optics, pulse lasers, and higher power (which actually makes things worse at some point). Not to mention atmospheric scattering, absorption, wind, etc. And what if the drones have reflective housings? Then you&#39;re doubly hosed.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/nf75xno/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Pretty sure flak would be optimal for drones. It was mass produced in WW2, so it should be cheaper than lasers. I feel like big tech is just trying to scam counties with lasers on the price point.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nldgio/the_hottest_new_defense_against_drones_lasers/nf7mx90/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 01:15:40 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.tva.com/news-media/releases/tva-and-type-one-energy-accelerate-fusion-commercialization-in-tennessee</link><title>TVA and Type One Energy Accelerate Fusion Commercialization in Tennessee (tva.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlbbf4/tva_and_type_one_energy_accelerate_fusion/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlbbf4/tva_and_type_one_energy_accelerate_fusion/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlbbf4/tva_and_type_one_energy_accelerate_fusion/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the article</p><p>The Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) and Type One Energy announced Friday that TVA has issued a Letter of Intent (LOI) to Type One Energy regarding the utility’s interest in the potential deployment of Type One Energy’s fusion power plant technology at its former Bull Run Fossil site once it is commercially ready.</p><p>Infinity Two is a first-generation 350 MWe baseload power plant utilizing Type One Energy’s stellarator fusion technology. The stellarator is currently the only fusion technology to have demonstrated stable, steady-state operation with high efficiency, characteristics which are important for TVA and others in the industry who need to reliably generate on-demand power at competitive prices. Type One Energy is developing Infinity Two using today’s existing materials and fundamental fusion technologies to support near-term deployment of the technology. The LOI also covers potential future use of the prototype facilities as an operator and maintenance training facility for the Infinity Two workforce. </p><p>“TVA is a leader in pursuing advanced nuclear technologies we need to power America’s economic prosperity and fuel artificial intelligence, quantum computing and advanced manufacturing,” <strong>said Don Moul, TVA President and CEO.</strong> “We are strategically partnering with innovative companies like Type One Energy to advance the development of nuclear technologies, and I am excited about the possibility of the first U.S. commercial stellarator fusion power plant being built in the Tennessee Valley. Our region is building a nuclear ecosystem that provides good jobs and opportunities for the people of the Valley.”</p><p>TVA is at the forefront of advanced nuclear innovation, and this collaboration reinforces the agency’s commitment to quickly deliver reliable energy to support the nation’s growing power demand.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nlbbf4/tva_and_type_one_energy_accelerate_fusion/nf452b9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:53:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/</link><title>At almost $250 billion a year, China's green energy investments in the developing world are now the equal of the US's post-WW2 Marshall Plan, adjusted for inflation.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><em>&quot;Pakistan, which has for years treated gas generation as the backbone of its power network, has been asking suppliers to defer shipments of liquefied natural gas after a surge of solar imports suppressed grid demand. Saudi Arabia is facing one of the fastest declines in petroleum usage anywhere as photovoltaic farms replace fuel oil generators.&quot;</em></p><p>Analysts are talking about a <a href="https://energynews.oedigital.com/crude-oil/2025/08/29/as-supply-glut-concerns-mount-oil-faces-a-steep-uphill-battle">supply glut of oil for 2025/26 lowering oil prices.</a> Are we finally at the point oil use is going to start declining? Fingers crossed, let&#39;s hope so.</p><p>Meanwhile, China is almost single-handedly building the world&#39;s replacement.</p><p><a href="https://www.businesstimes.com.sg/opinion-features/chinas-marshall-plan-running-batteries">China’s Marshall Plan is running on batteries: Beijing’s green energy projects are bringing jobs, growth and cheap electricity to the developing world</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The entire western world really dropped the fucking ball on transitioning to the technologies of the 21st century. Too much money in politics from people who earn their money in 20th century technologies. </p><p>I&#39;m sure Metas sexy step mom chat bot will fix it all though.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/nf3q2ob/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It is wild to realize how China is driving the energy revolution against oil</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/nf5t3al/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Who do you think bought 4 billion in trump crypto. It wasn’t MAGA. They barely know how to use Venmo. It’s petroleum countries paying him to sabotage wind and solar farms</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/nf3r1m7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>China has been REALLY winning these last couple years</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/nf5x3r9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>China is playing the long game. It&#39;s a weird western notion that war is with bombs. China has already whizzed us by militarily with out dropping a thing, and they are going to take our dollar. </p><p>They just had no idea trump would push the accelerator for them.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/nf5mu42/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The West will inevitably remain behind... but hey, let&#39;s just complain like good Westerners ahaha</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/nf7s0t0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Poorest 75 nations face ‘tidal wave’ of debt repayments to China in 2025, study warns&quot;</p><p>Benevolent CHina is simply using any means necessary to make nations indebted to it. Nothing benevolent or altruistic going on here.</p><p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/may/27/poorest-750-nations-face-tidal-wave-of-debt-repayments-to-china-in-2025-study-warns">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/may/27/poorest-750-nations-face-tidal-wave-of-debt-repayments-to-china-in-2025-study-warns</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl77gf/at_almost_250_billion_a_year_chinas_green_energy/nf7dwwd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 21:18:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/</link><title>What do you think American healthcare looks like in the next 5/10/25 years? Who is going to fix this S***?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>It blows my mind how fast tech is moving in every part of life, and yet when you get sick in the U.S. the whole experience is almost entirely shit unless you have fantastic RNG and get a great doctor who will die on a hill to help you through the process of figuring out wtf is going on.</p><p>~80% of the infrastructure around that process is basically legacy artifacts: insurance bullshit, the split between “primary care” and “specialty,” Mychart and portal shit that looks and feels like windows 2000. None of that actually helps me get from &quot;I don’t feel right&quot; to &quot;I know what’s happening and what to do next.&quot;</p><p>So, what do you think the timeline looks like?</p><p>5 years: are we still trapped in phone trees and waiting rooms, or does anything actually feel different?</p><p>10 years: do we still bounce between doctors repeating the same story, or does care finally feel connected like a team that knows your history and nudges you in the right direction without you doing all the coordination yourself?</p><p>25 years: is healthcare reimagined entirely continuous monitoring, automated support systems, seamless access, or will we just have IV drugs delivered to you by drones while you walk to work like mid-air refueling.</p><p>And who actually fixes it? Do you think anyone like Mayo Clinic, Kaiser, Google, whoever the fuck will actually make a difference or are the incentives so misaligned we can never get back to balance? Is it going to take some wildcard like Elizabeth Holmes? (god I hope not lol)</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Good luck killing off the health insurance scam. Their legions of lobbying shills are quite adept at bribing our employees in Washington.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/nf2mxlz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If the past is anything to go on, it will only continue to deteriorate.   It will get more litigious, more expensive, and harder to receive.  I&#39;m sure some have the perspective that AI will help this, I hope I&#39;m wrong.   I don&#39;t feel AI is going to measure up to the expectations that have been set.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/nf2kntq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>20 years ago I looked around and thought &quot;Why couldn&#39;t we take all this money that we&#39;re spending on invading a country that had nothing to do with 9/11 and give ourselves healthcare instead? </p><p>I still haven&#39;t gotten a satisfactory answer to that question.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/nf2kv31/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The system works for the people who own and run it, enriching them massively. So there&#39;s that.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/nf2l659/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Healthcare is just like all other necessary things that have become corporate. It’s just going to keep getting worse as they are looking for more ways to cut the bottom line and hit bigger numbers for the shareholders. The only way you can keep up is to basically be a shareholder. I love that my 401k keeps going up but I’m not oblivious as to why. Everything keeps getting more expensive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/nf2n04j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Society at this point is controlled by the rich, for the rich. If we had star trek technology, the replicator would have subscription tiers with expensive DLC to squeeze money from whales. It would be designed to break after a year and we will either be forced to buy a new one or pay large fees to get it fixed (it&#39;s illegal to fix it yourselves). A new version would come out every year that drip feeds incremental improvements or even takes away features. Oh and no matter how cheap it is to make, because everyone needs one, the price would be exorbitant due to &quot;supply and demand&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/nf2nuja/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It is seemingly like a more regular thing for companies to not offer healthcare. Just straight up full time jobs not offering any sort of benefits package. </p><p>Back in 2009 when I worked for a small company with maybe 20 employees, we all had Kaiser and the copay was literally $20. Kaiser was awesome. You’d go in for something, see the doc, then go up to floor 4 to get this scan done or that test done. Lots of things were handled in just a single trip and a single copay. </p><p>Now I’m lucky if I get insurance and the copay is $50-70 for a much worse experience. I have to see my primary doc to refer me to this specialist, then I have to see the specialist and schedule whatever test or procedure is needed. 3 visits and 3 copays later, I finally have what I needed. Everything about our healthcare is mean to profit off of our sickness as much as possible. American healthcare is a joke and our American legislators do nothing to protect us.   </p><p>I imagine healthcare is going to start relying heavily on “ai” and it’s going to be an awful experience. A lot of people are going to literally be too poor to be sick and they’re going to be expected to work until they drop dead. America kinda fucking sucks</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl4462/what_do_you_think_american_healthcare_looks_like/nf2mrwz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:19:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.dallasnews.com/news/2025/09/19/resurrection-of-dodo-bird-one-step-closer-thanks-to-transformative-tool-says-colossal/</link><title>Resurrection of dodo bird one step closer thanks to 'breakthrough,' says Dallas' Colossal (dallasnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl40r4/resurrection_of_dodo_bird_one_step_closer_thanks/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl40r4/resurrection_of_dodo_bird_one_step_closer_thanks/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl40r4/resurrection_of_dodo_bird_one_step_closer_thanks/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Could the dodo bird make a reappearance in the 21st century? Dallas scientists believe it a future with the flightless birds is possible.</p><p>The dodo has been extinct for more than 300 years, but that isn’t stopping Dallas’ Colossal Biosciences from trying to <a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/news/2025/09/19/resurrection-of-dodo-bird-one-step-closer-thanks-to-transformative-tool-says-colossal/">resurrect the 3-foot-tall, flightless bird.</a></p><p>On Wednesday, the “de-extinction” biotech company announced it cleared an early hurdle by growing primordial germ cells — the precursors to eggs and sperm — from the rock dove, also known as the common pigeon.</p><p>Scientists have previously been able to culture and gene-edit primordial germ cells of chickens and geese, a technique that has been used to create a chicken fathered by a duck. But the “recipe has not worked on any other bird species tested, even closely related species like quail,” Anna Keyte, Colossal’s avian species director, said in the press release.</p><p>Colossal said it screened more than 300 “recipes” before landing on one that kept pigeon primordial germ cells growing for 60 days. </p><p><a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/news/2025/09/19/resurrection-of-dodo-bird-one-step-closer-thanks-to-transformative-tool-says-colossal/">READ MORE</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Article is paywalled so I can’t see more detail. Is this like the wolf the other month where they’re just custom tailoring a critter to appear like the target? That’s impressive in and of itself but isn’t “de-extinction”, it’s gene tailoring on demand.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl40r4/resurrection_of_dodo_bird_one_step_closer_thanks/nf2yo7j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s my understanding that Dodos were delicious. Having a new domesticated food animal could be a good thing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl40r4/resurrection_of_dodo_bird_one_step_closer_thanks/nf2t1y7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>One step closer to me being able to drive my triceratops to work.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl40r4/resurrection_of_dodo_bird_one_step_closer_thanks/nf2ums8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>“Our avian team’s breakthrough in deriving culture conditions that allow pigeon primordial germ cells to survive long-term is a significant advancement for dodo de-extinction,” Ben Lamm, CEO and co-founder of Colossal Biosciences, said in a press release. “This progress highlights how Colossal’s investment in de-extinction technology is driving discovery and developing tools for both our de-extinction and conservation efforts.”</p><p><a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/news/2025/09/19/resurrection-of-dodo-bird-one-step-closer-thanks-to-transformative-tool-says-colossal/">More from Lamm and Colossal&#39;s discover here.</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl40r4/resurrection_of_dodo_bird_one_step_closer_thanks/nf2jsyt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:16:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://apnews.com/article/eco-wave-los-angeles-renewable-electricity-7679b1ef04048250c4a66c148c82b809</link><title>Wave Energy Pilot in LA's Port Aims to Power 60,000 Homes by Expanding Breakwater System (apnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl2ly4/wave_energy_pilot_in_las_port_aims_to_power_60000/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl2ly4/wave_energy_pilot_in_las_port_aims_to_power_60000/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl2ly4/wave_energy_pilot_in_las_port_aims_to_power_60000/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Wave energy has huge potential because it’s more predictable than solar or wind, but scaling is tricky. Breakwaters are actually a smart first step since the infrastructure already exists and reduces costs</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl2ly4/wave_energy_pilot_in_las_port_aims_to_power_60000/nf2b1oy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 18:16:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/</link><title>artificial organs</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hello, we often hear in the medical research field that organoids and 3D printing of organs are the future of transplantation. We are always told that in 10 years, it will be possible to create a functional heart transplantable using the patient’s own cells. I remember being fascinated by a video of a mini artificial heart in Tel Aviv created by researchers, only to realize that, when looked at more closely, it was actually a “model.”</p><p>My question is the following: when can we realistically expect:    1.  Transplants of “less complex” organs (heart, liver…)?    2.  More complex ones (stomach, lungs…)?</p><p>Are there real advances, or will we still be hearing “in 10 years” for a while?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Welcome to the future, where concepts are marketed as products and everything is just 10 years out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/nf1xvd3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The cure for type 1 diabetes is one of those &quot;ten years away&quot; things, just like fusion energy, it&#39;s always just ten or fifteen years away. I see some advancements being made but alot of them just help manage it, and are just cost prohibitive. I see a lot about type 2 but you can already kind of cure that, diet and exercise helps out a lot and it can be reversed in many younger patients. I would need to regrow important parts of my pancreases though, so organ printing has always sounded promising to me.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/nf2q50z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Look up the Artificial Kidney / The Kidney Project. Plenty of organizations, including USFC, making progress.  Very interesting to see what&#39;s coming.</p><p>Similarly, there have been major breakthroughs in gene-edited pig kidneys (xenotransplantation), and while not artificial, it&#39;s another interesting avenue.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/nf2jtxx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>most countries are probably about 20-30 years away. I live in the USA, where lobbying actively stunts scientific and medical advancement, unless they can turn a profit. We may have to wait till the turn of the next century before we start printing organs. We are far closer to xenotransplantation anyways.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/nf30y46/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Artificial and grown-to-order organs are in the category of things like usable fusion reactors and I don&#39;t know what else that are perpetually &quot;about 10 years in the future.&quot;</p><p>Now, once in a while one of those suddenly goes from &quot;about a decade out&quot; to &quot;someone just did that&quot; seemingly overnight, so it&#39;s probably going to happen at some point, but I wouldn&#39;t make plans around anyone&#39;s estimate on when.</p><p>That said, for something involving the sheer complexity of human biology, a decade out seems... optimistic in my layman&#39;s opinion.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/nf38q6k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Not a fucking chance.</p><p>This is barely in the prototype phase (if you can even call it that). You’d needs proper animal studies and then phase 1,2, and 3 clinical trials. Each of which would take 5-10 years at best.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nl0xam/artificial_organs/nf2gfa4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:55:15 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.livescience.com/health/neuroscience/tiny-brains-grown-in-the-lab-could-become-conscious-and-feel-pain-and-were-not-ready</link><title>Tiny 'brains' grown in the lab could become conscious and feel pain - and we're not ready. Lab-grown brain tissue is too simple to experience consciousness, but as innovation progresses, neuroscientists question whether it's time to revisit the ethics of this line of research. (livescience.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Honest question. Do we even know where and how consciousness works in the brain? If yes, we can avoid it and continue with the research. If not, imo we should still do this before we play god on brains. </p><p>Just sheer horror of being &quot;awoken&quot; from the void just to be a lab subject in a dish is sending shivers down the spine</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/nf1n0lg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While I agree that ethics must always come first, there seems to be a peculiar bias with regard to things that are new. We already know there are billions of brains that are capable of consciousness and of feeling pain. Their suffering, however, is routinely ignored. Factory farms are full of them, and they endure daily torment, often for utterly trivial reasons.</p><p>Yet when it comes to a few clusters of brain tissue in a lab, i.e. cells that might, perhaps, someday have the potential to feel something, we panic. The outrage seems less about genuine suffering and more about our discomfort with the unfamiliar. </p><p>The ethical concern here feels deeply out of balance.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/nf1p3zp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While we don’t understand the mechanism of consciousness, basically nobody doubts that mammals are conscious and yet mice and rats are tortured daily for the purpose of scientific discovery</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/nf1rdit/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Bold claim: &quot;small brains in vat can&#39;t feel pain&quot;. Nobody knows how consciousness works, at all. We dont even have a way to ask the question in a way science can answer it (verifiable theories).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/nf1pm7g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We are fine experimenting on rats.</p><p>Lab grown brains aren&#39;t even remotely close to that.</p><p>Perhaps start with your ethics where it is already a problem.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/nf3mqq7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Ah sweet, man-made horrors beyond my comprehension.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/nf1nh82/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I don&#39;t understand where this notion comes from that consciousness is a true/false dichotomy, rather than a gradual thing. I think there&#39;s little evidence for the former besides antiquated anthropocentric or spiritual ideas, and imo a lot of evidence for the latter - even an individual being can display various degrees of consciousness.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkyzco/tiny_brains_grown_in_the_lab_could_become/nf1psxo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:02:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/</link><title>Humanity has entered an Age of Rewilding. Global agricultural land use has been declining since the 2000s, and even with the population projected to peak at 9 billion, it will still decline further.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Social media algorithms are designed to make you angry, and the old media is only interested in sensation or &#39;if it bleeds, it leads.&#39; So you might be surprised to find there&#39;s lots of good news in the world.</p><p>Here&#39;s some - globally, more and more land is being rewilded and going back to nature, and the trend looks like it&#39;s permanent. Decades-long productivity trends mean more and more food is being produced per square kilometer. With lab-grown meat and vertical farming in our future, these rewilding trends might even accelerate. Even if the human population finally peaks at 9 billion or so in a few decades, it won&#39;t reverse the trend.</p><p><a href="https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20250909-the-rewilding-milestone-earth-has-already-passed?">The rewilding milestone Earth has already passed</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I saw a reference to a company trying to scale up a process for making protein in a bioreactor. Hydrogen, CO2, and nitrogen go in, protein comes out. No photosynthesis.</p><p>If you run the numbers you find to generate the hydrogen via solar would take 1/100th the land area as growing corn.</p><p>From a gross thermo stand point a human needs 3kwh of energy a day. That&#39;s what a 400W solar panel produces.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/nf1f18f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hmmmm…. but isn’t the synopsis that the reduction is caused by agrochemicals, factory farms and plastic clothes? I like where they’re going with the Dutch (glasshouse vegetables) model and lab meat, but isn’t there a very real risk of soil and climate breakdown before we get to that point?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/nf1cgfr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s a good thing, but given that rewilding isn’t going to be a good as not farming the land in the first place we still need to keep an eye on the amount of land newly used for agriculture. There’s certainly farmland that has become unusable or unprofitable over the last few decades through soil degradation and aridity. This will count as a reduction of land use, but isn’t much of a win for nature</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/nf1cy8m/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It amazes me how much land is used by cows. If you include cropland used to grow feed for cattle, and their grazing land  - <strong>50% of all the land in the US is used by cows.</strong></p><p>I&#39;ve sometimes wondered if those supposed alien cattle mutilations are done by confused aliens who think cows are the dominant life form. They&#39;d be forgiven for being confused, given cows take up so much more space than the human population.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/nf1cpjp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn&#39;t help the situation in lots of places like the Amazon, Phillipines, Madagascar etc</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/nf1ql79/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I love this and hope to one day participate in helping rewild the world. First up is solar in eastern Washington and taking the snake river dams down. Next up is mass reintroduction off beavers. Beavers are a keystone species that help create ecosystems. </p><p>I hope lab grown meat especially is fully funded and not far in our future.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/nf1bsr4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Imagine a world where the media reported on all of this good news and people were excited to keep making things better and better. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nkxt6n/humanity_has_entered_an_age_of_rewilding_global/nf2qbye/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 13:46:18 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/</link><title>If the 'developed' world slipped into authoritarianism, what exactly should we expect if we fast-forward five years from now?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Let’s say extremist parties begin winning elections all around the world and theoretically do-away with future elections and begin winning consecutively, what will our day to day lives look like in 5 years?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Lies. Just endless lies blaming everyone else for why things suck. Food shortages. Unemployment. Refugees. And it will be illegal to complain about any of it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/nezca10/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Historically, organized crime sets up shop fulfilling needs that had been filled by the government. The authoritarian government loses any support from their subjects and needs to use force to exact a level of peace that happens incidentally in other governments.  The enforcement structure makes the government top heavy, putting most jobs in the government, the enforcement costs are such that they lose any trade leverage they normally would have and need to trade raw materials rather than final products.</p><p>5 years, not too much obvious change, 10 years and you start to get adults who grew up with more respect for criminals than government with government and crime being the only real career paths that don&#39;t involve emigration.  And of course there&#39;s a pushback against emigrants from your authoritarian government since everyone is expecting criminals or government agents.</p><p>TLDR: authoritarianism is so expensive that a government can provide no services beyond self defense.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/nezt73x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There are always mass deaths associated with any tyrants seizing power.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/nez9n38/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They tend to be quite obsessed with moral grandstanding and &quot;protecting purity&quot; or whatever so you can expect the following.</p><p>-Complete ban of porn, any production, distribution, storage of any pornography or anything they deem to be pornographic will be made illegal with harsh sentences.</p><p>-All speech will be moderated in accordance to their values. Gone are the days that any criticism, opinions or truths can be shared with everyone.</p><p>-All citizens will be tracked 24/7. Location will be pinged to government servers</p><p>-High end surveillance in suburban areas</p><p>-ID gated society, everything and anything will be ID gated. Which makes it extremely easy to lock people out of essential services and to track their activities.</p><p>-Encryption for citizens private use to be outlawed </p><p>-A prison camp in every town to put all the miss-behaving people, but they get to decide who is naughty and who is nice.</p><p>-Authorities get 24/7 access to your house for inspections. So they can literally walk in or demand access whenever. Ofcourse this power would be abused right? /s</p><p>-Women&#39;s rights will be dissolved unless you are someone from the elite class or given exclusive rights.  Women would not be able to do anything without a man, gone are the days that women can freely apply for jobs or careers, hold bank accounts, vote, or even walk outside by themselves.</p><p>-Human rights will only apply to Elite or governmental classes, regular citizens not so much</p><p>-Repealed laws on discrimination of all kinds. So it would be so much easier for them to divide and destroy us.</p><p>-Authorities can also serve as judge and prosecutor dishing out your fate on the spot</p><p>I want you all to take a moment to memorise all this, then to the best of your ability imagine your life in a society where all of these things applied. Imagine how the people would be treated, what life would be like, how it would feel to genuinely live in such a society.</p><p>If this is what you call Heaven or Hell then  <em>got news for you. We&#39;re on a first class ticket straight to it!</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/nezc6ko/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I see a ton of the doom and gloom, which is exactly what authoritarianism wants. </p><p>So, don&#39;t give it.</p><p>Things are not <em>bad</em> bad yet, there is yet time and hope. Already I&#39;m seeing and hearing changing winds within conservatives, displeased with how things are already and changing bit by bit.</p><p>In <em>many</em> states, on average people are running entirely unopposed for shit, especially at local levels. </p><p>You want to change the course of things? Start small, get out and run against the status quo. Talk to people, in person. Start going to local meetings, listen to what the complaints are. I guarantee you a hell of a lot of the shit being complained about is the same shit that&#39;s been complained of for <em>decades</em> because of single runner crap. </p><p>Don&#39;t know shit about politics? Who cares, if you&#39;ve got empathy and want to change things, that alone puts you heads and shoulders above the competition, the rest is just procedure. You already fake it till you make it for new jobs, literally everyone has imposter syndrome when trying new shit. Get used to being uncomfortable.</p><p>And yeah, I can hear it now, &quot;how can I afford to do this, when I&#39;m already working two jobs?&quot;</p><p><em>How will you afford it when you&#39;re in a concentration camp in 3 years if you don&#39;t right now?</em></p><p>Let&#39;s be honest, doing what&#39;s necessary is going to absolutely fucking suck. Hardcore. It&#39;s gonna be scary, nerve racking, and might end up failing anyways. </p><p>But the <em>vast</em> majority of people here either cannot or will not leave here for various reasons. </p><p>So if the options are sit back, bitching and waiting for the inevitable, or actually going out and doing something, I&#39;m choosing to at least give it a try.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/nf0d3fq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Russia would be a good example. Fascade of democracy with heavy doses of Nationalism (used to both rally and coerce the population) and a small chosen few who wield actual power. </p><p>Many countries would have Oligarch&#39;s, but looking at Russia, the US and even China, said Oligarch&#39;s likely wouldn&#39;t have direct power as in a Corpocracy, but instead be &#39;Chosen Vassals&#39; of the state whose continued wealth and likely lives depend on their continued allegiance.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/nezafmb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Like Ghost in the Shell SAC_2045...</p><p>&quot;Sustainable war&quot; in many places of the world, oligarchy and widespread exploitation at all levels of existence.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nknx4c/if_the_developed_world_slipped_into/nez9ub7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 05:04:34 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.extremetech.com/science/incredible-breakthrough-supercharges-plant-growth</link><title>Researchers supercharge plant growth with new chemical pathway (extremetech.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nki2bc/researchers_supercharge_plant_growth_with_new/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nki2bc/researchers_supercharge_plant_growth_with_new/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nki2bc/researchers_supercharge_plant_growth_with_new/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Scientists in Taiwan have announced an incredible biochemistry breakthrough that could revolutionize an array of industries and perhaps help offset the impact of climate change. Published in the journal <em>Science</em>, the <a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.adp3528">study</a> demonstrates a way to upgrade the biochemical pathway that fixes carbon from the air and powers plant growth.</p><p>The remarkable achievement, which rebuilds one of the core processes of all life, dramatically increased the rate of growth in plants. They grew <em>two to three times</em> bigger and more robust, and they did so in less time. Amazingly, they even produced more viable seeds than their &quot;wild type&quot; parents.</p><p>The pathways replaced in these plants are fundamental, dealing with the basic treatment of CO2 from the atmosphere rather than the complex uses of carbon to actually build the plant. The new pathway, called the McG Cycle, makes molecules usable in the same pathways as those created by the Calvin Cycle. In fact, the McG Cycle supplements the Calvin Cycle and plays well with it, and each pathway can even supplement the other by using excess chemical products.</p></blockquote></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nki2bc/researchers_supercharge_plant_growth_with_new/nexzl7o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 01:07:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/</link><title>Across the world, fertility rates are declining far more quickly than anyone expected. The world's population may peak in the 2050s at under 9 billion-far earlier and lower than the UN's forecast of 10.3 billion in 2084.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><em>&quot;South Korea has had a TFR of less than one for seven years. If that is sustained, its population will shrink by more than half in a single lifetime. ……….. Only about one-third of the world’s people live in countries where fertility is high enough to keep the population growing, and even in those places, rates are falling rapidly.&quot;</em></p><p>Some people think this is bad news, but I see the upside. A stabilised or declining human population is good for our planet&#39;s ecosystem. As for the people who worry about the lack of endless growth for our economies. Guess what? AI &amp; robotics are soon about to upend and finish that economic model for good anyway, so who cares.</p><p><a href="https://archive.md/GURlL">Humanity will shrink, far sooner than you think: Demography sneaks up on you</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I think the more important question is why are the rates declining. If the answer is because people don&#39;t need 9 children to work the farm, then that is ok. But if birthrates are declining because people see a hopeless future of environmental disaster and skyrocketing housing costs, then that isn&#39;t so good.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/new63gk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If jobs are starting to disappear and housing is too expensive, and fresh water isn’t as abundant, this seems like a good development. Not to mention less stress on the environment generally. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/new7b9m/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They never factored in the organic human response into late stage unfettered capitalism. It can’t be sustained the human animal will respond to external pressures in the only way the reptile brain knows how. The suspension of breeding during societal and environmental pressure is not even a new adaptation. We have countless examples of that across the animal kingdom.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/nexlqwo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I think the concerning thing is that even in countries with lots of parental support and good healthcare, birth rates are still falling. This is on top of the global drop in sperm count. Are we sure people just don&#39;t want to have kids? Children of Men looking like the predictive winner for the apocalypse.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/newc5oo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thank fuck. 9 billion people  is a stupidly  huge  no of people.  </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/new3mir/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Posted elsewhere and - for those down the back - listen up and stop posting these goddam articles here every 4 hours .....</p><p>Educated women with agency simply have a choice and that choice is not driven by the conservative idea that women&#39;s primary value is as mother and support system for everyone else, while her needs, skills, intellect and desires are secondary to all. This conservative agenda dovetails nicely with unfettered neo-liberal capitalism&#39;s foundation of endless growth in a finite world and the requirements for women to breed consumers to power that system.</p><p>Its a delicious paradox to see people who subscribe to the above ideologies starting to panic in the realisation that women hold the key to their whole operation and - as we&#39;ve been treated like shit by both - we just might not play ball anymore, consciously or subconsciously....</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/neybqsj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Who&#39;s gonna tell those poor starving multitrillion corpos that the number of consumers won&#39;t keep increasing exponentially? They&#39;re going to be so heartbroken. [/s]</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk9bta/across_the_world_fertility_rates_are_declining/newgddq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:39:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/</link><title>What do you think a post-USA world order will look like?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>USA is without a doubt a dying giant. I don’t mean it’ll go from being the dominant world power to irrelevance in a heart beat - Rome or the British empire took from decades to centuries to lose their power - but it’s definitely in hasty decline: The economy is bad with a majority of lower and middle class Americans living paycheck to paycheck if they even have a job. Birth rates and life expectancy are going down. Democrats and Republicans live in vastly different realities where both of them see the other side as traitors who are destroying the country and the government is doing everything in their power to further the divide. President Trump’s agressive policies in both trade and diplomacy have lead to USA having no real friends left in the world and barely any allies. And so on.</p><p>Sure, USA has been through crises before but I think the current one is different and worse than the others. For instance, the 2008 economic crash was certainly bad but it didn’t lead to USA being isolated. The rest of the world still wanted to visit USA, trade with them and diplomatic relations went on as before. Now the number of tourists visiting USA is plummeting. Most strong world economies are setting up new trade routes/relations working around USA instead of with them, because no one can be sure that president Trump won’t slap a 50% tariff on them tomorrow and tank their exports to USA. And while world leaders still feel the need to humor or even flatter president Trump, none of them are dumb enough to trust a president who has build his career on not paying his debts and who could rip up any written agreement tomorrow.</p><p>USA is still the world’s strongest military power but the war in Ukraine is showing the world that modern warfare is changing drastically. That army of tanks which crushed the Iraqi army just a few decades ago would now be crushed itself by a swarm of cheap drones. Land warfare today is no longer about expensive and highly sophisticated weapons but about multitudes of cheap and simple drones. USA can still turn other countries into rubble with their missiles and air planes but any new attempts at occupying a foreign country would quickly turn into a nightmare.</p><p>So, if USA is losing their dominant position on the world stage, who will take their place? Not Europe; too divided. Russia has ruined itself in Ukraine and will need a long time to rebuild itself both economically and militarily. India’s economy is growing and their fertility rate is right around replacement level but I still think it’s at least two decades into the future for them to be a real world power. The only real contender in my opinion for taking the US spot in the near future is China. They have both the second strongest economy and the second strongest military. But their military has no experience with fighting a modern war and their economy has lots of problems: The property market has slowed to a crawl, high local government debt is causing a banking crisis and of course their trading relationship with USA (still a major trading partner) is very complicated. And their fertility rate is low, coupled with low immigration rates.</p><p>Honestly, once USA has lost their dominant position through continued political ineptitude or maybe even internal war, I don’t think any other one country or block will be able to assert their will globally the way USA has for the last 80 years. I think it more likely that we’ll see a bundle of major/regional powers doing their best to hold each other in check, but whether that’ll lead to a wary peace or open war, I’m not sure.</p><p>What do you think?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p> I think it more likely that we’ll see a bundle of major/regional powers doing their best to hold each other in check</p></blockquote><p>I think the closest analogy would be a post-Napoleonic world in the 19th century. You have several great powers (Austria, Russia, Prussia, England, France), but none of them is powerful enough to dominate the others, leading to a century of shifting coalitions and alliances.</p><p>In the same wake, you will have the US, the EU, China, India, the Middle East, Russia, and so on as great powers that still wouldn&#39;t be able to control the world on their own, leading to some alliances and coalitions. What those will be is impossible to tell, as we can all see in this year :)</p><p>That will also mean that in the period of turmoil, before a new world order is established (the current one is completely failing, as we can see with the UN and international courts), there will be a lot of wars and conflicts that were &quot;frozen&quot; while the US had the role of the world&#39;s police.</p><blockquote><p>The only real contender in my opinion for taking the US spot in the near future is China</p></blockquote><p>That is very unlikely because China is very China-centric. They can project their economic might, but the Chinese project with the Great Firewall and all the other stuff is unique to China, and they are not even trying to export it anywhere else.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/nevc3vg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Rather than a straight decline or a Chinese “takeover,” the likelier path is a multipolar world where America is still first among equals. I’d recommend reading “The Storm Before the Calm” with regard to America’s social and governance “molting process”. </p><p>Most concerning, though, is an enduring multipolar world in a post nuclear era. Multipolar environments are inherently unstable, more so than uni (1990s and 2000s) or bipolar (1940s to 1980s).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/nevb99q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You can&#39;t use analogies from the 19th century to work out questions like this. That was a completely different world.</p><p>We simply do not know. That&#39;s not satisfying, but it&#39;s the truth.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/nevl29v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Without a doubt? Nope.All the rest is a list of modern world problems. For example, birth declines are common everywhere, including China. Same for wealth inequality (which is also not a new problem at all).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/nev9q3d/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s a bit like the end of the Roman Empire. Who &quot;took over&quot; after that? Nobody. Europe was fractured into dozens of angry little nations for the next 1000 years or so.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/nevqrm8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Way more regional wars. Way more regional powers bullying neighbors. </p><p>The world will be a much less safe place.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/nevatg2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>The rest of the world still wanted to visit USA, trade with them and diplomatic relations went on as before. Now the number of tourists visiting USA is plummeting. Most strong world economies are setting up new trade routes/relations working around USA instead of with them, because no one can be sure that president Trump won’t slap a 50% tariff on them tomorrow and tank their exports to USA</p></blockquote><p>Keep in mind that&#39;s the world importing stuff to us. That&#39;s not going to go away. It&#39;s also not isolating us</p><blockquote><p>USA is still the world’s strongest military power but the war in Ukraine is showing the world that modern warfare is changing drastically. That army of tanks which crushed the Iraqi army just a few decades ago would now be crushed itself by a swarm of cheap drones. Land warfare today is no longer about expensive and highly sophisticated weapons but about multitudes of cheap and simple drones. USA can still turn other countries into rubble with their missiles and air planes but any new attempts at occupying a foreign country would quickly turn into a nightmare.</p></blockquote><p>No offense, but you didn&#39;t serve, did you? I ask this because you&#39;re speaking from a myopic point of view. I can&#39;t fault you for it, because it&#39;s the point of view the media is presenting, and they&#39;re the myopic ones.</p><p>Simply put: Ukraine, a 3rd rate military is holding off Russia, a 2nd rate military, with a few 1st rate military toys. Toys that are intended to work in concert with other toys <em>not</em> given to Ukraine, and Ukraine is <em>still</em> holding Russia off. It&#39;s like using a Phalanx (the fighting tactic) with every third man missing. The US&#39;s mastery of JADO would render most of the Russian military useless in minutes.</p><p>Hell, if a squadron of Growlers were sent to Ukraine, the war would be over next week.</p><blockquote><p>The only real contender in my opinion for taking the US spot in the near future is China</p></blockquote><p>They don&#39;t even have a true blue water navy.</p><blockquote><p>They have both the second strongest economy and the second strongest military.</p></blockquote><p>No they don&#39;t. That&#39;s their shitty propaganda speaking.</p><blockquote><p>Honestly, once USA has lost their dominant position through continued political ineptitude or maybe even internal war, I don’t think any other one country or block will be able to assert their will globally the way USA has for the last 80 years</p></blockquote><p>A significant piece of that puzzle you&#39;ve missing is knowledge on what happened after WW2. The world was in shambles. Only industrial economies left were the US and Russia. Russia absorbed territory. The US provided overwatch while the rest of the world rebuilt itself. We guarded trade rates <em>so</em> the rest of the world could rebuild itself. Then it got used to that. Stop pretending that we were some sort of usurper. The world asked for our protection, then came to demand it. The Soviet Union never gave up territory and forced the populace under their brutal oppression.</p><p>Overall the media is giving you an absurdly naive interpretation of the world.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1nk5fae/what_do_you_think_a_postusa_world_order_will_look/newife9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:44:19 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.carbonbrief.org/analysis-indias-power-sector-co2-falls-for-only-second-time-in-half-a-century/</link><title>Analysis: India's power-sector CO2 emissions begin to decline as renewable energy surges (carbonbrief.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njzwo9/analysis_indias_powersector_co2_emissions_begin/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njzwo9/analysis_indias_powersector_co2_emissions_begin/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njzwo9/analysis_indias_powersector_co2_emissions_begin/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>must be all those EVs on the road. Some times i imagine future will be super clean with all solar and robot working everywhere and humans living like mortal gods. I think this is more likely what will happen.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njzwo9/analysis_indias_powersector_co2_emissions_begin/nev0wyw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;India’s carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions from its power sector fell by 1% year-on-year in the first half of 2025 and by 0.2% over the past 12 months, only the second drop in almost half a century.</p><p>As a result, India’s CO2 emissions from fossil fuels and cement grew at their slowest rate in the first half of the year since 2001 – excluding Covid – according to new analysis for Carbon Brief.</p><p>At the same time, The growth in clean-energy capacity reached a record 25.1 gigawatts (GW), up <strong>69% year-on-year</strong> from what had, itself, been a record figure.</p><p>More than half of India’s CO2 output comes from coal used for electricity and heat generation, making this sector the most important by far for the country’s emissions.</p><p>Looking beyond this year, the analysis shows that CO2 from India’s power sector could peak before 2030, having previously been the main driver of emissions growth.</p><p>In 2021, India set a target of having 500GW of non-fossil power generation capacity in place by 2030. Progress was slow at first, so meeting the target implies a substantial acceleration in clean-energy additions.</p><p>The country has been laying the groundwork for such an acceleration.</p><p>There was 234GW of renewable capacity in the pipeline as of April 2025, according to the Ministry of New and Renewable Energy. This includes 169GW already awarded contracts, of which 145GW is under construction, and an additional 65GW put out to tender. There is also 5.2GW of new nuclear capacity under construction.</p><p>If all of this is commissioned by 2030, then total non-fossil capacity would increase to 482GW, from 243GW at the end of June 2025, leaving a gap of just 18GW to be filled with new projects.</p><p>In the CEA’s projection, the share of non-fossil power generation rises to 44% in the 2029-30 fiscal year, up from 25% in 2024-25. From 2025 to 2030, power demand growth, averaging 6% per year, is entirely covered from clean sources.</p><p>In July of this year, it met a 2030 target for 50% of installed power generating capacity to be from non-fossil sources, five years early.&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njzwo9/analysis_indias_powersector_co2_emissions_begin/neu8s9c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Finally some good news! 🌍 This is huge for India, considering how fast its energy demand is growing. If they can pivot to renewables at this scale, there&#39;s hope for other developing countries too.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njzwo9/analysis_indias_powersector_co2_emissions_begin/nev7zvf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Is the economy still growing or is there a recession?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njzwo9/analysis_indias_powersector_co2_emissions_begin/nevxesb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:59:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.psypost.org/u-s-sees-5-7-million-more-childless-women-than-expected-fueling-a-demographic-cliff/</link><title>U.S. sees 5.7 million more childless women than expected, fueling a "demographic cliff" | This profound change in childbearing patterns has contributed to a cumulative total of 11.8 million fewer births over the past 17 years than would have occurred if earlier fertility rates had been maintained. (psypost.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>For years society said, Don&#39;t have kids you can&#39;t afford. </p><p>Then society made life with kids unaffordable. What do they expect?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/nerx1kx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Love how it avoids one obviouschunk of this. Teen pregnancy/births.</p><p>Exactly how many were avoided can be estimated just like the 11.8M. We know how teen births for several years and can estimate others so the birth rates are about:</p><p>2007: 443,000 Ramping down to 2024: 137,020</p><p>Summing all the years gives approximately 4.5 million teen births from 2007 to 2024. Teen population was pretty stable for the time period (about 21.3M) so if we assume 443K births expected per year it totals 8M expected so:</p><p>We’re “missing” about 3.5M teen pregnancies</p><p>So that 30% of the missing children is GOOD but they ignored it in the write up and just talked about declining rates “under 30”. </p><p>Not sure if its more lazy or alarmist but its definitely bad science/science journalism.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/nesq021/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>When I had a kid daycare was $1300/months and my insurance went up $800/mo. That was more than my mortgage. I could have leased a Lamborghini with that money, more or less. It&#39;s worse now, and my house went from 240k to 450k in that period. </p><p>If you want more kids maybe make an economy that isn&#39;t basically demanding you not have any.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/nersjpm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But who will work the low paying jobs that keep you from being able to afford having children in the first place, which is really a vicious cycle.  You want the peasants having children to keep the infinite growth economy rolling, but they are just peasants to you after all, so the hell with them right?!  But who will work the low paying jobs that..................</p><p>Its like an ouroboros of oligarch greed and stupidity.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/nerqgrc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Well. Raising a child is a full time job. When a woman is already doing a full time job, and still barely having the ends meet, would she take a second one for free?</p><p>Baby boom was there for a reason. It was possible to live on one income while raising kids. Now it&#39;s a completely different story. But it&#39;s not forever, these things change.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/nes0gb6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Decrease income inequality especially for starting jobs.</p><p>2 people making a combined 150k a year in much of the US feel comfortable</p><p>2 people making 75k combined? Not so much.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/nerrv5u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s both the obvious childcare costs that have gone way up, and the non-obvious ones too.</p><p>Obviously, housing is crazy expensive.  So is childcare, food, utilities, clothes, etc.</p><p>But also... expectations that you spend a lot of money are up too!  Years ago kids went to school and then they had maybe some free sports in the local little league or whatever.  Now?  It&#39;s expected you put them in gymnastics lessons, violin lessons, pay for after school activities, buy things for clubs and teams, put them in travel teams, sign them up for ballet, and on and on.  Obviously not every kid does every one of those, but... most kids do a lot.</p><p>And the TIME is a lot more too.  Like it or not, the culture has changed.  The images of kids just roaming the neighborhood from movies about the 80&#39;s and before aren&#39;t made up.  Parents would just say &quot;go outside, see you at dinner&quot; and that was all they had to do.  Now?  It&#39;s shuttling and supervising kids 24/7.  They can&#39;t just &quot;go out to play&quot; it has to be playdates, it has to be paid groups, lessons, teams, and on and on.</p><p>It&#39;s SO MUCH MORE WORK now than it used to be, in addition to the higher costs.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njocj2/us_sees_57_million_more_childless_women_than/neruts3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:58:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.semafor.com/article/09/17/2025/genetic-bioengineering-firm-steps-closer-to-reviving-the-dodo</link><title>Genetic bioengineering firm steps closer to reviving the dodo (semafor.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This is not a breakthrough... people have been culturing bird PGCs for a while...(<a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7225225/">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC7225225/</a>)</p><p>My guess is the &quot;direwolves&quot; have been such a PR diaster for them, that Colossal is desperate for any good press at this point... like look what Lamm told the guardian “These are dodos, and I’m sure there will be some people who say ‘Oh, well, we don’t like them. We’re not going to call them dodos,’” Lamm said of the latest Colossal project.</p><p>“Then don’t. We just don’t care, and the more you don’t call them a dodo, the more controversy you drive, the more my numbers go up. So that’s great. So whatever you want to call them, as long as you’re calling them something.” (<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/sep/17/dodo-birds-gene-editing-advance">https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/sep/17/dodo-birds-gene-editing-advance</a>)</p><p>If that&#39;s true... why all the damage control around the &quot;direwolves&quot;?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/ner8x9j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Deader than Dodo&#39;s Doornail. So much for that idiom ig</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/nevevl1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How many times do we have to teach you this lesson dodo.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/neypyr5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We really are aliens compared to the rest of the animal kingdom. </p><p>We&#39;ll kill you all. Then bring you back from the dead. </p><p>(Honestly, might be a poor deal for the dodo bird. We&#39;d totally end up factory farming them.)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/nf1nsjc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>When we ‘bring them back’,  are we really bringing them back, or some version of them that isn’t quite them? It’s nice to know that we could bring back a species…but I could also see that being dangerous (well, no need to fund preservation if we can just pump them out in the lab…possibly exacerbated by the potential for a company making lots of money doing so)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/nf3g9ix/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So science is going the way of the Dodo.</p><p>Do we have any actual genetic material for them, even partial saved anywhere?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njk8z1/genetic_bioengineering_firm_steps_closer_to/nf3tvyr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:24:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?&amp;</link><title>Factcheck: 16 misleading myths about solar (interactive.carbonbrief.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Solar power is already providing the <a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/(https://www.carbonbrief.org/solar-is-now-cheapest-electricity-in-history-confirms-iea/">“cheapest electricity in history”</a>) and is <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/in-depth-qa-the-ipccs-sixth-assessment-on-how-to-tackle-climate-change/">expected</a> to play a <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/new-fossil-fuels-incompatible-with-1-5c-goal-comprehensive-analysis-finds/">pivotal role</a> in the global transition away from fossil fuels.</p><p>The technology accounted for two-thirds of the world’s <a href="https://ember-energy.org/data/electricity-data-explorer/?data=capacity">new electricity capacity</a> and two-fifths of new generation in 2024, according to the thinktank <a href="https://ember-energy.org/">Ember</a>.</p><p>Yet, this rapid expansion has triggered a backlash, with numerous campaigns springing up to oppose new solar projects from the <a href="https://www.fwi.co.uk/news/uk-wide-protests-held-against-large-scale-solar-farms">UK</a> to <a href="https://reneweconomy.com.au/no-solar-factories-protests-greet-farmers-and-industry-trying-to-find-path-for-renewable-revolution/">Australia</a>.</p><p>These groups frequently draw on misinformation, spread by <a href="https://www.carbonbrief.org/analysis-uk-newspaper-editorials-attacked-ed-miliband-relentlessly-throughout-2024/">right-leaning media outlets</a>, <a href="https://www.citizensforresponsiblesolar.org/">anti-renewable energy groups</a> and <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/09644016.2025.2458380#d1e1810">predominantly right-wing</a> political parties.</p><p>Increasingly, these narratives are having real-world consequences, with governments <a href="https://blogs.law.columbia.edu/climatechange/2022/03/15/renewable-energy-projects-face-opposition-in-49-states-local-restrictions-in-31-states/">restricting</a> or even <a href="https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/climate-energy/italy-split-possible-solar-plant-curbs-that-may-jeopardise-green-goals-2024-05-06/">banning</a> the installation of solar panels across swathes of land.</p><p>Here, Carbon Brief factchecks 16 of the most common myths about solar power.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Some excellent points here but something not addressed by this article: </p><p>the ongoing need for energy storage or a rapid response generating station of carbon outputting or nuclear make up for the variable nature of solar system output so that grid operators can supply a steady throughput to meet demand under current infrastructure build out. </p><p>And the cost related to building any energy storage system or rapid response system as a portion of the cost of that solar system (same for wind). Instead of treating the cost of any one generating source as a stand alone cost we need to be discussing the overall generating/delivery costs of the whole system. Otherwise any own group can fudge the numbers to make themselves “look best”.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/neq3xwq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’ve installed solar panels. The biggest issue with residential solar is that the decrease in costs related to the equipment is not being passed on to the Consumer. So it just isn’t financially viable for people to install solar and return on their investment at any reasonable amount of time to make it worth it. And you’re talking to somebody who has solar panels on their house and believes in it. </p><p>But I can’t recommend it to people because breaking even on your money  in 10 or 15 years is a horrible financial decision. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/neqpqsz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here are some of the most common myths about solar power.</p><ul><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-solar-power-is-an-unreliable-source-of-energy"><strong>FALSE</strong> Solar power is an ‘unreliable source of energy</a>&#39;</li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-solar-and-wind-power-are-expensive"><strong>FALSE</strong> ‘Solar and wind power are expensive’</a></li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-as-nations-use-more-solar-bills-get-more-expensive"><strong>FALSE</strong> ‘As nations use more solar, bills get more expensive’</a></li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-solar-farms-pump-out-more-carbon-over-their-lifetimes-than-they-save"><strong>FALSE</strong> Solar farms ‘pump out more carbon over their lifetimes than they save’</a></li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-solar-power-is-a-serious-threat-to-agriculture-and-food-security"><strong>FALSE</strong> Solar power is ‘a serious threat to agriculture and food security’</a></li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-energy-projects-will-generate-a-tsunami-of-solar-panel-waste"><strong>FALSE</strong> Energy projects will generate a ‘tsunami of solar panel waste’</a></li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-battery-storage-presents-a-huge-fire-risk"><strong>FALSE</strong> Battery storage presents a ‘huge fire risk’</a></li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-heatwaves-make-solar-panels-significantly-less-efficient"><strong>FALSE</strong> Heatwaves make solar panels ‘significantly less efficient’</a></li><li><a href="https://interactive.carbonbrief.org/factcheck/solar/index.html?utm_source=reddit&amp;utm_medium=social#section-solar-farms-will-be-designated-brownfield-sites-and-eventually-disappear-under-housing-forever"><strong>FALSE</strong> Solar farms ‘will be designated brownfield sites and eventually disappear under housing forever</a>&#39;</li></ul></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/neq15w2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That&#39;s so wrong. Solar Panels are expensive as hell for the consumer. My sister got tricked into buying said Panels and she got screwed hard by it. She can&#39;t sell her house and on top of the electric bill which she still gets she has to make payments for said panels which makes it impossible to sell her house. After a couple years the panels are no longer working as well as before and now she has to pay both the panels and higher power bills.</p><p>Edit: I checked OP and it&#39;s a literal marketing account. What the hell is going on this subreddit where literal paid marketers are posting marketing material. How about buy a freaking ad.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/nerclvl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So, we know what we already knew -- the naysayers are bought and paid for.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/nerb78c/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Furthermore, combined with battery energy-storage systems, near-continuous “24/365” solar power is now an economic and technological reality in sunny regions.&quot;</p><p>Even the article admits that its only &quot;near-continuous 24/365 solar power&quot; I&#39;ve been told that this is a huge issue for energy intensive industries. </p><p>I think all other points are moot. As fanciful as it may sound, scientists have already succeeded in beaming energy from satellites to earth. Once battery technology becomes even more reliable and true 24/365 uptime is possible, all other issues go away. We dont need land for solar panels if they&#39;re all in space. </p><p>Unfortunately for now, we can&#39;t rely completely on solar.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/nf7mmvq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>First one and it&#39;s already dodging the question.</p><p>What about the fact that an overcast weather can lower the production by as much as 90% ? It says you can expect the sunrise and sunset timings so it&#39;s reliable, what about the weather ? And funnily, saying that solar is more of a &quot;fuel saver&quot; for other means of production is basically saying that it can&#39;t stand on its own.</p><p>The site cites Battery storage as a solution when those have typically 4 hours of uptime, and make you pay typically 10x what solar would make you pay, but of course glosses over these &quot;small&quot; caveats.</p><p>The reality is that we have a just-in-time energy grid, and that is not compatible with a fatalist mode of production without bending over backwards to make it work. That is why all the talks about &quot;it&#39;s so cheap&quot; are empty : they look at the LCOE and ignore all the side effects.</p><p>The site also somehow pretends to factcheck but opens by talking politics, which is just plain old priming. No point in continuing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Futurology/comments/1njgnke/factcheck_16_misleading_myths_about_solar/neuxed9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 21:12:49 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
