<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=automation&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/automation</title><description>Hot posts in /r/automation (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 11:44:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qrbn-styles-communityIcon_acjcf9t7btac1-144x400.jpg</url><title>/r/automation</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/</link><width>144</width><height>124</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/</link><title>What's one process you wish you could automate right now ?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>We used to manually route every support request.</p><p>copy → paste → assign → repeat.</p><p>lots of delay. lots of frustration.</p><p>Then we built visual workflows to handle the repetitive steps:</p><ul><li>auto-assigning tickets</li><li>tagging based on topic</li><li>escalating based on priority</li></ul><p>Response times dropped.<br/>Nothing fancy — just less friction.</p><p>Most speed problems aren’t about people.<br/>they’re about process.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Literally there are 10+ of these lazy ChatGPT ‘WhAt CaN I aUtOmAtE’ shit posts a week. Go away.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/nf4h1oo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Love this exactly my experience. Most bottlenecks aren’t lack of effort but repetitive steps. I’ve been using Pokee AI to automate posting + task workflows, and it feels like the same kind of “friction removal” you’re describing</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/nf68b6w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/nf3rpvu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Finding people offline and in my general vicinity</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl9mga/whats_one_process_you_wish_you_could_automate/nf6anwx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 22:49:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/3zz4thkc35qf1.png</link><title>How I built  sold my first $1,800 AI Automation to a boutique Law Firm (full deal breakdown) (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl6lm4/how_i_built_sold_my_first_1800_ai_automation_to_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl6lm4/how_i_built_sold_my_first_1800_ai_automation_to_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl6lm4/how_i_built_sold_my_first_1800_ai_automation_to_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>We just finished building and selling a lead gen automation to a small law firm based out of Austin Texas that specializes in insurance mediation. At a high level, it&#39;s a pretty simple system that scrapes law firms from a lawyer directory → crawls law firm sites for profile pages → then adds all those leads to a Google spreadsheet. Even though it is simple scraping system, it solves a real problem that was too manual for our client do by hand.</p><p>I wanted to share both the sales process we followed here, as well as the technical build-out of the exact automation we sold to give you guys some context on how we approached a client project like this. </p><p>We also make a Youtube video that breaks down the sales process + n8n automation in more detail: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtPUtfxQZYU">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtPUtfxQZYU</a></p><h2>Sales Process Breakdown</h2><p><strong>1. Start with personal network</strong>Since we&#39;re pretty new, we went to our personal networks first. Thought process here, it&#39;s going to be way easier to get our first leads by tapping our network first. So we went through the list of people who we know that either ran independent practices or ran their own businesses. Jason, who is the lawyer in this case, was one of the top people that came to mind. </p><p><strong>2. Initial qualification call (15-30 min)</strong>We approached this by not initially trying to sell anything here. The goal was just figuring out if there&#39;s actually a problem in their business worth solving. We asked him where his business felt slow or manual, how he gets clients today, what (if any) process eats up the most of his time.</p><p>Within 10 minutes we both saw clear opportunities on his own process (lead gen).</p><p><strong>3. Discovery call (the most important part)</strong></p><p>On this call, our goal was to act like an automation doctor and ask a bunch of diagnostic questions to understand what part of the current workflow is painful. We had him go through the manual process he was following for lead gen in extremely detailed steps and went through every single step they were performing each day for finding new clients. </p><p>We had Jason literally share his screen and walk us through his exact process:</p><ul><li>Uses Texas lawyer directory to find insurance litigation firms</li><li>Researches each firm manually</li><li>Identifies individual attorneys that fit his niche</li><li>Copies everything into a spreadsheet (name, email, website, notes)</li><li>Sends personalized cold emails</li><li>Tracks replies manually</li></ul><p>Every time something felt vague during this conversation, we dug deeper. How does he use the directory? What’s the process for deciding if a lawyer is a good candidate to reach out to or not? More details here are better.</p><p><strong>4. The close</strong>Normally we&#39;d present our offer here ($2,500 build + $400/month retainer), but since this was one of our first clients, we cut him a deal in exchange for us to use this as a case study. This combined with the fact that this automation was directly tied to a process that would generate him more revenue made closing this <em>much</em> easier.</p><h2>Technical Breakdown</h2><p>For the build-out we have this system split up into two separate workflows:</p><ol><li>This is going to be the entry point into this whole system that allows you to paste in a page from the Texas Insurance Legal Directory. This goes ahead and scrapes all of the law firms that you can find from that page and then passes those details off to Automation 2.</li><li>The second automation here is going to be what processes each firm website individually. It takes in the firm name and a URL of the firm and then it goes ahead and crawls that firm website for any lawyer profile pages it can find. Regardless if the firm is a good match or not, we still go ahead and save that on our output spreadsheet with our decision here. This will get used by our client if they want to go ahead with cold emailing them or not. </li></ol><h3>1. Scrape the law firm directory (Entry to the system)</h3><p>The first workflow takes a URL from the Texas Insurance Law Section directory and extracts all law firms listed on that page:</p><ul><li>Uses Firecrawl&#39;s extract feature to scrape firm names and cities from the directory table</li><li>Validates each firm hasn&#39;t been processed before using Google Sheets lookup</li><li>Searches the internet to find each firm&#39;s actual website URL</li><li>Uses AI to verify the search result is actually a law firm website (not a courthouse or directory)</li><li>Saves verified firms to a Google Sheet and passes them to the second workflow within the core loop</li></ul><h3>2. Scrape lawyer profiles from each firm</h3><p>The second workflow processes each law firm&#39;s website to extract individual attorney profiles:</p><ul><li>Uses Firecrawl search with site-specific queries to find attorney profile pages<ul><li>Searches for keywords like <code>attorney</code>, <code>partner</code>, <code>associate</code>, <code>insurance</code> to find relevant profiles</li></ul></li><li>Uses a simple prompt + gemini-2.5-flash to evaluate each search result to confirm it&#39;s an individual attorney profile page or not</li><li>Scrapes detailed information from each attorney&#39;s profile using structured extraction:<ul><li>Full name and contact information</li><li>Position at the firm</li><li>Areas of practice and specializations</li></ul></li></ul><h3>3. Qualify and process each lead</h3><p>For each attorney found on the firm website, we then do the following:</p><ul><li>AI analyzes their the scraped profile page + practice areas to determine if they&#39;re a good match for insurance mediation referrals</li><li>Validates contact information to ensure we have individual email addresses (not generic firm emails like <a href="mailto:support@xyz.com">support@xyz.com</a>)</li><li>Drafts a personalized cold email using the attorney&#39;s name and background</li><li>Creates a Google Doc with the formatted email ready to copy into Gmail</li><li>Saves all lead data to Google Sheets, decisions made for determining if the lawyer is a good match,  and a link to the cold email draft</li></ul><h2>Workflow Link + Other Resources</h2><ul><li>YouTube video that walks through this workflow step-by-step: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtPUtfxQZYU">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RtPUtfxQZYU</a></li><li>The full n8n workflow, which you can copy and paste directly into your instance, is on GitHub here: <a href="https://github.com/lucaswalter/n8n-ai-automations/blob/main/deal_breakdown_lawyer_lead_gen.json">https://github.com/lucaswalter/n8n-ai-automations/blob/main/deal_breakdown_lawyer_lead_gen.json</a></li></ul></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/3zz4thkc35qf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>We are planning to ramp up our outbound sales process in the near future for our agency. any interest in seeing more breakdowns like this on how we approach it?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl6lm4/how_i_built_sold_my_first_1800_ai_automation_to_a/nf35huc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is gonna save me some legal fees. My lawyer never shuts up, but bills me for our conversations about the weather</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl6lm4/how_i_built_sold_my_first_1800_ai_automation_to_a/nf53twh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl6lm4/how_i_built_sold_my_first_1800_ai_automation_to_a/nf33ytv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Nice work. Do you feel you undercharged/are undercharging?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nl6lm4/how_i_built_sold_my_first_1800_ai_automation_to_a/nf3xhwj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:56:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/</link><title>We turned a clinic's $10K/month loss into profit with a single WhatsApp workflow and now we get $2k/mo to keep it going</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 4 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey everyone, I just wanted to share a recent success story from my Ai agency, which I should add, is just 4 months old. We just helped a small skin aesthetic clinic in Dubai fix a major leak in their business: their lead follow-up process. They were literally losing about $10,000 every month because inquiries were falling through the cracks, they were missing a lot of calls and even follow ups. </p><p><strong>What was happening:</strong> The clinic relied only on a receptionist to handle calls and a basic google form. If a potential client reached out after hours or via Instagram, chances were they’d get no response until the next day (if at all). By then, the lead often went to a competitor or went cold. Even during the day, the receptionists were overwhelmed – she’d miss calls while on other calls, forget to follow up with people etc. No CRM, no automation, just pen-and-paper and manual database management. The result? Dozens of interested customer inquiries slipping away. </p><p>So we built a simple but effective automation workflow (using n8n) to support their existing process. Key steps we implemented:</p><ul><li><strong>Instant acknowledgment:</strong> Whenever someone fills the website form or sends a message, they get an immediate WhatsApp reply saying “Thanks for contacting, we’ll be with you ASAP” with the clinic’s name. No more radio silence. This happens 24/7 within seconds.</li><li><strong>Lead logging:</strong> That inquiry automatically goes into a Google Sheet (shared with the clinic) so no lead is forgotten. The receptionist sees the new entry and the details when she starts work.</li><li><strong>Notify staff:</strong> The system shoots an email alert to the receptionist (and clinic manager) that a new lead came in, with all details. Now they know who to call and why, first thing in the morning or sooner.</li><li><strong>Faster follow-up:</strong> Because the lead got a WhatsApp message, they often even reply with more info or preferred appointment times. When the receptionist follows up, she has context and the client already feels taken care of. We also gave them a Calendly link to send for scheduling if someone prefers self-service booking.</li><li><strong>Reminders:</strong> Once an appointment is booked, our workflow schedules auto-reminder messages on WhatsApp 1 day and 2 hours before the appointment. This dramatically reduced no-shows (which had been a problem).</li><li><strong>Post-visit:</strong> We even added a post-appointment thank-you and feedback request. A nice touch that makes clients feel valued and helps the clinic gather reviews or testimonials.</li></ul><p><strong>The results (after 2 months):</strong></p><ul><li>The clinic’s conversion rate from lead to show-up <strong>jumped from around 30% to 50%+.</strong> They’re filling their schedule now. </li><li>No-show rate got cut in half<strong>.</strong> People actually remember and show up to their appointments now, thanks to reminders.</li><li>The receptionist saves hours of time and a lot of stress. She’s not juggling as much – the “system” (as they call it) does the tedious follow-up stuff automatically.</li><li>The clinic estimates at least $15K in extra monthly revenue from those saved leads and kept appointments. This is huge for them.</li><li>The clinic owner is over the moon. She said it feels like they hired an extra staff member who works 24/7, but for a fraction of the cost.</li></ul><p>After seeing the difference, they decided to keep us on a retainer for ~$2,000/month to maintain and further optimize the system for them. Considering they’re getting 5-7x that back in revenue, they’re super happy with that investment (and so are we!). This is our biggest retainer yet and it gives me a lot of confidence in what all we can achieve. (In the past, we have closed quite a few deals in the $1k range, which are pretty awesome too, lmk if y&#39;all might be interested in knowing about them as well)</p><p><strong>Key takeaway:</strong> If you run a small business and you’re spending money to get leads, make sure you’re not losing those leads due to slow or no follow-up. People’s attention spans are short, and speed wins. In our case, just <em>automating the initial response and reminders</em> made a night-and-day difference. You don’t need fancy AI or expensive software either – we pieced this together with pretty accessible tech (WhatsApp API, Google Sheets, etc.).</p><p>The clinic went from old-school to cutting-edge literally in two weeks without hiring new staff. I’m proud of the win, and the client is ecstatic. Just thought I’d share in case it sparks ideas for others here dealing with similar issues. Feel free to ask any questions; happy to nerd out on the setup or share more specifics (would love to share the JSON code for the automation we implemented; I am not sure if sharing the code snippet is the right way to go here, so if anyone knows the best way, let me know!) </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/nf1egx5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Awesome work! (I’m not in Dubai :)</p><p>This can be life changing for a business. Clients feel acknowledged, appreciated and that the company cares throughout their process. All the while giving auto touch points where a client can provide feedback good or not so …and the not so can be dealt with and resolved quickly which is what matters. </p><p>I’ve done similar work with our business in Canada and it has created loads of good will. Our Google reviews tell the story of how good our clients feel about strong follow up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/nf1n9jg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Sounds great! I have a question. How did you manage to secure your client, what outreach method did you use?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/nf230dl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How were you able to get the client in the first place?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/nf3ozib/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Great example. I also live in Dubai and do automation work. Thanks for the details. Very inspiring.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkyawz/we_turned_a_clinics_10kmonth_loss_into_profit/nf1fyj4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:18:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/2359cmh8f1qf1.png</link><title>ChatGPT Image to AI Generated 3D Model to Full Render (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkskaa/chatgpt_image_to_ai_generated_3d_model_to_full/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkskaa/chatgpt_image_to_ai_generated_3d_model_to_full/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkskaa/chatgpt_image_to_ai_generated_3d_model_to_full/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Models were done using 3daistudio, nothing else was done to it, all the textures, mesh, the whole model is as it was generated. Whole process took about 5 minutes in total, waiting for ChatGPT to generate, then waiting for 3daistudio to generate.</p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/0luhyxsbu1qf1.png?width=1459&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1d1a293de404ba3408394f62886e6ec05ac46df9">https://preview.redd.it/0luhyxsbu1qf1.png?width=1459&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=1d1a293de404ba3408394f62886e6ec05ac46df9</a></p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/fni4o51du1qf1.png?width=779&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=e89f0e02fc0be6feaaca484e2e11309a45e12839">https://preview.redd.it/fni4o51du1qf1.png?width=779&amp;format=png&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=e89f0e02fc0be6feaaca484e2e11309a45e12839</a></p><p>Honestly this could be a nice workflow if you needed a lot of 3d models for a game or 3d printing, or even for webpages using something like Three.js.</p><p>What do you guys think?</p><p>Edit: gahhh seems like reddit didn&#39;t upload my images properly!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/2359cmh8f1qf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Great idea for automating 3d models! Any project needing 3d models this would be amazing but how accurate is the 3d tool?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkskaa/chatgpt_image_to_ai_generated_3d_model_to_full/nf0f35a/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkskaa/chatgpt_image_to_ai_generated_3d_model_to_full/nf0anyp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Whats the file name of the 3d file?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkskaa/chatgpt_image_to_ai_generated_3d_model_to_full/nf0ra52/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Share prompt plz</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkskaa/chatgpt_image_to_ai_generated_3d_model_to_full/nf0cyj5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 08:43:25 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkmxgx/hitting_the_ceiling_with_maken8n/</link><title>Hitting the ceiling with Make/n8n?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkmxgx/hitting_the_ceiling_with_maken8n/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkmxgx/hitting_the_ceiling_with_maken8n/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkmxgx/hitting_the_ceiling_with_maken8n/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I’ve seen this pattern a lot: teams start with no-code tools like <strong>Make</strong> or <strong>n8n</strong> to get quick wins. But once things need to run in production, dev teams get pulled in to rewrite those workflows in code. The usual reasons? Cost, scalability, error handling, maintainability… and just making sure it doesn’t break at 3AM. </p><p>If you know some coding, AI can actually help bridge that gap. For example, you can export the JSON plan from a n8n workflow and ask Claude (or another LLM) to turn it into code. It works surprisingly well in many cases—sometimes you’ll need to tweak or “vibe code” a bit, but it’s a solid starting point. The harder part is then deploying and managing it in production (auth, scaling, monitoring, etc.), which isn’t trivial.</p><p>Another option is to use something like AutoKitteh. It has a built-in “vibe automation” capability: you can feed it the JSON workflow plan and it will generate a Python-based automation for you. With just a few clicks for authenticating the applications, like in no-code tools, you end up with a code-based automation that’s easier to scale, cheaper to run, more robust with error handling, and more maintainable over time—because it’s code.</p><p><strong>Disclosure</strong>: I work at AutoKitteh, where we build automation and AI-agent workflows similar to those people create in n8n. I often handle use cases like the ones I described above, so my perspective comes from both what I see in the community and what I encounter directly with teams building these solutions.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkmxgx/hitting_the_ceiling_with_maken8n/nez1jdr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 04:20:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkjqpy/i_stopped_getting_blocked_by_cloudflare_and_my/</link><title>I stopped getting blocked by Cloudflare and my automation costs dropped 100x</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkjqpy/i_stopped_getting_blocked_by_cloudflare_and_my/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkjqpy/i_stopped_getting_blocked_by_cloudflare_and_my/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkjqpy/i_stopped_getting_blocked_by_cloudflare_and_my/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><h1>If your Playwright/Puppeteer scripts work fine and never get blocked, this isn&#39;t for you.</h1><p>But if you&#39;re tired of your automation breaking every time a site updates their anti-bot detection, keep reading.</p><p><strong>The problem:</strong> Traditional browser automation gets flagged. You spend more time fixing broken scripts than actually automating things.</p><p><strong>What I switched to:</strong> CDP MCP (Chrome DevTools Protocol with Model Context Protocol)</p><p><strong>Here&#39;s the magic:</strong> The LLM reasons and performs the action once, and it learns the pattern (saving it with {variables} ). After that, it runs without the LLM - making it 100x cheaper and way more reliable.</p><p><strong>What I&#39;m automating now:</strong></p><ul><li>Go to twitter and post this {content}</li><li>Open Gmail and send this email: {content} to {recipient} with subject:{subject}</li><li>Open my web app and Test the login functionality with these credentials {username}, {password}</li><li>Go to this LinkedIn profile {profile link} and extract the professional experiences and details of this person (output in JSON)</li><li>Go to Reddit and post {content} in this community: {community}, adhering to Guidelines: {guidelines}</li><li>Go to Reddit and get all comments from this post: {link}</li><li>Go to Reddit and reply {response} to this comment {comment}</li></ul><p><strong>The killer feature:</strong> These workflows become API calls you can plug into n8n, Make, or your own pipelines.</p><p>Same outcome every time. No more &quot;why did my automation break overnight?&quot;</p><p><strong>For the automation engineers here:</strong> How much of your time is spent debugging scripts that worked yesterday?</p><p>Because mine just got that time back. And my monthly LLM costs went from $200 to $2.</p><p>It&#39;s free and open source if you want to try it out.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>From the way you describe it, it seems like you’re recording one LLM-driven browser session and then replaying it later with variable substitution, only falling back to the LLM if something breaks.</p><p>Is that right, or is there another mechanism under the hood? I haven’t seen an open-source tool that already does this reliably AgentRR and some MCP/browser projects point in that direction but don’t seem production-ready.</p><p>If you’ve got a repo or example implementation, would be great to check it out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkjqpy/i_stopped_getting_blocked_by_cloudflare_and_my/nf1iqp9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkjqpy/i_stopped_getting_blocked_by_cloudflare_and_my/neyczuv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;ve literally never had an automation blocked. But, I&#39;m also not a filthy spammer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkjqpy/i_stopped_getting_blocked_by_cloudflare_and_my/nf2e7dr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 02:11:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/</link><title>I built my own AI Secretary - and it actually works! 🤖✉️</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/t3q0qmt99ypf1.jpg?width=492&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=8432a10821ca6c5af7055e88dd839c8f6c7a0068">https://preview.redd.it/t3q0qmt99ypf1.jpg?width=492&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=8432a10821ca6c5af7055e88dd839c8f6c7a0068</a></p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/rjhxtnv99ypf1.jpg?width=1305&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=74b87bad5460181dc402853d76f432abd3f33bf8">https://preview.redd.it/rjhxtnv99ypf1.jpg?width=1305&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=74b87bad5460181dc402853d76f432abd3f33bf8</a></p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/0y7font99ypf1.jpg?width=1279&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=60ec12e0222768986c65b67c47d8c0312d4fd79a">https://preview.redd.it/0y7font99ypf1.jpg?width=1279&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=60ec12e0222768986c65b67c47d8c0312d4fd79a</a></p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/9lv8gpt99ypf1.jpg?width=1305&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d51d008a26b9725fd21559e93c6d8e37d786f0d9">https://preview.redd.it/9lv8gpt99ypf1.jpg?width=1305&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=d51d008a26b9725fd21559e93c6d8e37d786f0d9</a></p><p><a href="https://preview.redd.it/po348ot99ypf1.jpg?width=1196&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=764bf8dcc26bb71d010f9ca571bdda2457b4e92c">https://preview.redd.it/po348ot99ypf1.jpg?width=1196&amp;format=pjpg&amp;auto=webp&amp;s=764bf8dcc26bb71d010f9ca571bdda2457b4e92c</a></p><p>I love experimenting with AI + automation, so I decided to see if I could build something that manages my emails almost like a personal assistant. The result? A fully automated AI Secretary that drafts replies, classifies messages, and even alerts me when something urgent comes in.</p><p>Here’s what it does: </p><ul><li><strong>Reads &amp; Classifies Emails:</strong> GPT automatically figures out if an email is a customer query, sponsorship request, spam, or personal.</li><li><strong>Drafts Replies:</strong> Using my writing style + context from a knowledge base in Airtable, the AI drafts emails ready for me to review.</li><li><strong>Sends Alerts:</strong> Urgent messages? I get an instant SMS. Never miss a high-priority email again.</li><li><strong>Remembers Everything:</strong> Airtable acts as the AI’s memory. Update it once, and the AI uses that info in future emails.</li><li><strong>Interactive App Interface:</strong> Built a chat-style interface with Lovable.dev. I can draft replies, query emails, manage Airtable “memories,” and trigger workflows all from one place.</li></ul><p><strong>Tech stack:</strong> GPT-4o, n8n (automation), Airtable, Gmail API, GoHighLevel, Lovable.dev.</p><p><strong>Outcome:</strong></p><ul><li>About 80% of routine emails are auto-drafted.</li><li>High-value emails reach me instantly.</li><li>Feels like having a 24/7 assistant built entirely with AI + automation.</li></ul><p>I’d love to hear what you think! Would you use something like this for your workflow?</p><p><a href="https://www.loom.com/share/4d3589ab44ba41f7884038b917191d6c?sid=4fe5dcdf-d14c-43c8-bac1-57b2153fa87f">Loom video of AI Secretary Demo</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>That&#39;s Lovely , I have myself build an Ai agent for our finance team that automates their invoice data extraction process, it works on Outlook and whenever an email with invoice comes it fetches the invoice and process it to our accounts application that is aggresso.</p><p>I am using Fask with html css being a developer. I&#39;d like to explore n8n seems powerful and interesting.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/nexl1ha/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I actually wantes to build just the secretary for me, thats cool</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/newyusj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You told your AI secretary that you are building an AI secretary? lol</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/nez2cez/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Are you planning to open source this or sell it? Seems useful but also not that difficult to replicate</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/nezbwbi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I built almost same Ai agent using Make. The process is pretty simple:</p><p>1: Reads Form filled by client on website</p><p>2: Understand the intent of message/email</p><p>3: Fetches data required to respond from database (simple Google docs or sheets)</p><p>4: Writes and send a decent response email fulfilling the intent of customers.</p><p>I used only:</p><p>Forms submission as trigger (direct email could be used as well)</p><p>Gemini API for understanding query and custom response generation.</p><p>Google docs as a database to store information to be used in response writing e.g (opening time or product price etc)</p><p>I will see how i can add alert for important Emails on WhatsApp like you. This is very useful tbh.</p><p>you can see more about it from my profile, 3rd post ig.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/nezoglh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And what about the JSON file?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/nf05htb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is seriously cool, great work putting this all together. The use of n8n and Airtable as the &#39;memory&#39; is a really clever way to build out the knowledge base. It&#39;s a proper personal automation engine.</p><p>How was the process of training it on your specific writing style? I imagine getting the tone just right for different types of emails (customer query vs. personal) must have been a fun challenge.</p><p>it’s funny, this is basically a custom-built, personal version of what we build at eesel AI for customer support and internal teams. I work there, and it&#39;s awesome to see someone build a similar workflow from scratch just for their own inbox. We do a lot of the same stuff – learning from past conversations and connecting to knowledge bases to automate replies and classify/triage tickets in helpdesks like Zendesk or Intercom.</p><p>Really impressive what you&#39;ve managed to build on your own. Gives you a proper feel for what a full-on AI agent can do</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nkcynu/i_built_my_own_ai_secretary_and_it_actually_works/nf0klkz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:56:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/1rxkilli7wpf1.png</link><title>Scaling Lead Magnet Creation Without Burning Out (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nk3poa/scaling_lead_magnet_creation_without_burning_out/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nk3poa/scaling_lead_magnet_creation_without_burning_out/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nk3poa/scaling_lead_magnet_creation_without_burning_out/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>When you’re working with multiple clients, creating unique lead magnets becomes overwhelming. I hit that wall last year.</p><p>The solution? Automation. Using <strong>N8N with OpenAI and Claude</strong>, I designed a system that scales content creation without sacrificing quality. </p><p><strong>Each magnet takes minutes, not days.</strong></p><p>I shared the complete workflow in this tutorial:<br/>👉 <a href="https://youtu.be/AA33S3PF4t8">https://youtu.be/AA33S3PF4t8</a></p><p>How do you handle scaling when multiple content projects stack up?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/1rxkilli7wpf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nk3poa/scaling_lead_magnet_creation_without_burning_out/neuwruh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is a seriously cool workflow. N8N is a beast for this kind of automation, and I can totally relate to that content creation wall when juggling projects. Burnout is real.</p><p>full disclosure, i work at eesel AI, and we&#39;re obsessed with this kind of stuff. We&#39;ve been applying a similar principle to our own knowledge base. Instead of creating articles from scratch, our AI analyzes resolved support tickets and automatically drafts help center articles based on successful solutions. It’s been a massive help for finding and filling content gaps with stuff we know is useful.</p><p>It’s awesome to see how people are using different sources whether it&#39;s prompts like in your case or past conversations like in ours to scale up content creation. This is definitely the future.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nk3poa/scaling_lead_magnet_creation_without_burning_out/nezs8s8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:03:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/</link><title>Best Free YouTube Video Summariser (AI) with Good UI/Functions?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey folks,</p><p>I’m looking for a <strong>free AI tool/website/extension</strong> that can summarise YouTube videos effectively.<br/>Ideally, I’d like something that:</p><ul><li>Works well with long videos (lectures, podcasts, etc.)</li><li>Gives clear, concise summaries (bullet points or text would be great)</li><li>Has a <strong>clean, user-friendly UI</strong></li><li>Doesn’t require too many sign-ups or hidden paywalls</li><li>Bonus if it can generate timestamps or chapter-wise breakdowns</li></ul><p>I’ve seen a few floating around but many are either clunky, limited, or push you to pay after a couple of uses.</p><p>What are you all using that works well and is actually free?</p><p>Thanks in advance!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>i use ChatGPT by copying the transcript and giving a prompt. it s not perfect but it s not that bad either</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/nev1psk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Just use chat gpt or perplexity</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/neu9f0j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>hey! I’ve been trying out a bunch of these lately too, some are super clunky like you said</p><p>the one I keep going back to is <strong>Eightify</strong> (Chrome extension). It gives nice bullet-point summaries, works on long vids like lectures and podcasts, and the UI’s clean. It has some free uses per day, which is usually enough unless you’re binging.</p><p>another one that’s been decent is <strong>YouTubeDigest</strong>. You can choose how you want the summary (bullets, paragraph, etc.) and it does timestamps too.</p><p>Sometimes I just grab the video transcript and toss it into ChatGPT myself if I want more control, but yeah, not the most fun if you&#39;re trying to save time.</p><p>What kind of videos are you usually summarizing? I might have some better picks depending on the type.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/neuaqdx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I built infocaptor. Give it a try</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/neuuiu8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>cofyt .app  hits most of what you’re asking for and there is some really bad advice here in the comments suggesting apps and models that are inadequate and do not stay grounded in the source material. </p><p>Obviously those tradional apps are fine if you don&#39;t need to trust the AI answers are based on the transcript...</p><p>Search for cofyt. app on Google, perplexity or reddit and get real feedback from users.</p><p>yes, it is my app and you may think that i´m just promoting so please do your try it and do a review based on the points you mentioned...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/neuylm5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hey, you can check out my side project TimestampAI (timestamps.video). Unfortunately it’s paid, but not that much. Otherwise it’s all you’re looking for including sub chapter timestamps etc</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/nevzm3a/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>vidiopintar</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njzmsf/best_free_youtube_video_summariser_ai_with_good/nez3c03/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:43:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/Entrepreneur/comments/1njsth0/would_you_trust_ai_to_handle_your_first_100/</link><title>Would you trust AI to handle your first 100 customers?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njuyj1/would_you_trust_ai_to_handle_your_first_100/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njuyj1/would_you_trust_ai_to_handle_your_first_100/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njuyj1/would_you_trust_ai_to_handle_your_first_100/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>For founders, the first 100 customers are make or break. Some teams hand off repetitive onboarding or support tasks to automation so they can focus on building. Others say it is too risky early on. </p><p>Would you trust AI with your earliest customers or keep everything human? I&#39;m thinking both- hybrid approach. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njuyj1/would_you_trust_ai_to_handle_your_first_100/net5hkz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Totally feel this dilemma. I&#39;m leaning toward a hybrid approach too.</p><p>In my case, I used GPT + Make to automate first-touch replies and simple onboarding questions for a side project (SaaS-style info product). It freed me up to do deep-dives with interested users, but I <em>always</em> had manual override or routing to myself for anything slightly nuanced. What worked really well was using tags like “needs-human” based on certain keywords or sentiment scoring in the chat.</p><p>That said, for the <em>first</em> 100, I’d be extra cautious. Those early convos are gold for understanding friction points and building trust. Maybe automate the scaffolding (FAQs, booking links, reminders), but keep the heart of it human, especially for feedback loops and objections.</p><p>Curious, what part of the experience are you thinking of automating first? Onboarding? Support? Sales convos?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njuyj1/would_you_trust_ai_to_handle_your_first_100/neumq8p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>For the first 100 customers I’d probably go hybrid too. Early customers give you the raw feedback you need to refine your product so keeping some direct human interaction is important.</p><p>Using AI for supporting tasks (like answering repeat questions) can save a ton of time without losing the personal touch. It’s less about replacing the human side and more about making sure founders aren’t buried in admin work instead of learning from those customers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njuyj1/would_you_trust_ai_to_handle_your_first_100/nevnn3r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:43:21 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/qiixu332lspf1.png</link><title>First time using AI agents with SAP S/4HANA (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njporq/first_time_using_ai_agents_with_sap_s4hana/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njporq/first_time_using_ai_agents_with_sap_s4hana/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njporq/first_time_using_ai_agents_with_sap_s4hana/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Had a client ask me to handle procurement in S/4HANA, basically creating and submitting a PO. Normally that’s hours of clicking through screens and filling fields.</p><p>This time I tried setting up an AI agent as a browser worker. It logged in, went into Procurement, created the PO, filled the header fields, added line items, and submitted. Whole thing wrapped up in less than 5 mins.</p><p>Anyone here tried something similar? and also do you think these Agents will start becoming part of daily SAP workflows, or is it still too early for that?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/qiixu332lspf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njporq/first_time_using_ai_agents_with_sap_s4hana/nes09av/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What platform did you use to build this?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njporq/first_time_using_ai_agents_with_sap_s4hana/nesjuzw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What platform is this?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njporq/first_time_using_ai_agents_with_sap_s4hana/nesz5k0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:51:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/jir0pqf8bqpf1.jpeg</link><title>Are we going to live to see perfectly safe industry? (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njdj39/are_we_going_to_live_to_see_perfectly_safe/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njdj39/are_we_going_to_live_to_see_perfectly_safe/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njdj39/are_we_going_to_live_to_see_perfectly_safe/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://i.redd.it/jir0pqf8bqpf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Hell no. Too expensive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njdj39/are_we_going_to_live_to_see_perfectly_safe/nepltto/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1njdj39/are_we_going_to_live_to_see_perfectly_safe/nepcq6o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 19:12:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/</link><title>What is an automation you actually pay for?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>A lot of automation tools float around promising to save time, but I’m curious about the ones people actually find worth paying for.</p><p>For example:</p><ul><li>Some marketers swear by email drip automations.</li><li>Devs might pay for CI/CD pipelines or error monitoring.</li><li>Ops teams sometimes invest in invoice/payment automations.</li></ul><p>What’s that one automation tool or setup you happily pay for because it saves you way more time/money/mental energy than it costs?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>If you could AI as automation, I pay $100+ every month for automations for my business</p><ol><li>Coding Automation: I pay for Windsurf to use their Cascade AI Agent which basically automates most of trivial coding changes for me. Its been able to handle most of bigger tasks as well as long as I split it into small steps</li><li>Blog Automation: We pay for Frizerly which scans our competitors top keywords they rank on Google and then automatically create content on our website around those same keywords to complete with them. It can also pick trending topics and create content around that on a daily basis. All we have to do is flip the switch from draft to published after reviewing it everyday.</li><li>Support Automation: We pay for Intercom Fin which automatically handles and resolves support queries that have already been answered or is already documented on our website!</li></ol><p>Curious, what others are paying for tho. Always looking for more automation!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/neo88r2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>marketing tool - leadverse.ai</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/neoclf3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>parent control</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/neodlrt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Call response automation and incident resolution for customer service</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/nepcglt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>For me it’s customer support automation. Even simple things like auto-routing tickets or having a bot handle the top five repeat questions save a small team hours every week.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/neps92r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Thank you for your post to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation">/r/automation</a>!</p><p>New here? Please take a moment to read our rules, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/about/rules/">read them here.</a></p><p>This is an automated action so if you need anything, please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fautomation">Message the Mods</a> with your request for assistance.</p><p>Lastly, enjoy your stay!</p><p><em>I am a bot, and this action was performed automatically. Please <a href="https://www.reddit.com/message/compose/?to=/r/automation">contact the moderators of this subreddit</a> if you have any questions or concerns.</em></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/neo7rb7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>For me it is error monitoring tied into deployment pipelines. I don’t mind paying because the time saved catching silent failures before users notice is way more valuable than the subscription cost.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/automation/comments/1nj7pf4/what_is_an_automation_you_actually_pay_for/neoda4v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:12:06 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
