<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=economics&amp;averagePostsPerDay=5&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/economics</title><description>Hot posts in /r/economics (roughly 5 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 08:47:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132/img/platforms/reddit.png</url><title>/r/economics</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/economics/</link></image><item><link>https://apnews.com/article/h1b-visa-trump-immigration-8d39699d0b2de3d90936f8076357254e</link><title>Trump signs proclamation imposing $100K annual fee for H-1B visa applications (apnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The companies that benefit most from the H1B program are deep in Trump&#39;s pockets. I give this half-baked plan less than 7 Scaramuccis before he walks it back.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5jylb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This strikes me another scam where he gets the tech bros to grovel and bribe, a month from now this isn’t a thing.</p><p>Same scam, different week. Would it be good in some ways to shift hiring domestically? Sure, but as many have pointed out above there are a number of potential negatives as well. </p><p>Again though, I do not see this as serious policy.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5oyu0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This requires congress approval. Will get shut down on a month; and this time of the year there&#39;s a hiring freeze anyways since the holidays are coming up.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5j5c2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Proclamation?!?! He’s not a fucking king, not unless we’re talking about the king of sex with underage ladies. When is he gonna crawl back under his rock?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5vj5b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How’s his drug cost proclaiming going? He signed an executive order to lower drug prices a long time ago and NOTHING HAS CHANGED. The rich run this country, I’m sure they had a good laugh about that too.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5loh7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Its not per year. Lutnik doesn&#39;t even read his own proclamations. And all the news just ate it up. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/09/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-suspends-the-entry-of-certain-alien-nonimmigrant-workers/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/09/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-suspends-the-entry-of-certain-alien-nonimmigrant-workers/</a></p><p>Its 100k per petition. So more like 33k/year.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5xbje/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is trump throwing a tantrum because Modi snubbed him and made a deal with China. Also, he will never impose this policy. Chaos will ensue and the economy may collapse. </p><p>Edit: My thoughts are that this if implemented will cause huge chaos and there will be only losers in the short term. No one can predict what will happen in the long term. But we’ll all experience pain for sure. </p><p>What a shame.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nlho22/trump_signs_proclamation_imposing_100k_annual_fee/nf5ldd7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 04:09:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.economist.com/leaders/2025/09/18/chinas-200m-gig-workers-are-a-warning-for-the-world</link><title>China's 200m gig workers are a warning for the world (economist.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Gig work in general was supposed to be there as a form of supplementary income. The fact that it had become a primary form of earnings for so many is the red flag.</p><p>It is a highlight for how the wealthy wish things were for everyone, and with the massive push for AI globally, they are very likely to get their wish.</p><p>Remember, the goal of AI is not to be transformational; it is to be <em>good enough</em> that it can justify firing workers. Service quality is irrelevant. See: Verizon.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf31qjd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>China has a total population of 1.4 billion with a workforce population of about 770 million in 2023. The same ratio as America&#39;s 170 million workforce population to 340 million total population.</p><p>China&#39;s ~200m gig workers represents about 26% of their workforce. America has, by conservative estimates, between 57 to 72 million (36~45%) gig workers. I think America is the warning for the world.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf1txr3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Are these primary jobs or second jobs?</p><p>I know very few people who try to make a living solely on gig work. They are usually working multiple crappy jobs, which is a different kind of economic warning.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf23ltp/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is Trump&#39;s vision for America. No wages or benefits or protections, Just a disjointed working system where people work and pay taxes while costing corporation nothing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nl0f5s/chinas_200m_gig_workers_are_a_warning_for_the/nf4opcq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:28:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://fortune.com/2025/09/17/jerome-powell-ai-bubble-inequality-rich/?&amp;</link><title>Jerome Powell on signs of an AI bubble and an economy leaning too hard on the rich: 'Unusually large amounts of economic activity' (fortune.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The S&amp;P 500&#39;s CAPE (cyclically adjusted price-to-earnings) ratio is currently ~39, hit an all-time high of 44 during dot-com bubble, and historically averages ~17-18.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezeehu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A few people got really rich and everybody else is going to be really poor and not be able to afford the same lifestyle they had even 6 months ago. </p><p>I have worked so many different recessions so far as both an investment broker and also a banker and also a construction worker and also a contractor. </p><p>The biggest pet peeve I have or the biggest thing that I&#39;m annoyed about is that the farmers who voted for Trump are getting bailouts while everybody else are paying for those bailouts not only by the increased fees due to tariffs but also due to the fact that we&#39;re paying taxes that are going to people who voted against their better interest and now we&#39;re going broke and we now have to pay for them so they don&#39;t commit suicide</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezik88/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is 1929 all over again. The stock market is booming because it has sucked all the money from the rest of the economy and that is a proven recipe for economic collapse. It will not be different this time</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezsdoc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><em>I summarised this article from Fortune.com. Most of the words are the authors - any issues lmk!</em></p><p><strong>- Before we read the article, what is an Economic Bubble?</strong></p><p>&quot;An economic bubble is the <strong>rapid escalation in asset prices that exceeds intrinsic value</strong>, <strong>leading to a sudden market contraction known as a crash</strong> or bubble burst.&quot; - from Investopedia. </p><p><strong>Article summary</strong></p><ul><li>Wall street commentators have worried that the <strong>AI boom looks like a bubble</strong>, with some analysts estimating investment could reach $3 trillion by 2028. </li><li>Very recently they received an <strong>acknowledgment</strong> from the chair of the FED</li><li>&quot;U.S. is seeing &quot;unusually large amounts of economic activity through the AI buildout&quot; - this is skewed towards the wealthy.</li><li>Consumer spending has taken on a K shape- &quot;where the performance of different parts of the economy diverges like the arms of the letter K&quot; (Some parts of the economy may experience growth whilst others decline)</li><li>This K shape is evident today - in the U.S, spending is skewed - todays higher earning consumers are spending more, whilst lower income families cut back on essentials</li><li>Powell notes that layoffs are rare but job creation has slowed - that combined with the concentration of economic gains in AI and among the wealthy risks deepening inequality (K shape!). It also complicates the Fed&#39;s attempt to balance its inflation and employment mandates because of the risk of demand pull inflation and lowering employment rates</li></ul><p>My summary leans slightly on the negative side - but this AI capex isn&#39;t all negative !!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nezch2p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So I’m not an economist, but from what I’ve gathered this time is structured different from the dot com bubble - in that crash the companies were all small startups. </p><p>In this economy, ai is being funded and propped up by the wealthiest mega corporations in the world, that have other means of income and (from what I understand) a better ability to weather, outlast, and pivot from downturns and such.</p><p>I’d love to hear from someone more educated about this than me though, how might it play out differently this time?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nf4ivf8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The country’s economy doesn’t work for 80% of the citizens and the economy is based on the spending of the top 10% and the stock market is held up by the whims of the top 1%.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkobkf/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nf56vu4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 05:22:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.marketwatch.com/story/why-mortgage-rates-are-actually-going-up-after-the-fed-cut-interest-rates-87c712bd</link><title>Why mortgage rates are actually going up after the Fed cut interest rates -- 'We actually anticipated the possibility that rates would tick up after the Fed announcement,' economist says (marketwatch.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Say it louder in the back - the Fed doesn&#39;t control mortgage rates and by cutting fed funds rates, housing will get more expensive, just like everything else as the dollar continues to devalue</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neytfp2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s because mortgage rates are mostly correlated with 10Y Treasury yields which while somewhat influenced by the fed funds rate are mostly market driven</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neyuziq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Jesus fuck seriously what is up with the length rule for comments.</p><p>I write actual constructive thoughts and every time I have to come back and add more... because automod deletes it for being too short.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neywijj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And that is why the bond market is important and when countries dump US bonds, the mortgage rates increase. When less people want US debt, it becomes a problem for those who hold the debt.</p><p>Right now despite the interest rate cut, the yield went higher because most investors are scared of US job losses accelerating and market slowdown.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/nf0lsat/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Don’t ignore the impact of QT in the MBS market. The Fed continues to reduce its holdings of MBS and the bond market isn’t interested enough to keep rates from going up. Housing prices need to come down to unfreeze the housing market.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/nezh9w5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>After Jpow is gone they are going to put someone in there that is going to implement &#39;QE with a twist&#39;. They are going to buy up longer term bonds to get the yield on the 30 year lower and to also get mortgage rates lower. Kind of like &#39;operation twist&#39; that they did in 2011-2012 iirc</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neytsc6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Selfishly...good.  I bought points to get a sub-6% rate a year ago, and I wouldn&#39;t mind if rates stayed above that for another 18 months so the cost of the points ended up being worth it.</p><p>But also selfishly, lower interest rates would increase business for my job.</p><p>But also also selfishly, lower rates plus tariffs might turbocharge inflation.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkl9cf/why_mortgage_rates_are_actually_going_up_after/neyxyqn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 03:10:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://apnews.com/article/supreme-court-trump-lisa-cook-federal-reserve-d7cd7bf7b8bca591b1748591836c3645</link><title>Trump asks the Supreme Court for an emergency order to remove Lisa Cook from the Fed board (apnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>This just makes one wonder what the end game is for Trump in this whole thing. Just yesterday the Fed dropped rates 25bp and signaled continued cuts for the foreseeable future.</p><p>What does Trump want that he isn’t getting here? And why is that thing worth blowing up the “full faith and credit” of the US dollar?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newqdss/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Why is it always an emergency when this man doesn&#39;t get what he wants? His parents really should have done something about that spoiled bully attitude when he was younger.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newujpi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Although I’m not an American, Trump’s attempt in controlling the Fed and removing its independence is perhaps the worst thing he has done to the U.S.</p><p>If Trump does manage to effectively control the Fed, it would be a major blow for American hegemony. </p><p>He will inevitably slash rates to rock bottom in a bid to boost the economy. But it will probably lead to inflation because the problem isn’t high interest rates causing rising unemployment, its fiscal uncertainty caused by his erratic economic policy. </p><p>Central Bank’s gained independence precisely to prevent Presidents misusing central banking tools like cutting interest rates at the wrong time to boost the economy leading to high inflation. </p><p>While abusing central banking tools isn’t an inevitability in general, but with Trump at the helm, it’s practically a certainty.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newtxwv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>trump wants fed rates at 1% or less right now to shoot the economy up and hide the stagflationary impacts of his far-right kleptocratic jingoistic economic policy. So he needs to subjeugate the FED right now to proceed.</p><p>By next may it might be too late and people will have begun to feel the consequences of electing this total wreck of a Party to power.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newrn6f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>All evidence undercuts the supposed crime, they should not be allowed to remove people from our most important institution with a bullshit casus belli, and before even being adjudicated? Whatever happened to innocent until proven guilty?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newtfwq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Seeing the dot plot from yesterday and the vote from Miran makes me very worried about him being the new Fed president regardless of what happens to Cook here. Having a corrupt Fed president could lead to issues even if the sane faction continues having a majority. Think of the fallout if a partisan Fed decided to do unlimited QE? Rates are a small fraction of the problem here.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newslgy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I suspect this will be the rare case where they turn him down. This is an opportunity to pretend to be impartial on an issue that has little actual consequence. Even if she was replaced it would not have impacted the decision this week.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nkc4nd/trump_asks_the_supreme_court_for_an_emergency/newzu92/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:25:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.yahoo.com/finance/news/jerome-powell-signs-ai-bubble-222907233.html</link><title>Jerome Powell on signs of an AI bubble and an economy leaning too hard on the rich: 'Unusually large amounts of economic activity' (yahoo.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Does anyone else see a huge risk in this massive AI spending? MIT recently refitted that in a survey of companies adopting it, there was nothing gained. The growth of data centers is consuming large amounts of energy with rates climbing as a result. Wyoming already has data centers using more power than all its residential customers combined. Other states are on the verge of this. If AI fails to provide returns which justify this, isn’t a huge collapse likely?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nevpuj6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Given so much of the economy is now the top 10%, if we do see a stock market correction, I think the actual change in GDP will be greater than previous corrections. </p><p>Why? Because the rich own most of the stocks and will feel poorer. Their spending is mostly discretionary. They dont need most of anything they buy. They just wont spend it. </p><p>Before when the stock market declined, it didn&#39;t affect consumption nearly as much. Workers just kept spending and didn&#39;t even look at their 401k if they had it. </p><p>Now you&#39;ve got to please this top 10% and if you dont they wont keep propping up the economy single handedly. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/neuhq6k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>start your watches</p><p>Alan Greenspan&#39;s famous &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; comment was made on December 5, 1996, during a speech at the American Enterprise Institute. The dot-com crash is widely recognized as beginning when the Nasdaq Composite peaked on March 10, 2000, before entering a sharp decline.</p><p>There were about 3 years and 3 months (approximately 39 months) between Greenspan&#39;s &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; speech and the peak that marked the start of the dot-com crash.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nev4nbh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;Every American is a momentarily embarrassed millionaire&quot; is the greatest con perpetuated upon the ethos of USA. The degree to which the poors and working class vote against their own interests never ceases to amaze. The farmers seem to not be enjoying the finding out part. Anyways...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/neuc9b2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The data centers can not make enough profit to pay for themselves, the amount spent is just too high. The technology is obsolete now that there are other systems that use less energy. Our AI is dependent upon things that should be illegal and inevitably will be in the rest of the world. This is beyond buying stock with borrowed money, this is just burning dollars in the furnace to mint pennies.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nev30e0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>AI bubble is no different from the telecom boom &amp; bust of the early 2000s. There will be an excess of GPUs in the market when AI usage does not materialize as expected. AI won’t go away but the bubble would have been pricked.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nev9124/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The die for this economic model was cast over 50 years ago leading into Reagan&#39;s run and eventual 2 term presidency. Accountability for and taxes on the wealthy have been slashed since then, so it&#39;s hardly shocking that we have a 2 tier economy and embarassingly horrific inequality.</p><p>That was the point; funnel as much of the benefits to the top. It wasn&#39;t some fluke. They knew trickle down didn&#39;t work, but this propaganda which is even more extreme today, was designed and implemented for this exact outcome. The plan was an extraordinary success but the wish list still isn&#39;t complete. Project 2025 goals defines most of that. Left unchecked, these people&#39;s aggression will not end. It&#39;s up to the public to stop it. But how bad will things get before then?</p><p>Today orruption abounds and leadership for both parties, brazen and aggressively by one more than the other, caters to the top. A 2 tier justice system has always existed in the country. Most of government has been captured by rent seekers. These discrepancies can be found in court cases, economic data, and anecdotes from every day lives of Americans. Maybe those records will be deleted or whitewashed like government records on terrorism that were deleted this week, or shutdown through censorship that&#39;s ongoing.</p><p>The country&#39;s leaders and millions of uneducated, highly persuadable voters have completely dismissed the idea of democracy altogether and we march down the path of fascism. Yes men replace anyone in the way of personal agendas and grift. We&#39;re always at war or involved with them. We&#39;ve seemingly returned to the time of kings and religion as a state prop.</p><p>Powell sees the writing on the wall. Anyone can observe the points his made and will see an unstable future ahead if they&#39;re honest with themselves. Even this relatively independent institution has been or is being captured now. I think of a cartoon picture I saw where &quot;small government&quot; is promoted and the frames progress from left with checks and balances, to the right with 1 man in control of everything. The country has abandoned everything it was supposed to stand for.</p><p>I&#39;m still optimistic for the country, but to rediscover and motivate the public to return to our idea of &quot;dream,&quot; a lot more suffering is going to take place before then. This feels like opening innings into a dark period ahead.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njyym9/jerome_powell_on_signs_of_an_ai_bubble_and_an/nevx86l/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:05:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/15/business/chinas-snub-of-us-soybeans-is-a-crisis-for-american-farmers.html?unlocked_article_code=1.mE8.owWy.o4cddSKR3fwk</link><title>China's Snub of U.S. Soybeans Is a Crisis for American Farmers (nytimes.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>They wanted this just like last time. Not like it matters. Apparently Brazil has filled the soybean orders for China and by next year they will have replaced American contracts. </p><p>The soybean farmers will move to other crops and what will happen will be an increase in competition for cash crops as more of them switch over causing profitability concerns.</p><p>None of this will translate to cheaper &quot;soybeans&quot; at the super market in America. Because of capitalism, they rather let it rot and lose money than condition you to accept cheaper products</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netn1ey/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Oh it’s a “crisis” for the people that voted for the guy that said he would do this? The same people that won’t say that they regret their vote? </p><p>That’s not a crisis. It’s a result they voted for.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netjia6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We are now getting to the &quot;finding out&quot; phase after &quot;fucking around&quot;. We&#39;re in for a world of economic hurt, and Trump his &quot;yes men&quot; are all to blame. Plenty of economists warned against this, but I&#39;m sure we&#39;ll hear the usual &quot;how could we have known&quot; responses from Trump et. al.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netkgu7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They suffered eight years ago when Trump did it the first time, did they really expect anything different? They don&#39;t care because they&#39;re the new welfare queens receiving massive payouts any time Trump cripples their industry.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netlprh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Oh no. Anyway, you were saying? Oh you were talking about how some people can&#39;t handle the consequences of their own actions? Like when they fuck up and find out? And when they realize that all the Obama blaming on Fox News is not gonna make their own lives better?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netk4hz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It’s not a crisis, it’s a way for American soybean farmers to rob their fellow citizens and inflate the currency by way yet another Bailout. They get to hate trans and people of color while receiving cash money from those same individuals. It’s pathetic but it’s no different than the first Trump administration.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netkurv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It would be easier to sympathize if they learned anything from their mistake.  Instead, the lesson they learn is to grab the hot stove harder.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njwm2r/chinas_snub_of_us_soybeans_is_a_crisis_for/netmoxi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:02:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.nbcnews.com/business/economy/federal-reserve-interest-rates-decision-rcna231729</link><title>Federal Reserve cuts interest rates for the first time this year (nbcnews.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Is this likely to really have any meaningful ramifications on employment? To me it seems like business are not hiring or planning investments because of policy uncertainty, not because high interest rates are preventing them from doing so.</p><p>It&#39;s the wrong medicine for the underlying disease. I feel like the employment issues gave them the narrative to cut despite inflation. They have to try and get yields down to refinance their debt burden.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqz8lm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Inflation has increased some and is higher than the <a href="https://www.cbo.gov/publication/60870">2.1%</a> CBO projected for this year back in January...but also job growth has slowed dramatically. So it&#39;s not the easiest decision. They decided the risk from a decidely more negative economic outlook surpasses the inflation risk. Never mind that long sought after 2% target.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/ner3x4s/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This was basically the only thing to do based on data I suppose.</p><p>The labor market is cooling down and has been this entire year, and while inflation is obviously going up, the unemployment and the economy was the bigger issue for the Fed.</p><p>In an ideal world, the Fed would have cut rates without having to worry about inflation and not because the market was cooling down and had to be saved, but because it was a stable time and they could just look forward.</p><p>Instead.....sigh.</p><p>Anyway, if the people were complaining about inflation last year.....lol.</p><p>What&#39;s funny is that I don&#39;t see even half the cries about inflation now in the media like they did in 2024 with Biden, even though pretty much everything has very noticeably increased and will increase even more. The media environment is so bad that if the same media existed in the 70s, Nixon would never have had to resign. Which of course was the point of Roger Ailes creating Fox News, so his dream came true.</p><p>I sometimes wonder if Trump isn&#39;t just a Russian asset, but also a Democrat asset, because he&#39;s doing everything in his power to ruin the GOP for a generation a la Herbert Hoover lmao. Not that it will happen, people love their parties like its their family dynasty.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqvves/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Is inflation really only around 3%. I feel like I&#39;m being gaslit when everyone is saying this yet my budget shows a 20% increase in general expenses.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/ner78l4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As expected. Will be interesting to see how many dissent on both sides (no rate cuts versus larger rate cuts), and what the &quot;dot plot&quot; looks like for the future.</p><p>I think the Fed made the best choice given the data currently available to it (along with likely projected trajectories of labor markets, growth, and inflation).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqw3dy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There&#39;s not much he can really do really; inflation isn&#39;t coming down and the job market even after Trump cooking the books shows the economy isn&#39;t doing well.  Damned if you do, damned if you don&#39;t moment.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/neqzpd1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Even though inflation is still 3% the Federal Reserve was so worried about unemployment that they had to lower rates. That said pretty much means the economy has fallen into the tank ever since Donald J Trump took office. Sad believe him and all the Republican traitors that follow him.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkm5r/federal_reserve_cuts_interest_rates_for_the_first/nesb2uq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:36:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-17/fico-scores-fall-at-fastest-rate-since-financial-crisis-mfo4a5hy</link><title>Gen Z Leads Biggest Drop in FICO Scores Since Financial Crisis (bloomberg.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I’m assuming that this is almost assuredly tied to the resumption of student loan payments, which had been on deferment until late 2023, then had a 1 year “ramp-up” back to normal ending in late 2024. Since the beginning of this year payments are pretty much back to business as usual (as far as I am aware) and as such, delinquencies are increasing causing credit hits.</p><p>The current state of the labor market certainly isn’t helping this which may be why the Fed was onboard with a rate cut to try and stimulate hiring in some capacity.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/neqzghu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I see a troubling trend with young people: they have zero hope in a better future.</p><p>“Who care about a credit score when I’ll never be able to afford a home?” Is something I can imagine hearing echoed across the generation.</p><p>Our entire society has been structured to siphon off wealth from the poor and young, and funnel it into the greedy mouths of the rich and old. Yet they act surprised when, after robbing all hope of a better life, young people act nihilistically?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nerjqt2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There has been a lot of indications that the economy is being carried by increasing debt and this looks like another one. We are at peak margin loan debt and credit card debt in an environment with very punitive interest rates. At some point, especially for folks &lt;30, it just makes more sense to default and declare bankruptcy. If enough folks do that you end up with a financial crisis. As an anecdotal sidenote, all of my Gen Z family and co-workers seem incredibly flippant about credit in general. It seems to be a combo of ignorance and fatalism. If that mentality proves too common we could have big long term issues.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nerbttl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As a millenial I feel so relieved now that gen z has taken the mantle of dealing with stupid journalists. My advice to them is to save on avocado toast and labubus.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/neuxvf8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There’s no way to sugar-coat this. Fico numbers are basically unreliable at this point. Not only did they not capture student loans until recently, but they also are not fully capturing the bnpl debts which are estimated to be tremendous, given how little time they have existed.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/ner77ty/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is a drop from like 717 to 715 on the overall score whereas the drop before 2008 was a 3 point drop to about 678</p><p>Important context. Although the Gen Z figure is interesting. 676 is where that cohort is at. Would be interested to see where that number has been historically.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nesegbg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Does this country understand that you can just invest in US Stocks and NOT invest in the young people that will have to run and staff those companies? Hello?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1njkcvq/gen_z_leads_biggest_drop_in_fico_scores_since/nexip0f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:27:57 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.fastcompany.com/91405390/u-s-credit-scores-suffer-largest-two-year-drop-since-great-recession</link><title>U.S. credit scores suffers largest 2-year drop since Great Recession (fastcompany.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The new national average is 715, down from 718 two years ago, as household debt climbs and inflation bites.</p><p>The data also shows that compared with 2021, more Americans are falling into the low and high ends of the credit score range rather than the middle. In 2021, 38% of scores were between 600 and 749; in 2025, that percentage is 33.8%. The highest FICO score is 850.</p><p>U.S. borrowers continue to grapple with high interest rates, a side effect of the Federal Reserve’s efforts to rein in the soaring post-pandemic inflation that’s driving high prices. In spite of those efforts—and with rate cuts imminent—President Trump’s tariffs are pushing inflation up yet again, making the cost of gas, groceries, clothes, and other essentials even less affordable. </p><p>“The recent K-shaped economy has led to financial stress for some borrowers impacted by affordability concerns stemming from inflation and higher interest rates, while others have benefited from increases in their stock market portfolios and home price appreciation,” the FICO report states. That data reflects America’s wealth gap, wherein the rich get richer and the poor get poorer, hollowing out the middle class in the process.</p><p>Falling credit scores among young people are linked to resumed student loan delinquency reporting, which reappeared on credit reports in February for the first time after the CARES Act. While only 17% of the broader U.S. population is still paying down a student loan, that percentage is 34% for Gen Z. It’s no surprise then that 14% of Gen Zers had a 50-point score drop in the last year, with late student loan payments hitting their credit reports for the first time.</p><p>For people in the U.S distant from the stock market’s highs, the economy is starting to feel like America during a very different era—a malaise backed by the new data. “Delinquency rates on auto loans, credit cards, and personal loans are at or near their highest levels since 2009, during the Great Recession—and are more consistent with an economy in recession than one still in expansion,” the FICO report states.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/neob80n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I don’t know enough about credit scoring in aggregate, but wouldn’t this be a sign that we are already underway an economic event? Scores fluctuate with 30, 60, and 90 day delinquencies and defaults, along with high balances being carried over? Doesn’t seem like it’s a good indicator of economic health.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/nepp69y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s down 3 points in 2 years. The range is 300-850, or 550 points. The average score is down 0.55% of the range. In other words, a 3 point change over 2 years is hardly concerning. Also, we should consider that the way credit scores are calculated isn&#39;t publicly available. These private companies have most likely tweaked their scoring systems.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/Economics/comments/1nj87c9/us_credit_scores_suffers_largest_2year_drop_since/nept2ud/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 14:44:55 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
