<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=linux&amp;averagePostsPerDay=9&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;filterPinnedComments&amp;filterOldPosts=3&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/linux</title><description>Hot posts in /r/linux (roughly 9 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 21:19:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/styles-redditmedia-com-t5_2qh1a-styles-communityIcon_m00t4v99ksj11-144x400.png</url><title>/r/linux</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://lore.kernel.org/git/20250904-b4-pks-rust-breaking-change-v1-0-3af1d25e0be9@pks.im/</link><title>Git: Introduce Rust and announce that it will become mandatory (lore.kernel.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Kind of a misleading title.  This is introducing the ability to write rust code as part of git, to figure out if this is useful.  As part of that the rust toolchain becomes a mandatory part of building git, but does not (yet) make writing rust code mandatory.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/nf9w482/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This won&#39;t be controversial at all...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/nf9sxtn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Unless I&#39;m missing something, Git 3.0 &quot;requiring Rust&quot; is just a goal. Its not official (yet). And what does &quot;requiring rust&quot; even mean, they&#39;re just adding rust code?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/nf9v5og/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Cool. Anubis blocked me calling me an AI scraper, although I&#39;m a real human behind WireGuard. While I get it, give me a capcha or something don&#39;t straight up call me a bot and block me.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/nf9wyqz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Mandatorty*</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/nf9u4v4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Move away from perl? Yeah!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/nf9w5zo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I can feel the anguished mental emanations of 100.000 nerds who have not coded <em>anything</em> in their lives.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm2y05/git_introduce_rust_and_announce_that_it_will/nf9vf9e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 22:09:12 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/</link><title>A quick guide to choosing the right linux distro and desktop environment</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 3 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Disclaimer: This is my opinion, but I will try to make it as objective as possible. This post is meant for beginners, searching for their first linux distro or desktop environment (DE). Look at the comments for differing opinions as well.</p><p>General guidelines: -You should choose something popular, because that usually means there’s more bug reports, more development and therefore more stability.-If a DE only has experimental wayland support, don’t use wayland yet.</p><p>First off, I believe, that choosing the DE is the first thing you should do. </p><p>-KDE: It’s a modern and polished DE with an intuitive design, especially if you’re coming from windows. Most things should “just work”.</p><p>-GNOME: It’s also a modern and polished DE, but might be a bit less intuitive for a windows user (I have heard it’s better for MacOS users, but I can’t comment on that). You can install a few extensions to suit your needs, and that should make it easy to switch from windows.</p><p>-Cinnamon: It’s polished and intuitive, but a bit less modern in feature set and imo in design (look at pictures online and judge for yourself) </p><p>These are the DEs that a first time user should use imo, other ones have less development and are either older in feature set, design, or are less stable (or targeted at experienced linux users). If you’re reading this in the future, when COSMIC DE has released, then you can look into that as well.</p><p>When you’ve decided on the DE, then the only thing you should worry about is the update-cycle of the distro. If you have very new hardware, then choosing a distro with a quick update cycle is the best option.</p><p>If you chose KDE, then there are a few options:If you want updates once every 2 years, choose DebianIf you want updates twice a year, choose kubuntuIf you want updates a few times a month, choose fedora KDEand If you want updates a few times a day, then choose something Arch based (Endavour OS is my recommendation)</p><p>If you chose GNOME, If you want updates once every 2 years, choose DebianIf you want updates twice a year, choose UbuntuIf you want updates a few times a month, choose fedoraand If you want updates a few times a day, then choose something Arch based (Endavour OS is my recommendation)</p><p>And if you chose Cinnamon, I think that Linux Mint is the best option, because Cinnamon is developed together with Mint. </p><p>I don’t recommend installing POP OS until the COSMIC de releases, because it’s not getting updates until it does.</p><p>For transparency, I currently use Arch with Enlightenment WM, and have experience with all of the DEs and distros that I mentioned except Debian. I also have experience with hyprland, xfce, cosmic alpha and probably other ones that I don’t remember at the moment. </p><p>When I first tried to install linux I really wanted a simple and quick guide for choosing the right distro and DE combination for everyone, and so I wrote it now, that I have more experience with linux. In pursuit of keeping it simple I only mentioned the options that I think a beginner should use.</p><p>If I got anything wrong, or if you don’t agree with something, comment on this post and I will update it.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I dunno.  I put my very non-technical mother and my very non-technical brother-in-law on XFCE4 and they did fine.</p><p>Pretty much all desktops use similar &quot;minimize-maximize-close&quot; buttons on the window frame, and XFCE (IMO) is much harder for a newbie to accidentally bork than the more &quot;advanced&quot; DEs.</p><p>Most software developers completely fail to take into account that older users and newbies can accidentally click something that changes the environment, and not even know what they did.  IMO, every DE should have a button that locks it down from any further customizations, with the only way to unlock it hidden deeply in a menu or requiring a CLI tool.</p><p>So I guess I would recommend Debian or a Debian-derivative like Mint, with XFCE4.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/nf9nidx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I agree 100%. Also most 3rd party software and support is debian/ubuntu/kubuntu, so maybe mention that.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/nf9nira/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I 100% agree</p><p>I hate the concept that you choose your distro based on use case</p><p>If you want to game choose distro X, if you want to do multimedia choose distro Y, if you do programming choose distro Z</p><p>It makes no sense , no distro is better at gaming ? Any distro can be a gaming distro if you install wine/proton/steam</p><p>Yes the biggest difference between distros is update cycles , do you want something stable that will only updtate every 2 years , something stable that will update 2 times a year, or a rolling distro that will update daily/weekly </p><p>Thats pretty much the question to ask , not if you game, or program , or do multimedia stuff</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/nf9pfm9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>First off, I believe, that choosing the DE is the first thing you should do.</p></blockquote><p>I disagree. Though people seem to obsess about DEs, it really doesn&#39;t matter that much to a new user. They&#39;ll all be different than what they&#39;re used to and none of the mainstream options are particularly difficult to learn.</p><p>The best advice for new users is to stop trying to figure out the &quot;best&quot; options. Simply install Linux Mint with the Cinnamon DE and start using it. They&#39;ll get a reliable, well-supported, easy-to-use system to help them over the learning curve. They can learn where to get help, find applications to do the things they need to do, learn how to run Windows games (if that&#39;s their thing), etc.</p><p>If they eventually decide that they want something different than what Mint/Cinnamon offer, switching isn&#39;t that hard (or people wouldn&#39;t be so addicted to distro-hopping). And, they&#39;ll have enough knowledge/experience at that point to make <em>informed</em> choices about things like DEs and distros. Since consumer-oriented Linux distros generally don&#39;t require a financial commitment, there&#39;s no reason that someone needs to agonize over getting the perfect one for them on the first try.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/nf9x8ok/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>All Linux newbies should use Linux Mint or Ubuntu Cinnamon until they have about 6 months of experience and have decided they want to make using Linux a hobby rather than just using their PC for normal purposes.</p><p>Unless someone wants to make a part-time hobby of OS configuration and fixing system issues, including broken drivers, adjusting system font sizes, using more than 1 monitor at once and avoiding random crashes from buggy beta software like Wayland, then stick with Cinnamon on Mint or Ubuntu.</p><p>The &quot;modern&quot; term is overused to describe subtle nuances in user interface design that almost nobody cares about but ex-Mac users and Mac users. If you&#39;re using Linux, then it&#39;s mostly about making your PC fully functional, when Windows will not allow that, usually because the system overhead is excessive or the OS has the privacy of a public bulletin board.</p><p>The exception is people who want to use Linux only to play Steamdeck-compatible Windows games. Then you might use Bazzite, but the Atomic file system isn&#39;t new user friendly at all for general purpose use if what you need isn&#39;t available as a flatpak. It&#39;s not experienced-user friendly either. It wasn&#39;t actually intended for desktop PC use.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nm22va/a_quick_guide_to_choosing_the_right_linux_distro/nf9nu2n/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 21:35:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/</link><title>Can someone explain to me how you all use Flatpaks willy nilly when they take up x10 or even x100 more space</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>So, question in title. My software manager has this nice option to compare install packages, including flatpaks. For some software, the system package can take a few MBs, while the flatpak for the same software takes up hudreds, sometimes more.</p><p>I understand the idea of isolation and encapsulation. But the tradeoff of using this much storage seems very steep. So how is flatpak so popular?</p><p>Edit: </p><p>Believe me I am a huge advocate for sandboxing and isolation. But some of these differences are just outlandish. For example:</p><p>Xournal++ System Package: 6MB.Xournal++ Flatpak: Download 910MB, Installed 1.9GB.</p><p>Gimp System Package: Download 20MB, Installed 100MB.Gimp Flatpak: Download 1.2GB, Installed 3.8GB.</p><p>P.S. thank you whoever made xournal++, it&#39;s great.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I don&#39;t use a lot of flatpaks but their weight is not always additive since flatpaks have the ability to share their runtime. Imagine you use gnome DE but want to use some KDE app and install it via flatpak, that flatpak includes the KDE runtime, if you later install another KDE app that second app doesn&#39;t need to download the whole KDE runtime again, it will only download the app part and use the existing KDE runtime from the first app.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/nf7jqsn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I don’t use flatpaks but my entire OS takes up less diskspace than a new AAA video game. The only thing on my primary drive besides programs is my home directory, and my spreadsheets aren’t exactly taking up gigs. I haven’t felt pressured for disk space for programs on a home PC since like, windows xp. Games take up so much more space it just isn’t even worth thinking about how much space Firefox takes up. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/nf7jsrg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><ol><li><p>Sandboxing</p></li><li><p>Works regardless of your distro</p></li></ol></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/nf7jqev/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Storage is extremely cheap these days and the tradeoff is worth it to many people.Even if you installed 100 flatpaks with 200MB each you&#39;d need at most 20GB — which is an amount I personally don&#39;t care about (and that I&#39;ll stay <em>far</em> below in practice)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/nf7jvbq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Flatpaks makes it easy to install apps because everything they need to run is included or shared through common runtimes. This means they work the same way on almost any Linux system. With traditional installs, your system has to manage all the pieces, which can sometimes cause conflicts or errors.</p><p>Using Flatpak also makes updates simpler, improves security with sandboxing, and helps reduce the problems of software working differently across Linux distros. It’s not meant to replace native installs, just to offer another choice. For most people with enough storage space, the larger size of Flatpaks is a small tradeoff for the convenience and compatibility they provide.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/nf7kq9b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They don&#39;t.</p><p>Once you start building up dependencies flatpaks aren&#39;t that big, and as many users have a lot of dependencies it just... works. My flatpak lib folder is 30 gigs which sounds like a LOT, but I also have many flatpaks installed. Flatpaks are about as big as programs you&#39;d get from your distro&#39;s repo after everything&#39;s said and done. I&#39;m not a baller on storage either(though we all wish we were), my boot drive is 512 gigs and I get that every mega/gigabyte saved is important. But flatpaks make sense for quite a few apps including OBS and VLC.</p><p>Though tbh if appimages were easier to grab and catalog(I know how to add them to my app menu, dw) from one place like Flatpaks I&#39;d rather use them as they work better with programs from my repo(e.g LSFG-VK shits itself in PCSX2 and RPCS3 flatpak but not the appimages)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/nf7jz4v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Once you’ve downloaded 5-10 flatpaks, quite a few shared runtimes you need are already installed and do not need to be downloaded again. When that happens, future downloads are more normally sized.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlrkex/can_someone_explain_to_me_how_you_all_use/nf7nv6e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 12:42:03 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/</link><title>Is there any name for... I call it dependency fragmentation, in package management?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>The thing that flatpak and every similar package does. Software ends up needing gnome-runtime 0.8.0001, then something else uses .0002, then something else .0003, and so on, and you waste a ton of bandwidth and disk space. Haven&#39;t seen any system like that avoid it because ultimately they&#39;re kinda just, accidentally designed to facilitate it.</p><p>Is there any widespread name for it? It&#39;s a known issue, I&#39;ve seen it come up time and time again in practice and theory, but I&#39;ve never seen a name for it, other than it being a distinct type of dependency hell.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The neutral term is &quot;parallel installation&quot; (of multiple versions).</p><p>If you want to complain about it, you can call it &quot;code duplication&quot;, because that is essentially what it amounts to. Or more specifically &quot;library duplication&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/nf6qlvz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That would probably be called something along the lines of &quot;duplicated files&quot;.</p><p>Flatpak actually has a feature called de-duplication, so the files in common are shared among different runtimes and apps.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/nf6jmu7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Depending on what you&#39;re trying to describe or the lens through which you view it, it&#39;s sometimes called &quot;bundling&quot;. For example, Fedora tries to avoid bundling whenever possible: <a href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fesco/Bundled_Software_policy/">https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/fesco/Bundled_Software_policy/</a></p><p>But you might also simply call it asynchronous updates, which is one of the benefits that the stable release process is designed to provide.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/nf6ku9y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah, that&#39;s what bundling is supposed to do.</p><p>With the kind of bandwidth and storage capacity we have today, I don&#39;t really see a problem there.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/nf7dujw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I call it poorly versioned broken libraries. Now explain to me what is the reason you can&#39;t change all the .0001&#39;s and .0002&#39;s to .0003 and have it working just fine?  Fatt paks shouldn&#39;t allow this to happen and default to the newest .0.8.x version unless the package specifies some &quot;no it really is broken and we need to use an old .0.8.1 version&quot; flag. They would still have to host the old stale runtimes which is a security hazard for the users, but it&#39;s better than hosting every stale runtime that ever existed. If the scope of vulnerable runtimes is limited they at least have a chance of managing and patching vulnerabilities.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/nf6trqb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How does windows and macOS solve this?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/nf8m7e5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dependency_hell">Dependency hell</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlmcot/is_there_any_name_for_i_call_it_dependency/nf826jm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 07:49:59 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://lwn.net/ml/all/20250918222607.186488-1-xiyou.wangcong@gmail.com/</link><title>Kernel: Introduce Multikernel Architecture Support (lwn.net)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Genuinely asking what does that do? I don&#39;t have low level knowledge of things. Is it going to help Linux users in general or is it going to help developers?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/nf6h487/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I have build something similar as a research project before. We published the results at a conference.</p><p>Something like this kind of works, but it&#39;s impossible to achieve true isolation. It&#39;s actually not that hard to make the kernel just believe some memory doesn&#39;t exist or that the CPU has less cores than it does etc and then just start some other OS on the remaning RAM and core. We ran an RTOS on one of the cores and Linux on the others.</p><p>But we found you either have to deactivate some capabilities of modern CPUs or you have to designate primary and secondary OS. PM is an issue for example, unless you have a system where you can independently PM each core. One system throttling the whole CPU including the cores of the other system will wreak havoc.</p><p>In the end we had to make the RTOS the primary system and just deactivate some functionalities that would have broken the isolation.</p><p>We also had inter-kernel communication to send data from one OS to the other, e.g. so Linux could ask the RTOS to power off the system after shutdown (i.e. RTOS would request shutdown, Linux would shutdown and then signal back when it was done).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/nf7h1tw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It sounds to me like a more low level version of Usermode Linux, probably to assist hardware driver development.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/nf6lrt2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Could you potentially update your system and then update the kernel without needing to restart by launching a 2nd kernel during the update?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/nf6vrqa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>L. Torvalds hates microkernels, maybe we can trick him into working on one by calling it a multikernel.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/nf6wg3b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Hello, completely ignorant on the matter: could this enable kernel level anticheat without letting kernel anticheat run in the main kernel?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/nf6o6x8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This sounds chaotic</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nlm1uk/kernel_introduce_multikernel_architecture_support/nf7x73j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 07:34:48 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/ckz73jzqh6qf1.png</link><title>Flathub popularity by country (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I&#39;ve decided to divide downloads by population per country and got Vatican on the 1st place. Note that 3-13 were skipped due to value error. In brief Flathub is quite popular in Europe, USA and Canada, Australia, New Zealand. Really not popular in Asia or Africa. If anyone wants to see the full spreadsheet: <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1plHluS3haCjhjGhNahrdB1RXw8n8txyJ/view?usp=sharing">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1plHluS3haCjhjGhNahrdB1RXw8n8txyJ/view?usp=sharing</a> conditional formatting might not work</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/ckz73jzqh6qf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>I bet the user of Flathub in the Vatican is a sysadmin.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/nf4tuh1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I always knew Flathub had the Holy Father&#39;s blessing!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/nf4sjba/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I think this is much more an indicator for the size of the linux user base (than the popularity of flathub) by country.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/nf50d9b/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I think it would be better to compare the Linux userbase in the country to the flathub downloads.</p><p>Of course people who use Windows or don&#39;t use a computers at all won&#39;t download stuff from flathub.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/nf4zf09/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Pope be cooking!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/nf4u4xy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>With the average Flathub app being several hundred megabytes large, it&#39;s not very surprising it&#39;s not popular in developing countries.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/nf4uwnu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Was flashback written in Holy C?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nle38v/flathub_popularity_by_country/nf6s5jm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 01:40:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/redditdev/comments/1nl8657/i_built_an_interactive_terminalbased_minimalist/</link><title>I built an interactive terminal-based minimalist Reddit CLI browser/client</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl8h58/i_built_an_interactive_terminalbased_minimalist/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl8h58/i_built_an_interactive_terminalbased_minimalist/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl8h58/i_built_an_interactive_terminalbased_minimalist/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Hey everyone! I made a small TUI utility called <a href="https://github.com/WeWeBunnyX/Le-Termuddit"><strong>Le-Termuddit</strong></a> as part of my Operating Systems Lab project. It’s a lightweight Reddit client that runs entirely in the terminal along with proper color coded formatting, nested comments etc , all written purely in Bash script and powered by the Reddit API along with other parsing tools. Everything is documented in README. Contributions and suggestions are welcome. Most of such Reddit terminal browsing utilities that exist on Github are in python and unmaintained (as far as I have seen). Let me know your feedback on this. <strong>And don&#39;t forget to star or contribute via code . Would be really grateful.</strong></p><p>- Features</p><ul><li>Browse subreddits</li><li>View posts with nested comments</li><li>Interactive navigation with simple key commands</li><li>Optional image rendering in the terminal</li><li>Colorful minimalist UI</li></ul><h1>- Limitations:</h1><ul><li>Mostly read-only: no posting, voting, or messaging yet</li><li>May not be the best finished product but if you are looking to just browse reddit via terminal in legible and colorful format then this does the job.</li><li>Credentials required</li></ul></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Suggestion: a screenshot that shows the logged-in session timeline, or a post, would be more useful to potential users than a screenshot of the initial setup page.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl8h58/i_built_an_interactive_terminalbased_minimalist/nf3xzcf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>No anonymous (as in &quot;no login&quot;) option?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl8h58/i_built_an_interactive_terminalbased_minimalist/nf3ms44/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Very interesting</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl8h58/i_built_an_interactive_terminalbased_minimalist/nf94ii7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 22:06:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/</link><title>Kernel 6.17 File-System Benchmarks. Including: OpenZFS  Bcachefs</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Source: <a href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux-617-filesystems">https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux-617-filesystems</a></p><p>&quot;<a href="https://www.phoronix.com/search/Linux+6.17">Linux 6.17</a> is an interesting time to carry out fresh file-system benchmarks given that <a href="https://www.phoronix.com/review/linux-617-ext4">EXT4 has seen some scalability improvements</a> while <a href="https://www.phoronix.com/news/Bcachefs-Externally-Maintained">Bcachefs in the mainline kernel is now in a frozen state</a>. Linux 6.17 is also what&#39;s powering Fedora 43 and Ubuntu 25.10 out-of-the-box to make such a comparison even more interesting. Today&#39;s article is looking at the out-of-the-box performance of EXT4, Btrfs, F2FS, XFS, Bcachefs and then OpenZFS too&quot;.</p><p>&quot;... So tested for this article were&quot;:</p><p>- Bcachefs<br/>- Btrfs<br/>- EXT4<br/>- F2FS<br/>- OpenZFS<br/>- XFS</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>tl;dr; Ext4 and XFS are best performing, bcachefs and OpenZFS are the worst performing. SQLite tests seem to be only ones where Ext4 and XFS are not the best, so I would like to see comparison with other databases.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/nf2owo9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Theoretically, is this because B* and ZFS have more book keeping going on? And a bit of &quot;less time micro optimising&quot; I guess.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/nf2role/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>XFS gang.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/nf2wq01/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Good to know that using good ol&#39; ext4 is still a good option.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/nf2ra5g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This flies with my experience. At this point in time XFS+MergerFS+SnapRAID is an easy contender for best bulk storage solution between the flexibility of mergerfs especially for upgrades/replacements and the performance of xfs, although I don&#39;t think it&#39;s necessarily worth transitioning from some kind of more traditional RAID setup unless you <em>really</em> want to do so for personal reasons or are replacing the bulk of the storage in the RAID anyway.</p><p>XFS is also quite mature at this point too, I know people like ext4 for its sheer maturity but XFS is just as mature when it comes down to brass tacks (Being an SGI-sourced fs from 1993, when ext1 was first released in 1992) and has always had its performance benefits albeit not as &quot;global&quot; as they seem to be currently. Although honestly you can&#39;t go wrong with either choice.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/nf2qjf3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Interesting. This is why I use F2FS on my sdcards when I can. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/nf2saxt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;d honestly go and use LVM + XFS in order to have snapshots and more features if I had the time and if it was mega easy. I remember I tried once one year ago, but I should re-setup my disks and practice a lot. </p><p>XFS really seems nice.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl4hka/kernel_617_filesystem_benchmarks_including/nf30xys/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:34:45 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/</link><title>Any designers in here?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m a web designer and developer, and I&#39;m considering switching to Linux, from macOS.</p><p>From what I was able to check, I believe the only app I wouldn&#39;t be able to easily port to Linux is Sketch—that&#39;s only for macOS.</p><p>I don&#39;t want to use Adobe products—and frankly I don&#39;t even know if they&#39;re available for Linux—and I never used Figma (browser-based), but wouldn&#39;t say no to it.</p><p>How are you designers doing on Linux? What are you using?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>An aside just to be aware of something: As a webdev, another app you likely might need to be familiar with (since accessibility is mandatory in many cases nowadays) is screenreaders. Note that linux does only support Orca and while it is a workable screenreader, it is not the screenreader most of your customers will be using (which will be VoiceOver/NVDA/Jaws, depending on if they use Mac or Windows).</p><p>You can still get decently far with it, I use linux at work with exactly that limitation, but there are limitation to bugs specific to various screenreader/browser combos.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/nf2qb5y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Inkscape and penpot</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/nf2gedz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>UX designer here... I daily use figma web </p><p>other than that, you have inkscape for vector and penpot as a figma alternative :)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/nf3ljll/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Believe it or not, I do print design.  And yes, on Adobe.. mainly InDesign.  Which I run in a VM.</p><p>It isn&#39;t perfect.  But its not like print design gains much by having GPU access. And I had gotten use to using only linux at home for something like 17 years now.  For the first 12 of that I only ever did it at work on their windows or macs.  And was happy to leave it there.  </p><p>I&#39;m back to freelancing from home and I can&#39;t bring myself to install windows on raw hardware.  That would be way worse for me than any imperfections of running things in a vm.</p><p>There is the added luxury of launching the vm and having ps, ai and indesign all loaded up the same way every time.</p><p>But if you are comfortable with having windows installed raw and aren&#39;t bothered by the ick, then you&#39;re not going to agree with me.</p><p>I try to use foss apps when I can.  Mainly Krita (actually supports CMYK) and occasionally scribus for simple things.  </p><p>I am pretty sure I could do pretty much everything I do with photoshop on Krita, but its hard to fight the decades of experience that make using adobe second nature and often subconscious.  But I keep trying and I take small steps in the right direction.</p><p>With that said...  Web Design should be way easier.    Perhaps putting adobe in a vm will get you half way there more easily.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/nf6cu74/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Designer here, not web or UI but for commercial print (mesh vinyl, adhesive vinyl, books, large format sublimation, cutting...).</p><p>I love Linux for everything except for what I do for a living; I&#39;ve found open source tools to be grossly inadequate. So I&#39;m currently dual-booting Arch and Windows 11 until I&#39;ve saved up enough for a Mac because I&#39;m not gonna hold my breath for those sellouts at Affinity to port their shit to Linux or for a WINE patch to make Adobe software magically work flawlessly.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/nf6w8o4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’m a full stack dev if that counts.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/nf2vi27/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>BoxySVG + Figma.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nl3crr/any_designers_in_here/nf4ozvr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 18:48:31 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/s7tyjlkmrypf1.png</link><title>My first submission!!!! (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Yeap I sucessfully submitted my first package into an oficial repo of a linux distro.</p><p>This is a tool for manipulating .env files, files containing environmental variables. The app is also available in ubuntu&#39;s ppa and fedora&#39;s corpr.</p><p>More info on project&#39;s repo: <a href="https://github.com/pc-magas/mkdotenv">https://github.com/pc-magas/mkdotenv</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/s7tyjlkmrypf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Nice bro</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/nexi6xa/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Congrats big guy</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/nexlm6z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Upvoted because it&#39;s copyleft</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/nf543fe/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It was probably doable in 100 lines of perl.No compilation, no packages for each distro, no hassle.</p><p>And --input-file --output-file is too long to write, make a shortcut for example like the dd command:dd if=/file.txt of=/file2.txt .....</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/nf61pkz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Learn SAP instead... life time settlement career</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkfs7u/my_first_submission/nf07yhc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 23:41:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://kde.org/announcements/plasma/6/6.4.90/</link><title>Today is Plasma 6.5 Beta test day (1)! Tester needed! (kde.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nke5hb/today_is_plasma_65_beta_test_day_1_tester_needed/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nke5hb/today_is_plasma_65_beta_test_day_1_tester_needed/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nke5hb/today_is_plasma_65_beta_test_day_1_tester_needed/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>(1)!=1</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nke5hb/today_is_plasma_65_beta_test_day_1_tester_needed/nf7div3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>this means 6.4 is likely stable already and i can already use it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nke5hb/today_is_plasma_65_beta_test_day_1_tester_needed/nez7ldw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 22:40:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/yai45zndxxpf1.png</link><title>"htez" -- Easy file server/sharing. Files can now be deleted! Revised code! (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkc9jd/htez_easy_file_serversharing_files_can_now_be/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkc9jd/htez_easy_file_serversharing_files_can_now_be/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkc9jd/htez_easy_file_serversharing_files_can_now_be/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p><a href="https://gitlab.com/gee.8ruhs/writteninc/-/raw/main/htez.c">Click here</a> to grab the code (and read the instructions on how to compile it.).</p><p><a href="https://i.imgur.com/T0OPXkI.png">Its CPU and memory usage is (still) nonexistant.</a></p><p>It&#39;s (basically) a &quot;What if &quot;python -m http.server&quot; and micro_httpd could work on a thermostat&quot; approach -- something minimal yet funcional, with all the basic/required features you&#39;d expect out of a file server without using any other third party software.</p><p>tl;dr: Download the code via the link above, compile it with &quot;<code>gcc htez.c -o htez -static -O3 -Wall</code>&quot;, move the compiled binary to where you want to start the file server, run the binary, access the file server via &quot;http://localhost:8080&quot; on your browser.</p><p>Possible &quot;use cases&quot;:</p><p>* Internet is down and you need a local solution to hold/access critical files</p><p>* You don&#39;t have a external hd/portable solution to hold critical files locally</p><p>* You are using a device that has one or no usb inputs at all (i.e a cellphone) and you need to copy a file to it</p><p>Also, it has been configured to limit files up to 512KiB (to keep it cozy for potatoes), but you can increase the limit easily to (whateveryouwant) in the code itself.</p><pre><code>Disclaimer: This is meant to be run (only) on your private network, as a &quot;last resort&quot; in case your internet goes down and/or someone on your network needs a critical file asap.</code></pre></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/yai45zndxxpf1.png' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Yo, which distro?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nkc9jd/htez_easy_file_serversharing_files_can_now_be/nex25ok/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:30:58 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/</link><title>This subreddit is being overrun with posts about moving from windows. The mods should consider a megathread or weekly post to consolidate this content.</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I can&#39;t be the only one who&#39;s noticed that over the past year and change, there has been a lot of interest in linux on the desktop. Whether that&#39;s because of Windows 10 EOL, the ongoing headaches associated with Windows 11, the growth of this subreddit, or something else, as a result there are now multiple posts per day about some variation of &quot;windows sucks / moving to linux is like drinking the nectar of the gods / I can&#39;t go back to windows anymore (because it sucks)&quot; etc. etc.</p><p>in my opinion, after you&#39;ve seen a few of these, you&#39;ve seen them all, and as a result it&#39;s really boring and bad content for the subreddit. personally, i&#39;d prefer if there was less of it, but i understand that people like posting about their move to linux. </p><p>a nice compromise would be to create a daily or weekly pinned megathread where people can talk about moving from windows to linux, or their newbie linux &quot;journey&quot; or whatever.</p><p>All subreddits are on the path to eternal september. lets take a few steps backwards.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>&quot;What distro should I use?&quot;</p><p>&quot;GNOME or KDE?&quot;</p><p>&quot;Arch is easy. Why do people say it&#39;s hard?&quot;</p><p>&quot;Has anybody used this &quot;bazzite&quot;?&quot;</p><p>&quot;Linux isn&#39;t ready yet.&quot;</p><p>&quot;Nvidia works fine. What are people talking about?&quot;</p><p>&quot;I have a black screen on boot. Is it Nvidia?&quot;</p><p>&quot;How can I optimize my installation?&quot;</p><p>&quot;Is Linux good for gaming?&quot;</p><p>&quot;What&#39;s wrong with X11?&quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/new4e63/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>But will my 8 core 12 thread cpu, 32gb of ram and 1tb nvme be enough for linux mint?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/new5mfo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>had to leave <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/linuxmint">r/linuxmint</a> because of this, never any discussion about the os, just endless stories about the great enlightenment of choosing mint, &quot;rice&quot; / rate my desktop posts (love the icon pack and wallpaper!). if you make a post about an issue, people get aggressive like &quot;noT iN My iNsTAll!&quot; (that is to say, they claim the problem cannot exist, even with screenshot proof or any pastes from the terminal)</p><p>it&#39;s a shame since the forum reaches less people and can be really slow. then again ubuntu troubleshooting always works, so not an issue for me, but kinda disappointed that this sub is so similar</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/newnf9r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This has been the case since a few years now.</p><p>The rule #1 does not account for people who cannot read, same goes for your proposals.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/new4nrx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Would love a &quot;this isn&#39;t an airport&quot; rule. No need to announce you arrival or departure!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/nex75ga/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I agree. 90% of posts are about that. At this point that topic needs its own subreddit.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/new433x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>I can&#39;t be the only one who&#39;s noticed that over the past year and change</p></blockquote><p>You must have your rose-tinted glasses on because I&#39;ve been lurking here for years and &quot;windows sucks / moving to linux is like drinking the nectar of the gods / I can&#39;t go back to windows anymore (because it sucks)&quot; posts have been cluttering the subreddit since 2018 and maybe even earlier.</p><p>Also, what ABotelho23 wrote. It&#39;s either this or DE wars or distro wars or display server wars or essay length first impressions where the person using Linux for all of 20 days has decided that they figured everything out better than anyone else. Or, worse than all of that, it&#39;s news coverage from the Phoronix spamblog. If you are lucky it&#39;s a beer120 post and he is making an ass of himself in the comments.</p><blockquote><p>a nice compromise would be to create a daily or weekly pinned megathread where people can talk about moving from windows to linux, or their newbie linux &quot;journey&quot; or whatever.</p></blockquote><p>This doesn&#39;t stop people who don&#39;t read. I&#39;ve seen it on other subreddits which have dedicated pinned QnA threads for simple questions. People still create separate threads to ask a simple question. Doubly so for these opinion pieces because <em>their</em> opinion is <em>special</em> and deserves its own dedicated thread.</p><p>You just gotta accept these posts and try to filter them because the only reasonable way to get rid of them is having a large, active moderation team that instantly nips them in the bud when they appear.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk9dav/this_subreddit_is_being_overrun_with_posts_about/new607z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:41:07 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://docs.projectbluefin.io/blog/bluefin-lts-ga/</link><title>Bluefin LTS Released (Bluefin + CentOS Stream) (docs.projectbluefin.io)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Please, please, keep an eye on Universal Blue and project Bluefin even if you don&#39;t use their systems. It&#39;s just very interesting, and gives you peace of mind and excitement at the same time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/newk2jw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Running Bluefin on my framework has been the best laptop linux experience I&#39;ve had, better than Mint. Excited for all that is to come with this</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/nezbeez/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Been using Bluefin GTS for quite some time now, amazing experience and all round fantasic. It&#39;s amazing and I see my myself using it on a permanent basis.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/nf13pps/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Downloading the ISO and going to fire up a VM.  They used dinosaurs, I like dinosaurs.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/nf47i67/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Out of the loop on this. This is built on top of silverblue? What&#39;s added on top or? If I was about to install silverblue, why would I install this instead?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/nf0yivx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>Bluefin LTS ships with Linux 6.12.0, which is the kernel for the lifetime of release.</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://access.redhat.com/solutions/2074">When will the Red Hat Enterprise Linux package be updated to the upstream version?</a></p><p>Red Hat rebases entire subsystems of the kernel for minor releases. Of all the packages in the distribution, the kernel is the singular one where the version number is effectively meaningless. All it denotes is the kernel&#39;s <em>baseline</em> feature set capabilities, but is not representative of its current state.</p><p>For example, RHEL 9 ships a kernel package versioned as 5.14.0. This is purely just an artifact of when the feature freeze for RHEL 9.0 went into effect. The actual kernel today is more or less a relatively recent 6.x kernel if you were to compare the actual subsystems Red Hat enables. But instead of bumping the version number it gets conveyed as <code>kernel-5.14.0-570.44.1.el9_6.x86_64</code>. CentOS Stream doesn&#39;t use the intra-minor-version Z-Stream numbering, so you see it move from <code>-570</code> to <code>-571</code>, <code>-571</code> to <code>-572</code>, etc.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/nf86152/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>holy shit nice, i was looking forward to this. I&#39;m thinking about switching. I really lied podman being automatically set up for vscode which is normally a pain in the ass and i&#39;ve given up on doing every time I tried</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk91ab/bluefin_lts_released_bluefin_centos_stream/nf9qebk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:27:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Ubuntu-Rust-Coreutils-Perf</link><title>Ubuntu 25.10's Rust Coreutils Transition Has Uncovered Performance Shortcomings (phoronix.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>FYI: all the mentioned performance issues have already been closed. (the bug is still open however)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/neuxeja/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Seems pretty normal for this phase of testing integration. The only reason this is &quot;news&quot; at all is because Rust is mentioned.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/neuyhcx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Two things can be true at the same time.  First, these articles by Phoronix and Lunduke are the worst sort of mouth breathing Linux rage bait, and, second, Canonical is also moving way, way too fast to integrate uutils into Ubuntu, and putting Rust into the firing line (because they are Canonical and they can&#39;t help themselves?).</p><p>I think the uutils project is amazing.  I am a contributor.  But certain stuff still doesn&#39;t work the same as its GNU counterparts.   I just gave one example in another comment --  locales do not work at all.  See for example:</p><p>```</p><blockquote><p>./target/release/sort ~/Programming/1brc.data/measurements-10000000.txt | tail -1İzmir;9.9gsort ~/Programming/1brc.data/measurements-10000000.txt | tail -1Zürich;9.9LC_ALL=C gsort ~/Programming/1brc.data/measurements-10000000.txt | tail -1İzmir;9.9LC_ALL=en_US.UTF-8 ./target/release/sort ~/Programming/1brc.data/measurements-10000000.txt | tail -1İzmir;9.9```</p></blockquote><p>And while locales may not be important to you, when you expect a sort order according to <code>LC_ALL=en_US.UTF-8</code> and get <code>LC_ALL=C</code> that could be a huge deal for someone else. </p><p>This has nothing to do with whether Rust is ready, or Rust is as performant as C, or whether uutils has edge cases (because of course it does!).   The real issue is that there is real functionality which simply hasn&#39;t been implemented yet, and won&#39;t be ready by next month.</p><p>And Canonical will blame anyone but themselves when and if it doesn&#39;t work out.  My guess is uutils will basically work well enough for most people.  UTF8 supremacy is a thing, etc.  But it will annoy the shit out of people who expect a stable system which does the same thing every time.  And there will be a dozen more half-assed &quot;articles&quot; and YouTube rants about whether Rust is the problem, when the problem is, obviously, Canonical&#39;s hubris.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/nev5q8j/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The fact that the rust re-write is not GPL fills me with a dread foreboding.</p><p>A decade from now, when the big tech companies abandon a Linux they have to contribute to for a Rustix they don&#39;t have to share their work on, we&#39;ll look back at this as the turning point; the beginning of the end of open-source.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/nevpoi8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>it&#39;s a new implementation. what do you expect.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/nevnxso/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>why are they switching to rust coreutils?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/nexm6er/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m glad I dumped Ubuntu just in time for this silly nonsense</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1nk3pes/ubuntu_2510s_rust_coreutils_transition_has/neygqzc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 15:02:55 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://youtu.be/4YUkD5oslmc</link><title>Operese - Windows-to-Linux migration tool that's now open-source! (youtu.be)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njv61o/operese_windowstolinux_migration_tool_thats_now/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njv61o/operese_windowstolinux_migration_tool_thats_now/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njv61o/operese_windowstolinux_migration_tool_thats_now/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Operese is a Windows-to-Linux migration tool which seamlessly transfers files, programs, and settings in-place from Windows 10 to Kubuntu, no technical knowledge required!</p><p>Since my post 2 months ago announcing the project, I&#39;ve kept things pretty quiet, but there&#39;s been a lot going on behind the scenes. The TL;DR is that I&#39;ve added support for program migration, cleaned up the code massively, and started work on making it distro-agnostic, to eventually be able to support targets other than Kubuntu. It&#39;s still very much alpha software, though.</p><p>It&#39;s also been released under the AGPL 3 license, and I&#39;m looking forward to welcoming more contributors! You can find the code here if you&#39;re curious: <a href="https://codeberg.org/Operese/operese">https://codeberg.org/Operese/operese</a></p><p>I plan on stepping back from Operese to some degree over the next few months, and am looking for a co-maintainer to fill that void. If you have Rust/Linux/open-source experience and are interested, please send me an email at [<a href="mailto:hello@operese.com">hello@operese.com</a>](mailto:<a href="mailto:hello@operese.com">hello@operese.com</a>) :)</p><p>Thanks!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='embedded-media'><iframe width="356" height="200" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4YUkD5oslmc?feature=oembed&enablejsapi=1" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen title="Operese Progress Update! Program Migration, Open-Source, and More"></iframe></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>good idea</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njv61o/operese_windowstolinux_migration_tool_thats_now/neukaxv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>This is a cool project. Especially for getting normies onto Linux with the upcoming Windows 10 EOL for the regular editions.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njv61o/operese_windowstolinux_migration_tool_thats_now/newguc1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Yeah, but normal people wouldn&#39;t need this.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njv61o/operese_windowstolinux_migration_tool_thats_now/neyrtoc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 06:52:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://i.redd.it/lwh4i6mf2spf1.jpeg</link><title>Blender CEO Announced His Decision to Step Down After Over 30 Years (i.redd.it)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>At today’s Blender Conference keynote, Ton Roosendaal announced to step down as chairman and Blender CEO per January 1st 2026, passing on his roles to Blender COO Francesco Siddi. New Blender Foundation board positions will also include Sergey Sharybin (head of development), Dalai Felinto (head of product) and Fiona Cohen (head of operations).</p><p>Francesco Siddi has been part of the Blender organization since 2012, functioning in many roles including as animator, web developer, pipeline developer, producer and managing Blender’s industry relations.</p><p>“We’ve been preparing for this since 2019,” said Roosendaal, “I am very proud to have such a wonderfully talented young team around me to bring our free and open source project into the next decade.”</p><p>Ton Roosendaal will move to the newly established BF supervisory board.</p><p>More details will be provided later this year.</p><p>Amsterdam, 17-09-2025</p><p>Blender Foundation</p><p><a href="https://www.blender.org/press/blender-foundation-announces-new-board-and-executive-director/">https://www.blender.org/press/blender-foundation-announces-new-board-and-executive-director/</a></p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='preview-image'><p>&nbsp;</p><img src='https://i.redd.it/lwh4i6mf2spf1.jpeg' /></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>He proven a FOSS app/product can be industrial level.</p><p>Hope everything goes well after him as well.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/nereuff/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>o7</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/nergad7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Noooo, man he was good, hopefully they dont do anything bad </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/nernykc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Blender is a triumph of FOSS. I hope he&#39;s very proud, and I am very thankful.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/nestruo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>What a Champion.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/nertnqv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I remember donating to &quot;free&quot; Blender back in the day. Definitely the best $50 I ever spent.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/netavns/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Did he figure out how to use Blender?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njn0f2/blender_ceo_announced_his_decision_to_step_down/nerfcga/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 01:07:14 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njlio7/language_settings/</link><title>Language settings</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njlio7/language_settings/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njlio7/language_settings/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njlio7/language_settings/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I wanted to try fedora 43 and I noticed something that has been nagging me before.  This time it was with KDE plasma, but this is the same for Gnome, Cinnamon, maybe others.<br/>The language settings never allow for a decent and complete European language setting,  One that has British English, A4 pages,  Euro currency, 24H clock,  Day/month/year date Format,  Week starting on Monday, Metric units for distance, Celcius for temperature.  space for thousands separator, comma for decimal point and as a convenience point also as decimalpoint.|</p><p>Basically all settings in one go.  On Cinnamon I end up to use English(Ireland) but that has the weekdays in Gaellic, I believe there is also an Danish English that has some deficiencies.<br/>I think this would be a very welcome thing for those that want to use their computers in a convenient format and that want to have a Os and applications in English to accomodate multiple users and that do not want the UI language to switch with each user.<br/>I live in Belgium and I am a native Dutch speaker.  I do not want a Dutch UI and and neither do I want an English UI but with Dutch weekday names to get the rest of the date formats in sensible way and to get the currency symbol. </p><p>It seems strange that we have profiles for Belgian Dutch, French and Gernan but not one for EU english.</p><p>We even have profiles for limburgish, whish is not an official language but a dialect and a small one at that.<br/>This should be a no brainer to have such a profile standard</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comment</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://sourceware.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=22473">https://sourceware.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=22473</a></p><p>There is some discussion there, and on the links it references.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njlio7/language_settings/nes68aj/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:10:30 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/</link><title>Zram vs. Zswap, 2025 How's your config?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Still using <code>zram</code>. Not worried about LRU inversion. All the system loads. Spill to SSD is just an extra web tab, or a big boinc block. I want to avoid SSD writes as a high priority. I have full control as there is no virtual process background from server share. I use <code>zram lzo-rle</code> BTW.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>If you have actual swap space on your disk, you almost certainly want to be using zswap instead of ZRAM. It behaves better when you have to actually hit the disk, and it behaves significantly better when you no longer need to use swap space.</p><p>Once a page hits a given swap device, Linux will keep it there until the page is invalidated, the swap device is deactivated, or the page was swapped in and the kernel needs more space for other pages (that is, <em>all</em> of your swap space is full). This means that swapping a page in does not free up space on the swap device that the page was on, which in turn means that ZRAM swap generally does not free up memory very readily on a typical system. It also means that pages that are likely to be needed again quickly may still end up on the slower storage device when pairing a ZRAM swap device with swap space on disk.</p><p>Zswap has neither of those issues. Once a page is swapped back in, zswap drops it and frees the memory. And stuff always goes to zswap first, only gets pushed out to disk when zswap runs out of space, and even then only the least recently used pages get pushed to disk.</p><p>Also, zswap’s memory usage is specified as actual memory usage, while ZRAM primarily specifies memory usage as how much uncomrpessed data it can store. Because the compressed data size is nondeterministic, this means that ZRAM is harder to reliably quantify exactly how it will impact the rest of the system when under high memory pressure, because you can’t reliably predict how much memory it will actually use.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/nes42tw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Zram with zstd compression and no disk swap. Works as a miracle for a low RAM machine. The compression ratio is 1:4.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/neupm2g/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>When I needed it, I didn&#39;t know how to do it. Now I know where to find out, I have more RAM than I can reasonably use.</p><p>More physical memory won me out, apparently.</p><p>Edit: We&#39;ll see in another 3-4 years though.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/nerrj4z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Whatever it is the default for Debian/Ubuntu.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/nes6k76/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>zram all the way, who needs writing to a disk?</p><p>```</p><p>total        used        free      shared  buff/cache   available<br/>Mem:            62Gi        44Gi       7.0Gi       4.9Gi        14Gi        18Gi<br/>Swap:           62Gi       3.8Gi        58Gi</p><p>```</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/ner0jgf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;ve got my entire ram set up on a single zram + btrfs partition, shared between $HOME/.cache, /tmp and $HOME/Downloads. And it &quot;just werks&quot;.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/neriwjt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Zswap.  I would like to adopt Ariadne or a similar approach, but it&#39;s at a PoC level and needs to be developed and merged into the kernel first.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njl16e/zram_vs_zswap_2025_hows_your_config/nes7zum/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:52:23 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/</link><title>With all these supply chain attacks going on (such as NPM), are Linux Desktop users safe?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I recently heard of all all these recent supply chain attacks that have been going on. I want to know if us desktop linux users will be safe or not, and if there are any particular distros be watch out for (or at least be more careful on).</p><p>I personally use CachyOS (so if anything I&#39;d probably be more at risk on this since it&#39;s a rolling release distro).</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Everyone is just as safe/unsafe as they were last year, and 10 years ago.<br/>Supply chain attacks are not new, and no platform is safe from them. Windows, Mac, HP-UX, iOS, Android, ChromeOS, FreeBSD et al ad nauseam are vulnerable to supply chain attacks. Maintain offline backups, adopt safe computing practices, wear a helmet and take your vitamins.<br/>Good luck!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/neqw12z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>... as long as there is a supply chain, there can be supply chain attacks. If you want to be immune, better get to coding your own compiler &amp; os from scratch</p><p>Cachy is largely controlled by one person. If Peter Jung decides to ship malware you will feel it.</p><p>If you use corporate distros likeUbuntu, Tumbleweed or Fedora, there is a legal body behind it, so at least chances are slim it&#39;s the distro maintainers, but malicious open source contributions still affect those too</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/neqvili/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>No one is safe my dude.</p><p>The internet is a wild place and you have to know what you&#39;re doing if you&#39;re going to venture out there with your own tools, protected only by your own wits and experience.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/neqxgdk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In general, the mainstream distributions are &quot;safe enough&quot;, pretty much as safe as Windows, Macintosh, etc. </p><p>A more detailed answer: how trustworthy is the distribution, and what steps do they take to protect their packages? Many digitally sign their packages, to help ensure that what is downloaded is what the official packager created. Some (many?) do vulnerability scans of the software being packaged. The larger distributions have teams to monitor the latest reports of attacks against upstream packages. </p><p>There was a kerfuffle about a year ago regarding a popular package (I forget which one) that had a supply chain attack (I think the package build script downloaded a vulnerable tar file). I believe it was caught before any distribution made the vulnerable version available. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/neqxpav/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Javascript is everywhere. The recent &quot;npm worm&quot; works on linux just as well. However, the target currently are developers themselves, so if you are, you can just follow various recommendations how to set up your stuff to disable post installation scripts.</p><p>Else, It depends entirely on the repository and package. The more people who use a repository, the more checks and balances there usually are - because shit needs to be organized when a few hundred people work on it.  </p><p>For the package - same. The more people who use it, the more likely it will be spotted - not always at once. In the NPM world, if a package is popular, within a few hours.</p><p>The individual maintainer who gets targeted for a supply chain attack to start is just a human being. They might be tired, overworked or in a rush. They might have mental health issues. They might urgently need money. On the other hand, a core maintainer of a distro usually lives a relatively transparent life with their peculiar &quot;hobby&quot; so to speak and would not just throw everything away over night, or be easily bribed by a ransomware gang.   </p><p>Then it depends on the repository next - what kind of checks are there? What could set of a tripwire?</p><p>And next, what can the packages do after installation? </p><p>So overall, you want to not use stuff randomly on your daily driver. Do remove software and packages you do not need, do not &quot;hoard&quot; software and accounts. If you want to test random things or you usually are interested in something only for a while - set up a VM.</p><p>De-cluttering is one step, the next step is being informed - make sure you know where you distro posts stuff and any other repository you use.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/nerb8zs/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Nobody on any operating system is safe lol</p><p>NPM isn&#39;t a linux thing either.  </p><p>I think the closest thing recently was someone putting some viruses on the AUR? I kinda thought that was what the AUR was for though, I mean, no one verifies anything on there as far as I am aware, that&#39;s why arch has an actual package manager also.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/neqvt6e/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I think as long as you are installing from your distro’s repos (and you trust your distro) you should be fine. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/1njkby3/with_all_these_supply_chain_attacks_going_on_such/neqv8a0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 23:27:04 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
