<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=technology&amp;averagePostsPerDay=3&amp;content&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/technology</title><description>Hot posts in /r/technology (roughly 3 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 23:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/b-thumbs-redditmedia-com-J_fCwTYJkoM-way-eaOHv8AOHoF_jNXNqOvPrQ7bINY-144x400.png</url><title>/r/technology</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/media-censorship-accountability-charlie-kirk-act-b2825988.html</link><title>Trump shares call for media ‘accountability’ with ‘Charlie Kirk Act’ after shooting (the-independent.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nghkfj/trump_shares_call_for_media_accountability_with/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nghkfj/trump_shares_call_for_media_accountability_with/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 7 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nghkfj/trump_shares_call_for_media_accountability_with/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://static.the-independent.com/2025/09/13/16/53/5050-Templete-(1).jpg?trim=0,0,0,0&width=1200&height=800&crop=1200:800' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Donald Trump has shared a video calling for the president to reinstate a Cold War-era media &ldquo;accountability&rdquo; law in response to the assassination of right-wing activist Charlie Kirk, with a petition calling for its revival gathering more than 5,000 signatures within 13 hours.</p><p>Following the 31-year-old Kirk&rsquo;s killing at Utah Valley University and the arrest of 22-year-old <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/charlie-kirk-shooting-tyler-robinson-hate-b2825465.html">Tyler Robinson</a>, TikTok user Ellie May called for the president to reintroduce the Smith&#8209;Mundt Act, a U.S. law once intended to prevent domestic dissemination of U.S.-backed foreign media, and to give it a new name: the &ldquo;Charlie Kirk Act.&rdquo; </p><p>May&rsquo;s video went viral and was shared on the president&rsquo;s Truth Social account.</p><p>In her video, May accused media outlets of &ldquo;spreading propaganda&rdquo; and<a href="https://www.the-independent.com/topic/misinformation"></a> conspiracy theories that spread rapidly across social media platforms. </p><p>AI&#8209;generated images and false claims misidentifying the suspect were among the content circulated, some of which gained additional reach via Grok, X&rsquo;s AI chatbot. It reportedly acknowledged errors only after several false posts had already gone viral. </p><div><figure><figcaption>MAGA supporter Ellie May is calling on President Donald Trump to reinstate the Cold War-era Smith&#8209;Mundt Act after Charlie Kirk's death<span> (Getty Images/TikTok/@official_elly_may)</span></figcaption></figure></div><p>&ldquo;I think the only way to bring forward decent change in this country is to start speaking up,&rdquo; May told <em>The Independent </em>in a direct message on X.</p><p>&ldquo;We had one Charlie Kirk before he passed since his death,&rdquo; May added. &ldquo;We have seen more people who have never put their faces in front of a camera start speaking truth to power. I think this is, not to play words on his organization, a <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/charlie-kirk-tyler-robinson-suspect-b2825455.html">turning point</a> in our country.&rdquo;</p><p>Changing the law would require an act of Congress.</p><p>In her TikTok video, where she largely reads from the <a href="https://www.change.org/p/enact-the-charlie-kirk-act-to-restore-media-accountability?recruiter=1375406487&amp;">Change.org </a>petition she created, May, who told <em>The Independent</em> she only began engaging in elections in 2016, when she became eligible to vote, claims that media outlets frequently label individuals as &ldquo;fascists,&rdquo; &ldquo;Nazis,&rdquo; &ldquo;white supremacists,&rdquo; or &ldquo;bigots&rdquo; without evidence, fueling public hostility.</p><p>She argued that accountability should extend beyond traditional news outlets to include content creators who disseminate propaganda and half&#8209;truths online. </p><p>&ldquo;Each violation should be subject to a fine amounting to at least 35 percent of the company's value,&rdquo; May read from the online proposal she wrote. &ldquo;Baseless accusations, such as labeling individuals as bigots, fascists, or racist, without verifiable proof, tarnish reputations and endanger lives. Such acts should not be tolerated and must invite strict accountability measures.&rdquo;</p><p>Her petition, which has <a href="https://x.com/officialellymay/status/1966888975274225830">5,000 signatures</a> in less than a day since its launch, also includes the proposal of &ldquo;stringent penalties for social media companies that censor information unfairly.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Each violation should be subject to a fine amounting to at least 35 percent of the company's value,&rdquo; May wrote. &ldquo;Baseless accusations, such as labeling individuals as bigots, fascists, or racist, without verifiable proof, tarnish reputations and endanger lives. Such acts should not be tolerated and must invite strict accountability measures.&rdquo;</p><p>May told <em>The Independent</em> that the response to her petition has been &ldquo;a lot more digestible&rdquo; than she expected.</p><p>&ldquo;Each time I check, it&rsquo;s going up by about 100 signatures, so I feel like this could become a pivotal moment in American history,&rdquo; she said. &ldquo;If I were to ratio it percentage-wise, it&rsquo;s about a 70-30, and the 70 percent are behind it.&rdquo;</p><p>May called on Trump in her video to restore the Smith&#8209;Mundt Act, which she falsely claimed was abolished in 2013 by then-President Barack Obama and then-Vice President Joe Biden, and to rename it in Kirk&rsquo;s honor. </p><div><figure><figcaption>May&rsquo;s proposal also includes severe penalties for social media companies that engage in censorship or allow unverified defamatory labels<span> (Copyright 2025 The Associated Press. All rights reserved.)</span></figcaption></figure></div><p>Obama did not abolish the Smith-Mundt Act. Instead, his administration oversaw the passage of the Smith-Mundt Modernization Act of 2012, which amended parts of the original law.</p><p>Nothing in that bill applies to what private media organizations in the can or cannot publish.</p><p>The original 1948 act created a ban on the domestic dissemination of informational materials produced by the U.S. government intended for foreign audiences, like those from the <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/voice-of-america-director-fired-illegal-b2802264.html">Voice of America</a>.</p><p>The amendment, becoming effective on July 2, 2013, lifted the decades-old ban, so Americans can access content from the U.S. Agency for Global Media and the media organizations that it supports.</p><p>May also posted a <a href="https://x.com/officialellymay/status/1966874352408019209">follow-up video</a> to X on Saturday addressing backlash she received for allegedly promoting media &ldquo;<a href="https://www.the-independent.com/topic/censorship">censorship</a>,&rdquo; captioning the post, &ldquo;Do not put words in my mouth that I didn&rsquo;t say.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;So here&rsquo;s what we're not going to do: We're not going to conflate what I said with your feelings,&rdquo; May said. &ldquo;I'm not calling for censorship, I'm calling for media organizations to be held accountable for the ignorant s**t that they say.&rdquo;</p><p>May criticized viral claims suggesting Robinson was a MAGA-aligned, ultra-conservative Republican, as well as proliferation of AI-doctored photos related to <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/crime/tyler-robinson-family-republican-b2825943.html">Robinson&rsquo;s political views, </a>including altered images of the shooter in MAGA apparel and allegedly fabricated screenshots showing donations to pro-Trump causes, which May insisted are entirely fake.</p><p>&ldquo;That photo does not f***ing exist,&rdquo; she said. </p><div><figure><figcaption>Kirk&rsquo;s alleged killer, Tyler Robinson, 22, is being held without bail at the Utah County Jail</figcaption></figure></div><p>Erika Kirk, Charlie&rsquo;s widow, vowed Friday to continue his legacy by advancing the right-wing movement he founded in an emotional tribute from Phoenix, Arizona.</p><p>As she addressed supporters, Erika, who is also the mother of their two young children, promised to grow Turning Point USA, the conservative youth organization her husband started, into &ldquo;the biggest thing this nation has ever seen.&rdquo;</p><p>Robinson is being <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/us-politics/charlie-kirk-shooting-tyler-robinson-suspect-erika-live-updates-b2825825.html">held without bail </a>at the Utah County Jail. He is expected to be formally charged with aggravated murder, felony discharge of a firearm causing serious bodily injury, and obstruction of justice. </p><p>Aggravated murder is a capital felony under Utah law, which means if convicted, Robinson could face the death penalty.</p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://static.the-independent.com/2025/09/13/12/Charlie_Kirk_Vigil_37414.jpg"></p><p><img src="https://static.the-independent.com/2025/09/12/20/Charlie_Kirk_Shot_40179.jpg"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 09:43:13 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://theintercept.com/2025/09/13/marco-rubio-revoke-us-passports-terrorism/</link><title>New Bill Would Give Marco Rubio “Thought Police” Power to Revoke U.S. Passports (theintercept.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngft6b/new_bill_would_give_marco_rubio_thought_police/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngft6b/new_bill_would_give_marco_rubio_thought_police/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngft6b/new_bill_would_give_marco_rubio_thought_police/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://theintercept.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/GettyImages-2221348960-e1757705424289.jpg?fit=8208%2C4104&w=1200&h=800' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>In March,</span> Secretary of State Marco Rubio stripped Turkish doctoral student R&uuml;meysa &Ouml;zt&uuml;rk&rsquo;s of her visa based on what a court later found was nothing more than her <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/30/tufts-rumeysa-ozturk-ice-immigration-op-ed/">opinion piece</a> critical of Israel.</p><p>Now, a bill introduced by the chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee is ringing alarm bells for civil liberties advocates who say it would grant Rubio the power to revoke the passports of American citizens on similar grounds.</p><p>The provision, sponsored by Rep. Brian Mast, R-Fla., as part of a larger State Department reorganization, is <a href="https://docs.house.gov/Committee/Calendar/ByEvent.aspx?EventID=118618">set for a hearing</a> Wednesday. </p><p>Mast&rsquo;s legislation says that it takes aim at &ldquo;terrorists and traffickers,&rdquo; but critics say it could be used to deny American citizens the right to travel based solely on their speech. (The State Department said it doesn&rsquo;t comment on pending legislation.)</p><blockquote>&ldquo;Rubio has claimed the power to designate people terrorist supporters based solely on what they think.&rdquo;</blockquote><p>Seth Stern, the director of advocacy at Freedom of the Press Foundation, said the bill would open the door to &ldquo;thought policing at the hands of one individual.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Marco Rubio has claimed the power to designate people terrorist supporters based solely on what they think and say,&rdquo; Stern said, &ldquo;even if what they say doesn&rsquo;t include a word about a terrorist organization or terrorism.&rdquo;</p><h2><strong>Vague &ldquo;Terrorist&rdquo; Designations</strong></h2><p>Mast, for his part, has publicly voiced his <a href="https://washingtonreporter.news/p/exclusive-free-him-more-like-deport">support</a> for &ldquo;kicking terrorist sympathizers out of our country.&rdquo; At the time, he was talking about deporting Mahmoud Khalil, a Palestinian green-card holder who the Trump administration <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/06/20/mahmoud-khalil-homeland-security-investigations-ice-surveillance/">detained and attempted to deport</a> based on what <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/13/briefing-podcast-mahmoud-khalil-free-speech/">critics of the move</a> said were <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/10/mahmoud-khalil-palestine-columbia-immigration-deport/">his pro-Palestine views</a>.</p><p>Mast&rsquo;s new bill claims to target a narrow set of people. One section grants the secretary of state the power to revoke or refuse to issue passports for people who have been convicted &mdash; or merely charged &mdash; of material support for terrorism. (Mast&rsquo;s office did not respond to a request for comment.)</p><p>Kia Hamadanchy, a senior policy counsel at the American Civil Liberties Union, said that language would accomplish little in practice, since terror convictions come with stiff prison sentences and pre-trial defendants are typically denied bail.</p><p>The other section sidesteps the legal process entirely. Rather, the secretary of state would be able to deny passports to people whom they determine &ldquo;has knowingly aided, assisted, abetted, or otherwise provided material support to an organization the Secretary has designated as a foreign terrorist organization.&rdquo;</p><p>The reference to &ldquo;material support&rdquo; disturbed advocates who have long warned that the government can misuse statutes criminalizing &ldquo;material support&rdquo; for terrorists &mdash; first passed after the 1996 Oklahoma City federal building bombing and toughened after the 9/11 attacks &mdash; to punish speech.</p><p>Some of those fears have been borne out. The Supreme Court <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/archive/national/2010/06/22/court-upholds-ban-on-terrorrelated-aid/c652dfbe-39cb-49eb-8b8a-139fc388a4a9/">ruled in 2010</a> that even offering advice about international law to designated terror groups could be classified as material support.</p><p>The government even deemed a woman who was kidnapped and forced to cook and clean for Salvadoran guerrillas a material supporter of terrorism, <a href="https://theintercept.com/2018/06/09/immigration-terrorism-prosecutions-material-support-united-states/">in order to justify her deportation.</a></p><p>Since the October 7 Hamas attacks, pro-Israel lawmakers and activists have ratcheted up attempts to expand the scope and use of anti-terror laws.</p><p>The <a href="https://theintercept.com/2024/02/21/adl-palestine-terrorism-legislation/">Anti-Defamation League</a> and the Louis D. Brandeis Center for Human Rights Under Law <a href="https://theintercept.com/2024/02/21/adl-palestine-terrorism-legislation/">suggested in a letter</a> last year that Students for Justice in Palestine was providing &ldquo;material support&rdquo; for Hamas through its on-campus activism.</p><p>Lawmakers also tried to pass a<a href="https://theintercept.com/2024/11/10/trump-nonprofit-tax-exempt-political-enemies/"> &ldquo;nonprofit killer&rdquo; bill</a> that would allow the Treasury secretary to strip groups of their charitable status if they are deemed a &ldquo;terrorist-supporting organization.&rdquo; The bill was beaten back by a coalition of nonprofit groups, most recently during the debate over the <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/05/19/nonprofit-killer-trump-big-beautiful-bill/">so-called Big, Beautiful Bill.</a></p><p>Mast&rsquo;s bill contains eerily similar language, Stern said.</p><p>&ldquo;This is an angle that lawmakers on the right seem intent on pursuing &mdash; whether through last year&rsquo;s nonprofit killer bill, or a bill like this,&rdquo; Stern said.</p><p>The provision particularly threatens journalists, Stern said. He noted that Sen. Tom Cotton, R-Ark., in November 2023 <a href="https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2023/11/tom-cotton-hamas-journalists-fake-news-disinformation-netanyahu-gantz/">demanded a Justice Department &ldquo;national security investigation&rdquo;</a> of The Associated Press, CNN, New York Times, and Reuters over freelance photographers&rsquo; images of the October 7 attacks.</p><p>Rubio also revoked &Ouml;zt&uuml;rk&rsquo;s visa on what appears to be nothing more than an op-ed she wrote for the Tufts University student newspaper in 2024 &mdash; which <a href="https://www.tuftsdaily.com/article/2024/03/4ftk27sm6jkj">did not mention Hamas</a> &mdash; calling on the school to <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/03/30/tufts-rumeysa-ozturk-ice-immigration-op-ed/">divest from companies tied to Israel</a>.</p><p>Since taking office, Rubio has also added groups to the State Department&rsquo;s list of foreign terrorist organizations at a blistering pace, focusing largely on gangs and <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/08/15/trump-mexico-war-cartels/">drug cartels </a>that were previously the domain of the criminal legal system.</p><h2><strong>Free Speech Exception?</strong></h2><p>There is an ostensible safety valve in Mast&rsquo;s bill. Citizens would be granted the right to appeal to Rubio within 60 days of their passports being denied or revoked.</p><p>That provided little comfort to the ACLU&rsquo;s Hamadanchy, who is helping rally opposition to the bill.</p><p>&ldquo;Basically, you can go back to the secretary, who has already made this determination, and try to appeal. There&rsquo;s no standard set. There&rsquo;s nothing,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Hamadanchy said the provision granting the secretary of state discretionary power over passports appeared to be an attempt to sidestep being forced to provide evidence of legal violations.</p><p>&ldquo;I can&rsquo;t imagine that if somebody actually provided material support for terrorism there would be an instance where it wouldn&rsquo;t be prosecuted &mdash; it just doesn&rsquo;t make sense,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>While the &ldquo;nonprofit killer&rdquo; bill drew only a smattering of opposition on the right from libertarian-minded conservatives such as Rep. Thomas Massie, R-Ky., Stern said Republicans should be just as concerned about the potential infringement of civil liberties in the passport bill.</p><p>The law, he said, would also grant nearly unchecked power to a Democratic secretary, he said.</p><p>&ldquo;Lately, it appears that the right is so convinced that it will never be out of power that the idea that one day the shoe might be on the other foot doesn&rsquo;t resonate,&rdquo; Stern said. &ldquo;What is to stop a future Democratic administration from designating an anti-abortion activist, a supporter of West Bank settlements, an anti-vaxxer to be a supporter of terrorism and target them the same way? The list is endless.&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 08:08:50 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/13/business/charlie-kirk-death-fired-comments</link><title>People are getting fired for allegedly celebrating Charlie Kirk’s murder. It looks like a coordinated effort (cnn.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngd46f/people_are_getting_fired_for_allegedly/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngd46f/people_are_getting_fired_for_allegedly/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 15 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ngd46f/people_are_getting_fired_for_allegedly/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/ap25255111943391.jpg?c=16x9&q=w_800,c_fill' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><cite> <span>New York</span> &nbsp;&mdash;&nbsp; </cite> </p><p>Dozens of social media posts and messages about the murder of Charlie Kirk, including some that celebrated his death, are being spotlighted by conservative activists, Republican elected officials and a doxxing website as part of an online campaign to punish the posters behind the messages. </p><p>Prominent far-right influencer Laura Loomer, a US senator, and a site called &ldquo;Expose Charlie&rsquo;s Murderers&rdquo; have all drawn attention to people who have posted messages about Kirk&rsquo;s Wednesday assassination. </p><p>The campaigns show how social media posts or personal messages &mdash; even by accounts with few followers or from people who are not public figures &mdash; could easily be surfaced and publicized, and people&rsquo;s personal information can be spread across the internet at a time when doxxing is easier than ever. </p><p>The Charlie&rsquo;s Murderers site, whose domain was registered anonymously and which says it is not a doxxing site, claims it has &ldquo;received nearly 30,000 submissions,&rdquo; according to a message on the site&rsquo;s front page on midday Saturday. Currently, there are a few dozen submissions published on the site. &ldquo;This website will soon be converted into a searchable database of all 30,000 submissions, filterable by general location and job industry. This is a permanent and continuously-updating archive of Radical activists calling for violence.&rdquo; </p><p>Most people whose messages have been posted on the site do not seem to refer to themselves as activists, nor did it seem many were calling for violence. Administrators for the site did not respond to a request for comment. The site also opened an X account on Friday. </p><p>Loomer posted on X on Wednesday, hours after the fatal shooting, that &ldquo;I will be spending my night making everyone I find online who celebrates his death Famous, so prepare to have your whole future professional aspirations ruined if you are sick enough to celebrate his death.&rdquo; CNN was unable to reach Loomer for comment. </p><p>On <a href="https://x.com/ParkerThayer/status/1966199376247926941">X</a>, one account has begun a running &ldquo;Trophy Case&rdquo; &mdash; a &ldquo;mega-thread of all of the people Twitter gets fired, updated live as the news comes in,&rdquo; with dozens of entries of people it claims have lost their jobs. </p><p>And after MSNBC fired senior political analyst <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/11/msnbc-fires-matthew-dowd-charlie-kirk-shooting">Matthew Dowd</a> after he said Kirk&rsquo;s rhetoric might have contributed to his shooting, President Donald Trump himself weighed in. </p><p>&ldquo;They fired this guy, Dowd from (MSNBC), who&rsquo;s a terrible guy, terrible human being, but they fired him. I hear they&rsquo;re firing other people,&rdquo; Trump said on Fox News on Friday morning. <a href="https://matthewdowd.substack.com/p/a-time-to-see-with-new-eyes">On his Substack</a> after the firing, Dowd said the &ldquo;Right Wing media mob&rdquo; attacked him on several platforms. CNN has reached out to Dowd for comment. </p><p>Some of the people whose posts have been highlighted say they&rsquo;re now receiving a barrage of harassment and are worried about becoming the victims of violence. </p><p>For example, Canadian independent journalist Rachel Gilmore posted that she is &ldquo;terrified&rdquo; about retaliation from Kirk&rsquo;s &ldquo;far-right fans&rdquo; after the shooting. That post is the first listed on the anonymous website, including a part where Gilmore said she hoped Kirk survives. She said in a <a href="https://x.com/atRachelGilmore/status/1966553673581912495">video</a> online that she did not celebrate Kirk&rsquo;s death and said she hoped he survives in another post. She also said she received a &ldquo;tsunami&rdquo; of threats and called the last 48 hours of her life &ldquo;a living hell.&rdquo; </p><p><a href="https://x.com/GeoRebekah">Rebekah Jones</a>, a former Florida coronavirus data scientist <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2022/05/27/us/florida-report-coronavirus-numbers-manipulated">who in 2022 claimed</a> the state of Florida pressured her to manipulate pandemic data, said she contacted the police twice about death threats and about the &ldquo;hit list,&rdquo; her name for the anonymous site. Jones&rsquo; claims about Florida&rsquo;s pandemic data were found to be &ldquo;unsubstantiated,&rdquo; according to a state inspector general report, a finding she disagrees with. </p><p>Jones posted about Kirk on Wednesday, writing: &ldquo;Save your sympathies for the innocent bystanders caught in the crossfire of MAGA&rsquo;s violent political messaging machine.&rdquo; The website republished that post along with other pieces of Jones&rsquo; personal information. </p><p>&ldquo;It is absolutely fair to call it a coordinated harassment campaign,&rdquo; said Laura Edelson, assistant professor at Northeastern University and director of the Cybersecurity for Democracy Project. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s absolutely why it exists, to coordinate and target the harassment toward the selected individuals.&rdquo; </p><p>Some Republican elected officials are also publicizing people who posted about Kirk&rsquo;s murder, including some public-sector employees like teachers. </p><p>Republican Sen. Marsha Blackburn of Tennessee <a href="https://x.com/MarshaBlackburn/status/1965966859259490315">said</a> a Middle Tennessee State University employee should be removed after writing they had &ldquo;ZERO sympathy&rdquo; for Kirk&rsquo;s death. The university <a href="https://www.tennessean.com/story/news/local/2025/09/11/charlie-kirk-death-mtsu-assistant-dean-fired-comments/86090129007/">confirmed</a> to CNN in a statement that the employee was fired &ldquo;effective immediately.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;No university employee who celebrates the assassination of Charlie Kirk should be trusted to shape the minds of the next generation in the classroom. The firing of this MTSU employee was the right decision, and it sends a clear message that this kind of reprehensible behavior must not be tolerated,&rdquo; Blackburn said in a statement to CNN. </p><p>GOP Rep. Nancy Mace of South Carolina also encouraged the firing of a public school teacher, whom the school district later <a href="https://www.kktv.com/2025/09/11/teacher-no-longer-employed-saying-america-became-greater-after-charlie-kirk-shooting-district-confirms/?outputType=amp">confirmed</a> to local news was no longer employed with the district. </p><p>And private companies, such as <a href="https://x.com/FreddysUSA/status/1966159699197264332">Freddy&rsquo;s Frozen Custard &amp; Steakburgers</a> and the <a href="https://www.wral.com/news/local/panthers-employee-fired-controversial-comments-charlie-kirk-death-raleigh/">Carolina Panthers</a>, have also let employees go for their social media posts about Kirk. </p><p>DC Comics <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/11/entertainment/dc-comics-red-hood-charlie-kirk">canceled</a> the just-released &ldquo;Red Hood&rdquo; comic book series after its author, Gretchen Felker-Martin, made comments about Kirk&rsquo;s death on social media. </p><p>In since-deleted posts captured in screengrabs shared by other social media users, <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/11/entertainment/dc-comics-red-hood-charlie-kirk">Felker-Martin</a> allegedly wrote on social media after news of Kirk&rsquo;s death: &ldquo;Hope the bullet&rsquo;s OK.&rdquo; </p><p>&ldquo;At DC Comics, we place the highest value on our creators and community and affirm the right to peaceful, individual expression of personal viewpoints. Posts or public comments that can be viewed as promoting hostility or violence are inconsistent with DC&rsquo;s standards of conduct,&rdquo; the company, which like CNN&#8239;is owned by Warner Bros. Discovery, said in a statement. CNN has reached out to representatives for Felker-Martin for comment. </p><p>In most places, private companies can fire employees for any reason &mdash; and that includes crass social media posts, said Jeffrey Hirsch, a professor of labor and employment law at the University of North Carolina. It&rsquo;s a little trickier for public sector employees, but their firings are also justified if the speech is &ldquo;so egregious it disrupts operations.&rdquo; </p><p>In a 1987 <a href="https://firstamendment.mtsu.edu/article/rankin-v-mcpherson/">case</a>, the Supreme Court decided that it was constitutionally protected speech, and not grounds for firing, for a government employee to tell her co-workers she was sorry that a would-be assassin failed to kill President Reagan. </p><p>And it&rsquo;s extra sensitive for teachers, Hirsch said, since they work with young people, especially if the posts are applauding political violence. &ldquo;The reality of the situation is, if they&rsquo;re getting flooded, even if it&rsquo;s from one political wing, with complaints, it&rsquo;s likely to push an employer to fire somebody,&rdquo; he said. </p><div><picture><source height="undefined" width="679" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_679,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="967" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_967,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><source height="undefined" width="860" srcset="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill/f_webp"><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234476784.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill" alt="People visit a memorial for Charlie Kirk at the Turning Point USA headquarters on September 12, in Phoenix." height="3723" width="5584"></source></source></source></source></source></picture> </div><p>In other cases, some social media users highlighted Kirk&rsquo;s pro-Second Amendment stance, including <a href="https://x.com/JasonSCampbell/status/1643977032509067272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1643977032509067272%7Ctwgr%5E7e432a9549d971e4b137121ddba2b23374452b57%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.newsweek.com%2Fcharlie-kirk-says-gun-deaths-worth-it-2nd-amendment-1793113">past</a> news reports that he said some gun deaths were &ldquo;unfortunately&rdquo; worth it to keep the Second Amendment. </p><p>The highlighted social media entries span a range of responses to Kirk&rsquo;s shooting. One post, for example, simply noted the world continued on. </p><p>The website says its explicit aim is to get the people it spotlights fired.&#8239;It was <a href="https://www.whois.com/whois/charliesmurderers.com">registered</a> through a privacy service with an address in Iceland. </p><p>And the site&rsquo;s name already implies that the people whose information it shares are responsible for Kirk&rsquo;s murder, paving the way for harassment, Hank Teran, CEO at open-source threat intelligence platform Open Measures, told CNN. The website also echoes back to Kirk-founded conservative group Turning Point&rsquo;s &ldquo;Professor Watchlist,&rdquo; whose <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2021/sep/17/turning-point-usa-professor-watchlist">purpose</a> was to unmask what it called &ldquo;radical professors,&rdquo; but often led to harassment and violent threats directed toward people named on that list. </p><p>Altogether, &ldquo;it could be reasonable to conclude that there&rsquo;s some intent to incite harassment,&rdquo; Teran said. </p><p>High political tensions across the country are ramping up people&rsquo;s emotional responses, said Edelson, the Northeastern professor, and it &ldquo;creates a need to do something.&rdquo; </p><p>The blanket blame on &ldquo;the left&rdquo; in some cases extends the blame past the shooter into an amorphous enemy, Whitney Phillips, assistant professor of information politics and ethics at the University of Oregon, told CNN. </p><p>&ldquo;Attempts to call out people designated as being celebratory of Kirk&rsquo;s death, or merely critical of Kirk&rsquo;s life, work to give shape and weight to that enemy,&rdquo; Philips said. That feeds into &ldquo;a false culture war framing.&rdquo; As a result, she said, disconnected groups can be perceived as &ldquo;a downright spiritual enemy of conservatives, and by extension, of America itself.&rdquo; </p><p><em>CNN&rsquo;s Dan Heching contributed to this report.&#8239;</em> </p><p>This story has been updated with additional content. </p></div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://media.cnn.com/api/v1/images/stellar/prod/gettyimages-2234109280.jpg?c=original&amp;q=w_860,c_fill"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 05:52:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2025/09/girlsdoporn-owner-michael-pratt-gets-27-years-for-sex-trafficking-conspiracy/?comments-page=1#comments</link><title>“You are evil”: GirlsDoPorn ringleader Michael Pratt sentenced to 27 years | Sentence is longer than US asked for; judge "never had a case like this before." (arstechnica.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ng6tp7/you_are_evil_girlsdoporn_ringleader_michael_pratt/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ng6tp7/you_are_evil_girlsdoporn_ringleader_michael_pratt/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ng6tp7/you_are_evil_girlsdoporn_ringleader_michael_pratt/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/michael-pratt-most-wanted-1152x648-1757435496.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>"For almost a decade, the Defendant led the scheme to systematically coerce and defraud women into engaging in filmed sexual activity for profit," the sentencing recommendation said. "A sentence of 260 months is warranted, given the longevity of the scheme, the amount of profit, and the extent of the damage to the victims."</p><p>Pratt's <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.casd.654852/gov.uscourts.casd.654852.450.0.pdf">plea agreement</a> limited his rights to appeal the sentencing, but said he "may appeal a custodial sentence above 260 months." The 27-year (324-month) sentence exceeds that. While the government agreed to recommend no more than 260 months, the plea agreement said the government "may support on appeal the sentence or restitution order actually imposed."</p><p>Pratt fled the US in 2019, shortly before being charged with sex-trafficking crimes. "He was named to the FBI's Ten Most Wanted list and lived as an international fugitive for more than three years until his arrest in Spain in December 2022 and extradition to San Diego in March 2024," the DOJ said.</p><h2>Pratt tried to minimize his role</h2><p>Pratt is the fourth person to be sentenced in the GirlsDoPorn case. Pratt's business partner, Matthew Wolfe, <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdca/pr/friend-and-business-partner-girlsdoporn-owner-michael-pratt-sentenced-14-years-prison">received 14 years</a>. Ruben Andre Garcia was <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdca/pr/twenty-year-sentence-girlsdoporn-sex-trafficking-conspiracy">sentenced</a> to 20 years, and Theodore Gyi was <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdca/pr/cameraman-pleads-guilty-girlsdoporn-sex-trafficking-conspiracy">sentenced</a> to four years. Defendant <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-sdca/pr/girlsdoporn-employee-pleads-guilty-sex-trafficking-conspiracy">Valorie Moser</a> is scheduled to be sentenced on Friday this week.</p><p>Pratt's <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.casd.654852/gov.uscourts.casd.654852.457.0_4.pdf">sentencing memorandum</a> tried to minimize his role in the conspiracy. "Circa 2014, Mr. Pratt's childhood friend, Matt Wolfe, took over as the cameraman and Mr. Pratt spent more time in the office doing post-production work and other business related activities," the filing said.</p><p>Pratt argued that Garcia exhibited "erratic and unpredictable" behavior and that "much of this conduct occurred outside of Mr. Pratt's presence." Pratt's filing said he should not receive a sentence as long as Garcia's.</p><p>Garcia "was a rapist," Pratt's filing said. "Mr. Pratt had no involvement in Garcia's sexual activities with the models before or after filming, nor did he condone it. When he received some complaints about Garcia's behavior, Mr. Pratt took precautions to ensure the safety of the models, including setting up nanny video cameras, securing hotel incidental refrigerators, and ensuring everyone left the hotel as a group."</p><p>The government's sentencing memorandum described Pratt as "the ringleader in a wide-ranging sex-trafficking conspiracy during which many women were defrauded into engaging in sex acts on camera, destroying many of their lives." The "scheme would never have occurred" if not for Pratt's actions, "and hundreds of women would not have been victimized," the government filing said.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 01:13:42 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/09/12/hyundai-raid-immigration-us-battery-manufacturing-south-korea-workforce/?&amp;tpcc=gifting_article&amp;gifting_article=aHl1bmRhaS1yYWlkLWltbWlncmF0aW9uLXVzLWJhdHRlcnktbWFudWZhY3R1cmluZy1zb3V0aC1rb3JlYS13b3JrZm9yY2U=&amp;pid=PNI6oXabXq1ydw6</link><title>Trump’s Hyundai Raid Drains U.S. Battery Brains: The United States can’t build the powerful technologies on its own. (foreignpolicy.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ng4jly/trumps_hyundai_raid_drains_us_battery_brains_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ng4jly/trumps_hyundai_raid_drains_us_battery_brains_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 9 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1ng4jly/trumps_hyundai_raid_drains_us_battery_brains_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://foreignpolicy.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/hyundai-plant-trump-immigration-raid-batteries-south-korea-GettyImages-2233996992.jpg?w=1000' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>For all of its efforts to drive a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/16/business/energy-environment/trump-battery-factories-electric-vehicles.html">domestic manufacturing boom</a> in key industries, the United States remains heavily reliant on Asian expertise to build batteries, the powerful technologies that underpin drones, electric vehicles, and much more.&nbsp;</p><p>It&rsquo;s a reality that was laid bare last week when U.S. immigration officials raided an EV battery plant construction site in Georgia and detained around <a href="https://apnews.com/article/us-south-korea-ice-raid-georgia-hyundai-9394482c195664d7cc3db67ae998ac05">475 workers</a>, most of whom were South Korean nationals. The plant is co-owned by <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/07/us/politics/hyundai-plant-immigration-raid-georgia.html">Hyundai</a>, a South Korean carmaker. U.S. authorities said the raid was the biggest <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/us-immigration-agents-arrest-hundreds-hyundai-plant-mostly-koreans-2025-09-06/">single-site enforcement operation</a> in the Department of Homeland Security&rsquo;s history.&nbsp;</p></div><div><p><span>For all of its efforts to drive a </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/16/business/energy-environment/trump-battery-factories-electric-vehicles.html"><span>domestic manufacturing boom</span></a><span> in key industries, the United States remains heavily reliant on Asian expertise to build batteries, the powerful technologies that underpin drones, electric vehicles, and much more.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>It&rsquo;s a reality that was laid bare last week when U.S. immigration officials raided an EV battery plant construction site in Georgia and detained around </span><a href="https://apnews.com/article/us-south-korea-ice-raid-georgia-hyundai-9394482c195664d7cc3db67ae998ac05"><span>475 workers</span></a><span>, most of whom were South Korean nationals. The plant is co-owned by </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/07/us/politics/hyundai-plant-immigration-raid-georgia.html"><span>Hyundai</span></a><span>, a South Korean carmaker. U.S. authorities said the raid was the biggest </span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/us-immigration-agents-arrest-hundreds-hyundai-plant-mostly-koreans-2025-09-06/"><span>single-site enforcement operation</span></a><span> in the Department of Homeland Security&rsquo;s history.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The raid ignited a diplomatic firestorm with longtime U.S. ally South Korea and has cast a spotlight on the state of the U.S. battery sector. Batteries are essential to powering many of the world&rsquo;s most cutting-edge defense and energy technologies, including military drones and </span><a href="https://source.benchmarkminerals.com/article/batteries-and-defence-the-new-demand-driver"><span>submarines</span></a><span>. Yet the U.S. industry remains deeply dependent on foreign know-how to grow its own sector, and experts warn that the Trump administration&rsquo;s Hyundai crackdown risks further spooking investment.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;We are reliant on foreign help to build and scale this technology,&rdquo; said Chris Berry, the president of House Mountain Partners, an independent metals analysis consultancy. &ldquo;The United States labor force is not going to be able to build these types of extremely technically detailed plants without foreign help.&rdquo;&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>It&rsquo;s not unusual for foreign companies to first rely on their own talent when initially scaling up operations overseas and then train a local workforce, experts said.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;The number of Korean employees at the beginning, while they&rsquo;re transferring the management technology, [is] higher&mdash;and then as quickly as they can, they transfer that knowledge, and then they go home, and it&rsquo;s less expensive for the company,&rdquo; said Tami Overby, an international business consultant who previously headed the U.S.-Korea Business Council at the U.S. Chamber of Commerce.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>South Korean President Lee Jae-myung made a </span><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/sep/12/south-korean-outrage-at-us-detention-ordeal-as-300-workers-return-home"><span>similar point</span></a><span> on Thursday: &ldquo;</span><span>This isn&rsquo;t long-term permanent employment but to establish facilities and equipment for factories; we need technicians to install machinery and equipment. The U.S. doesn&rsquo;t have such personnel, and they won&rsquo;t give visas for [our workers] to stay and work.&rdquo;</span><span> He warned Washington that South Korean businesses would &ldquo;</span><span>hesitate to make direct investments&rdquo; in the United States if it failed to resolve visa issues quickly.</span></p><hr><p><span><span>The Hyundai case</span> has exposed the state of U.S. battery manufacturing expertise. Today, the world&rsquo;s </span><a href="https://www.iea.org/commentaries/the-battery-industry-has-entered-a-new-phase"><span>biggest battery powerhouse</span></a><span> is China, which produces more than three-quarters of all batteries sold globally&mdash;and does so significantly more cheaply and efficiently than its global competitors&mdash;according to the International Energy Agency (IEA). China is the source of more than 70 percent of all EV batteries ever produced, driving ample manufacturing and production expertise.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>After China, South Korea and Japan are global battery giants that have made hefty overseas investments. Korean firms in particular top the charts in overseas manufacturing capacity, and last year Korean producers filled more than 20 percent of global electric car battery demand.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;The Koreans, the Japanese, and the Chinese in particular all really understand the technology behind these batteries and the chemistries and the pros and the cons&mdash;but they also understand how to scale at speed,&rdquo; Berry said.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>To fuel a U.S. battery boom, the Biden administration harnessed its landmark climate bill, the Inflation Reduction Act (IRA), which used hefty tax incentives to encourage </span><a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2022/09/16/inflation-reduction-act-critical-mineral-chains-congress-biden/"><span>domestic manufacturing</span></a><span> and drive new investment and interest in the sector. The IRA was &ldquo;game changing legislation,&rdquo; Manish Dua, an analyst with Benchmark Mineral Intelligence, </span><a href="https://source.benchmarkminerals.com/article/one-year-on-the-ira-has-changed-the-battery-landscape-in-the-us"><span>said</span></a><span> in 2023. &ldquo;Massive outlay of subsidies and tax credits has boosted private sector participation across the whole cleantech space.&rdquo;</span></p><p><span>U.S. President Donald Trump has gone in another direction entirely, with an onslaught of moves meant to </span><a href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/08/29/trump-china-clean-energy-transition-renewables-fossil-fuels-wind-farm/"><span>gut the U.S. clean energy sector</span></a><span>, </span><a href="https://blogs.law.columbia.edu/climatechange/2025/04/29/100-days-of-trump-2-0-the-inflation-reduction-act/"><span>unwind</span></a><span> many of the Biden tax credits, and unleash more fossil fuel production. The Trump administration&rsquo;s </span><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/06/16/business/energy-environment/trump-battery-factories-electric-vehicles.html"><span>targeting of EVs</span></a><span>&mdash;a key market for batteries&mdash;has injected fresh uncertainty into the U.S. battery sector, as has its trade war with China, which dominates battery supply chains.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>At the same time, the U.S. Energy Department has </span><a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/energy-department-announces-actions-secure-american-critical-minerals-and-materials-supply"><span>announced up to $500 million</span></a><span> in funding opportunities to boost battery manufacturing and recycling, and U.S. automakers are eager to propel the United States to the forefront of the battery race.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Early this year, General Motors battery chief Kurt Kelty <a href="https://www.ft.com/content/e9509c6b-2579-425e-8344-04abf44321ce">urged</a> North America to &ldquo;seize EV battery leadership from China.&rdquo;&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;By advancing battery technologies and driving innovation, strengthening our onshoring, and making our supply chain the most competitive in the world, we&rsquo;re building not just better batteries but a stronger and more resilient U.S. industry for the future,&rdquo; Kelty </span><span>said</span><span>.&nbsp;</span></p><hr><p><span><span>U.S. firms</span> have indeed made big strides in research and innovation for batteries, particularly with developing new battery chemistries. But that&rsquo;s just one part of the battery equation, experts said.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;There is sometimes a gap between research and development and really scaling it up at an industrial and a commercial level,&rdquo; said Bryan Bille, a policy expert at Benchmark. &ldquo;That&rsquo;s basically what China is really good at.&rdquo;</span></p><p><span>Days after the Hyundai raid, Trump himself <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-07/trump-says-georgia-raid-shows-need-for-help-training-us-workers">acknowledged</a> that there was a gap in U.S. battery manufacturing that foreigners have helped plug. &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t have people in this country who know about batteries,&rdquo; Trump said on </span><span>Sunday</span><span>. &ldquo;Maybe we should help them along and let some people come in and train our people.&rdquo;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;We do have to work something out where we bring in experts so our people can be trained so they can do it themselves,&rdquo; Trump added.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Yet U.S. immigration rules and the Hyundai raid&mdash;which has sent </span><a href="https://www.ft.com/content/f236cf29-c4d2-4f5a-adb4-8a49fc2fe748"><span>shockwaves</span></a><span> through other Korean and international firms&mdash;also risk deterring the very investment that Trump has been courting as part of his big plan to build up U.S. </span><a href="https://www.wsj.com/economy/us-manufacturing-decline-service-economy-ee97a1e2?gaa_at=eafs&amp;gaa_n=ASWzDAgsfoHd15LayXM65lwFSWOcJdbegBO0Fl7rI2Hr67DymHB3qWbc6iDTBgGwPEU%3D&amp;gaa_ts=68c1be32&amp;gaa_sig=GdUNa1j2dtUbPi4BeOycQGnVNLGS3Gzp6uOSnLvHHilLDhmOME5zc637JwMbqClHr4HMbiUy6JsNrEohqzSpLw%3D%3D"><span>manufacturing might</span></a><span> and </span><a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/09/05/trump-hyundai-georgia-raid"><span>push companies</span></a><span> to bring production to the United States. The United States lacks a visa program for foreign companies that wish to bring in skilled workers for a short-term period for construction purposes, the </span><i><span>Washington Post </span></i><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/2025/09/09/hyundai-raid-georgia-trump-immigration-jobs/"><span>reported</span></a><span>.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>The fallout from the raid may already be biting. South Korean officials </span><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/trump-offered-let-detained-korean-workers-stay-us-almost-all-heading-home-2025-09-11/"><span>said</span></a><span> on Thursday that Trump offered to allow hundreds of those arrested workers to stay in the United States to train an American workforce. But only one Korean worker decided to stay, the officials said.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>Many of the large foreign investors in the United States are likely &ldquo;quite shocked,&rdquo; Overby said. &ldquo;It gives everyone a moment to take a breath and review their immigration compliance rules and regulations, not just for their employees but for contractors, subcontractors, everyone up and down the supply chain.&rdquo;</span></p><p><span>After the raid, South Korean firms have halted work on at least </span><a href="https://newrepublic.com/post/200295/donald-trump-ice-raid-hyundai-georgia-business-investment"><span>22 projects</span></a><span> in the United States, and Hyundai&rsquo;s chief </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-09-11/hyundai-ceo-says-battery-plant-delayed-after-immigration-raid"><span>told</span></a><span><em> Bloomberg</em> that the incident had resulted in a &ldquo;minimum two to three months delay&rdquo; on the battery plant.&nbsp;</span></p><p><span>&ldquo;</span><span>I look at it as a little bit of an own-goal,&rdquo; Berry said. &ldquo;We&rsquo;re cutting off our nose to spite our face here in the United States.&rdquo;</span></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 23:42:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.npr.org/2025/09/13/nx-s1-5538476/charlie-kirk-jobs-target-social-media-critics-resign</link><title>People are losing jobs due to social media posts about Charlie Kirk (npr.org)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nftyt3/people_are_losing_jobs_due_to_social_media_posts/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nftyt3/people_are_losing_jobs_due_to_social_media_posts/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nftyt3/people_are_losing_jobs_due_to_social_media_posts/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 15:49:35 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://thehill.com/policy/defense/5501199-military-retribution-charlie-kirk/#amp_tf=From%20%251%24s&amp;aoh=17577091123432&amp;csi=0&amp;referrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.google.com&amp;ampshare=https%3A%2F%2Fthehill.com%2Fpolicy%2Fdefense%2F5501199-military-retribution-charlie-kirk%2F</link><title>Hegseth says Pentagon ‘tracking’ service members, civilians who celebrate Charlie Kirk killing (thehill.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfkpfg/hegseth_says_pentagon_tracking_service_members/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfkpfg/hegseth_says_pentagon_tracking_service_members/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfkpfg/hegseth_says_pentagon_tracking_service_members/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 06:54:08 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theverge.com/politics/777630/wsj-trans-misinformation-charlie-kirk</link><title>The WSJ carelessly spread anti-trans misinformation (theverge.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfghxi/the_wsj_carelessly_spread_antitrans_misinformation/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfghxi/the_wsj_carelessly_spread_antitrans_misinformation/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 9 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfghxi/the_wsj_carelessly_spread_antitrans_misinformation/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/09/gettyimages-2226524376.jpg?quality=90&strip=all&crop=0%2C10.732984293194%2C100%2C78.534031413613&w=1200' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>While I generally respect <em>The Wall Street Journal,</em> every once in a while it sees fit to remind me that it is, in fact, owned by Rupert Murdoch. This time, it printed something dangerously close to anti-trans blood libel in the wake of Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s shooting.</p><p>In its live-update blog yesterday, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/azintel.bsky.social/post/3lyl4pn6uek25">the<em> Journal</em> wrote</a>, &ldquo;Ammunition engraved with transgender and antifascist ideology was found inside the rifle authorities believe was used in Kirk&rsquo;s shooting, according to an internal law enforcement bulletin and a source familiar with the investigation.&rdquo; That language was echoed in social media <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/wsj.com/post/3lykxa7bblx2s">posts</a>.</p><div><p>The right wing, including sitting members of Congress, has been making false claims blaming trans people for gun violence for years</p></div><p>We know now that the<em> Journal</em> royally fucked this up &mdash; the bullets did have messages, but nothing about transgender people was on them. This reporting was demolished slowly and then quickly. First, <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/09/11/us/charlie-kirk-shooting-news/investigators-eye-a-hunting-rifle-for-clues-to-the-gunmans-identity-and-motive?smid=url-share"><em>The New York Times </em>had a source </a>who said the <em>WSJ</em>&rsquo;s information contradicts other conclusions. Then, CNN reported that investigators just <a href="https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/charlie-kirk-shot-utah-death-09-11-25#cmffuxfs800003b6tpgkbk78c">saw some arrows on the casings</a>. The final nail in the coffin came from a press conference held by Utah Gov. Spencer Cox, who did not confirm that anything about trans people appeared on the casings.</p><p>The right wing, including sitting members of Congress, has been making false claims blaming trans people <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/02/06/nx-s1-5288145/trump-anti-trans-executive-order">for gun violence for years</a>. &ldquo;Another trans shooter,&rdquo; said Georgia Rep. Marjorie Taylor Greene of a mass shooting in Philadelphia in 2023. (The <a href="https://whyy.org/articles/kingsessing-mass-shooting-suspect-philadelphia-police/">suspect arrested was not trans</a>.) Missouri Sen. Josh Hawley said of a 2024 Texas church shooting, &ldquo;So the Lakewood church shooter was a transgender, pro-Palestine radical&hellip;&rdquo; (The <a href="https://www.the-independent.com/news/world/americas/crime/lakewood-shooting-genesse-jeffrey-moreno-transgender-b2495803.html">suspect arrested wasn&rsquo;t</a>.) At least Arizona Rep. Paul Gosar had the basic sense of shame needed to <a href="https://perma.cc/R3S2-HQZ2">delete his 2022 tweet</a> about the Uvalde school shooting in which he blamed &ldquo;a transsexual leftist illegal alien.&rdquo; (Again, <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/uvalde-records-shooting-campus-safety-concerns">the suspected perpetrator was not trans</a>.)</p><p>After Kirk&rsquo;s death, the right wing loudly began blaming leftists for the shooting &mdash; everyone from <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/politics-news/charlie-kirks-death-prompts-outpouring-shock-grief-condemnations-polit-rcna230472">Donald Trump</a> to <a href="https://x.com/RepLuna/status/1965861283636588668">Florida Rep. Anna Paulina Luna</a> to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/09/10/us/charlie-kirk-reaction-trump.html">Elon Musk</a>. Journalists have known for decades now that initial reports on shootings are often wrong. So given the history of false accusations against trans people and leftists, the <em>Journal</em>&rsquo;s decision to go live with shaky information was staggeringly, shockingly irresponsible.</p><div><p>Trans people have been under attack from the right for the better part of a decade. Republicans now consider terrorizing trans people to be <a href="https://www.politico.com/news/2025/01/02/trans-rights-marquee-fight-house-republicans-00196013">a signature issue</a>. Besides <a href="https://stateline.org/2025/06/26/more-states-pass-laws-restricting-transgender-peoples-bathroom-use/">bathroom bills</a> &mdash; which seem aimed at <a href="https://michiganadvance.com/2025/09/04/lgbtq-advocates-deride-michigan-house-bathroom-bill-as-attack-on-transgender-students/">criminalizing being trans in public</a> &mdash; the Republican Party has spent valuable time at its national convention <a href="https://19thnews.org/2024/07/rnc-transgender-people/">demonizing trans people</a> specifically. Trans people&rsquo;s access to healthcare has been <a href="https://stateline.org/2025/07/09/many-medical-treatments-could-be-affected-by-supreme-court-transgender-ruling/">curtailed by the Supreme Court</a>. The <a href="https://michiganadvance.com/2025/08/25/university-of-michigan-health-ends-gender-affirming-care-after-doj-subpoena/">University of Michigan&rsquo;s hospital network stopped providing gender-affirming care</a> to minors after receiving a subpoena; it is one of at <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/nbc-out/out-news/least-21-hospitals-ended-restricted-trans-care-minors-january-rcna226640">least 21 hospitals to do so</a>. The Federal Trade Commission has also begun an <a href="https://www.axios.com/2025/07/28/ftc-claims-transgender-gender-affirming-care">investigation into care for minors</a>.</p></div><div><p><em>Why</em> did the <em>WSJ </em>run with its half-baked report?</p></div><p>So this is a vulnerable minority group that has been widely demonized. Any good journalistic practice would involve nailing down accuracy to avoid making things worse. That did not happen at <em>The Wall Street Journal</em>.</p><p>This story was later rewritten without a correction or editor&rsquo;s note, <a href="https://www.status.news/p/david-ellison-paramount-warner-bros-discovery-cnn?utm_source=www.status.news&amp;utm_medium=newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=the-emerging-ellison-empire&amp;_bhlid=525fc5f03d1ab650fb5e79cf31d4ef7300aefc78&amp;last_resource_guid=Post%3Ac21bd2ef-4048-453e-85ee-adebbab3e79d">according to <em>Status</em></a>, a newsletter about the media industry. <em>Status</em> asked why. Here&rsquo;s the response from the <em>WSJ</em>:</p><div><blockquote><p>Like any breaking news situation, we update our reporting&mdash;which we published in the form of a live blog&mdash;with new information and further reporting as it becomes available. Our initial report about the internal bulletin was appropriately attributed. We built it out later in the day as we got more reporting, and felt that the added material spoke for itself. There was no correction added to that original story because none was deemed necessary.</p></blockquote></div><p>Well, an editor&rsquo;s note has been added now. Here it is in full:</p><div><blockquote><p><strong>Editor&rsquo;s Note:</strong> An earlier version of this article detailed how an internal law enforcement bulletin said that ammunition recovered following the Charlie Kirk shooting was engraved with expressions of &ldquo;transgender and anti-fascist ideology.&rdquo; Justice Department officials later urged caution about the bulletin by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, saying it may not accurately reflect the messages on the ammunition, and the article was updated Thursday to reflect that. This editor&rsquo;s note was appended on Friday, Sept. 12, after Utah Gov. Spencer Cox said the engravings included one that said &ldquo;Hey fascist!&rdquo; along with other messages and symbols. He gave no indication that the ammunition included any transgender references.</p></blockquote></div><p>I still have questions about how this happened. <em>Why</em> did the <em>WSJ </em>run with its half-baked report?</p><p>I suspect that someone saw a post by Steven Crowder and felt competitive. <a href="https://x.com/scrowder/status/1966118431511433267">In a post yesterday</a>, Crowder said he&rsquo;d received an email from an Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms officer containing &ldquo;a screen shot from what appears to be an internal message,&rdquo; he wrote. The purported message contained the following sentence: &ldquo;All cartridges have engraved wording on them, expressing transgender and anti-fascist ideology.&rdquo; Crowder, a professional dickhead, is not exactly a reliable source &mdash; he&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.imdb.com/name/nm0189589/">a former child actor</a> best known for <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20180524040133/https://www.thedailybeast.com/the-unmaking-of-a-conservative-pundit">beefing with his then-employer Fox News</a>, <a href="https://nypost.com/2023/05/02/steven-crowder-wife-rant-vid-reveals-abusive-pattern-ex-staff/">chewing out his pregnant wife</a>, <a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/krystieyandoli/carlos-maza-youtube-hate-speech">violating YouTube&rsquo;s hate speech policies</a>, and hosting the political commentary program <em>Louder with Crowder</em>.</p><div><p>Blaming trans people is, after all, the Republican party line, and who promotes the party line better than News Corp?</p></div><p>Shortly after Crowder&rsquo;s post, the<em> Journal</em> went live with its update. Viewing Crowder as a competitor worth matching is the sort of thing I&rsquo;d expect out of the <em>New York Post</em>, or indeed most other sensationalist papers owned by Murdoch, who is also responsible for Fox News. (You&rsquo;d think after <a href="https://www.theverge.com/culture/700082/nyt-mamdani-news-judgment"><em>The New York Times</em>&rsquo; attempt to compete with Chris Rufo</a> backfired spectacularly, leading them to serve as the mouthpiece for <a href="https://www.theverge.com/cyber-security/710480/columbia-hacker-nazi-nyt-affirmative-action">a Nazi hacker</a>, serious media would know better.) Blaming trans people is, after all, the Republican party line, and who promotes the party line better than News Corp? But the <em>Journal</em> is supposed to be the crown jewel in the empire, with real, respectable reporting. Its editors and reporters should know better. <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> ran with its wrong report in an environment where the left was being vociferously blamed for the shooting, and where trans people had persistently been smeared for shootings they did not commit.</p><div><p>As we know now, <a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/777313/charlie-kirks-alleged-killer-scratched-bullets-with-a-helldivers-combo-and-a-furry-sex-meme">the bullets actually did have messages on them</a>. They included a furry meme (&ldquo;Notices bulges OWO what&rsquo;s this?&rdquo;), the phrase &ldquo;If you read this, you are gay lmao,&rdquo; and a reference to the video game <em>Helldivers 2</em>. This seems more indicative of internet brain rot than any specific ideology. It&rsquo;s confusing enough that <a href="https://x.com/PeterHamby/status/1966523439717683302?utm_source=www.garbageday.email&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=charlie-kirk-was-killed-by-a-meme&amp;_bhlid=d4996aff9280155400e38f87c693df197bea7ca1">at least some</a> of <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/15/24218765/nick-fuentes-groyper-war-trump-campaign-curtis-yarvin">the groypers</a> (and also, apparently, <a href="https://x.com/brucewilson/status/1966533940044288345">Musk&rsquo;s chatbot Grok</a>) seem to think <a href="https://x.com/asukagrypr/status/1966335931121914364">the shooter was a groyper</a>, so <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/editorials/guides/what-is-a-groyper-and-why-are-people-saying-charlie-kirks-shooter-is-one-nick-fuentess-groyper-army-explained">make of that what you will</a>. The <em>Journal</em> has pivoted into suggesting the alleged shooter, Tyler Robinson, was simply a troubled young man, despite other remarks from Cox. Cox said that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/09/12/us/tyler-robinson-charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect-invs">one of Robinson&rsquo;s relatives informed investigators</a> that Robinson &ldquo;had become more political in recent years.&rdquo;</p></div><p><em>The Wall Street Journal</em> has not retracted its report about the trans community, nor has it apologized. I guess it really is a Rupert Murdoch paper after all.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/777630/wsj-trans-misinformation-charlie-kirk#comments"><span>0 Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Elizabeth Lopatto</span></span></span></li><li><li><li><li><li><li></ul></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 03:40:53 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.404media.co/comcast-nbcuniversal-email-charlie-kirk/</link><title>Comcast Executives Warn Workers To Not Say The Wrong Thing About Charlie Kirk (404media.co)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfdafa/comcast_executives_warn_workers_to_not_say_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfdafa/comcast_executives_warn_workers_to_not_say_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 5 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nfdafa/comcast_executives_warn_workers_to_not_say_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.404media.co/content/images/size/w1200/2025/09/4096px-Four_More_Tour_IMG_6374_-50396253541-.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><article><div><p>A company-wide email from Comcast executives, sent to everyone working at NBCUniversal on Friday morning, mourns right-wing pundit Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s death and reminds employees that saying the wrong thing about Kirk&rsquo;s legacy can get you fired swiftly.&nbsp;</p><p>The email, obtained by 404 Media and first <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/comcast-execs-criticize-msnbc-matthew-dowd-charlie-kirk-shooting-memo-1236516014/?ref=404media.co"><u>reported by Variety</u></a>, has the subject line &ldquo;A message from Brian Roberts, Mike Cavanagh, and Mark Lazarus.&rdquo; In it, the executives eulogize Kirk, calling him an &ldquo;advocate for open debate, whose faith was important to him.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>Roberts is the Chairman and CEO of Comcast Corporation, Cavanagh is the president, and Lazarus is the prospective CEO of VERSANT, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/05/06/comcast-spinco-corporate-name-versant.html?ref=404media.co"><u>Comcast&rsquo;s new spinoff</u></a> that will include the majority of its NBCUniversal cable network portfolio. NBC, MSNBC, CNBC, Bravo and more journalistic and entertainment properties are under the NBCUniversal umbrella.</p><p>&ldquo;You may have seen that MSNBC recently ended its association with a contributor who made an unacceptable and insensitive comment about this horrific event,&rdquo; the executives wrote. &ldquo;That coverage was at odds with fostering civil dialogue and being willing to listen to the points of view of those who have differing opinions.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><div><p>&#128161;</p><p><b><strong>Do you have information about how your company is speaking to employees about Charlie Kirk's death, or political speech in general? I would love to hear from you. Using a non-work device, you can message me securely on Signal at sam.404. Otherwise, send me an email at sam@404media.co.</strong></b></p></div><p>Political analyst Matthew Dowd was fired from MSNBC on Wednesday after speaking about Kirk&rsquo;s death on air. During a broadcast on Wednesday following the shooting, anchor Katy Tur asked Dowd about &ldquo;the environment in which a shooting like this happens,&rdquo; <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/matthew-dowd-fired-msnbc-charlie-kirk-death-1236514875/?ref=404media.co">according to Variety</a>. Dowd answered: &ldquo;He&rsquo;s been one of the most divisive, especially divisive younger figures in this, who is constantly sort of pushing this sort of hate speech or sort of aimed at certain groups. And I always go back to, hateful thoughts lead to hateful words, which then lead to hateful actions. And I think that is the environment we are in. You can&rsquo;t stop with these sort of awful thoughts you have and then saying these awful words and not expect awful actions to take place. And that&rsquo;s the unfortunate environment we are in.&rdquo;</p><p>MSNBC president Rebecca Kutler <a href="https://variety.com/2025/tv/news/msnbc-apologizes-matthew-dowd-charlie-kirk-death-1236514778/?ref=404media.co"><u>issued an apology</u></a> in response, calling Dowd&rsquo;s words &ldquo;inappropriate, insensitive and unacceptable.&rdquo; Dowd also apologized publicly, <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matthewjdowd.bsky.social/post/3lyj6q4q7ik2l?ref=404media.co"><u>posting on Bluesky</u></a>: &ldquo;On an earlier appearance on MSNBC I was asked a question on the environment we are in. I apologize for my tone and words. Let me be clear, I in no way intended for my comments to blame Kirk for this horrendous attack.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><figure><a href="https://www.404media.co/charlie-kirk-was-not-practicing-politics-the-right-way/"><div><p>Charlie Kirk Was Not Practicing Politics the Right Way</p><p>The mainstream media seems entirely uninterested in explaining Charlie Kirk&rsquo;s work.</p><p><img src="https://www.404media.co/content/images/icon/favicon-3-124.svg" alt><span>404 Media</span><span>Jason Koebler</span></p></div></a></figure><p>MSNBC is a division of NBCUniversal. The letter from Comcast executives reiterates to current employees that their jobs are on the line if they stray from bland, milquetoast statements about a man who spent his life fomenting hate will have consequences on their careers. The entire mainstream media environment has been working overtime to sanitize Kirk&rsquo;s legacy since his murder&mdash;<a href="https://www.404media.co/charlie-kirk-was-not-practicing-politics-the-right-way/"><u>a legacy that includes</u></a> targeted harassment of professors at schools across the country and normalizing the notion that basic human rights are up for &ldquo;debate.&rdquo;&nbsp;</p><p>The full email is below.</p><p><em>Dear Comcast NBCUniversal Team,</em></p><p><em>The tragic loss of Charlie Kirk, a 31-year-old father, husband, and advocate for open debate, whose faith was important to him, reminds us of the fragility of life and the urgent need for unity in our nation. Our hearts are heavy, as his passing leaves a grieving family and a country grappling with division. There is no place for violence or hate in our society.</em></p><p><em>You may have seen that MSNBC recently ended its association with a contributor who made an unacceptable and insensitive comment about this horrific event. That coverage was at odds with fostering civil dialogue and being willing to listen to the points of view of those who have differing opinions. We should be able to disagree, robustly and passionately, but, ultimately, with respect. We need to do better.</em></p><p><em>Charlie Kirk believed that "when people stop talking, really bad stuff starts." Regardless of whether you agreed with his political views, his words and actions underscore the urgency to maintain a respectful exchange of ideas a principle we must champion. We believe in the power of communication to bring us together. Today, that belief feels more vital than ever. Something essential has fractured in our public discourse, and as a company that values the power of information, we have a responsibility to help mend it.</em></p><p><em>As employees, we ask you to embody our values in your work and communities. We should engage with respect, listen, and treat people with kindness.</em></p><div><div><p>About the author</p><p>Sam Cole is writing from the far reaches of the internet, about sexuality, the adult industry, online culture, and AI. She's the author of How Sex Changed the Internet and the Internet Changed Sex.</p></div></div></div></article> </div><div class="gallery"><p><img src="https://www.404media.co/content/images/thumbnail/CleanShot-2025-09-11-at-10.43.06@2x.png"></p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 01:33:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.theverge.com/politics/777313/charlie-kirks-alleged-killer-scratched-bullets-with-a-helldivers-combo-and-a-furry-sex-meme</link><title>Charlie Kirk’s alleged killer scratched bullets with a Helldivers combo and a furry sex meme. ﻿The suspected shooter left a hodgepodge of extremely online taunts. (theverge.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nf9izc/charlie_kirks_alleged_killer_scratched_bullets/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nf9izc/charlie_kirks_alleged_killer_scratched_bullets/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 6 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nf9izc/charlie_kirks_alleged_killer_scratched_bullets/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/09/gettyimages-577078448.jpg?quality=90&strip=all&crop=0%2C10.670307492385%2C100%2C78.65938501523&w=1200' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p>Tyler Robinson, apprehended last night in connection to the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/776079/charlie-kirk-shooting">fatal shooting of conservative activist Charlie Kirk</a>, allegedly left engraved bullets at the crime scene that were covered in a furry meme, a reference from the video game <em>Helldivers 2, </em>and an extremely online taunt.</p><p>In an FBI briefing this morning about his arrest, Utah Gov. Spencer Cox described the sequence of events that led to the capture of Robinson, 22, who was turned into the police by his father. They also clarified the nature of the notes engraved on the bullet casings found at the scene, which had been rumored to be slogans relating to antifascist and &ldquo;transgender ideology.&rdquo; As it turns out, the messages are a confusing mix of internet memes and pop culture.</p><p>As described, the bullets read (exact capitalization not confirmed at this point):</p><div><ul><li><span>&ldquo;Notices bulges OWO what&rsquo;s this?&rdquo;</span></li><li><span>&ldquo;Hey fascist! Catch!&rdquo; Up arrow symbol, right arrow, three down arrow symbols</span></li><li><span>&ldquo;Oh bella ciao bella ciao bella ciao ciao ciao&rdquo;</span></li><li><span>&ldquo;If you read this, you are gay lmao&rdquo;</span></li></ul></div><p>The first bullet casing, which was fired, is a meme referring to furry online roleplay, according to <a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/notices-bulge-owo-whats-this">Know Your Meme</a>.</p><p>It&rsquo;s not hard to see where the &ldquo;antifascist&rdquo; conclusion came from on two of the other bullets: &ldquo;Bella ciao&rdquo; is an Italian song adopted by partisans and resistance fighters while Italy was governed by the fascist dictator Benito Mussolini. Cox said in response to a question during the conference that the &ldquo;hey fascist&rdquo; message &ldquo;speaks for itself.&rdquo; Three downward-slanting arrows are a symbol used by both historical and contemporary antifascists.</p><p>But the full arrow sequence was quickly recognized as something else: a combo from <em>Helldivers 2</em> for calling the <a href="https://helldivers.fandom.com/wiki/Eagle_500kg_Bomb">Eagle 500kg Bomb</a> stratagem. The world of <em>Helldivers</em> &mdash; which evokes Robert Heinlein&rsquo;s book <em>Starship Troopers</em> and the subsequent movie &mdash; concerns fascism thematically; developer Arrowhead has <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/games/fps/the-united-nations-asked-helldivers-2-studio-arrowhead-if-itd-give-a-talk-on-psychological-manipulation-could-we-brainwash-an-entire-community-to-fight-for-a-fascist-state-would-we-be-okay-with-that-turns-out-yeah/">characterized it as a satire</a> where players fight for a fascist state.</p><p>As for the use of &ldquo;Bella ciao,&rdquo; the song has no obvious connection but given its historical significance, unsurprisingly does appear in a <em>Helldivers 2 </em>mod, as well as in at least one other video game, a World War II-themed strategy game called <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u-qTuXDEnFo"><em>Hearts of Iron IV</em></a>.</p><p>The fatal shooting of Kirk on Wednesday led to an intense manhunt across Utah, though it encountered numerous complications along the way. Several leads, publicly teased by FBI Director Kash Patel, quickly petered out. Leaked documents from law enforcement published by MAGA influencers led to false narratives about how markings on the bullet indicated that the shooter was in favor of &ldquo;transgender ideology.&rdquo;</p><p>It was nearly impossible to divorce politics and internet misinformation from Kirk&rsquo;s death, however. The 31-year-old was a powerful figure in the MAGA movement, as the founder and leader of the right-wing college group Turning Point USA, and a prominent podcaster and MAGA influencer himself, famous for appearing on college campuses to confront liberal students. President Donald Trump credited Kirk and TPUSA as a factor in his return to office, and frequently relied on him as an emissary to youth voters.</p><div><p>The messages on the shooter&rsquo;s bullet casings can best be described as bizarre and extremely online</p></div><p>In the aftermath of Kirk&rsquo;s death, his allies in the MAGA movement, including lawmakers and influencers, promised swift retribution against the left should the killer share their ideology. The themes of <em>Helldivers 2</em> could have an ideological meaning, albeit not necessarily a straightforward one. But ultimately, the messages on the shooter&rsquo;s bullet casings can best be described as bizarre and extremely online.</p><p>According to the FBI, evidence leading to Robinson&rsquo;s arrest included screenshots from his roommate&rsquo;s Discord chat, in which he mentioned leaving a rifle wrapped in a towel in some bushes. Law enforcement recovered a Mauser .30-06 from an area near the campus that was wrapped in a towel.</p><p>Fans of the game immediately noticed. Shortly after the press conference on Friday morning, the <em>Helldivers</em> subreddit was flooded with players who had picked up on what may be references to the game. A thread, now deleted, was titled: &ldquo;Hey Facist Catch!&rdquo; with the poster asking, &ldquo;Did anyone else hear/notice?!&rdquo; A commenter, responding to the thread, said, &ldquo;The moment I heard [the arrows] my eyes widened.&rdquo;</p><p>Another thread, also apparently deleted by moderators, referenced the arrows that authorities say were on one of the unfired bullet casings recovered at the scene. &ldquo;It sickens me having people like this playing this game and using it to real violence to tarnish this awesome game and community,&rdquo; the poster wrote. Other posts implored the subreddit moderators to lock down the forum. Moderators for the subreddit didn&rsquo;t immediately respond to a request for comment. A <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/helldivers2/comments/1nf5sxh/damn_not_for_nothing_but_its_gonna_be_weird_to/">thread in the separate r/Helldivers2 subreddit</a> remains active, with people discussing the apparent parallels.</p><p>Arrowhead, the maker of the <em>Helldivers</em> games, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p><p><span><a href="https://www.theverge.com/politics/777313/charlie-kirks-alleged-killer-scratched-bullets-with-a-helldivers-combo-and-a-furry-sex-meme#comments"><span>0 Comments</span></a></span></p><div><p><span><strong>Follow topics and authors</strong> from this story to see more like this in your personalized homepage feed and to receive email updates.</span></p><ul><li><span><span><span>Tina Nguyen</span></span></span></li><li><span><span><span>Mia Sato</span></span></span></li><li><li><li><li></ul></div></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 23:05:16 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.mediaite.com/media/tv/we-should-put-our-phones-down-utah-governor-says-there-is-a-tremendous-amount-of-disinformation-about-charlie-kirk-assassination/</link><title>‘We Should Put Our Phones Down’: Utah Governor Says ‘There Is a Tremendous Amount of Disinformation’ About Charlie Kirk Assassination (mediaite.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1neyi6s/we_should_put_our_phones_down_utah_governor_says/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1neyi6s/we_should_put_our_phones_down_utah_governor_says/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 2 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1neyi6s/we_should_put_our_phones_down_utah_governor_says/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://www.mediaite.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/SpencerCox-scaled.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span><a href="https://www.mediaite.com/author/charlie-nash" title="Posts by Charlie Nash">Charlie Nash</a></span><span>Sep 11th, 2025, 10:40 pm </span></p></div><div><p>Utah Gov. <strong>Spencer Cox</strong> urged social media users to put their &ldquo;phones down&rdquo; on Thursday, claiming there was &ldquo;a tremendous amount of disinformation&rdquo; about the assassination of <strong>Charlie Kirk</strong>, with bots &ldquo;from Russia, China, all over the world.&rdquo;</p><p>During a Thursday evening press conference on the investigation into Kirk&rsquo;s murder, Cox said:</p><blockquote><p>I would also just add a word of note for those people who are spending so much time on social media. I think Charlie said it best that when things get bad, we should put our phones down and spend a little time with our families. There is a tremendous amount of disinformation. We are tracking &ndash; our team, the state team, and I&rsquo;m sure the federal team as well &ndash; what we&rsquo;re seeing is our adversaries want violence. China&ndash; we have bots from Russia, China, all over the world that are trying to instil disinformation and encourage violence.</p><p>I would encourage you to ignore those, to turn off those streams, and to spend a little more time with our families. We desperately need some healing. We&rsquo;ll have more to say about that in the days and weeks to come. More than anything, we are going to catch this person.</p></blockquote><p>The killer responsible for Kirk&rsquo;s assassination at Utah Valley University on Wednesday is still at large, with the <a href="https://x.com/FBISaltLakeCity/status/1966320840544227680">FBI</a> urging witnesses to provide videos and any potential tips to the agency.</p><p>The Utah Department of Public Safety <a href="https://www.mediaite.com/crime/officials-release-new-photos-of-person-of-interest-in-charlie-kirk-assassination-wearing-disabled-veterans-shirt/">released</a> photos of a &ldquo;person of interest&rdquo; on Thursday, who could be seen wearing a cap, sunglasses, and a t-shirt that was given to donors by the Disabled Veterans National Foundation.</p><p>Watch above via CNN.</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 14:52:26 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://thehill.com/homenews/house/5498536-clay-higgins-targets-charlie-kirk-killing-celebrators/</link><title>GOP lawmaker seeks lifetime bans for social media users celebrating Kirk's assassination (thehill.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nei6ht/gop_lawmaker_seeks_lifetime_bans_for_social_media/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nei6ht/gop_lawmaker_seeks_lifetime_bans_for_social_media/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1nei6ht/gop_lawmaker_seeks_lifetime_bans_for_social_media/'>Post permalink</a></p></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 01:01:06 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.wired.com/story/right-wing-activists-are-targeting-people-for-allegedly-celebrating-charlie-kirks-death/</link><title>Right-Wing Activists Are Targeting People for Allegedly Celebrating Charlie Kirk's Death (wired.com)</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1neh62x/rightwing_activists_are_targeting_people_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1neh62x/rightwing_activists_are_targeting_people_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 10 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/1neh62x/rightwing_activists_are_targeting_people_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='preview-image'><img src='https://media.wired.com/photos/68c1e61e06538db7e12f69fd/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/pol_charliekirk_AP25253696005520.jpg' /></section><section class='parsed-content'><div><p><span>Far-right influencers and</span> violent extremists are posting identifying details about people they view as celebrating or glorifying <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/charlie-kirk-obituary/">the murder of right-wing activist Charlie Kirk</a>. The campaign has been swift and widespread and has already led to at least one person losing their job and others receiving death threats.</p><p>The people posting the identifying information include Chaya Raichik, who runs the hugely influential, hate-filled LibsofTikTok account on X, <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/trumpworld-tired-of-laura-loomer/">Trump-whisperer Laura Loomer</a>, and <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/proud-boys-comeback-revenge/">former Proud Boy leader Enrique Tarrio</a>.</p><p>A central hub of this activity is a website called Charlie&rsquo;s Murderers, which was registered in the early evening on the day <a href="https://www.wired.com/tag/charlie-kirk/">Kirk</a> was shot and is revealing certain personal information, such as social media usernames and email addresses, of individuals the operators believe were celebrating the horrific murder.</p><p>One of the first names listed on the sites was Rachel Gilmore, an independent journalist at Bubble Pop Media who <a href="https://x.com/atRachelGilmore/status/1965864556745601394">wrote on X</a> that she was &ldquo;terrified to think of how far-right fans of Kirk, aching for more violence, could very well turn this into an even more radicalizing moment. Will they now believe their fears have been proven right and feel they have a right to &lsquo;retaliate,&rsquo; regardless of who actually was behind the initial shooting?&rdquo;</p><p>As <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/far-right-reactions-charlie-kirk-shooting-civil-war/">WIRED reported</a>, this is exactly how much of the far right&mdash;along with Republican lawmakers including President Donald Trump&mdash;did respond to the news, even though no suspect had been arrested and no motive had been revealed.</p><p>For Gilmore, the impact of her inclusion on the website was instant and terrifying.</p><p>&ldquo;This website has me genuinely afraid for my safety,&rdquo; Gilmore tells WIRED. &ldquo;I feel awful for anyone whose name is on it. It&rsquo;s clear that the purpose of the website is to do exactly what the post that landed me on there warned Kirk&rsquo;s supporters might do: retaliate.&rdquo;</p><p>Gilmore has received multiple death and rape threats since the site went live on Wednesday evening. (WIRED reviewed screenshots of emails and direct messages Gilmore has received to verify the threats.) She has not reported the threats to the police yet, she says.</p><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve gotten emails and DMs promising to find out where I live,&rdquo; Gilmore says. &ldquo;I have folks claiming my information is all over 4chan telling me in the same breath that they hope I get &lsquo;raped and killed&rsquo; and telling me to &lsquo;have fun walking the streets of&rsquo; my city, which they name.&rdquo;</p><p>At the time of publication, two dozen people were listed on the site, with many entries including full names, employment details, location, and social media accounts. The site&rsquo;s operators, who are anonymous, claim to have received &ldquo;thousands&rdquo; of submissions. &ldquo;All of them will be reviewed and uploaded shortly,&rdquo; a note on the website reads. &ldquo;This is a permanent archive and will soon contain a search feature.&rdquo;</p><p>&ldquo;Most likely, we'd be happy to answer your questions,&rdquo; the people controlling the website told WIRED in an email. Subsequent emails, though, went unanswered.</p></div><div><p>The website asks people to submit a potential target&rsquo;s full name, location, and employer information, as well as screenshots of incriminating social media posts, via email. An About section on the website, added on Thursday morning, says: &ldquo;This is not a doxxing website. This website is a lawful data aggregator of publicly-available information. It has been created for the purposes of public education.&rdquo;</p><p>It continues: &ldquo;We seek to collect and archive instances of individuals promoting or glorifying of political violence, much like archive.org or archive.is. We firmly denounce all political violence and criminal activity.&rdquo;</p><p>Many of the allegedly incriminating posts WIRED reviewed did not glorify or promote violence. &ldquo;The entire atmosphere has been stoked by conservative media and amplified by MAGA bullshit,&rdquo; reads one Facebook post highlighted by the site.</p><p>&ldquo;And the world kept spinning,&rdquo; another person listed on the site wrote in a Facebook comment, under a post about Kirk&rsquo;s death.</p><p>Quinn Huddleston, another name listed on the site, told WIRED he has received &ldquo;countless messages&rdquo; since his name was published on the site, some urging him to take his own life. Huddleston also says that people have threatened his life, claiming to know where he lives. However, he points out that the information shared on the website was out of date and as a result the threats contained inaccurate information.</p><p>&ldquo;I did not glorify anyone&rsquo;s death,&rdquo; says Huddleston. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t believe political violence is the answer to anything on either side. They took a comment I made prior to [Kirk] even passing and now, as radicals usually do, spin it to work for their agenda, whatever that may be.&rdquo;</p><p>A WIRED review of the social accounts linked to the people listed on the site revealed that the vast majority of them have been either deleted or set to private.</p><p>Many of the names listed on the site have already been shared on social media platforms by prominent figures seeking retribution.</p><p>&ldquo;I will be spending my night making everyone I find online who celebrates his death Famous, so prepare to have your whole future professional aspirations ruined if you are sick enough to celebrate his death,&rdquo; Loomer <a href="https://x.com/LauraLoomer/status/1965915114072101118">wrote on X</a> hours after Kirk&rsquo;s death. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m going to make you wish you never opened your mouth.&rdquo;</p><p>Loomer followed through on her threat in at least one instance, targeting a woman in Arizona who she claimed worked at a kids&rsquo; club in a fitness center. Loomer posted a screenshot of the woman&rsquo;s Instagram account where she wrote: &ldquo;Today&rsquo;s a good day y&rsquo;all&rdquo; under a news story about Kirk&rsquo;s death.</p><p>&ldquo;I hope this dumb bitch is fired,&rdquo; Loomer wrote, alongside a video showing her calling the woman&rsquo;s place of employment and speaking to her manager. &ldquo;I can&rsquo;t imagine somebody that sick celebrating the death of a young father, who has children who are never going to know their father, working at the kids&rsquo; club there,&rdquo; Loomer said during the call. &ldquo;I think it&rsquo;s a risk to the safety of the children.&rdquo;</p></div><div><p>The gym where Loomer claimed the woman worked did not respond to a request for comment. WIRED was unable to contact the woman in question, and her Instagram account appears to have been deleted.</p><p>Loomer did not respond to a request for comment.</p><p>While Loomer was hoping to get someone fired, it appears Raichik succeeded.</p><p>Shortly after she <a href="https://x.com/libsoftiktok/status/1965979194380124377/photo/1">highlighted</a> that the assistant dean at the office of Student Care and Conduct at Middle Tennessee State University wrote on her Facebook page that she had &ldquo;zero sympathy&rdquo; for Kirk, the woman was fired.</p><p>&ldquo;An MTSU employee today offered inappropriate and callous comments on social media concerning the horrific and tragic murder of Charlie Kirk,&rdquo; Sidney McPhee, the school&rsquo;s president, said in a statement posted on the <a href="https://www.mtsu.edu/">university&rsquo;s website</a>. &ldquo;The comments by this employee, who worked in a position of trust directly with students, were inconsistent with our values and have undermined the university&rsquo;s credibility and reputation with our students, faculty, staff and the community at large. This employee has been fired effective immediately.&rdquo;</p><p>Another target of Raichik&rsquo;s was a firefighter at the New Orleans Fire Department who has since deleted her Instagram account and Facebook page. The New Orleans Fire Department did not respond to a request for comment.</p><p>Raichik did not respond to a request for comment.</p><p>&ldquo;The Patriot Oasis,&rdquo; a far-right news account that spreads disinformation, also used its large following to direct threats and hate toward others online. As is typical in situations like this, the account shared inaccurate information about targeted individuals. In one case, the account highlighted a video posted to Instagram by a woman who said that she was &ldquo;really glad Charlie Kirk got himself fucking shot.&rdquo; This woman, the account said, worked at Larkin Community Hospital.</p><p>The hospital was forced to <a href="https://x.com/LARKINHOSPITAL/status/1965993730487296032?s=19">issue a statement</a> clarifying that the woman had completed her residency there in 2018 but has not had any affiliation with the hospital since. Despite this, another far-right account suggested on Instagram that she had been fired.</p><p>The doctor in question did not respond to WIRED requests for comment and appears to have deleted her Instagram account.</p><p>Tarrio, who had his sentence for seditious conspiracy with regards to the January 6 Capitol riot pardoned by Trump earlier this year, targeted a member of staff at a school in Miami, claiming he posted a comment on Instagram that celebrated Kirk&rsquo;s death. &ldquo;He died. Oh well. He ironically promoted gun usage. Karma,&rdquo; the person wrote according to a screenshot shared on X.</p><p>&ldquo;YKWTD,&rdquo; Tarrio posted on X in the early hours of Thursday morning, referring to the phrase &ldquo;you know what to do.&rdquo; The comment was shared alongside a screenshot of the address and phone number of the Miami Country Day School.</p><p>Neither the individual involved nor the school responded to WIRED&rsquo;s request for comment about the threat. Tarrio tells WIRED he is not concerned about threats that people being targeted are receiving and claims he had succeeded in getting five people fired by Thursday afternoon. When asked for details about those people, Tarrio did not provide them.</p><p>The Proud Boys are focusing our efforts into these threats and celebrations,&rdquo; Tarrio says. &ldquo;We will not call for violence, but we will inform their employers of who they have on staff.&rdquo;</p><p>Dozens of other accounts on X, <a href="https://x.com/RealBookerScott/">many of which</a> have <a href="https://x.com/DisrespectedThe">hundreds of thousands</a> of followers, were sharing personal details about other people they saw as celebrating Kirk&rsquo;s murder.</p><p>&ldquo;Someone could get killed or, if the harassment they&rsquo;re receiving is anything like what I&rsquo;ve gotten, even engage in self-harm,&rdquo; Gilmore said. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s sick, it&rsquo;s wrong, and it&rsquo;s terrifying.&rdquo;</p></div></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:22:12 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
