<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://192.168.1.132/?platform=reddit&amp;subreddit=explainlikeimfive&amp;averagePostsPerDay=4&amp;content=0&amp;comments=7&amp;view=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>/r/explainlikeimfive</title><description>Hot posts in /r/explainlikeimfive (roughly 4 posts per day)</description><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/</link><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 14:51:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Upvote RSS</generator><image><url>http://192.168.1.132//app/cache/images/a-thumbs-redditmedia-com-KZESzgF91cP3KEAR29JhCFmX0zxsPgY1sYhv7XCtiW0-144x400.png</url><title>/r/explainlikeimfive</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/</link><width>144</width><height>144</height></image><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/</link><title>ELI5 why are road fatalities per capita in the US so high?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>According to the Wikipedia page, the US is 111 out of 191 in the world for road fatalities per capita, lower numbers being better: <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_traffic-related_death_rate">https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_traffic-related_death_rate</a></p><p>This is  <em>way</em> worse than basically all Western nations. It&#39;s worse than even the poorest European countries, and at the same level as Bangladesh and Syria. (China, Brazil and South Africa are still worse, however)</p><p>Maybe the US is more car dependent, and more people own cars? But Canada is probably similar enough and it is in 32nd place.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Just because the US is a car reliant country doesn&#39;t mean most of us know how to actually drive properly</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5e0ie/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The metric you are looking at is deaths per capita, this means any country with a high rate of driving will have high results. </p><p>In your same link you can look at deaths per kilometer driven. The only problem with that data is it only lists 23 countries of which the US is #8. Slightly better than countries like Mexico, South Korea, and New Zealand, and slight worse than countries like France, Australia, and Canada.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5fu2k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>More people driving in general is the easiest answer, but it has a lot of cultural elements that affect how we approach driving and road infrastructure.</p><p>In my opinion, the biggest issues informing how policy is shaped around driving is that <strong>people need to drive to get to work, and drive to buy things</strong>. These two issues are critical to our economy, meaning the barrier to entry for driving has to be relatively low to not impede people&#39;s ability to act as consumers and a workforce. </p><p>Directly connected to this, we allow many people who probably should not be driving to drive. The very old and the very young stick out in particular. Because cars are required to get to work, there is pressure for people to continue to drive without a license if it is suspended or they don&#39;t have one to begin with. </p><p>Downstream of this, roads have to be designed to let people with cars get from point a to point b expidently. Many stretches of roads have relatively high speed limits for the type of traffic traversing it. This inherently makes changing lanes and attempting to turn dangerous.</p><p>Further down from that, we also have to think about suburban sprawl.  Many suburban and suburbanizing-rural areas are covered in Stroads. Stroads are extremely dangerous for pedestrians and drivers. They have very high collision rates for both parties as they are high speed but designed for local areas rather than traveling between distant places.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5ga98/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because the US is built around cars and driving everywhere. There is very little public transportation,  mostly located in the biggest cities.  And even there a lot of people still choose to drive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5emrq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s our culture. </p><ul><li>we drive more</li><li>we drive faster</li><li>we let ourselves be more distracted </li><li>we drive under the influence of more substances</li><li>we believe ourselves to be more skilled drivers than we actually are, so we blame the problem on other drivers instead of prioritizing safety</li></ul></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5fe79/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You are looking at fatalities, not accidents. The US has a lot of dumb drivers (everywhere does), but the high speed limits and relatively less traffic mean people drive faster and if an accident happens, speed kills.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5eqwk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A lot of it has to do with the size of the vehicles as well. Not many places will allow the super compensator 350 with dual axles and a semi on the road.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nlh1we/eli5_why_are_road_fatalities_per_capita_in_the_us/nf5f393/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 03:42:29 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/</link><title>ELI5. Why don't brain biopsies kill you?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>ELI5. Basically the title. How do brain biopsies not further damage people? How does it not hurt people more? Does the brain grow back if missing small piece?</p><p>Thanks!</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Hi there.  Person who has received a brain biopsy here. The truth is they only need a handful of cells to confirm a diagnosis, and typically the cells they need to biopsy are not brain cells but tumor cells, so the potential for harm is already greatly reduced. </p><p>Put it this way; if you can DNA test cells from your cheek with a cotton swab it ought to be similarly easy to get tumor cells surgically on a probe.  The difficulty isn’t in collecting the cells but in getting there safely.  In my case the tumor was in my midbrain so they had to tunnel through brain matter to get there.  They use a very thin needle and CT scans to get a 3D image of the brain then map out the least destructive path avoiding critical regions and blood vessels. The brain can withstand such micro punctures with little to no damage.  So they find the best approach to the target tissue and slowly insert the probe/needle using stereotactic (precise, 3D modeling based) guidance and remotely controlled robotic equipment.  </p><p>To further protect the brain, they attach a metal frame to the patient’s skull, completely immobilizing it to the operating table so there is no chance for movement.  In my personal experience, that’s the worst part, because they literally screw the frame into the bone of your skull to keep it still.  Sorry for the graphic explanation, but it’s the truth.</p><p>Granted, it’s still brain surgery, but it’s not like they’re excising portions of the brain.  </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf2zsrd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s a tiny bit that&#39;s taken, think like having a scrape on your knee. And yes, it is not without risk. But if it&#39;s being done, risk of not doing it is much higher. No, it doesn&#39;t grow back.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf2xxu4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m a neuropathologist, meaning my job is to look at brain biopsies all day long.</p><p>Saying &quot;brain biopsies are small,&quot; while true, isn&#39;t really the answer.</p><p>Saying &quot;the tissue they take is diseased&quot; also isn&#39;t really the answer. Many biopsies, by the nature of brain tumors, also take some normal brain with them.</p><p>The main reason is, simply, there are large areas of the brain that can be removed without causing serious problems. The brain has a lot of redundancy and interconnectedness.</p><p>There are some distinct areas of the brain that, when damaged, will kill you. In general, these are in the deeper regions of the brain that control things like consciousness, breathing, etc. Surgeons like to stay away from these areas.</p><p>There are other large areas of the brain that, if damaged, can cause severe consequences like paralysis, memory loss, language impairment, etc., but will not kill you. Surgeons also like to avoid these.</p><p>The main risk of a brain biopsy is hitting a critical structure that will cause a neurologic deficit. Typically, the main risk of death during brain surgery is damage to a vessel that causes a bleed or a stroke.</p><p>Some surgeries, especially in young people, can remove enormous parts of the brain with little consequence. In the past, neurosurgeons have attempted to remove an entire half of the brain to treat certain tumors. Although very morbid, patients could still live with half a brain.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf5p81v/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Pretty much every surgery is a controlled wound. The big thing that makes a surgery special is the number of specialized tools and experience needed to make sure the wound is as small and controlled as possible while still doing whatever the surgeon is trying to do.</p><p>A brain biopsy is a perfect example. Whatever is damaging / afflicting the brain is <em>probably</em> worse than the surgery on its own, so by doing a biopsy you can minimize the amount  of damage for the full treatment.</p><p>The biopsy itself is small enough that it doesn&#39;t destroy the brain to a degree where you would die -- but, it&#39;s also really important to consider <em>where</em> a biopsy might be taking place, because that will impact the net effect of the surgery to the brain, surrounding skull, and general tissue.</p><p>Asking &quot;why don&#39;t brain biopsies kill you&quot; is similar to asking &quot;why wouldn&#39;t a blood draw take all your blood?&quot; The answer is always that the damage isn&#39;t enough to be lethal, and blood loss &amp; tissue damage are controlled as much as reasonably possible.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf2ydr2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As long as no vital parts are damaged you&#39;d be surprised what kind of trauma to the brain people can survive. Hell we used to stick ice picks into people&#39;s brains as a mental health remedy lol.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf36dm4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Surgeons take a rice-grain sized sample through a tiny hole using image guidance (not a big chunk). Beforehand they map the brain with MRI or CT and plan a path that dodges speech, movement and major blood vessels. During the biopsy a rigid frame or camera guidance keeps the needle on that safe path. The brain itself doesn&#39;t feel pain, so with the scalp and skull numbed or under anesthesia the procedure isn&#39;t felt the way you&#39;d expect.</p><p>Removing a tiny bit doesn&#39;t make a hollow that &quot;kills&quot; tissue around it. The spot bleeds a little then seals, immune cells clean up and scar tissue fills in. Neurons don&#39;t grow back like skin or liver, but the brain has redundancy and can usually compensate for such a small sample. There are risks like bleeding or seizures, which is why it&#39;s only done when the benefit of getting a diagnosis outweights those risks.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf3gls9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Neurosurgeon here.Most of the brain is considered “non-eloquent” which means that when parts of them are removed there is no obvious outward neurological deficit or stroke-like symptom that results. There are two types of biopsies - one uses a small needle that’s inserted to suck up a little rice grain sized piece of brain and the other is a surgery that drills a piece of your bone off through a bigger incision to sample a piece of the brain. Sometimes these biopsies actually involve sampling the bone or the covering of the brain which doesn’t damage the brain at all.</p><p>When we do a biopsy we tend to aim for safer areas of the brain that are “non-eloquent” such as the right frontal lobe or the very front parts of the left frontal lobe. We try to avoid places that would mess up vision, movement, sensation, and language.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl5mpq/eli5_why_dont_brain_biopsies_kill_you/nf6rd0h/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:19:39 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/</link><title>ELI5: How do TSA/customs agents open our luggage with their special keys? What's stopping thieves or criminals from making the same keys?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Nothing. You can buy TSA master keys on ebay. This is why many people consider TSA approved locks to be inherently insecure.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2pyqy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Short answer: nothing. You can get TSA keys from eBay and people have been using those to loot luggage.</p><p>This is the same as “back doors for good guys” in encryption - except that it is much easier for bad guys to peek into data packages than into suitcases.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2q7qc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The reality is that thieves or criminals don&#39;t need a TSA key to open your luggage because zippers are extremely unsecure. Any piece of luggage with a zipper can be popped open in seconds with a standard ball point pen. Just push the pen through the zipper and pull apart the gap that it created.</p><p>Those padlocks do add a little bit of security in that they prevent people from quickly rifling through your luggage and then zipping it back up with no outward signs of tampering.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2r3q0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><blockquote><p>What&#39;s stopping thieves or criminals from making the same keys?</p></blockquote><p>Absolutely nothing. </p><p>Good luck. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2qjbz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You can buy the keys online for a couple of bucks. There’s 7 TSA master keys.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2pys5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The only real difference is access to your luggage. </p><p>Most people dont use the locks unless they are travelling. And when you&#39;re travelling, the only people who really have access are yourself and airline/airport workers.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2qkiv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you really want your luggage secured, you need to pack a gun in a hard well locked case, you can pack valuables in the same case.<a href="https://www.tsa.gov/travel/transporting-firearms-and-ammunition">https://www.tsa.gov/travel/transporting-firearms-and-ammunition</a>No really. They will inspect your firearm, and all contents of your luggage in front of you. Then it needs to be securely locked without a TSA lock. And they put a special label on it as well. It will not be opened during transport. If it, report it, as there are heavy penalties.</p><p>I&#39;ve heard a starter pistol will work for this as well, if you don&#39;t want to own a real gun.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl4rd5/eli5_how_do_tsacustoms_agents_open_our_luggage/nf2vt4k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 19:45:32 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/</link><title>ELI5 are there muscles that are automatically ripped?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Are there any muscles that you use all the time without knowing like your heart? And does that mean they are super ripped all the time?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Depends on the person, but some people’s calves are WAY stronger than they realize if they walk a lot day to day</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/nf1veww/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>AFAIK, the anus is a muscle that is working constantly without your own input, just like your heart. The purpose is obvious, to keep the Nutella in the jar. When you poop you use muscles that basically counter that muscle to force it out. So yeah, you&#39;re ripped down there...</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/nf25yk4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Our jaws are surprisingly strong. Seemingly compared to other apes aside from the gibbon we have a significantly larger bite force</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/nf1x6tt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I mean muscles are muscles. &quot;Ripped&quot; is really just referring to muscle <em>definition</em> which comes from the lack of fat on top of the muscles. </p><p>Look at Brad Pitt in Fight Club. He&#39;s honestly pretty thin. His muscles are not huge, but he is definitely ripped because he got his body fat so low. A lot of normal looking people have similar muscles underneath. Fat people have enormous leg muscles, but they don&#39;t look &quot;ripped&quot; because you see the fat and not the muscle.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/nf1xl9q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Your diaphragm and small muscles between your ribs work 24/7 to keep you breathing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/nf211wd/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You need progressive overload to make muscles bigger. You body decides to make muscles bigger when they are consistently challenged, particularly in the stretched position. </p><p>If you get a new job at an oil rig or something, the first day you&#39;ll be sore. The second day, you&#39;ll still be sore. By the end of the week your body will be like &quot;okay bro if this is what we&#39;re doing now I&#39;ll use some of the food you&#39;re giving me to make the muscles you keep tiring out stronger&quot;. Once that gets too easy, you&#39;ll need to move even more stuff at work to start the process again and get stronger still.</p><p>Therefore there are no muscles that are &quot;ripped&quot; just be passively using them every day. They must be challenged to get bigger and stronger. Your body is strategically lazy. It&#39;s not going to waste potentially scarce resources building muscle it will have to send blood and oxygen and nutrients to all the time if you haven&#39;t proven to it that you&#39;ll use it or that you&#39;ll have a consistent stream of resources to keep them.</p><p>Even muscles that you may think could be automatically strong, like your heart. If you don&#39;t exercise, your heart is probably very weak, even though it has (hopefully) been working non-stop since before you were born</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/nf275c9/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Your abdominal muscles and obliques grow a bit, but really not as much as you think. If you are intermediate gym goer or even advanced weightlifter but just don&#39;t care about abs, you don&#39;t need to really train them at all.</p><p>This means everyone is carrying a 6 pack quite comfortable. The difference between seeing and not seeing it is body fat percentage.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nl0qui/eli5_are_there_muscles_that_are_automatically/nf1yfih/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 16:45:52 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/</link><title>ELI5 how rice-cookers make better rice than just boiling the rice in a pan?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I understand the benefit of the rice cooker to keep rice warm after it’s cooked, but I just fail to see how the <em>cooking</em> differs between a rice-cooker and a basic pan.</p><p>Rice + boiling water (in a pan) = Rice + boiling water (in a rice-cooker)</p><p>What am I missing? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>A rice cooker automatically stops the heat once the rice is done (by detecting the temperature raising above 100C, meaning all water has been absorbed and boiled)</p><p>This is all done without lifting the lid, which means the steam doesn&#39;t escape and the rice can cook with it</p><p>You can do all the same things in a pan, it&#39;s just less consistent</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1favo/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A rice cooker uses the fact that when there is water in the pot, the temperature of the pot cannot rise above boiling point.</p><p>Once the water is fully absorbed by the rice, the temperature rises again, a thermostat detects the rise (usually using a special magnet), and it stops cooking.</p><p>This is the difference.</p><p>A pot on a stove you can do the same, just not as accurately. So you may have almost cooked rice with gloopy water at the bottom, or overcooked rice without water but starting to catch and burn.</p><p>A rice cooker is simple (one moving part) and reliable (using physics to stop cooking) for perfect rice every time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1hc13/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p><a href="https://youtu.be/RSTNhvDGbYI?si=nbQWI4vZRjRk40Rv">https://youtu.be/RSTNhvDGbYI?si=nbQWI4vZRjRk40Rv</a></p><p>Tech Connections has a great video on how they work</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1ieqx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Basic rice cookers don&#39;t make better rice than just boiling in a pan, as long as we&#39;re comparing apples to apples: same rice/water ratio, same heat output to the pan/pot, <strong>same distribution of heat</strong>.</p><p>That last one is particularly important. Boiling something over a gas stove puts a <strong>lot</strong> of energy into the bottom of the pot (and usually around the sides) very quickly. A good rice cooker will have a heating element that heats the bottom and sides of the pot a bit more evenly, and a bit more slowly. This prevents rice at the bottom of the pan from receiving too much heat energy too quickly, which would cause it to dry out and become hard. A good rice cooker excels at producing cooked rice with a consistent texture.</p><p>I&#39;m sure fancier rice cookers go even further with heat cycles / cooking times, but the basics remain the same. The more evenly distributed the heat in your rice/water is, the more evenly the rice will cook.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1ftmv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I&#39;m not sure it makes better rice, but it is foolproof. Set it and forget it</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1gldl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In addition to making consistent rice and being able to keep it warm for hours, to me the number one advantage of a rice cooker is you start it and walk away. You’re not standing at the stove watching it, you can do something else. Some fancy ones even let you do things like load it up in the morning and set so that rice is ready (not start, but ready) at a specific time, like right at dinner time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf2dwvn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Rice cookers use a very simple system to detect when the moisture has dropped enough and the rice is cooked, but not overcooked. This switches the heat down to a low level that keeps it warm. </p><p>Between perfect timing and tight temperature control, this can make better rice (and defiantly easier rice) then most people can make in a pan.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkycuy/eli5_how_ricecookers_make_better_rice_than_just/nf1foti/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:22:04 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/</link><title>ELI5: why is Saffron so expensive in the modern age?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I just came back from a supermarket and i saw that Saffron was ~26,000 USD per Pound(~57,000 USD per KG). I did a quick comparison against gold, and it&#39;s almost half the value(~58,000 USD per Pound or ~128,000 USD per KG). I can understand how, in the past, it may have been expensive with spice trade stuff. </p><p>Why is it so absurdly expensive in this day and age? Even more important, what&#39;s keeping it from being mass-produced like other spices? Thanks!</p><p>Edit: wow! Lots of responses really quick, thank you all! </p><p>As a Tldr; for people who just want to read and go, basically it is a very fragile crocus flower that requires very specific environmental conditions and produces a significantly small yield per plant. Automation is virtually impossible because of damage and expensive residue. There&#39;s a lot of cool info in the comments about the specifics.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>One flower produces 3 threads of saffron and needs to be taken by hand. It is a delicate long process. I just looked it up and it would take 75,000 flowers to make one lb. That is a huge amount of land and time.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqyq1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It can&#39;t be machine farmed, so people have to individually pick the stigmas of the saffron flower. Human labour still costs the same as in the past.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqhuh/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Saffron is the dried stigma and styles of the saffron crocus flower. The only way to harvest it is by hand, and you get very little saffron from each plant. Therefore, it is hard to produce and harvest in large quantities and very valuable by weight. </p><p>But practically speaking, recipes don&#39;t use very much saffron, so it isn&#39;t really as expensive as it seems. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexr0ij/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Its a flower, and of the flower the red stigma from the flower is the actual saffron.  Each flower has 3(?) stigma im pretty sure.   So 1 flower, produces 3 very small, very light, very fragile things that we call saffron the spice.  Its just super hard to grow a lot of it....</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqrz7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because it takes a ridiculous number of crocus plants to make a tiny amount, and its such a small amount that we can&#39;t really make a system to automate it much because even the amount that would be left on the machine itself would be worth a fortune.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexqtx6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s not that it is a particularly hard crop to produce. The problem is on the manual labor required to process it.</p><p>The saffron strands you see are actualy the stigma from the crocus flower. They have to be handpicked from a flower, then dried, then they are graded (yes, there are saffron grades, and they are differents based on place of origin... Spain has its own grades and middle eastern countries have another. They are somewhat aligned)</p><p>When you take into consideration that a gram of saffron requires MANY stigmas, and that they have to be handpicked, the labor costs is what makes the final product so expensive.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/nexsnnl/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s because saffron only grows in specific conditions and is astoundingly labor intensive to harvest.</p><p>Saffron the spice is the <a href="https://cdn.britannica.com/25/203625-050-64EDAEEE/Saffron-crocus-bloom-stigmas-flower-saffron-spice.jpg">stigma</a> of the saffron flower. Saffron flowers are difficult to grow, and they only bloom once per year. Each flower only produces three stigma, known as threads, of saffron. It takes approximately 150 to 170 saffron flowers to produce a single gram, and a pound (just over 450 grams) requires approximately <em>70,000 to 75,000</em> saffron flowers.</p><p>Saffron is also very delicate, it must be picked by hand. That means that one gram of saffron requires a person to carefully and individually hand pick the threads from 150 flowers. It is also incredibly sensitive to temperature, even the heat of the sun causes the flowers to wilt and the saffron to die. This means that all of this harvesting has to occur early in the morning.</p><p>This makes it a very labor intensive spice to grow, and makes it essentially impossible to mass produce like other spices.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkgvzk/eli5_why_is_saffron_so_expensive_in_the_modern_age/next77r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:22:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/</link><title>ELI5: why do horses get shot once they have a broken leg? Or is this just a joke?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>There&#39;s no humane way to keep a horse&#39;s weight off a broken leg so it can heal. They can&#39;t lay down for that long without damaging their internal organs, and a sling or cast is a struggle when you can&#39;t explain to the animal what&#39;s going on.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0cud/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Horse&#39;s legs do not really recover from breaks.  Sadly, it&#39;s better to end their suffering.  A prize winning horse broke his leg and they supported him in a sling so they could still collect semen, but that&#39;s no life.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/newzszz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Typically horses are euthanized, not shot, but before humane euthanasia was common, shooting was the way too quickly and suffering of an animal. </p><p>Because of their anatomy, horses generally do not do well healing from a broken leg.  Horses are built to be on their feet the vast majority of the time, they only lay down for short periods for deep sleep.  It is damaging to their body to lay down for a long period of time.  Horses also carry 70% of their body weight on their front legs, so if you have one broken leg, the rest of that weight gets shifted to the other leg which it is not equipped to handle.  In the famous case of Barbaro, he had to be put down because he developed lameness in the supporting leg despite their attempts to save him. It is also extremely mentally damaging for a horse to be kept confined for long periods of time that it would take to heal a broken leg. They are a prey animal whose main defense is to run away and being unable to do so causes them extreme stress.  They also do not have any muscle below the knee, which means less blood supply and slower healing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0ngz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>ELI5: <a href="https://thunderdungeon.com/2025/06/15/fun">Horses are incredibly fragile creatures who exist despite God’s grace.</a> Horses are often put down after a broken leg for a number of reasons. The bigs are that</p><p>A) horse bones are comparatively light for such a heavy creature. Sometimes when a horse’s legs break it just <em>shatters</em> to the point that it can’t be set.</p><p>B) horses can’t support the weight on the other three legs while the horse recovers. The horse can develop laminitis, which damages the other three legs immensely, so now you have an even more injured horse. </p><p>C) horses can’t really lay down for long periods of time since they’re so heavy (they develop basically bed sores) so you can’t even put a horse to rest while the legs recover.</p><p>Essentially, horses are often euthanized because once a leg is broken you can’t guarantee them a quality of life.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex15l8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Horses depend on movement for all kinds of things like proper sleep, circulation, digestion, etc. if you try to immobilize a horse for a protracted period of time, all kinds of other health problems start happening, including life-threatening conditions.</p><p>You can&#39;t explain to a horse that it has to lie down and not move around for the next several weeks, so the only option is to tranquilize it, which incurs other risks.</p><p>It is possible to suspend a horse in a sling, and this has been done, mostly for stallions that the owners want to wring breeding fees from, but it&#39;s not always successful and it&#39;s hard to argue that it&#39;s humane.</p><p>TLDR: Horses are supposed to move around almost constantly and all kinds of things stop working when they don&#39;t.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0ucr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because horses aren&#39;t built to not be on their feet for long periods of time. While you can force them in a sling to holds them up off the ground that has other issues with it.</p><p>I&#39;m the end it&#39;s just easier on the horse to end it&#39;s life then make it suffer for the rest of it with a leg that isn&#39;t as well of as the other</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex0f1f/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I haven&#39;t seen this mentioned yet, so:</p><p>Horse legs are evolved from fingers. Like actually. Instead of developing longer arms, they got longer fingers to walk on. Their hoof is a fingernail. Or toenail. This is part of why they are so delicate compared to other animals.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nkdhbs/eli5_why_do_horses_get_shot_once_they_have_a/nex3wtm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 22:15:54 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/</link><title>ELI5 Is 20km/hr the top pace a human can run at distance?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Watching world athletics championship and was wondering..if marathon runners can run at approx 20km/hr for 2 hours why is pace for the 5000m only about 21-23 km hour (13-14 mins) ? Given the huge difference in distance I would expect that for the much shorter distance they could run faster than that. At what distance does human speed start to exponentially taper off? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>At about 400m.  Thats about the limit of anaerobic running.  </p><p>Below that your muscles can operate at an unsustainable level of oxygen consumption.  </p><p>Above that your lungs and blood need to be able to keep up with the oxygen consumption rate of your muscles.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevah1x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Two things.</p><p>First, a 5k is still mostly aerobic. Once you&#39;re past a couple of minutes, speed is capped by how much oxygen you can deliver and how efficiently you run, not by raw sprint power. Elites can hold roughly 80-85% of their max aerobic output for a marathon and about 95-100% for a 5k, so the 5k ends up only a bit faster. That&#39;s why world-best speeds are around 21km/h for the marathon and about 24km/h for 5000m, not double.</p><p>Second, championship 5ks are tactical. Packs jog-and-surge and then kick, so the average pace looks closer to marathon pace than a flat-out record attempt.</p><p>There isn&#39;t a single distance where speed suddenly falls off. Human speed follows a smooth power-duration curve. It drops quickly from sprints to the first minute or two, then eases down more gradually from 1500m through 10k to the marathon as you move deeper into purely aerobic territory.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevajuf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I know for Athletics training the furthest the sprinters ever ran was 600m. And even over 400m you will be ever so slightly slower in the second half of the race. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevayd6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s hard to put a hard cap on a biological benchmark but seeing as how world class athletes are meant to be the best functioning humans in their fields, those numbers can be safely considered as the closest to it.</p><p>Worth mentioning that our strength isn&#39;t that we can run fast (many animals can reach much higher speeds), it&#39;s that we can run continuously. Sweating is an absolutely broken mechanic that allowed us to maintain those relatively slow speeds for <em>hours</em>, which is uniquely a human thing because most animals can only sprint in short bursts.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevaxgm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Muscles need energy. This energy cam come in two main ways.</p><p>1) Breathing energy (aerobic), which is limited by the sugar your body can supply and your overall fitness.</p><p>2) Hold-your-breath energy (anaerobic), which can last for just about a minute and is limited by how strong your muscles, tendons and bones are.</p><p>So if the exercise is short enough for you to hold your breath the whole time, you can do a LOT more.</p><p>But even the best athletes can&#39;t break the laws of physics. Having 2 legs is great for running efficiently, but terrible for max speed. We&#39;re just not springy enough to get too much faster.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevz14w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>By that logic, at 30 meters they should be able to run at about 700km/h? Speed doesn’t really scale with distance - the limitations of muscle/bone/metabolism applies whatever the distance</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/neva8b3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The answers mentioning oxygen levels are all great but you also have to consider that human speed is biomechanically limited so far at about 45km/h (a bit less was peak speed for Usain Bolt when setting his 100m WR). </p><p>Oxygen levels explain how that scales down on other distances. At 200m in 19’’19  it’s about 41/42 km/h. At 400 is more like 37. At 800 30/31. You see how that goes down relatively quick. These are average speed rather than peak speeds but the longer the race the closer those are.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk5kd4/eli5_is_20kmhr_the_top_pace_a_human_can_run_at/nevdm7x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:51:56 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/</link><title>ELI5: why do athletes specifically eat bananas for quick fuel?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Why bananas and not oranges or a watermelon?</p><p>Or a chocolate chip cookie?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Bananas are full of potassium along with some other nutrients. They are quite nicely wrapped in a non messy container that does not need tools to open.<br/>I work as a medic for cycling events and anytime I stop for a rider with issues I hand them a banana and a bottle of water. Even if the issue is a chain problem, they still need the banana.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4m0u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>As my college wrestling coach said</p><p>&#39;Bananas are the best pre-workout food. They taste the same going down as when they come back up. &quot;</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nevblxy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Imagine trying to eat a banana compared to an orange or watermelon, from scratch.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4g3u/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>banana:<br/>doesn&#39;t make a mess with all the juices like both your fruit options<br/>doesn&#39;t need a knife to eat/prepare like a watermelon<br/>doesn&#39;t take a long time to peel like an orange<br/>doesn&#39;t melt in the sun like the cookie</p><p>another snack in this same category would be an apple, but if you need to eat fast because your break is short, you would probably be faster with a banana.</p><p>I don&#39;t know much about the nutritional benefits of a banana, my arguments are all based on practicality.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev5baz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It&#39;s a good mix of easily digestible energy (carbs) and potassium (electrolyte for muscle function) plus it&#39;s weiner shaped making them a little horny which can help athletes like me at least.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4o2w/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Have you ever seen a monkey get a cramp? No?</p><p>Do you know why? Because they eat banana.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev5yvz/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Bananas have both simple and complex carbohydrates which give you both the quick energy of simple sugars with longer lasting burn of starches.  Add in <del>Vitamins K,</del> potassium and the vitamins C and B6 and they&#39;re quite good for rejuvenating strained muscles as well.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nk4shi/eli5_why_do_athletes_specifically_eat_bananas_for/nev4slm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:09:11 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/</link><title>ELI5- Why do a lot of kids start out blonde and then become brunettes as they get older?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>This is pretty common but why?! </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Kids are often born with lighter hair because their bodies aren’t producing much melanin (the pigment that gives hair its colour) yet. As they grow, the genes that control melanin production kick in more strongly, so their hair gradually darkens. That’s why a lot of blond kids turn into brunettes as they get older, it’s basically genetics catching up</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/nesg5k4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They have the instructions to build the melanin molecule but they don’t actually start production until they are older. Then later in life they’ll stop producing melanin and their hair will go gray.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/neslnib/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Just a note, this happens with eye color as well. A lot of babies born with blue eyes end up with other colors once they age a bit. I can imagine a lot of brown-eyed, brunette couples out there freaking out a bit when they get a little Aryan surprise.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/nessyf8/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>And why does the reverse happen too, but rarer? Example: Pewdiepie’s son Björn came out with brown hair just for a bit, now blonde</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/net04f2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So just like your skin, your hair contains melanin.  You know the stuff that dictates your skin color.  </p><p>So when you&#39;re young, you produce less melanin.  When you get older, you produce more.</p><p>Your genes also dictate how much melanin you produce and when it changes.  </p><p>Environmental factors also play into this.  Sun exposure can cause an overproduction of melanin.  As well as exposure to hard water, chemicals and product buildup.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/neshkyy/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>My son, as I expected from his genetics, was born with a thick head of black hair. It...lightened. He was a redhead briefly as a one year old and now he&#39;s a kindergartener with auburn hair. Very odd. Every other kid I know started light and darkened as they grew!</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/netjn3q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I have some blonde streaks in my hair that never turned brown. They are now turning grey.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njro2v/eli5_why_do_a_lot_of_kids_start_out_blonde_and/netln33/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:13:28 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/</link><title>ELI5: How does my phone know where I am even without GPS turned on?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Sometimes my phone shows my location on apps like maps or weather, even when I’ve got GPS off. How’s it figuring out where I am? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Triangulating between 3 nearest cell towers if not on wifi.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqib5y/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Your phone&#39;s data works by contacting nearby cell towers. By measuring the signal strength from nearby towers, it can place you at a certain distance from those towers. If there&#39;s three or more towers in range, then it can use triangulation to provide a rough estimate of your location.</p><p>If you&#39;re on wifi, then the IP address assigned to the wifi can give a rough estimate of your location; some networks have more-precisely identified wifi, like a store.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqihm7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It can use several network methods: Wi-Fi positioning, cell tower triangulation or Bluetooth beacons.</p><p>But without those it works it out using two things: your last GPS signal and internal hardware.</p><p>Most modern smartphones come equipped with two pieces of hardware: an accelerometer and a gyroscope. Using that, your phone knows which direction you&#39;re going (gyroscope) and the distance you&#39;ve travelled based on your acceleration (accelerometer).</p><p>Knowing that and your initial position, it will do the math and give you an approximate location.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqj203/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Cell towers and triangulation. WiFi and triangulation. I bet you could point the camera and it could work it out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqihog/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Assuming you can turn off the actual GPS chip, and not just toggle “Location Services” which should disable location for all or selected app…</p><p>Location services in phones use GPS, Bluetooth, WiFi, and cellular networks to triangulate your position.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqisrx/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Phones that have their GPS on will find local WIFI networks and send the routers MAC address to the company (Apple, Google) to be added to a database. </p><p>Then when a phone without GPS enabled is near it can get the router’s MAC address and query the database to see where it is at.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqjirn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Your phone can take a good stab at where you are based on where it last knew you were and use things like the accelerometer to figure out where you have moved since then.  It can also use various network devices, which it knows the location of, to get an estimate of where you are.</p><p>From a network perspective, I used to work for a company that could locate any given phone provided it could talk to enough towers. Using the difference in time it took a signal to reach each given tower, you can draw some parabolas and they&#39;d all intersect at your position.  This is called UTDOA.  It was used primarily for E911 implementation for providers that didn&#39;t want to rely on the phone reporting its location.  It was <em>expensive</em> though, and last I knew, most companies had drop using the technology.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1njittv/eli5_how_does_my_phone_know_where_i_am_even/neqj9rv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 22:32:37 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/</link><title>ELI5 Why did audio jack never change through the years when all other cables for consumer electronics changed a lot?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Bought new expensive headphones and it came with same cable as most basic stuff from 20 years ago</p><p>Meanwhile all other cables changes. Had vga and dvi and the 3 color a/v cables. Now it’s all hdmi. </p><p>Old mice and keyboards cables had special variants too that I don’t know the name of until changing to usb and then going through 3 variants of usb. </p><p>Charging went through similar stuff, with non standard every manufacturer different stuff until usb came along and then finally usb type c standardization. </p><p>Soundbars had a phase with optical cables before hdmi arc.</p><p>But for headphones, it’s been same cable for decades. Why?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It does not need to deliver power or data beyond a simple electrical wave.  So really no need to.  It was robust and had a low impedance (added by the connector) and had zero issues with crosstalk.  No need to reinvent the wheel unless it can’t move the new truck anymore basically.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1gmw/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The only thing a headphone cable needs to transmit is an audio signal and what we got didn&#39;t need improving. </p><p>Video cables transmitted data differently or at high bitrates/ data rates, etc... Headphone jacks didn&#39;t need any of that. </p><p>Otherwise, there are many variants of headphone jacks. Though, most of them are for add-ons like an inline controller or microphone.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1k3t/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It did change.</p><p>The first ones (which I believe were first used in telephone exchange facilities in the late 1800s) were 1/4” (6.35mm) jacks.</p><p>These are still often used in pro audio because they are stronger.</p><p>The 1/8” (3.5mm) jack was developed about a century later in the 1950s as devices got smaller and the big jacks were too big to fit.</p><p>They still persist because they do the job and most devices are still thicker than 1/8”.</p><p>Anything smaller (or just as another option) can use Bluetooth anyway. </p><p>You can deliver audio on anything, usb, wireless, jack, lighting cable.</p><p>Standards are just fashion basically, and the jack is an “old reliable” like blue jeans.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo49c7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>1) It&#39;s inexpensive.</p><p>2) most other connections are intended to be digital, whereas a headphone jack is typically analog, going to analog headphones. If the cable transmitted a digital signal, then the DAC would have to be in the headphones, making them heavier, more expensive, and needing power (which could be transmitted through the same data cable, but it&#39;s just not needed with the headphone jack.</p><p>3) It&#39;s ultra-low latency.</p><p>4) It&#39;s durable as heck.</p><p>5) A good percentage of people who buy expensive headphones want them to work with high-end gear, including vintage high-end gear. And they all used analog headphone jacks.</p><p>The things that you&#39;d gain by switching to other technologies wouldn&#39;t really benefit a headphone user.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1vzu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Brah, 20 years?</p><p>Musical instrument cables have not changed in almost 100 years. There has basically only been one design.</p><p>Why? Because it just has to work, and musicians don&#39;t want to fuck around with a new cable every 5 years. </p><p>It&#39;s pretty awesome. They pretty much perfected the electric guitar seventy years ago, and you can still take one from 1955 and plug it into a new amp or whatever.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo7vmq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The jack now includes the microphone which used to require a separate plug. So while the jack looks the same it isn&#39;t. Also, audio is now available through Bluetooth, Wifi or USB cable, so the technology has not stood still.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo1ntg/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It did change but not on most consumer grade headphones. There&#39;s XLR, Pentaconn, 5 pin din, 6.35mm, 3.5mm and others. The difference in headphone cables and your examples is that those are digital connections being used for digital audio transfer, headphones are analogue. </p><p>If you look at a pair of headphones that can use a cable for digital audio you&#39;ll find they changed over the years too. Micro USB, USB C, Lightning, etc. </p><p>Perhaps a useful comparison is looking at a wall outlet or cigarette lighter plug in a car. They&#39;ve largely been unchanged in decades.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj6ncn/eli5_why_did_audio_jack_never_change_through_the/neo38o2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 13:01:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/</link><title>ELI5: how does Ozempic (or other weight loss jabs) work?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Is it that they just suppress appetite? Or do they help in another way to lose weight? </p><p>Say someone who is not on ozempic (A) makes sure to eat the exact same amount as someone who is taking it (B), would it achieve the same results had A been taking the jab? </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>A lot of good answers so far but a lot of people are ignoring your specific question about comparing two people with the same caloric intake.</p><p>From what I’ve researched and understand, more or less they’d look the same if they at the same thing with one person using ozempic to curb the appetite.</p><p>It’s just that for someone who’s used to eating a lot more, having to eat that low caloric intake is suddenly is unbearable. Like constant anger, pain in the stomach levels of hunger. It takes so much willpower to go from eating 3000+ calories a day to &lt;1200 calories a day.</p><p>Ozempic makes it almost effortless. You can eat a third of your normal helpings each meal and just be totally fine all day. The reporting of ozempic face and stuff is because the person drops weight so fast that you notice it more versus dropping that weight over the course of a year. If someone lost weight from caloric restriction from sheer willpower, they’d get that drastic face change too, but they’re gonna be in agony while doing it because it’s such major diet change.</p><p>Same with the muscle mass loss. You get the same muscle mass loss from caloric restriction. However, it could be pointed out that if the weight was lost more slowly, you could exercise and keep the muscle mass from losing by building it up faster than you lose it from losing weight.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/nendbp3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>It doesn&#39;t significantly affect metabolism. </p><p>So if you took two similar people like a pair of identical twins, they have the exact same food intake, but one is taking ozempic and the other is not - they would have the same outcomes. </p><p>Ozempic (and similar drugs) effectively suppresses hunger. People taking them in appropriate doses still feel hunger, but it is satisfied with relatively small quantities of food, and they do not get hungry again for longer periods of time. </p><p>People say it turns off &quot;food noise&quot; - that little voice in your head that encourages you to eat when you&#39;re not really hungry. </p><p>My partner is taking Mounjaro, a drug similar to Ozempic. She still eats normal meals, but towards the end of a meal she starts feeling a little nauseous, which maker her want to stop eating. It also makes her much less prone to cravings and snacking. Within a couple of days of her first dose, the difference was obvious.</p><p>She has previously struggled with extreme cravings and a compulsion to binge-eat. Now she doesn&#39;t really think about food until our regular meal times, and isn&#39;t really interested in snacking between meals.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neoeole/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Pretty much, they mimic a hormone (GLP-1) that helps regulate appetite and slows digestion. So yeah, part of it is feeling full sooner, but there’s also an effect on blood sugar and insulin that helps with weight loss. If two people ate the exact same calories, the one on Ozempic might still have an edge because of how their body processes food differently. ucofo. com has a plain breakdown of how GLP-1s work if you want a quick read.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neoqxnm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I see you&#39;re in the UK. Ozempic is not licensed for weight loss in the UK and is a T2DM medication. If interested, consider wegovy (cheaper) or mounjaro (more effective).</p><p>Source: Weight management specialist dietitian</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neoke38/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>More than suppressing hunger, ozempic has done wonders fo my blood sugar.  I never thought I&#39;d see the day when my blood sugar hit below 100 mg/dl</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neox45r/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>So, I have a food addiction. My A1C was high, so my doctor prescribed me Ozempic along with my Metformin to get it down. Being a food addict, I normally never get hungry because (surprise) I&#39;m usually eating a lot. While Ozempic hasn&#39;t totally killed the desire to eat, it has made me feel full faster. I think it&#39;s doing it&#39;s job. lol. </p><p>Not a medical person by any stretch of the imagination, just giving my input as someone who uses it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/nen9kn6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>GLP1’s help with insulin resistance and lower blood sugar levels in diabetics.  Insulin resistance is associated with PCOS and other hormone issues like gestational diabetes or liver issues </p><p>If a person with insulin resistance ate the same reduced calories as some with no insulin resistance they would lose less weight</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nj2hsb/eli5_how_does_ozempic_or_other_weight_loss_jabs/neorz9x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 09:02:38 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/</link><title>ELI5: How did people clip their fingernails 1000 years ago?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Did they just chew them off every time?</p><p>Did pretty much every man have a beard at all times? When did it become normal to shave your face down to the skin?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>1000 years ago? There were plenty of advanced societies with steel and iron tools. You can shave just fine with a sharp knife though it&#39;s trickier, hence barbers existing as well as specialized blades. In fact clean shaven faces were popular throughout history, greeks and romans shaved during different periods. But other cultures may have not. It became a military need during ww1 due to gas masks not sealing properly but otherwise it&#39;s been about fashion not lack of tools</p><p>As for fingernails, same thing. Manicures for higher classes have been a thing for a good 5000 years. You can make decent small shears or specialty tools out of hard stones and bronze. Not as convenient or fast as nail clippers, but they didn&#39;t have much going on.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemo69z/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Chimpanzees and other primates also have fingernails. They typically trim their fingernails by biting them off when they get too long or damaged, a behavior that can be a natural part of their grooming routine. Their active daily lives, which involve climbing and digging, also contribute to natural nail wear and tear that keeps them short. </p><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1mylf6/how_do_chimps_take_care_of_their_nails/">https://www.reddit.com/r/askscience/comments/1mylf6/how_do_chimps_take_care_of_their_nails/</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemtxjq/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>we have had steel/iron blades for 3000 years, bronze blades for 4700 years, and flint blades for <del>5500</del> 3.3 Million years.  </p><p>1000 years they just used a knife (or a kinda sheer shaped scissor (or even a special nail clipper like thing, good history section on the wikipedia <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nail_clipper">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nail_clipper</a> ))  and razor.</p><p>Shaving has been common for centuries, the ancient Egyptians would use shaving to separate classes as you would need money and time to get a good shave.</p><p>Now before that, say 10,000 years ago, yah long hair and beards.  as for fingernails, if you actually do hard work every day they are mostly self maintaining, and you can just chew them as you noted.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemodin/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>1000 years ago was medieval times. Humans had small scissors and tools which they used to trim nails, but also many people bit/chewed them as well.</p><p>If you’re wondering about pre-tool eras of human society, it was a combo of biting/chewing, wear and tear and occasionally scraping on rocks and rough surfaces - similar to what apes do today.</p><p>As for being fully shaven, that depends on the civilization and their cultural norms - but Ancient Egyptians have been shaving since almost 3000 BC.</p><p>In Ancient Rome it became fashionable to shave during the times of Christ - around 0 AD - (you often see ancient Roman statues depicting young men with clean shaven faces).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nempq1q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The first spring scissors were found in ancient Egypt 4000 years ago. The first two bladed pivot style scissors were a Roman invention around 100AD. </p><p>so how did people cut hair and nails 1000 or even 2000 years ago? Pretty much the same way we do. </p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nenh1qn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>I’m the only person I know that does this, but I peel my fingernails off</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/neou6gu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You don’t have to clip your nails, you can file them down with a rock. Trimming a beard can be accomplished with a sharp rock. You’re not going to shave yourself down to the skin with a rock, but you can definitely trim your beard.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nizm4s/eli5_how_did_people_clip_their_fingernails_1000/nemoatr/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 06:44:17 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/</link><title>ELI5 Why do humans live so much longer than other mammals?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Mammals under our care typically live longer than their wild counterparts parts too. </p><p>The wild isn’t easy. Animals eat anything mildly palatable good or bad for them because they need calories for survival. </p><p>Humans are smart. We constantly learn more about what is good or bad for our health, develop healthcare and ways to treat ailments, etc. </p><p>If another species gained our level of intelligence and development we would also most likely see their lifespans significantly increase in a similar way. Being smart lets us optimize our bodies</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/neldo1k/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>A cat can reproduce when it&#39;s 4 months old. Animals generally live at a minimum long enough until they can have grandchildren (so the species can survive). That takes 30 years or so for humans.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nelg19o/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>because we grow slowly, have big brains that help us solve problems, protect ourselves from predators, and invent medicine and technology. We also live in groups and take care of each other, which makes it easier to survive into old age.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/neld3ck/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because when we get old and slow, we sit down and play bingo while a nursing home takes care of us.</p><p>When animals get old and slow, they get eaten</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nelf3fn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We don’t. </p><p>Relatively speaking. Other great apes have similar lifespans. Comparing us to rodents or ungulates or whatever else is apples to oranges.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nem4psc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The big ones are modern medicine, vaccines, antibiotics and people who are wiling to feed you while you are healing. In the modern era: over 99% of people born in an advanced economy make it to puberty. For the entire world 95% born make it to puberty.</p><p>For comparison purposes:</p><p>Before modern medicine, the fatality rate for children was ruthlessly high: 1/3 of all live birth children died by age one. And 50% were dead by age 10. Less than half made it to puberty. And by age 40 only a third of each generation was still alive. </p><p>Brett Devereuax (a roman historian with a very good blog) has been working on a series about how peasants lived before the modern era. I am linking to his section on death. It is worth the read and expands on the comments I made above.</p><p><a href="https://acoup.blog/2025/07/18/collections-life-work-death-and-the-peasant-part-ii-starting-at-the-end/">https://acoup.blog/2025/07/18/collections-life-work-death-and-the-peasant-part-ii-starting-at-the-end/</a></p><p>I am only linking to one part of the series, but please take the time to read the rest of it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nen6as4/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Doesn&#39;t the speed of metabolism some how dictates how long we can live?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nitj20/eli5_why_do_humans_live_so_much_longer_than_other/nelvgc7/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 02:25:43 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/</link><title>ELI5: Why do phones and EVs say to keep the battery around 20-80%? What's physically happening at the extremes that wears batteries faster?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>I often see tips to avoid 0% and 100% on lithium batteries to make them last longer. Can you explain, in simple terms, what’s going on inside the battery near empty and near full that makes those levels rough on it?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>Take a deep breath. Super deep, keep trying to breath in more and you can even take a teeny tiny breath on top of your big one, but it’s really hard to do.<br/>That’s why charging over 80% is bad, it takes a lot more effort to cram in those last electrons into the battery because it’s so full, and that causes more wear on the battery.</p><p>Now let’s slowly exhale that breath. Keep breathing out steadily. Once you run out of air keep trying to blow. That last bit of air is really hard to push out.<br/>That is why discharging below 20% is bad, it takes a lot more effort to squeeze out those last electrons from the battery because there are so few, and that causes more wear on the battery.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejriyt/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>may I ask: is this still valid. with today&#39;s technology?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nek2jzc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>While I understand the concept,</p><p>Why can’t manufacturers just claim a 3000mah battery is only 2,400mah (80% of 3000mah). With a software limitation of only charging up to 2,400mah and representing that as the ‘100%’ and also presenting 600mah (20% of 3000mah) as the battery being at ‘0%’ ?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejtnzb/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Why don’t they just change the percentage of the battery to keep them where they need to be?</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejvkd5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Above 80%, further charging probably causes a small amount of electrolyte breakdown, and the products start forming a film on one of the terminals.  The effect is more pronounced when hot, so charging above 80% while hot is probably the worst thing to reduce battery life. </p><p>Below 20% is not inherently damaging, but batteries self discharge over time even if unused.  If it gets too low, your typical smart chargers may not see enough voltage on the battery to recognize it and start charging it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejsrav/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Think of a Li-ion battery cell like a ballon. If it gets too full, it can pop. If it gets too empty, it can stick together and make it hard to fill up again. Also, the process of going from 0% to 100% and back down to 0% puts a lot of stress on the cell, meaning it can&#39;t hold as much in future.</p><p>If you stick between 20% and 80%, it puts less stress on the battery so it can retain the max charge capacity for longer.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejqna3/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Every time you sit on a chair or stand up - it rubs the fabric on the chair and &#39;wears&#39; it out a bit.</p><p>Charging a battery causes electrons to &#39;attach&#39; themselves to plates.</p><p>Using a battery causes the electrons to &#39;detach&#39; themselves to plates.</p><p>This causes wear or &#39;degradation&#39; of the plates in the battery.  Very similar to people sitting up/down/up/down on chairs in say an airplane.</p><p>With me so far?</p><p>A &#39;high state of charge&#39; battery has electrons over most of the surface.  Like magnets - these electrons repel each other and as temp changes or just sitting there - the charged electrons &#39;get up&#39; and move to some less dense place.</p><p>A &#39;low state of charge&#39; battery also has electrons that decide to get up and move around.</p><p>A battery with a 50% charge tends to have less spontaneous movement of electrons. This results in less wear just sitting there.</p><p>Hope this helps.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nilvfp/eli5_why_do_phones_and_evs_say_to_keep_the/nejsvcm/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:43:44 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/</link><title>ELI5: Why does it take forever for hot water to reach the shower?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Every morning I turn on the shower and wait like two minutes before the water is hot. It’s the same with the sink. Honestly, those two minutes aren’t the worst though I usually just check my phone or play some slots on grizzly’s quest while I’m waiting. Where is the water “waiting” in those two minutes? Why can’t it just be hot right away?</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>The water in the hot water heater is hot.  The water in the pipes in between the hot water heater and your shower has cooled down since the last time you used it.  It takes time for the hot water to push all that cold water out.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7kzv/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You can add a circulation pump to your hot water line to so the hot water slowly circulates through the house and back into the water heater so the hot water gets to the faucet quicker.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/neiasth/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>If you have a mixer style tap, try setting the mix to 100% hot until the water gets hot otherwise you aren&#39;t allowing the existing cold water in the hot pipe to clear at full flow rate. You are also just wasting the water from the cold pipe while you wait for the hot to come through.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei8npc/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How far away is your shower from the water heater and do you have a tank or tankless system ? </p><p>If you have a tank the hot water is literally waiting there until you turn on a hot water source.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7jr2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Depends on your plumbing setup. In many homes there&#39;s a hot water tank. That&#39;s where the water is waiting. There are pipes between the tank and your fixtures. Water cools off it out sits in the pipes. If those pipes are long and/or large diameter, you have to clear out a whole bunch of cold water from the pipes until the hot can get to you.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7pqf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You know when you drink Coke with a straw, it takes a moment of sucking before it reaches your mouth? The longer the straw, the longer it takes.</p><p>Getting hot water in the shower is similar: long pipe, long wait. And if the system needs time to heat (depends on heating setup), the first water coming through won’t be warm anyway.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nejlnd6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>How far away from your water heater is your shower? The water has to travel that distance… on a low flow shower head, it can take a while to use up the cold water sitting in the pipes.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1niema5/eli5_why_does_it_take_forever_for_hot_water_to/nei7oqk/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 16:47:53 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/</link><title>ELI5: How are cured meats, like sausages made from raw meat safe to eat?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>How come those are safe to eat even though they&#39;re made from raw meat? Like, at what point of its making depending on the sausage, do all the bacteria die and how?</p><p>edit: Solved. Thank y&#39;all.</p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>They use a curing agent of some sort, and often involve the removal of most or all of the moisture from the meat, thus making it a hostile environment for harmful bacteria. </p><p>Essentially, they turn the meat too salty and dry for anything harmful to survive.  Kind of like a meat desert.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg0q87/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>if you think that&#39;s crazy, look up edible mold on sausages and cheeses. Basically mold that&#39;s not harmful to us, and makes food tastier, is out competing other molds that would be harmful to us</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg1w36/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>the curing process.</p><p>in general, you add &quot;curing salt&quot; which is regular table salt plus some amount of potassium or sodium nitrate (KNO3/NaNO3) and potassium or sodium nitrite (KNO2/NaNO2). the nitrite wards off <em>C. botulinum</em> (causes botulism) and other bacteria, then lactic acid bacteria reduce nitrate to nitrite over time to give you a time-released dose of anti-microbial action. nitrite also gets reduced further to nitric oxide (NO) which permanently binds myoglobin, preventing discoloration which is why cured meats stay nice and pink instead of turning brown.</p><p>the salt itself also removes moisture. once the water activity of the meat is below a certain point, it&#39;s shelf-stable, so the curing salts are just to prevent pathogen growth in the mean time while the meat dries. some styles like salami also use bacterial and fungal cultures similar to cheesemaking to add stability and flavor as well.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg3q76/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>They use a lot of salt, the salt dries the meat and germs can’t survive due to the low moisture environment.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg0u2x/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Low moisture and high salt.</p><p>This is why drying stuff is effective at preserving. Bacteria need water to survive. And when you add salt, it sucks the water out of bacteria, it creates this double hostile environment.</p><p>Raw meat&#39;s danger comes from the pathogen like bacteria and parasite. The longer they stay out, the more of them there is from multiplying.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg0ywi/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>You don&#39;t always need heat to make meat safe.  Anything like salt or acid can kill the microorganisms and prevent them from growing.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/neg18cs/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Prague powder, a pink salt, is mixed in with the rest of the salt when you&#39;re getting ready to cure some meat/fish. It contains some sodium nitrite, which kills a lot of bacteria. Whether the nitrites themselves have downsides health-wise is a point of contention, I think it&#39;s a tiny amount and the government generally says it&#39;s safe to eat.</p><p>Curing salmon and then smoking it to make lox is fun and surprisingly easy. Just make gravlax once, which is like the laziest process, and then next time add a cold smoking step. Fun.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1ni3dmm/eli5_how_are_cured_meats_like_sausages_made_from/negdfak/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 06:16:46 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/</link><title>Eli5 Why don't we just drill really deep holes to let extra floodwater soak back into the ground?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p>Reading time: 1 min | <a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-after-permalink'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='selftext'><!-- SC_OFF --><div class="md"><p>Edit: Thank you all so much for taking the time to reply. I really appreciate the way you explained so simply and clearly and I truly learned from your responses. </p></div><!-- SC_ON --></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>We kind of do, these are called &quot;sumps&quot;, and depending on where you live, you might actually have lots of them around - they usually look like 1/2 acre sized fields that are slightly lower than surrounding areas and usually fenced off. Where I grew up they are very common, easily 1 per neighborhood. </p><p>There are two goals here - A. letting surface water drain into the Earth which is much better ecologically than polluting near by streams, lakes, and oceans. B. recharging local aquifers (underground water sources), though this takes much more time than human-scale changes will effect (thousands and thousands of years).</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necbo1p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>We dig really wide holes instead (retention ponds) because that&#39;s a bit easier, less dangerous (people won&#39;t accidentally fall in), and looks better.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necbwe0/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>In regions prone to flooding, groundwater can often be found at as little as 10m underground.</p><p>If you wanted to clear 30cm of water from 1km square of flooded land, you&#39;d need a 1x1m hole that&#39;s 300m deep, which couldn&#39;t work becaude of aforementioned groundwater level.</p><p>Much easier to do what we already do: Dig big, wide ponds for runoff to let it drain into the groundwater.</p><p>Edit: Listen to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/u/Malcopticon">/u/Malcopticon</a></p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necclz5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>That is basically what storm drains and similar systems are. Japan has some very extensive flood management systems with huge underground tunnels.</p><p>The problem with just digging holes straight down is that then all the runoff and other pollutants the floodwaters pick up along the way go straight into the groundwater without being filtered by the ground itself. Then there&#39;s also the difficulty of maintaining however many huge holes you&#39;d need safely.</p><p>Edit: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metropolitan_Area_Outer_Underground_Discharge_Channel">This is one of the tunnels in Japan to which I referred.</a> It very much evokes the Mines of Moria to me.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necbu42/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Lots of good points about ground saturation - another is that groundwater (aquifiers) are commonly clean water sources. This naturally occurs as water percolates though the soil and rock which filters out contaminants. You do not want surface water to directly feed into groundwater.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necfd8p/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Because the soil is already saturated with water, and because you wouldn&#39;t be able to drill a hole large enough or deep enough to handle a tremendous amount of water that makes up a flood. I mean, you&#39;re talking about millions and millions of gallons of water.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necc0o2/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>There are 2 possible issues with flood water. The first one, is that it is not absorbed because the ground is already saturated and the water line is above ground. So digging a hole would change nothing as this hole is already full of water. The second one is that the ground can has properties that makes it hard to absorb water (either super dry, made of clay/rocks that absorb water super slowly, etc...). So digging a hole would only allow this hole to be filled quickly but the ground would not absorb that water more quickly. So you would need to dig a shit ton of holes to even be able to displace a very tiny amount of floodwater. If the ground was not saturated and can absorb water quickly, floodwater would disappear almost at the same speed with deep holes or not.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nhln57/eli5_why_dont_we_just_drill_really_deep_holes_to/necc0vn/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 18:49:24 +0530</pubDate></item><item><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/</link><title>ELI5: why is tobacco pipe, which is usually made from wood, not getting burned up when the tobacco is literally burning into ashes inside the pipe?</title><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/</guid><comments>https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/</comments><description><![CDATA[<section class='reading-time-and-permalink'><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/'>Post permalink</a></p></section><section class='separator separator-before-comments'><p>&nbsp;</p><hr><p>&nbsp;</p></section><section class='comments'><p>Top comments</p><ol><li><div class="md"><p>It will burn a small amount but the tobacco doesn&#39;t get hot enough for long enough to cause the wood to actually light on fire.</p><p>And the small bit of burning will cause a layer of carbon to build up on the walls of the pipe, protecting the wood underneath from further burning</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/ne9kfl6/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tobacco pipe smoker here.</p><p>Sometimes it DOES burn through the wood. But if that happens, you&#39;re smoking too hot, or there is a flaw in the wood or pipe design (usually cheap pipes). It&#39;s typically not getting hot enough to catch the wood on fire. It&#39;s a pretty rare occurrence.</p><p>Tobacco pipes are most often made from Briar Wood, which is the very dense root ball material of the Heath bush that grows in the Mediterranean. This wood is used for pipes specifically because it is resistant to burning.</p><p>Also the pipe smoker will usually leave a layer of ash &amp; resin on the walls of the bowl to act as a bit of insulation for this purpose, rather than cleaning the pipe bowl out to the bare wood regularly.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/ne9mlwf/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>The tobacco will burn in the bowl of the pipe, and you suck the smoke from the burning tobacco through the stem.</p><p>As to why it doesn&#39;t burn the pipe:</p><ol><li>It does, it just deposits residue (mostly ash) inside the bowl and stem of the pipe. You have to clean this out regularly, using a reamer to clean the bowl and a pipe-cleaner (guess why it has the name) to clean the stem, although leaving some ash inside the bowl is usually a good thing, since it acts as an insulator against heat</li><li>Its not super-hot for very long, usually just as you draw on the pipe (which sucks air through the bowl-and-stem, causing the smoldering tobacco to burn), and so long as you aren&#39;t sucking down pipe after pipe as fast as you can (which will likely make you sick, so don&#39;t try this), you can manage the heat fairly well</li></ol></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/ne9lffu/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Tobacco pipes are made of heat resistant wood like briar, corncob, or clay, so the combustion temperature of the pipe is usually higher than that of tobacco.  The design of the pipe also starves the inside of oxygen and expels heat quickly- the tobacco can smolder inside, but there&#39;s not enough oxygen for it to really start burning simply because air can&#39;t be drawn in from the narrow end of the pipe quick enough, and the bowl helps block air from coming into the big end since the smoldering releases smoke which helps to displace the air.  When you blow air in, you put more oxygen in, but you also blow the heat <em>out</em>, so the temperature stays down.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/ne9kl3q/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Pipe smoker here.</p><p>The quickest and easiest bit of information to convey is that the bottom third or so of the tobacco isn&#39;t typically smoked. Sure, people who are really really skilled can smoke the tobacco down to where there is only ash, but most folks leave a bit of &quot;dottle&quot; in the bottom of the pipe. Tobacco produces moisture as it burns, and most of the moisture goes up in smoke, but some sinks, as well as some of the oils that make the tobacco smell and taste. As it concentrates in the bottom of the pipe, the additional water and oils are less likely to burn.</p><p>When most folks tap out a pipe, the resulting material is mostly ash on top, but there&#39;s definitely unburned tobacco on the bottom.</p><p>That said, most of the heat escapes upwards, as well as most of the flame.</p><p>Finally, the material that is used for tobacco pipes is not wood usually. It looks like wood, but is actually briar, which is a very dense material with a much higher burning temperature than wood. With exposure to heat, the briar hardens. With exposure to smoke, the walls of the pipe become coated over time with &quot;cake&quot; which is essentially a mix of ash and oils from the smoke. The cake helps preserve and fireproof the walls of the pipe.</p><p>A well smoked well loved pipe will develop cake on the bottom of the pipe as well as the sides because of the drawing of smoke through the pipe into the stem. The cured bottom of the pipe is unlikely to burn unless it has flaws.</p><p>Because of this, a new pipe requires careful smoking at first, as it breaks in. Some pipe makers will coat the inside of the pipe, especially the bottom of the bowl, to give it additional protection during the break in period.</p><p>Breaking in a new pipe is a lot like breaking in a new car -- don&#39;t let it get too hot, let it go out periodically if it is getting hot, don&#39;t smoke full bowls, smoke partial bowls -- and even doing things like covering the top of the bowl when done and shaking the pipe up and down so the ash and dottle go around the inside of the pipe, helping with the cake building process.</p><p>(Just like a new car will often tell you not to rev it over a given RPM or to not drive it over a certain speed for the first 1,000 or 3,000 miles.)</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/ne9oeq5/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Get a lighter and try to set a tree on fire for a few seconds. Nothing but maybe a patch of charred wood. Get a lighter and try to set patch of dried leaves on fire. You get fire. </p><p>This is why you typically use kindling to start a fire and use wood to sustain it.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/nec96l1/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p><p>&nbsp;</p></li><li><div class="md"><p>Here&#39;s a different way to explain it.  Everything has an ignition temperture.  A certain temp. that it will ignite on fire when exposed to heat.  If you put a piece of paper in your oven and turn it up to about 450 degrees, the paper will bust into flames and burn up.  But the stove will be fine.  The metal that makes up the stove has a much higher ignition temperature and the paper will burn up well before the flames reach that higher ignition temperature.  Same thing with tobacco leaves vs. wood.</p><p>Fun fact:  Now you know where the book &quot;Fahrenheit 451&quot; got it&#39;s title from; the temp, that a book will burn.</p></div><p><a href='https://www.reddit.com/r/explainlikeimfive/comments/1nh7fh4/eli5_why_is_tobacco_pipe_which_is_usually_made/neaseqs/'><small>Comment permalink</small></a></p></li></ol></section>]]></description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 05:52:39 +0530</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
